<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.11.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/14/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 10/26/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton Spectator</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-11-18">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.11.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Reliance Upon God</head>
                <origin>Chattanooga Rebel</origin>
                <commentary>The Chattanooga <emph rend="italic">Rebel</emph> has the following:</commentary>
                <excerpt>"Our soldiers are fighting in a just and holy cause and we must, if we
                    desire success, put our trust in the God of Battles, whilst at the same time we
                    use all the human means necessary to accomplish the great purposes for which we
                    commenced this struggle."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Nothing is more evident in this war than that those Generals who put their
                        trust in God are the most fortunate and the most successful. Almost every
                        victory has been won under the lead of Generals who feared God, but not man,
                        whilst almost every defeat has been under Generals who were not God-honoring
                        and God-serving men. We know there are some who think and assert that the
                        Almighty has nothing to do with this contest, and that a wicked and profane
                        General, if he is a brave man and skillful officer, can accomplish as much
                        as one of piety and reverence.--Facts do not sustain this opinion. We admit
                        that no matter how pious a General may be, if he has no capacity and no
                        courage, he can not be expected to win victories; but if other things be at
                        all equal, the General who trusts in God will always prove the more
                        successful, as the history of this war has thus far clearly demonstrated.</p>
                    <p>Lee and Jackson are the two great Generals of the War, by common consent, and
                        they are the two men most remarkable for their religious elevation.
                        Beauregard, too, who, we are satisfied, is one of the great men of this
                        revolution is a man who feels his dependence on an Almighty Power. We could
                        mention several other bright and shining examples of men of this discription
                        [sic]. On the contrary, where have we sustained a signal defeat that a
                        General, who was notoriously a profane swearer or a drunkard was not highest
                        in command? We admit that sometimes wicked men may gain victories, but these
                        are the exceptions and not the general rule. Congress has passed an act
                        making drunkenness among officers a ground for their removal; and yet, are
                        there no high officers who get drunk and are not punished? The Army
                        Regulations say:</p>
                    <p>ART 3. "Any non-commissioned officer or soldier who shall use any profane
                        oath or execration, shall incur the penalties expressed in the foregoing
                        article; and a commissioned officer shall forfeit and pay for each and every
                        offence, one dollar, to be applied as in the preceding article." (That is to
                        the use of the sick.)</p>
                    <p>Now, if officers of high rank get drunk and use profane language, can they
                        expect anything else from the privates; and is it right to punish private
                        soldiers for following the examples set them by their officers? We have been
                        struck by the remarks maee [sic] by General Stuart in the latter part of his
                        report in reference to his expedition into Pennsylvania. He says:</p>
                    <p>"Believing that the hand of God was clearly manifested in the signal
                        deliverance of my command from danger, and the crowning success attending
                        it, I ascribe to Him the praise, the honor and the glory."</p>
                    <p>We are engaged in war with an enemy greatly superior to us in numbers and in
                        resources, who are mad with rage and disappointment. Our soldiers are
                        fighting in a just and holy cause and we must, if we desire success, put our
                        trust in the God of Battles, whilst at the same time we use all the human
                        means necessary to accomplish the great purposes for which we commenced this
                        struggle.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the generals who follow God have been the luckiest and the most
                    successful. Points to Lee, Jackson, and Beauregard, in particular, as examples
                    of this phenomenon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Speculators and Demagogues</head>
                <origin>Raleigh Standard</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Avarice among our merchants, farmers, and manufacturers and speculators,
                    is at the bottom of it, and it is a viper gnawing at the vitals of the country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are but two classes of persons in the North or South who are anxious
                        for the continuance of this wicked, unnecessary and destructive war. It is
                        stated among the thousand rumors, that Gen. McClellan recently remarked,
                        that were it not for the demagogues, General Lee and himself could end the
                        war at once. We place but little confidence in the rumor, yet of the
                        correctness of the remark attributed to him, we have no doubt.</p>
                    <p>The war was inaugurated and has been persevered in mainly through the bad
                        counsels of trading demagogues and merciless speculators and extortioners,
                        whose sole aim has been a selfish purpose to secure place and profit. The
                        peculation and speculation which have been carried on at the North have
                        saddled that Government with a debt which it will never pay; and the
                        official thefts and extravagant speculation upon the government and the
                        people of the South, have risen to such a pitch as to threaten our army and
                        people with starvation and consequent subjugation.</p>
                    <p>We have said repeatedly, that the speculation and extortion now practiced in
                        the South are doing more to hasten our subjugation than everything else
                        beside. Every thoughtful person in the country not involved in the high
                        crime of beggaring the people and the government, must see it. Look at the
                        deadening, chilling effect of this speculating mania upon the large masses
                        of the people whose sons and brothers are in the army. Every one is
                        melancholy and dejected, not at the ill success of our arms, but at the
                        certain disaster which is being brought upon the country by the speculators.
                        No one is cheerful but them. They "have never seen better times," they say,
                        they "have never made so much money before."</p>
                    <p>Many of these land sharks enjoy shade offices under the Confederate
                        government, and many others were among the most noisy advocates for
                        secession. They nor their sons have gone into the war, and do not intend to.
                        A day's or a week's speculation can pay for substitutes, whose blood may be
                        spilled as water, and what do they care? Verily, Yankee bayonets and ball
                        are not so effectually conquering as they are. The worst enemies of the
                        Confederacy are those who speculate upon salt, flour, bacon, corn, leather,
                        cotton and woollen goods. Many have suddenly become rich, both Jews and
                        Gentiles, and they have no concern except to keep the war raging that they
                        may make money. And what is to be the result, if they continue it? Is not
                        the overthrow of the South the inevitable consequence? What earthly power
                        can prevent our being overrun by the Yankee hordes, if this state of things
                        continue? And yet they cry, "All is well." Our victories and advantages
                        gained over the enemy are magnified by them, and when our reverses become
                        glaring, they talk of speedy "foreign intervention."</p>
                    <p>Let them be put down. Patriotism, humanity and the salvation of the country
                        demand it, and let it be done speedily. There is no good reason under heaven
                        why salt, and flour, and bacon, and corn, and leather, and cotton and woolen
                        goods, should demand the present prices. Avarice--avarice among our
                        merchants, farmers and manufacturers and speculators, is at the bottom of
                        it, and it is a viper gnawing at the vitals of the country.--Raleigh
                        Standard.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns speculators for perpetuating the war for their own profits and
                    argues that without speculators and the demagogues, the war would end at once.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Proclamation of Governor Letcher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a proclamation in which the Governor appeals to the people of the
                    state to help provide clothing for the soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Speculation and Extortion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The rage to run up prices is going to ruin us if anything does."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blames speculators and exorbitant prices for the crippling of the
                    Confederacy. Suggests that there is no stopping this "evil" and expresses
                    limited satisfaction in the notion that at least if the Confederacy is ruined,
                    these "money-makers" will perish with the cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Confederates in the Hospital at Sharpsburg</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the level of care of the Confederate wounded who are in the hands
                    of the North at Sharpsburg, Pennsylvania, as equal to that of wounded Union
                    soldiers at the North. Relates an individual case of a soldier who suffers from
                    a gunshot wound.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-4; poetry, column 5; war news, column 6; article
                giving the background of acting Brigadier General Reynolds, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.11.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lieut. Col. Doyle fight with the Enemy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes a battle in Hardy County involving Augusta troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Scripture Applicable to these Times</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes scriptural injunctions against speculating. Warns that those who
                    "exact exorbitant prices for what they have to sell" may be cursed and their
                    country along with them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Shoes for our Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Anything is better than marching through snow bare-footed."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that in one corps of the army, 2,600 men are going without shoes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The poor Negroes who fall into the hands of the Yankees are certain to see
                    hard times."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Yankees intend to put the "captured or stolen negroes of the
                    Confederacy" to work in coal mines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Court Relief of Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses the hope that the magistrates of the court will see fit to
                    appropriate additional money to the care of the soldiers' families in Staunton.
                    Also urges that private individuals make contributions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Colonel Imboden's Cavalry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the exploits of Colonel Imboden's command prior to the fight in
                    Hardy County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Yankee Soldiers Sick of the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The truth is that nine-tenths of the army want peace."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Northern soldiers, Republicans and Democrats alike, rejoiced
                    at the news of Democratic victories in the recent elections. Claims that the
                    troops want peace and that they are also dissatisfied with the war because they
                    do not receive pay for serving in the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Yankee Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that 236 Yankee prisoners passed through Staunton on their way to
                    Richmond the previous week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"For more than twelve months, I have become thoroughly convinced, that the
                    present war which the North is waging against us is not for the restoration of
                    the union nor the liberation of the negroes, but for the gratification of a
                    malignant hate towards the people of the South, and an indomitable love of gain
                    by obtaining possession of our lands and personal property."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Citizen</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disparages both Northern and Southern speculators.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Another Step Towards Independence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the editor's visit to the shop of Augusta citizen Harman Lushbaugh,
                    who has invented a shoe-peg machine. He is held up as an example of Southern
                    manufacturing abilities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Supple</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints resolutions adopted by the Augusta Gray's on the death of Thomas A.
                    Supple.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William A. Burnett and Kate Woodward were married on November 12 in
                    Staunton. Miss Woodward is the daughter of Samuel M. Woodward, all of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>William Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Samuel Curry, one year of age, died in Augusta County. No date or
                    cause of death is given.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report that General A. B. Burnside has taken the place of General McClellan as
                commander of the army of the Potomac, column 2; battlefield reports, columns 4 and
                5; notices and advertisements, columns 6 and 7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
