<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.10.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12.13.95</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-10-28">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.10.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Condition of our Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It becomes the duty of those at home whose lives and property they are
                    defending...to furnish them with good clothing to protect them against the war
                    of the elements."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The attention of the country has been directed to the destitute conditions of
                        the Army of Northwestern Virginia, by a recent letter from the correspondent
                        of the Savannah "Republican," which we thought it our duty to reproduce in
                        these columns, which we did, some days ago. We refer to the subject again
                        not for the purpose of finding fault with the Government, though it has been
                        guilty of the most unpardonable neglect, but to remind the people of their
                        duty in the premises. Our information is derived from persons who have been
                        with the army for some months, and whose opportunities have been such as to
                        leave no doubt as to the correctness of their statements.</p>
                    <p>The health, zeal and discipline of the army are all that the most sanguine
                        friend of our holy cause could desire. Since their return to Virginia the
                        troops have had ample time to rest and recruit their strength, and their
                        supplies of beer and flour are abundant. The stragglers and absentees,
                        including many of the sick and wounded, have rejoined their several
                        commands, and the army is stronger to-day, in numbers, than it has been at
                        any time since it left the banks of James river. But it is not of the
                        discipline, the health, or the Commissary Department of the army that we
                        propose to speak today, but of the destitute condition of the troops in
                        regard to clothing and shoes.</p>
                    <p>What, then, is their condition? We assert most emphatically and positively,
                        that up to the 15th day of this month, it was most deplorable. We do not
                        mean to say that such was the condition of the entire army, or even a
                        majority of the troops, but that large numbers of them were barefooted, in
                        rags, and covered with vermin; and that those in the hospitals at Winchester
                        were the victims of the most cruel neglect. As already remarked, this
                        information comes to us from such sources and in so direct a way, that we
                        feel authorized to assert, in the most positive manner, that such is the sad
                        condition of large numbers of the troops from all the States--the glorious
                        conquerors, too, at Richmond, at Manassas, in the Valley, and in Maryland.
                        We are assured, moreover, that any other statement showing a more favorable
                        condition of the army, while it may be gratifying to the public, is a cruel
                        wrong to the troops themselves, in that, it may lead the people and the
                        authorities to slacken their efforts to furnish the necessary supplies.</p>
                    <p>It may be asked, how is it that the troops should have become thus suddenly
                        destitute?--The answer is readily given. Having marched from the James river
                        to the Rappahannock, they fought their way from that stream to the Potomac,
                        passed into Maryland, reduced Harper's Ferry, fought two great battles at
                        Boonsboro' Gap and Sharpsburg, engaged in numberless skirmishes, and
                        returned to Virginia, all in the space of one month. The weather was
                        extremely hot, and many of the men fell out by the way; others wore out
                        their shoes; and were unable to carry their baggage on barefeet over stony
                        turnpikes; whilst others stripped themselves of their knapsacks when they
                        went into the fight, and coming out at different places, were never able to
                        recover them. In the "wear and tear of battle," too, among the chapparel
                        [sic] and sharp rocks of the mountains, and along the hills and valleys,
                        many lost portions of the clothing they had on, and emerged from the
                        terrible conflict with little else than their trusty muskets and
                        cartridge-boxes. Indeed, we learn from a gentleman, who speaks from personal
                        observation, that it was no uncommon thing to pass men on the march whose
                        miserable outfit was not sufficient to cover their nakedness. Some were
                        without shirts, others had on only the dirty remnant of a pair of pants,
                        without shoes, and almost without caps or hats. Some were barefooted, others
                        had on ragged socks but no shoes, while one man he saw was destitute of cap
                        and shoes, and had had one leg of his pants torn entirely away! Let it be
                        remembered, too, that many of these troops, thus ragged and destitute, and
                        limping along on feet covered with stonebruises, had been reared up in
                        luxury, and accustomed to all the comforts which wealth and industry can
                        supply.</p>
                    <p>But, bad as is the condition of the men in camp, those who were wounded and
                        sent back to the hospitals are still more unfortunate. Surgeons and
                        medicines were sent up to Winchester, to which point most of the sick and
                        wounded were taken, but up to the 15th instant we are assured that the
                        Medical Department had not furnished a solitary cot, bedsack, sheet, pillow,
                        or change of clothing for these unfortunates. With the single exception of
                        the York Hospital, which was formerly occupied by the Yankees, and where
                        they had left a complete outfit of hospital furniture, the sick and wounded
                        were huddled together upon the dirty floor--in many instances without a wisp
                        of straw between their aching bones and the hard plank! At Hollingsworth
                        Grove large numbers were placed under tent fires, with nothing to protect
                        them against the cold night air and riving mountain mists. A few cases are
                        reported where the patients were as naked as babes just born, their scanty
                        clothing having been torn off to dress their wounds, and but for a blanket
                        borrowed from a comrade, they would have been wholly destitute of any
                        covering save the narrow fly that had been stretched above them! Such as
                        were fortunate enough to get into into [sic] private quarters were well
                        cared for; but even the most wealthy citizens of the town and country are
                        but illy prepared to provide for the sick and wounded. The lower valley of
                        the Shenandoah has been occupied alternately by one party or the other for
                        eighteen months; and the people have been stripped of almost every comfort.
                        Some of the good women of Winchester had established hospital kitchens, and
                        in Warrenton they even tore up their calico dresses to make bandages for the
                        sufferers; but with every disposition to assist the wounded, they found it
                        impossible, from a lack of means, to relieve their destitute condition.</p>
                    <p>We are further informed, that the agents of the Georgia Relief and Hospital
                        Association arrived at Warrenton and Winchester, with supplies of medicines,
                        bandages, splints, bed-sacks, sheets and clothing, several days in advance
                        of the Government supplies. These agents even walked from Rapidan station to
                        Warrenton--a distance of forty miles--in a day and a half, through the the
                        [sic] hot sun, and over the dusty roads; and the surgeon also carried on his
                        back his case of instruments. They proceeded at both places to look up the
                        sick and wounded from their own state; to place bed-sacks, filled with
                        straw, under them, furnish them with a change of clothing, and to do
                        whatever else they could to render them comfortable. They even supplied the
                        Government surgeons at Warrenton, with medicines, and at Winchester with
                        such hospital furniture as they could spare.</p>
                    <p>Now, if the State of Georgia can do this much for her sick and wounded
                        soldiers, why may not the Confederate Government, which has ample means and
                        power, do the same? How is it that an association, organized by
                        philanthropic citizens, and supported by the Legislature of one of our
                        sister States, is able to accomplish more, with less means, and in less
                        time, than the Government of the entire Confederacy? If this association can
                        procure bed-sacks, sheets, clothing, and other hospital furniture, why
                        cannot the Surgeon-General of the Confederate Government do the same? Can
                        the Surgeon-General answer this question? Have we so many able-bodied men in
                        the country, and are the lives of our seasoned soldiers of so little value
                        that we can thus afford to sacrifice them, either by sheer neglect, or the
                        adoption of a brutal system? The country demands an answer to these
                        questions, and no owlish silence or affected official dignity will satisfy
                        this public demand.</p>
                    <p>But enough for the present. We shall advert to this painful subject again. It
                        is but just to add, that the Government has at length begun to move in the
                        matter of supplies, and that clothing and shoes are being forwarded to
                        Winchester for the relief of the destitute. We design to give the
                        authorities full credit for what they have done and may yet do, not only
                        because it is right and proper, but in order that the people may see how
                        much will still be left for them to do.--<emph rend="italic">Richmond
                        Whig.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article exhorts readers to donate winter clothing to the soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Give to the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We hear some cold-hearted, selfish miserly creature say, 'Will the
                    Spectator never cease ding-donging about the condition of our army, and never
                    let us who are at home rest in peace?'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Once again, the Spectator urges readers to donate supplies to the army. The
                    Spectator also criticizes speculators who make money off the added need for
                    supplies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Let Justice be Done</head>
                <origin>Knoxville Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The course of the Governor of this state has been not only patriotic, but
                    energetic to an unusual degree."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator takes offense at the Register's contention that the Governor
                    of Virginia fell prey to factiousness in opposing the Conscription Bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Grand Movement in Kentucky</head>
                <origin>Greenville (Tenn) Banner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article contends that Gen. Bragg captured from the enemy and purchased from
                    the citizens in Kentucky enough to load a train of wagons forty miles long.
                    Among the booty is allegedly 1 million yards of good Kentucky jeans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Call for more Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports that, being authorized by the Conscription act, the
                    President has called into service all persons between 18 and 40 not exempt by
                    the provisions of the exemption bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Augusta Lee Rifles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>Robert D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosen</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>H. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphries</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Uriah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Griever</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mines</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubeck</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>Ferdinand</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layton</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>George C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>Cicero</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of Lilley's Augusta Lee Rifles who have been killed, wounded, or
                    died of disease.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Recognition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item asserts that foreign recognition of the Confederacy is forthcoming.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Narrow Escape of General Polk</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article alleges that General Polk rode up to what he thought was a
                    Confederate artillery position in order to stop their fire. It turned out to be
                    a Union position, but he made good his escape before discovered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Cat out of the Bag</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports a letter from William H. Vanpelt to his uncle Seward. The
                    letter, printed elsewhere in this issue, gives evidence that the Yankees
                    intentionally falsify battle reports to make them look victorious in the eyes of
                    foreign powers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports that the County Court has instructed the Committee to meet
                    to discuss making an additional appropriation to soldiers families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaines</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaines</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of Andrew Bear and Eliza Gaines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edwards</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shanholt</ln>
                        <fn>Harriot E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of James Edwards and Harriot Shanholt.</summary>
                <note>Bride's last name not clearly legible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Joseph Good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breene</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Mary Jane Breene.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Noah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Rebecca Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various battlefield reports. Col. 7 notices and ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.10.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The March to Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Transcript of a poem found in a dead Union soldier's pocket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various battlefield reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
