<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.12.23">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/12/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/14/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-12-23">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.12.23.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Salt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer questions the method currently being used for apportioning salt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and notices, columns 1-4; proclamation by the governor, column
                5; further account of the battle at Fredericksburg, sketches of the lives of
                Brigadier General Maxey Gregg of South Carolina and Brigadier General Thomas R. R.
                Cobb of Georgia (both died in battle), column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.12.23.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Battle at Fredricksburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The victory won by our gallant army at Fredericksburg, on Saturday, the
                    13th inst., was more decided and brilliant than the first accounts represent."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The victory won by our gallant army at Fredericksburg, on Saturday, the 13th
                        inst., was more decided and brilliant than the first accounts represented.
                        It was known then that the enemy had been repulsed with great loss--much
                        greater than they had inflicted upon us--but, it was not then known that
                        they had been crippled to such a degree as to be unable to renew the
                        engagement. Gen. Lee supposed the engagement would be renowned the next day,
                        and was prepared to give the enemy as hospitable a welcome as he had done
                        the day before. It is shown by the despatch of Gen. Burnside that he
                        intended to renew the struggle on Sunday morning, but for some good reason
                        the battle was not renewed, and, instead of fighting, his army was
                        countermarched, and recrossed to the North side of the Rappahannock on
                        Monday night. At 4 o'clock on Sunday morning Gen. Burnside sent the
                        following telegram to President Lincoln:</p>
                    <p>Headq'rs. Army of the Potomac, <lb/>4 A.M., 14th Dec. </p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the President of the United states:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>I have just returned form the field.--Our troops are all over the river, and
                        hold the Ridge out side of the town, and three miles below. We hope to carry
                        the Crest to-day. Our loss is heavy--say five thousand.</p>
                    <p>(Signed) A. E. Burnside, <lb/>Maj. Gen'l Comd'g. </p>
                    <p>This despatch is brief, but it serves to reveal more than Burnside
                        intended.--It shows that all of his troops were on the southern side of the
                        river, and not a part only as had been supposed, and it shows, also, that,
                        at 4 o'clock on Sunday morning, he intended to renew the fight, for he
                        expresses to Lincoln his hope of carrying the Crest to-day (Sunday).--The
                        "Crest" to which he alluded is still standing, but the <emph rend="italic"
                            >crest</emph> of Burnside has fallen, and he is now in a fair way to
                        follow all of his predecessors who attempted to reach Richmond--Scott,
                        McDowell, McClellan, and Pope.--"Jordan is a hard road to travel." </p>
                    <p>It is very evident that Burnside was prevented from renewing the fight, by
                        the fact that his army had been so badly whipped and demoralized that the
                        officers and men would not agree to go into battle again at that place. "The
                        burnt child dreads the fire." They were taught the day before the efficacy
                        of the <emph rend="italic">fire</emph> of Southern troops, and were not
                        willing to take another lesson in the same branch of knowledge. Our loss
                        will not exceed in killed and wounded, 1,800, or 2,000, whilst the loss of
                        the enemy is supposed to be between twelve and eighteen thousand. Their loss
                        is supposed to be eight times as great as ours. </p>
                    <p>A correspondent of the New York Herald, speaking of the casualties among the
                        Yankee officers, says:</p>
                    <p>"Gen. Bayard was killed in the battle, and his body sent to Washington.--He
                        was to have been married on the Wednesday following. Brigadier General
                        Conrad F. Jackson, of Pennsylvania, was also killed."</p>
                    <p>It seems that Burnside took good care of No. 1 on the day of the battle. He
                        was at the Phillip's House about a mile and a half from the river on the
                        Northern side, beholding the death struggle of his troops by means of a
                        large spy glass.--The fate of Fredericksburg is a sad one. The old town has
                        been battered by balls and shells from 273 cannon--it has been sacked and
                        plundered by the enemy, who wantonly destroyed everything they could lay
                        their worse than Vandal hands upon. We hope it will not be long before it
                        will arise from its ruins, like the fabled Phoenix from its ashes,
                        revivified by the terrible baptism of fire through which, with such a heroic
                        spirit, it has passed.</p>
                    <p>Gen. "Stonewall" Jackson, who many almost believe, leads a charmed life, had
                        a very narrow escape. He was watching the battle, and standing at the time
                        near an oak tree, when a bullet struck not more than two inches above his
                        head. The Old Hero continued his observations, unmoved by the incident."</p>
                    <p>Since the battle, the question asked by every one is, "Where is Burnside?" He
                        has disappeared as suddenly a the Sora. The Richmond Whig says the question
                        is--</p>
                    <p>Burnside, oh Burnside, whither dost thou wander, <lb/>Since you left
                        Fredericksburg and went over yonder? </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges a Confederate victory at Fredericksburg. The author's evidence is
                    that the Northern forces were not able to renew their attack according to plan,
                    because the "army had been so badly whipped and demoralized that the officers
                    and men would not agree to go into battle again at that place."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Casualties in the 52nd and 5th Regiments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hulet</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zirckle</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayfield</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drains</ln>
                        <fn>Ryland</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dabney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaver</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Childers</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Painter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rogers</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shifflet</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the casualties from the 52nd and 5th Va. Inf., which are comprised of
                    mostly Augusta troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Organization of the Second Regiment of Partisan Rangers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that another regiment consisting of ten companies has been
                    organized under Col. Imboden. The regiment will be the Second Regiment of
                    Partisan Rangers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We understand that the draft for slaves from this county will take place on
                        Wednesday (to-morrow) at the Court House at 11 o'clock, and slave owners
                        desiring to be present to witness the draft can do so.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the draft for slaves will take place Wednesday at the Court
                    House. Adds that "slave owners desiring to be present to witness the draft" may
                    do so.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rucker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Dr. Rucker's trial, being held in Fincastle for the past two
                    weeks, will be concluded at the next term of Circuit Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Speculators</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Uses scriptural arguments from the Bible to condemn speculators.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Wants of the 52d Reg't.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Robert C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Wilford J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yount</ln>
                        <fn>Rudolph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dabney</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crutchfield</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gochenour</ln>
                        <fn>Martin J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landrum</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loring</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauver</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kersh</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nash</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruebush</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampler</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messerly</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the men in the 52nd Regiment who would like their overcoats sent to
                    them from home. Also mentions other items that citizens may wish to donate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn>Jane P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jane P. Shultz died on December 9 at an advanced age. She was the wife of
                    Adam Shultz, deceased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mollie Moore, age eighteen, died of consumption in Staunton on December 2.
                    She was the wife of John R. Woodward and the grand-daughter of the late Samuel
                    Shepphard of Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various battlefield reports, including Fredericksburg, columns 1-5;
                advertisements and notices, including a deserter list that was printed the previous
                week, columns 6 and 7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
