<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.12.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/17/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 10/26/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-12-09">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="09">9</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.12.09.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>W. S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprints a memorial in honor of Colonel W. S. H. Baylor and other officers
                    connected with the 5th Virginia Infantry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--We, the people, have been informed by the members of the Court
                        of Augusta county that the said Court had bought, through their agent, Mr.
                        Davis, 12,000 bushels of salt for equal distribution among all the citizens
                        giving to each individual 20 lbs. Now we, as tax-payers, and good and loyal
                        citizens of the Confederacy, want to know, nay, we have a right to know, how
                        the salt received, and being received has, and is being distributed, and why
                        so many families have not been able to get a pound, and we also wish to
                        know, whether or not, the horses, cattle, sheep, &amp;c., of the sub
                        agents of Mr. Davis were counted as inhabitants. Will our court, the
                        guardians of the people, please inform the public.</p>
                    <p>INDEPENDENT.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Independent</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a letter whose author asks how salt received by Augusta County is to
                    be distributed and why some families have yet to receive their allotment. The
                    writer also asks whether, for purposes of distribution, livestock are to be
                    counted as "inhabitants."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. D. Imboden, Col. Comd'g.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Colonel expresses his thanks to Mrs. William Campbell and daughters and to
                    Mrs. Robert Cowan for the donations of clothing and blankets they have made to
                    his men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and notices, columns 1 and 2; proclamation by the governor,
                column 3; public sales, columns 4 and 5; estray notices, column 6; war news from
                Wilmington, North Carolina, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.12.09.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Lincoln's message to the Yankee Congress will excite the contemptuous
                    derision of all civilized nations."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speaks disdainfully of the address Lincoln recently made to Congress in
                    which he proposed a Constitutional amendment that would end slavery by January
                    of 1900. The Spectator comments that this amendment shows that Lincoln has no
                    confidence in the effectiveness of his emancipation proclamation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Requests that the Soldiers' Aid Societies return socks intended for
                    Confederate soldiers to the Quartermaster's office at the post office. The socks
                    are to be sent with fifteen boxes of other articles of clothing the following
                    Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The People and the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Obedient to the voice of duty and the instincts of manliness and
                    patriotism, they are braving the hardships and discomforts of a soldier's life,
                    and the perils of the terrible field of battle."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Congratulates citizens of the Confederacy for their dedication to their
                    nation and the sacrifices they have made to sustain it. Also extols the bravery
                    of Confederate troops, labeling them "the best in the world."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Views of a British Statesman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts the speech of a member of the British parliament who sympathizes
                    with the Confederate cause and denounces the North as harboring a spirit of
                    "downright barbarism and brutality."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The War Cannot Last Long</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"mere time is a sword of destruction in our hands; every week they lose
                    being equivalent to a new victory on our side."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The people of the North are begining [sic] to feel that the war, if not soon
                        closed with success on their part, will not be a "paying job." As soon as
                        this conviction shall become more general in that benighted part of the
                        world, they will begin to take steps for a cessation of active hostilities.
                        They have already expended more money in the prosecution of the war than all
                        the property of the South, exclusive of slaves, is worth. If they do not
                        succeed in the present campaign they will be forced, for the want of means,
                        in the classic language of Lincoln, to "<emph rend="italic">guv it
                        up.</emph>" </p>
                    <p>With the Richmond Examiner, we trust and believe that defeats are in store
                        for them even more signal than any they have ever yet suffered; but, be this
                        as it may, we have only to keep in good heart, make a stout resistance
                        wherever they present themselves, and hold on to the bitter end. Mere time
                        is a sword of destruction in our hands; every week they lose being
                        equivalent to a new victory on our side. We may have a dark and gloomy
                        winter, but if true to ourselves we cannot fail of success. The second six
                        hundred thousand troops will be destroyed more easily and more rapidly than
                        the first; and it is not probable that a third will ever be recruited. The
                        war may nominally linger for a long time to come; but we can virtually end
                        it within sixty days. No success of the enemy can bring them nearer their
                        object. Mere failure of success on their part must conclude the war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses the belief that the North will soon realize that winning the war
                    and keeping the South would not financially be worth continuing to fight. The
                    longer the war lasts, the article predicts, the better chance the South has of
                    winning it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Abolition Outrage in Hamilton, North Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the "Abolitionists" burned forty-two houses in a raid on
                    Hamilton, North Carolina, vandalized churches, and robbed the Masonic Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Important to Officers and Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a recent general order from General Cooper commands all
                    officers and soldiers absent from their posts to return immediately or face
                    sanction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Tory Outrage in North Carolina</head>
                <origin>Raleigh Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a band of Unionists from east Tennessee broke into a jail in
                    Waynesville, North Carolina, and let a unionist free.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Howe Y. Peyton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Howe Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>John Howe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Introduces Howe Y. Peyton as a candidate for the seat in the House of
                    Delegates being abdicated by William Tate. Relates Peyton's qualifications and
                    endorses his candidacy for the office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Successor to William M. Tate, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter endorses J. Givens Fulton to replace Tate in the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The End Net Yet</head>
                <origin>Mobile Evening News</origin>
                <commentary>"An intelligent writer in the Mobile "Evening News," who scans the
                    horizon in search of some sign of peace, gives the following reasons for
                    concluding that we have nothing to expect but war, and that unrelenting and more
                    gigantic than we have yet had to confront:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"We have nothing to expect but war."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>1. The call by the abolitionists for a second army of 600,000 men.</p>
                    <p>2. Their building of a larger Navy and a larger number of iron-clad boats,
                        for operation against forts in harbors and upon rivers, and for the general
                        purpose of destroying our coast and river banks.</p>
                    <p>3. Their systematic fortification of all prominent cities and strategic
                        points now occupied on our soil, for permanent possession.</p>
                    <p>4. Their massing of troops at different points to be permanently held as
                        bases of operations against the Confederate States.</p>
                    <p>5. Their avowed intention of conquering every seaboard city and blockading up
                        all access to the sea, and fitting out expeditions for the same.</p>
                    <p>6. The inhuman and iniquitous proclamation of President Lincoln, looking
                        towards the utter destruction of our country.</p>
                    <p>7. The support tendered him by the Governors of he thirteen States in this
                        proclamation, and in the prosecution of the war.</p>
                    <p>8. The unity of the people of the North on the war. The Democratic party is
                        coming into power again, but that party declares it will prosecute the war
                        to our certain and entire subjugation and the restoration of the Union.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that there is no hope for peace on the horizon, in light of the
                    stepping up of preparations for war that the Union government has recently been
                    putting into effect.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Yankee Character</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"When the developments, now being made, of Yankee character, come to be
                    duly appreciated by the world, they will be held by impartial history, to be the
                    vilest race on the face of the earth."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When the developments, now being made, of Yankee character, come to be duly
                        appreciated by the world, they will be held by impartial history, to be the
                        vilest race on the face of the earth. They are without the one redeeming
                        virtue of which the Roman Historian speaks. Possessed of all the views,
                        which distinguish the Chinese, they have the additional one of pretending to
                        virtues which they do not possess. Bigotted [sic] and intolerant, rapacious
                        and stingy, fraudulent and roguish, boastful and cowardly, ostentatious and
                        vulgar, envious and spiteful--they are an exaggerated embodiment of all the
                        vices of the Puritan and Blackleg. What particular cause, or combination of
                        causes, conspired to produce this odious population, it is not our purpose
                        now to inquire. But great as may be the calamity of war, we cannot resist
                        the conviction, that it is an inappreciable blessing, and will so continue,
                        until every Southern bosom is filled with detestation and loathing for this
                        abominable race. To hate vice is the first step to virtue; and it may be
                        that Providence, in its mysterious, but wise and beneficent ways, may have
                        chosen to subject us to the ordeal of a disastrous war, in order to infuse
                        into all our hearts a becoming abhorrence of these living representatives of
                        all the vices. Had we continued in political connexion with them, we, too,
                        in the lapse of time, must inevitably have fallen into the same deplorable
                        state of moral degradation. A quiet and peaceful separation--continuing
                        commercial and social relations--would not have been sufficient to save us.
                        The rupture must be attended with violence and bloodshed, and pillage and
                        devastation, to open our eyes to the monsters with whom we had been
                        associated.--The God of Heaven, who, in former times, employed Satan to do
                        his will, did not perhaps, deem Seward an unfit successor of the elder
                        Mephistophiles, and prompted him to draw the sword, that the separation
                        might be thorough and final, and ensure the cause of freedom and virtue
                        throughout the world.--<emph rend="italic">Rich. Whig.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speculates that "providence" has brought on the war in order that
                    Southerners would realize the "abhorrence of these living representatives of all
                    the vices"--the Yankees. Argues that a violent separation between the sections
                    was necessary in order to "open our eyes to the monsters with whom we had been
                    associated."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Committee of Ladies for District No. 1</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summerson</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harasberger</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>Cameron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Thorton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hudson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the ladies of District 1 of Augusta County who have been designated
                    by the Magistrates as official solicitors of money and clothing for the
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Howe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Howe Peyton accepts the nomination by "a number of friends" to run for
                    House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain Abney announces his candidacy for the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layman</ln>
                        <fn>Harrietta C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frederick C. Ott and Harrietta Layman were married on November 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Halderman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin F. Houff and Mary S. Halderman were married on November 27, at the
                    same time as Frederick Ott and Harrietta Layman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>O.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sallie Morris, aged 62 years, died in Staunton on November 29. She was the
                    wife of O. C. Morris.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Imboden, aged 6 years, died of diphtheria on December 3. He was the
                    son of Colonel J. D. and Eliza Imboden.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mollie Moore, aged 18 years, died on December 2 at the residence of her
                    brother-in-law J. N. Woodward. She was the wife of John H. Woodward and
                    granddaughter of the late Samuel Shepherd of Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>Sidney Odelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>Odelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sidney Odelia Points, aged 3 years, died of diphtheria on November 20. She
                    was the daughter of James W. and Odelia S. Points.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grills</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieutenant Charles W. Grills, aged 19, died on October 3 at his residence
                    near Mint Spring.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Craig, aged 73, died at Craigsville in Augusta County on October
                    28. She was the widow of Samuel Craig.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports of news from the war, columns 1-5; list of letters at the Staunton
                post office, column 6; advertisements and notices, columns 6 and 7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
