<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.04.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/21/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-04-15">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.04.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Patriotic Ladies of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The ladies of this good old county are not degenerate daughters of the
                        mothers of the revolution. They are as lovely as they are beautiful and so
                        patriotic as they are lovely. From the beginning of the war, they have been
                        doing all that was withing the sphere of their power to do for the comfort
                        and relief of our soldiers, and for the advancement of the cause of the
                        South.--They have been assiduous in their labors, have spared no pains, have
                        made many sacrifices, and are still willing to make many more for the sake
                        of the cause in which the South is engaged.--When needed, they made with
                        their own fair hands, though unused to toil, Caps, Jackets, Pants, Drawers,
                        Shirts, Gloves and Socks for the soldiers. When sick, they ministered to
                        their comfort and relief, by all the means which their sex knows so well how
                        to employ. Many a sick soldier, as he lay upon his couch of pain and looked
                        upon the fair "ministering angel" who stood beside him, anticipating every
                        wish and supplying every want, mentally quoted the language of the poet:</p>
                    <p>"O woman, in our hours of ease, <lb/>Uncertain, coy, and hard to please;
                        <lb/>But when pain and anguish wring the brow, <lb/><emph rend="italic">A
                            ministering angel thou."</emph></p>
                    <p>Having done all they could at home, a voice reaches their ears that the
                        Capital of the State is in danger of being polluted with the unhallowed
                        tramp of vassal invaders, and that an iron-clad gunboat is desired for its
                        defence, and they immediately, in obedience to their instinct of fervent
                        patriotism, resolve to raise all the money they can for the purpose of
                        building a gunboat of that character. We learn that $1200 for this purpose
                        have been already contributed, and that much more will be. We are pleased
                        that they are also raising a fund for the support of the families of the
                        soldiers who are fighting the battles of their country. We hope that the
                        contributions to this latter fund will be liberal, so that no soldier in our
                        ranks need feel any uneasiness about the support of his family. The laudable
                        and patriotic labors of the ladies have not failed to be observed and
                        appreciated by the Congress of the Confederacy, as will be seen by reference
                        to the following resolution recently adopted by that body:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, by the Congress of the Confederate
                        States of America, That the thanks of the Congress of the Confederate States
                        are eminently due, and are hereby tendered to the patriotic women of the
                        Confederacy, for the energy zeal and untiring devotion which they have
                        manifested in furnishing voluntary contributions to our soldiers in the
                        field, and in the various military hospitals throughout the country. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Applauds the women of Augusta County for supporting the war through their
                    sewing, ministering to sick soldiers, and raising money so that the Confederacy
                    can build an iron-clad ship. Reprints a resolution in which the Confederate
                    Congress expresses its appreciation to the women of the Confederate states "for
                    the energy, zeal and untiring devotion" they have contributed to the Confederate
                    cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Corporation Officers Elected for 1863</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burks</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Alex. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunch</ln>
                        <fn>George G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the new officeholders that have been elected for the following year
                    for the city of Staunton. N. K. Trout will serve as Mayor, while George M.
                    Cochran has been chosen as the Recorder. George Baylor, Benjamin Crawford,
                    William B. Kayser, George E. Price, William A. Burks, and William H. Wilson will
                    occupy the position of Alderman. H. M. Bell, E. M. Taylor, B. F. Points, and
                    William G. Sterrett will serve as Councilmen, while James F. Patterson will be
                    Clerk. R. W. Stevenson has been elected Sergeant and Chief of Police, and
                    William B. Kayser, George E. Price, and R. H. Fisher will serve as Street
                    Commissioners. John M. Hardy, Alex. H. Taylor and George G. Bunch will occupy
                    positions on the Committee of Safety.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Free Fighters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints the act of the Confederate Congress that authorizes the President
                    to accept local companies of volunteers that have been formed to protect local
                    communities. Offers the suggestion that these companies be made up of men who
                    cannot serve the Confederate cause in the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Exemptions in Augusta Co.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are indebted to Mr. Wm. A. Burnett, Clerk of the Board of Exemption, for
                        the following statement of the number of exempts, substitutes and details in
                        this county:</p>
                    <p>About 469 exempted from disability and other causes; about 270 applicants not
                        exempted; 211 substitutes, and details, to wit: 15 Overseers, 20
                        Blacksmiths, 8 Clerks QuartermasterDepartments, 10 Va. C. Railroad, 47
                        Staunton Boot and Shoe Factory, 42 Government WorkShops, 8 Manufacturers of
                        Saltpetre, 31 Forrer's Iron Works, 14 Miller's Iron Works, 8 Shaw &amp;
                        Trevy Iron Works, 37 Millers, 3 Staunton Steam Mills, 14 Physicians, 15
                        Tanners, 6 Stage Drivers, 2 Deputy Sheriffs, 3 Bank Officers and 8
                        Druggists. Total 1,220.</p>
                    <p>The Board of Exemption will meet again on next Saturday, the 19th
                    instant.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the number of men in Augusta County who have been exempted from
                    serving in the military and the reason they have been exempted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Praise from the Enemy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a quotation printed in the Baltimore Sun in which Union General
                    Shields praises the bravery and effectiveness of the Southern forces at
                    Kernstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Singular Prophecy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a rumor that a soldier dreamed of his own death, which came to pass
                    as dreamed. In the same dream, the soldier predicted a bloody battle in late
                    April and peace in May.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Confederate Prisoners</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Baltimore correspondent of the New York "Herald" writes to that paper as
                        follows, concerning the Confederate prisoners taken at Winchester, and now
                        confined in the Baltimore jail:</p>
                    <p>The most of them have been in the Confederate service for the last nine or
                        ten months, and are now re-enlisted for the war. The officers say that all
                        the Virginia troops now in the field have re-enlisted for the war. I have
                        conversed with most of the above officers, and find them to be highly
                        intelligent men, and some of them have the manners of highly educated and
                        polished gentlemen. On their arrival here they were placed in the city jail,
                        where they placed in the city jail, where they will remain for the present.
                        The city jail is a building of enormous proportions, built of stone, with
                        white [illegible] lacings. It is about the size and height of the
                        Metropolitan Hotel in New York, and its magnificent towers and turrets give
                        it more the appearance of a castle of feudal times than of a prison. On
                        entering its spacious corridors, I found the prisoners grouped around one of
                        General Dix's clerks, who was taking down their names. The men were not at
                        all disinclined to converse and talked freely of the battle in which they
                        had been taken prisoners.</p>
                    <p>They are all comfortably elected, and apparently in good spirits. They all
                        had Virginia bank notes amounting in the aggregate to $1,500 or $1,800, but
                        stated that they had not been paid for the last two months. Having been
                        allowed to do so, many of them sent their Virginia bank notes out to-day and
                        had been exchanged for United States money or silver at a heavy discount. At
                        present they have to put up with the common jail fare--brown bread to eat,
                        and molasses and water, under the name of coffee to drink. But arrangements
                        are being made by the military authorities here by which they will have
                        proper food. Their washing will be done for them and everything else done to
                        render them comfortable. The men are to be allowed to walk in the spacious
                        yards of the jail, and the officers will be paroled and allowed to go about
                        the city.</p>
                    <p>The officers who were in the battle of Manassas declare that the battle of
                        last Sunday water bloodier than that, and far more hotly contested. They
                        marched from Mount Jackson to Strasburg to near Winchester, where they met
                        Gen. Shield's forces and the battle took place.--I infer, from what they
                        said, that it was General Jackson's idea that General Banks was endeavoring
                        to form a junction with General McClellan at Centreville, and that, in order
                        to prevent this, or, at least, to retard it, General Jackson returned to
                        Winchester and fought this battle.</p>
                    <p>The officers speak in the highest terms of Gen. Jackson. They say he never
                        sends his men into battle, but always leads them, and then the men follow
                        his example.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the condition of Confederate troops who were taken prisoner in
                    Winchester by federal forces and then transported to Baltimore. The Herald
                    correspondent points out that the soldiers are well-dressed and well-mannered,
                    and, he remarks, they also appear to be in good spirits.</summary>
                <note>**</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Areheart</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Richard Curry and Sarah Areheart, both of Augusta County, were married on
                    April 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Sue Archer</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sue Archer Harman, age 12 years, died on the previous Friday morning. She
                    was the daughter of Major J. A. Harman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fronger</ln>
                        <fn>Edmonia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fronger</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fronger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edmonia Fronger, 12 years old, died of diphtheria in Frederick County on
                    January 4, 1862. She was the daughter of John D. and Mary Fronger.</summary>
                <note>Names not clearly legible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sallie Harman, age 7 years, died on April 12. She was the daughter of Major
                    A. W. Harman, quartermaster at the port of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Eulogy for General Albert Sidney Johnston, column 1; correction of reports
                that a recent battle was fought at Corinth, Mississippi, with the information that
                the battle took place at Shiloh, battlefield report from Scott County in Tennessee,
                article outlining "the English view" on the war, column 2; dispatches from the
                battle at Shiloh, anecdotes and brief news items column 3; message from the
                President concerning the battle at Shiloh, report of the surrender of Fort Pulaski
                in Georgia, column 4; letter from General Johnston to President Davis, column 5;
                list of wounded prisoners in the hospital at Winchester, column 6; advertisements,
                column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.04.15.02">
            <pageNote>Poem, news from Nashville, column 1; letter to General Johnston, column 2;
                advertisements and notices, columns 2-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
