<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.01.21">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/20/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-01-21">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.01.21.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Flight of the Enemy from Romney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[t]he Federal forces . . . in apprehension of the advance of the
                    Confederate force under the command of Gen'l Thos. J. Jackson, stampeded and
                    scampered away from Romney as fast as their cowardly legs could carry them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Union forces under the command of General Lander retreated
                    from Romney, Virginia in anticipation of the advance of the Stonewall Brigade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Traitors to be Hung</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that J.P. Benjamin, Secretary of War, has recommended that several
                    traitors confined in the Richmond city jail be hung. They are George Aubrey,
                    Henry Ault, Benjamin Bone, John Berrydale, Aaron W.M. Donald, and John Alford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Augusta Lee Rifles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Charles D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>C.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports the promotion of McCoy to Junior 2nd Lieutenant in the Augusta
                    Lee Rifles as a result of the death of Lieut. C.G. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Judge Thompson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item endorsing Judge Thompson for the Confederate Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Hopeful View</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Lynchburg Republican takes a hopeful view of affairs and expresses the
                        conviction that the North will be unable to prosecute the war longer than
                        the present year. With an empty treasury, a ruined credit, an enormous
                        public debt, and heavy taxation, it is impossible for her to maintain
                        hostilities of such gigantic proportions as those which the war has now
                        assumed. The Northern volunteers are not fighting from patriotism or for
                        defence, but for pay, and when they cease to get that, they will cease to be
                        soldiers. The grand army will melt away like morning mist, and
                        disorganization and mutiny be the order of the day. The people of the North,
                        too, will proclaim for peace when the tax collector goes around with his
                        drafts upon their purses for the money to foot army bills.--Direct taxation
                        at the rate of three or four hundred millions a year, is more than the
                        dollar-loving Yankee is going to stand. Their attachment to the "glorious
                        Union," and to the "Stars and Stripes," were never known to equal their love
                        of the dime. Patriotism was never known to interfere with their purse. They
                        commenced the war as a money making operation. The loss of the South is a
                        loss of two hundred millions of dollars to the Yankees, but to conquer the
                        South will cost them at least $600,000,000 per annum. This fact is just
                        beginning to break upon their astonished visions. The New York Herald says
                        that something must be done or universal panic and bankruptcy will prevail
                        in the North. "The money question is assuming an alarming shape against six
                        hundred millions of expenditure."--Thus speaks the Herald. The people will
                        soon echo the sentiment, and the administration will be left without money
                        and without friends.</p>
                    <p>But this is not all. The leading minds of the North are now satisfied that to
                        conquer the South is an impossibility. They are running up millions of debt,
                        therefore, for nothing, which will become a permanent tax upon them and
                        their posterity. The prospects of becoming involved in disastrous
                        hostilities with England and France, are imminent, and will constitute an
                        almost insuperable basis to a prolonged war. We think it highly probable,
                        however, that in view of all these impending difficulties, which throw such
                        a deep gloom over the North, the Federal authorities will make a desperate
                        effort to force our lines and achieve a series of brilliant victories, upon
                        which they can afford to retire with some degree of honor from the contest.
                        A party in a desperate strait is almost sure to resort to desperate means to
                        extricate itself. But all the South has to do is, to remain firm and
                        vigilant, and relax not a single nerve until the struggle is over.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that the North will soon cease prosecuting the war for lack of
                    funds in the Treasury and lack of will among the citizenry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>President Davis and the Southwestern Publishing House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Jeff Davis to the Rev. R. J. Graves praising the quality of
                    books produced at the Southwest Publishing House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Arrest of Tories</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the arrest of two men in Berkeley County, Virginia for allegedly
                    passing information to the invading Yankees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of Ex-President John Tyler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item announces the death in Richmond of John Tyler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Western Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports resolutions passed by the legislature reasserting control over
                    western Virginia, "in view of the presence of traitors in Western Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Affair at Hanging Rock</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an account of a skirmish at Hanging Rock in Hampshire County
                    between a small band of Confederates and a much larger force of Union soldiers.
                    According to the writer, the Confederates decided to retire when they realized
                    how outnumbered they were. They were not routed, as a "Yankee account falsely
                    reported, as is usual with them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The War in Missouri--Federal Atrocities</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>J.W. Tucker, former editor of the Missouri State Sentinel, writes that the
                    Unionist press in Missouri has lied to the people and has claimed that the
                    Confederate States did not want Missouri as a member. He argues that the state
                    is in fact an "inseparable part of the Southern Confederacy," but he pleads with
                    the South to provide Missouri loyalists with military aid.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Burying a Man Alive--Singular Circumstance</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Clipper</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports a Wisconsin soldier being nearly buried alive in camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Cabinet and the Slavery Question</head>
                <origin>Continental Monthly</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Continental Monthly, a new abolitionist magazine, claims that a
                    majority of Lincoln's cabinet favors emancipation. The magazine also believes
                    that the majority of Republicans "are seemingly determined to press the great
                    measure, and purify this country for once and forever of its great bitterness.
                    It is a forgone conclusion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Female Spy on Horseback</head>
                <origin>New York Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a suspicious looking horseman was arrested in Washington. Once
                    in custody, it was discovered that the prisoner was actually a woman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>C.C.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter writer denounces the machinations of war speculators, who view the
                    war as a means to make a fortune.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from the Captain of the Clover Creek Guards (Co. E, No. 2, 31st Va.
                    Reg't) disputing an account published in the Spectator that the company ran from
                    an engagement with the enemy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Camp Allegheny requesting bandages from the "patriotic ladies
                    of Augusta."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To the Lutheran Sabbath School Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter thanks the school for 50 pairs of drawers donated to the Lewis
                    Rangers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wanger</ln>
                        <fn>Martin H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shenk</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 2. Miss Shenk is from Rockingham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helms</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Firth</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 5, 1861.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howumb</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reubush</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 27. Mr. Howumb is from Rockingham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silor</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosserman</ln>
                        <fn>Dorinda L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Silor and Miss Bosserman were married on January 5 at Mr. Holtz's
                    residence near Middlebrook. Miss Bosserman is from Botetourt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Meredith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 2 of diphtheria at age 55.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sales</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 12 at age 60.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 12 at age 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 8 at age 55. He was a long-time member of the M.E. Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>S.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Richardson died on January 19 at age 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bazzle</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died of typhoid fever on January 19 at age 57.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan Henry, the widow of Dr. Henry, died of typhoid fever on January 13.
                    She was a member of the Church of Christ.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butcher</ln>
                        <fn>O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Butcher, a refugee from his home in Randolph County, Virginia, died
                    near Churchville on December 21, 1861.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kincaid</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died of typhoid fever on January 9 at age 53.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Many items of war news, including battlefield reports, columns 2-3; markets
                and advertisements, columns 5-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.01.21.02">
            <pageNote>Transcript of the proposed State Constitution, columns 1-6; reprint of
                previously tagged legal notices, column 7; local ads and notices, column
            7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
