<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/3/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-01-18">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="1" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18.01">
            <pageNote>Article on an incident of Southern mistreatment of abolitionists.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="2" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18.02">
            <pageNote>Adventure history article.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="3" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18.03">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Reign of Terror</head>
                <origin>New York Independent</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>We clip all the foregoing instances of the progress of the "reign of
                    terror," at the South, from the N.Y. Independent, of the 29th ult. If this does
                    not show the existence of an "irrepressible conflict," what will?</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article details incidents of violence against abolitionists in the South.
                    Specific cases of violence against abolitionists are given full exposition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="4" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18.04">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Oppressed South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "This is the land of the free -home of the brave. Here all men have--or
                    should have--the inalienable right to life, liberty and the pursuit of
                    happiness. None, not even the humblest in the land, <emph rend="italic"
                    >should</emph> feel the keen lash of the heartless oppressor in Republican
                    America." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The reason given by Southern locofoco members of Congress for their action in
                        opposing an organization of the House is, that they are tired of the
                        encroachments of the North -that they are oppressed by the North.</p>
                    <p>A charge so grave in its character, deserves serious consideration. If any
                        one section of the country is really guilty of oppressing any other section
                        of our people the fact should be made known. The oppressors should be made
                        cease their oppression. This is the land of the free -home of the brave.
                        Here all men have--or should have--the inalienable right to life, liberty
                        and the pursuit of happiness. None, not even the humblest in the land, <emph
                            rend="italic">should</emph> feel the keen lash of the heartless
                        oppressor in Republican America.</p>
                    <p>The last Census report, prepared by a Southern man, the Editor of a Southern
                        Journal, shows that all the people, in the South, who are directly
                        interested in Slavery -including men, women, and their children, even the
                        babes- do not number the half of one million. It shows, further, that there
                        are some five millions of whites in the South who are not interested in the
                        "Peculiar Institution;" and that there are some fifteen millions of whites
                        in the Free North who do not crack the plantation whip over human chattels
                        -who do not hold their fellow men in bondage, as brute beasts. It follows
                        then that the slave-holding handful -about the one fortieth of the whole
                        white population- are justly entitled to official power and political
                        influence in proportion to their numbers. If they have that ratio of
                        offices, and about that amount of voice in the adjusting of the affairs of
                        this great nation, they have no just reason for dissatisfaction -no genuine
                        cause for charging the North with restricting them in the enjoyment of any
                        of their legitimate rights.</p>
                    <p>If an investigation should, however, show that the powerful, robust North, in
                        the magnanimity of true greatness, has given to the weak, erring sister -the
                        wayward, headstrong, but physically impotent member of the family- more than
                        she was entitled to; say the half or even more than the half of the common
                        estate and the largest share of the management of the whole domain, then
                        she, through modesty -if actuated by no sense of justice and truth- should
                        keep quiet.</p>
                    <p>How does the matter stand? Have they received their fortieth of the public
                        positions in the land -their fortieth of the loaves and fishes? Or have
                        they, during all these long years, since the adoption of the Federal
                        constitution, been pushed back from the National crib by the strong right
                        arm of the stalwart North -whom she now charges with being guilty of
                        oppressing her? The unerring page of truthful history will answer the
                        interrogatory.</p>
                    <p>By reference to the official statistics we find that these growlers have
                        received, not only their fortieth -which would be their honest share- not
                        only the one half -vastly more than they would be entitled to- but, so much,
                            <emph rend="italic">more</emph> than the populous North of the official
                        posts since the establishment of the confederacy, that we can scarcely
                        believe the figures -cannot understand how the North submitted to this
                        injustice for so great a period. Yet, startling as is appears, the following
                        is a plain statement of facts:</p>
                    <p>There have been, since the formation of our present Government, eighteen
                        elections for the first office in the gift of the people -the Presidency.
                        The Candidates chosen at twelve of these elections were Southern men
                        -slaveholders. The candidates who were triumphant at six of these elections
                        were citizens of the Northern, or Free States. Thus giving that important
                        office <emph rend="italic">two thirds</emph> of the time to those who should
                        have had it but one fortieth of the time. Nor is this all; one of the six
                        Northern men -Martin Van Buren- declared, at the outstart of his reign, that
                        he was a Northern man with Southern principles -and he redeemed his pledge.
                        Two of the remaining five -Pierce, and Buchanan- conducted their
                        administrations as boldly in the interest of the miserable handful of slave
                        owners as if they had never been born in the North -had never breathed Free
                        air. Thus reducing the number of Northern men who were elected to fill the
                        office of President to but three -one of whom died in one month after his
                        inauguration, and his mantle fell upon a pro slavery Virginian. So that,
                        altogether, the South has held the control of the Presidency about
                        eight-ninths of the whole period of our National existence; and now
                        threatens to dissolve the Union if the North should elect a President. Is
                        she not <emph rend="italic">modest</emph>?</p>
                    <p>If we had time to search through all the offices under the Government, since
                        the establishment of our present system of laws, the same spirit of
                        injustice, we have no doubt, could be shown to have existed. We may on some
                        future occasion take up the narrative and show, further, the falsity of
                        Southern charges against the North. Enough has already been exhibited to
                        show that they have no cause to complain of oppression; that they have
                        controlled the whole machinery of Government to suit themselves; have
                        enjoyed all the important offices and, starving with their months full of
                        public provender, they cry aloud more, more, oppression, oppression.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial suggests that the South be limited in its political power in
                    accordance with its overall size relative to the North. It argues that the South
                    has received disproportionate power in the governance of the nation.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frjan60.html#1.18a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Philadelphia Insolence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial sarcastically suggests that Philadephia Board of Trade's recent
                    ojections to Southern cotton shippers unfair practices of false packing will
                    lead to Southern indignance. The article snickers that this incident may lead to
                    disunion and welcomes a fight if it should occur.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Democracy and Disunion</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article on the nomination of Charles James Faulkner, an abolitionist, as
                    Minister to France. Editorial objects to Faulkner's appointment because he is a
                    disunionist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Slavery in Nebraska</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This is but a fair example of the way which the people of the North have
                    been bamboozled and deceived in regard to the Slavery question ever since the
                    first attempt was made to apply the "Wilmot" to the Territories."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Nebraska Legislature, says the <emph rend="italic">New York
                        Tribune</emph>, has just passed a law prohibiting Slavery in that Territory.
                        --There is no mistake, therefore, in the fact that that Territory does not
                        want that peculiar institution. Now, the innocents were informed at the of
                        the passage of the Kansas-Nebraska bill, both by the terms of that measure,
                        and by the repeated declarations of the men who originated and passed it,
                        that the Territories organized under it would be perfectly free to settle
                        the question of Slavery "in their own way." We Republicans were pronounce
                        immensely unreasonable because we refused to concur in such a settlement of
                        the question. We all know what has happened in Kansas. Now what do we see in
                        Nebraska. That Territory has declared that it does not want and will not
                        have Slavery. Under the Kansas-Nebraska bill this would seem to settle the
                        question. But does it? Not at all. At this point the President steps in and
                        says the Territorial Legislature has no power to prohibit Slavery, and that
                        it is a "mystery" how anybody could ever have tho't otherwise. And we are
                        informed by the telegraph, what we suppose will turn out to be true, that
                        Gov. Black, Mr. Buchanan's representative in that Territory, will veto the
                        measure, and thus leave the Territory open to Slavery despite the wishes of
                        the people.</p>
                    <p>This is but a fair example of the way which the people of the North have been
                        bamboozled and deceived in regard to the Slavery question ever since the
                        first attempt was made to apply the "Wilmot" to the Territories. Here is one
                        of the Territories that Mr. Webster considered to be protected by the "will
                        of God."--But the "Will" of Mr. Buchanan is nevertheless strong enough to
                        keep Slavery there, and it would stay there but for the persistent and
                        determined efforts of the Republicans to kick it out. Whether the collision
                        here intimated between hostile "wills," in which the President has the
                        advantage, actually exists, we shall not attempt to decide. The fact is so,
                        or else Mr. Webster, for once in his life, at least, is greatly
                    mistaken.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial on the controversy over Territory of Nebraska's law to prohibit
                    slavery. Article condemns President James Buchanan's suggestion that the law is
                    not binding.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frjan60.html#1.18b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="5" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18.05">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonner</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar Brown</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of the meeting of the Chambersburg Bar Association to remember
                    Bolivar Brown Bonner, who died on January 9, 1860.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Approaching Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Announcement that Reverend Peter Cartwright, Methodist minister, will
                    lecture to the Bible class of the Methodist Episcopal Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Rider's Nursury</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazlett</ln>
                        <fn>R.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of Benjamin Rider's large lemons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Hair Picture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bemiller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of art sketch of family cemetary which used the hair of William G.
                    Reed's children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The New Pastor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stech</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of Rev. Jacob Stech as the new pastor at Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>An Old Editor Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of death of John W. Boyd, longtime editor of the Repository
                    and Whig.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Camble</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Friday</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="6" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18.06">
            <pageNote>All Ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="7" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18.07">
            <pageNote>All Ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="8" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.01.18.08">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hay</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebman</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John J. Rebman married Miss Mary Watson Seibert on January 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ault</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Joseph White of New York married Miss Mary Catharine Huber on December
                    20.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Jacob H. Gsell married Miss Elizabeth Foreman on January 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ulrich</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clippinger</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kitzmiller</ln>
                        <fn>Peori</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John R. Clippenger of Cumberland Co. married Miss Peori Kitzmiller on
                    January 5 in Carlisle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn>Helen A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Wm. H. Gelwin married Miss Helen A. Brewster on January 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coulter</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coulter</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James P. Coulter of Leechburg, Armstrong County married Miss Margaret
                    E. Coulter, late of Mansfield, Ohio, on January 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Florence M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Florence M. Duncan, age 28, died on January 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Drusilla</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Drusilla Henneberger, wife of Mr. Christian Henneberger, age 61 years
                    7 months and 28 days, died on January 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="0">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dourty</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>Sen.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dourty</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine Dourty, wife of Mr. Peter Dourty, Sen., age 53 years 7
                    months and 10 days, died on January 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAlexander</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. George McAlexander died age 80 near Spring Run, Path Valley on December
                    25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Samuel Paul, age 89 years 9 months and 17 days, died near Dry Run, Path
                    Valley, on December 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Simon Miller, age 63 years 3 months and 6 days, died near Spring Run on
                    December 31.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
