<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-02-15">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>8</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="1" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15.01">
            <pageNote>List of U.S. Congress committee assignments.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="2" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15.02">
            <pageNote>Political speeches.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="3" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15.03">
            <pageNote>All Ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="4" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15.04">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Don't be Frightened</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "The fear of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> that the present
                    Republican Legislature will attempt to elect a U. S. Senator this winter are
                    groundless." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The fear of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> that the present Republican
                        Legislature will attempt to elect a U. S. Senator this winter are
                        groundless. Such a thing, we are assured has never been contemplated by the
                        Republicans. We are authorized by Senator McClure to say that he has never
                        heard the matter urged by a single member of the legislature, and that under
                        no circumstances would he support or sanction such a measure. It is enough
                        for the Locofocos of Indiana to nullify the laws to force a bogus
                        representation in the U.S. Senate, and the Republicans will never stain
                        their hands with such a record. The Republicans have no need to anticipate
                        the regular time for electing a U.S. Senator, for they will be quite able to
                        elect one of the right stamp in 1861.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the current Republican legislature will not try to elect a U.S.
                    senator in the winter, since they will be able to elect one handily in 1861.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Washington Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>The sons of Freedom, in the North, vote as they please. The serfs of the
                    South--for the poor whites, the non-slave holding portion of society, are
                    removed but one degree above the slaves--are compelled to vote as the lords of
                    the lash dictate.</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Nerva</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article describes the fight over control of the post office between
                    Southern Democrats and Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Sermon for the Benefit of the Poor.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The sermon delivered by Mr. Philips was an able effort. The incidents of
                    genuine benevolence which he cited were well worthy the imitation of all good,
                    pious zealous christians."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Rev. Samuel Philips, pastor of the German Reformed Church, of this
                        place, preached a powerful sermon, in his own church, on Sabbath evening
                        last, the 12th inst. After the sermon a collection was taken up for the
                        benefit of the poor of Chambersburg.</p>
                    <p>Wm. Heyser, Sr., Esq., the President of the Bank of Chambersburg, an Elder in
                        Mr. Philip's church, was to have delivered an address upon the same
                        occasion; but having been confined to his room for three or four days
                        before, and still being unable to go out, he was not present -greatly to the
                        disappointment of the audience. All of the congregation sympathize with him
                        in his affliction and hope that he will soon be able to be about again.</p>
                    <p>The sermon delivered by Mr. Philips was an able effort. The incidents of
                        genuine benevolence which he cited were well worthy the imitation of all
                        good, pious zealous christians. The rule of conduct in the life of the
                        founder of Methodism -John Wesley- we think can scarcely be equalled. It
                        appears that Mr. Wesley started out in his ministerial life with the firm
                        determination to do good to the poor. Accordingly he gave, the first year of
                        his ministerial labors, out of a salary of thirty pounds sterling, two
                        pounds to the poor -living on twenty-eight. His second year he got sixty
                        pounds sterling for his services, and, continuing to live upon twenty-eight,
                        he gave thirty-two to the poor. The third year his salary was one hundred
                        and twenty pounds. He made out to live, as formerly, on twenty-eight pounds,
                        and gave to the poor the enormous sum of ninety two pounds sterling -about
                        four hundred and sixty dollars in one year.</p>
                    <p>We never heard of this trait in the character of Wesley till Mr. Philips
                        related it; but such being part of Wesley's life, we have no difficulty in
                        accounting for the cause of his wonderful success in preaching the
                        everlasting word to famishing mortals.</p>
                    <p>Would it not be well enough for other ministers to continue this good work
                        which Mr. Philips has started -giving the proceeds of a collection taken up
                        every such an occasion to the poor of the town?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Sr., Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sermon on John Wesley's early efforts to give to the poor.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frfeb60.html#2.15b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Old Guard of 1812</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notice of the State Convention of the War of 1812 veterans to be held in
                    Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Family Physician</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Review of book on family medicine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"After being cursed for nearly seventeen years with horse cars and a worn
                    out Railroad, we were not surprised to find that the good people of our native
                    town, Greencastle, were highly pleased to see the regular passenger train of
                    cars entering their beautiful, thriving Borough, on last Monday, the 6th day of
                    February, 1860."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--At length this highway is opened up for the accommodation of the travelling
                        public. After being cursed for nearly seventeen years with horse cars and a
                        worn out Railroad, we were not surprised to find that the good people of our
                        native town, Greencastle, were highly pleased to see the regular passenger
                        train of cars entering their beautiful, thriving Borough, on last Monday,
                        the 6th day of February, 1860.</p>
                    <p>On Wednesday, the last day of May, 1843, the last train of cars, propelled by
                        steam, passed over the old road. On Thursday, June 1st, 1843, the first
                        horse-car traveled over that old flat-bar, no-rail, rickety concern.</p>
                    <p>A few years since the people in the Southern part of this county, petitioned
                        the Legislature for, and obtained, the passage of an act authorizing the
                        sale of the dilapidated old road, the jest and by-work of the whole country,
                        for the purpose of having it reconstructed. It was sold, but not re-laid.
                        Within a year or two, in pursuance of further legislation, it was again
                        sold. This time it fell into the hands of A.J. Jones, Esq., of Harrisburg,
                        and others who have rebuilt it -substancially. To the indomitable
                        perseverance of Mr. Jones are the people of this Valley indebted for the
                        present substancial thoroughfare -full blasted, heavy railed, it is one of
                        the best roads in the United States.</p>
                    <p>The Road is not yet completed to its terminus -Hagerstown, Md. The
                        arrangement, therefore, for running to Greencastle is not of that permanent
                        and satisfactory character which will be made as soon as the Road is
                        finished throughout. There is but one train per day, leaving Chambersburg at
                        11.25 A.M., and, returning, leaves Greencastle at 1.40 P.M., remaining an
                        hour and a half at the latter place.</p>
                    <p>Col. Lull, the polite superintendent of the Cumberland Valley Road, desirous
                        of affording facilities for the transportation of freight, and for
                        passengers to travel with comfort to and from Greencastle, made the above
                        described arrangement -the only one that could be made for the present.</p>
                    <p>The gentlemanly conductor on the C.V. R.R., Levy McCormack, Esq., who served
                        an apprenticeship on that same route, under the horse car arrangement;
                        George B. Ayres, Esq., the polite, efficient general Agent for the Company,
                        and Geo. W. Simmons, Esq., the unequalled Agent for the Adams Express Co.,
                        constitute a trio of good fellows, noble and true, all of them, upon whom
                        devolve the duty of serving the public on the highway -The Franklin Rail
                        Road. The more intercourse the people along the line of the road have with
                        these gentlemen the better they will like them.</p>
                    <p>The first Train which passed over the road to Greencastle, consisted of nine
                        heavily laden freight, and two passenger cars. The firm of C.W.Eyster,
                        &amp;Co., forwarding merchants of this place, have the credit of
                        bringing down from Greencastle, the <emph rend="italic">first</emph> loaded
                        car -which was done by Monday's return trip.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editors offer thanks to the new railroad for its service.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frfeb60.html#2.15c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Good News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editors praise the religious prayer meetings at the state legislature
                    organized by Col. James C. Austin, a delegate from the district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Messrs. Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Antrim</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>K. Shannon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter suggests Maj. K. Shannon Taylor as nominee for the Prothonotary of
                    the People's Party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Great Bargain</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of the sale of tavern in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Pilot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCrory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editors applaud new paper, The Pilot, in Antrim.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayers</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice reports the heavy volume of traffic on the new Franklin Railroad and
                    scoffs at the Spirit's criticism of the project.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Prolific</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Little, colored, gave birth to three babies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of Charles Steck's preaching at the Lutheran Church until the
                    arrival of the Pastor elect.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="5" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15.05">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="6" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15.06">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="7" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15.07">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Caledonia Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J.B.M.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article welcomes the Franklin Railroad and pushes for another road from
                    Gettysburg to Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Justice</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter answers many questions raised in the Valley Spirit's criticism of
                    the new railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bad Taste</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Forty Cents</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter refuting the Valley Spirit's criticism of the new railroad opening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="8" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.15.08">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Dinah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Dinah Thompson, age 63 years 4 months and 3 days, died near Loudon on
                    February 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Orr, wife of Hon. John Orr, died at the age of 63 at Orrstown on
                    February 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"She was a woman of strong mind and of much general intelligence; whe was
                    an ardent friend to the cause of Methodism."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Early, age 69, died at the Alms House on February 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sewell</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCory</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Reuben Sewell married Miss Margaret A. McCrory on February 14..</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ault</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullen</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Frederick Smith married Miss Catharine Mullen on February 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johns</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Peter Rosenberry married Miss Nancy Johns on February 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGarvey</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Augustus Baker married Miss Barbara Brown on February 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Angle</ln>
                        <fn>H.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nisewander</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. H. B. Angle married Miss Mary Nesewander on February 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
