<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/11/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chabersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-03-07">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>8</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07.01">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Speech of Hon. Edward McPherson of Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of speech on disunion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07.02">
            <pageNote>Speech by Hon. Edward McPherson on disunion.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07.03">
            <pageNote>Ads and fiction.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07.04">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Nigger Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A baser or more subservient stooping to lick the dust from off the shoes
                    of wealthy aristocrats, never exhibited itself to the astonished gaze of a race
                    of freemen, than is to be found in the columns of the Valley Spirit of the 29th
                    ult. Nigger, nigger, nigger, is their only theme. The interest of the nabobs of
                    slavedom, the only rights worth battling for."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A baser or more subservient stooping to lick the dust from off the shoes of
                        wealthy aristocrats, never exhibited itself to the astonished gaze of a race
                        of freemen, than is to be found in the columns of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Valley Spirit</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Nigger, nigger, nigger, is their only theme. The interest of the nabobs of
                        slavedom, the only rights worth battling for--the only principles worthy the
                        support of the party of which the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> is the
                        organ in this county. Everything freemen of the North do in behalf of free
                        white-men and the interests of free labor, is denounced by this advocate of
                        the labor of the woolly head--the friend to the extension of free labor,
                        with its necessary result; the crushing out of white laboring men.</p>
                    <p>Who, among working men, that has any respect for himself and for his wife and
                        children, wishes to see this free State of Pennsylvania overrun with
                        Slavery; every branch of industry, which now affords support for thousands
                        of white people, who are willing to work for a living, supplied with the
                        labor of negroes whose bodies and souls (while in the flesh) belong to their
                        masters--recognized as such by law? Who, among the high-minded, independent,
                        intelligent mechanics of Franklin County, desires to see his means of
                        supplying the wants of those who are dependant upon him, degraded by the
                        competition of Slave labor? Who, among all the different branches of
                        industry, so multifarious in its form wishes to be reduced to the level of
                        the poor whites of the South; those wretched beings of whom Locofoco United
                        States Senators says: "they are not fit to associate with a Southern <emph
                            rend="italic">gentleman's</emph> body servant?" No man, not even a voter
                        with the Nigger Democracy in the North, among poor working, white men
                        desires to witness any of all of these calamities to befal the beautiful
                        fills and dales of the dear old Keystone of the Federal arch-beloved
                        Pennsylvania. Yet there is nothing more certain to happen--not even the
                        setting sun to follow its rising--than that of Slavery, with all its
                        blighting effects, will again be introduced into every Northern State, if
                        the policy of the Nigger Democracy is suffered to be carried out to the
                        conclusion the oligarchs are hastened it as fast as circumstances will
                        permit. The Editor of that, and the Editor of every other locofoco paper,
                        knows as well as do we, that the object of the leaders of the odious dogma
                        of Slavery extension is to carry their system of labor not only into the
                        Territories, but into all the Northern States. The bolder among the hotspurs
                        have, over and over again, declared that slavery is the <emph rend="italic"
                            >best</emph> form of labor which <emph rend="italic">capital</emph> can
                        employ. Certain leading Southern locofoco orators have had the impudence to
                        declare that <emph rend="italic">"color</emph> had nothing to do with
                        slavery;" and that the "rightful and normal condition of <emph rend="italic"
                            >all poor laboring</emph> men is slavery." All these abominable
                        teachings fall from the lips of the Southern leaders of the Nigger
                        Democracy; their Northern allies see and hear the disreputable language and
                        have not the manhood to speak out in reprobation thereof in suitable terms.</p>
                    <p>Some of the purse-proud lords-of-the-lash have publicly declared "that the
                        great cause of the violent agitation in this country, is, to decide whether
                        it is better for capital to own or to hire its labor." Thus saying, as
                        plainly as language could express it, that there is an "irrepressible
                        conflict" between capital and muscles, at this time, going on in the land.
                        In this struggle the Republicans, like Jefferson, and all his compeers[
                        sic], are on the side of labor. The Nigger Democracy like the enemies of
                        poor working men in every age of the world, is on the side of capital.</p>
                    <p>If the Northern dough-face <emph rend="italic">followers</emph> of the
                        Slave-owning, man-stealing, man, woman and children selling, Southern
                        leaders of the Nigger Democracy, in all their wicked assaults upon poor
                        white working men, can find satisfaction in giving aid and comfort to these
                        bitter, unrelenting foes to the genuine interests of the industrious sons of
                        toil in the free North, they can go on in their dark, fiendish attacks upon
                        free labor till they bring about its necessary fruits, when, it is to be
                        expected, they will be assigned their wished-for position--will be made
                        overseers, their proper post.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial sharply criticises the Valley Spirit and the Democratic Party for
                    their allegiance to Southern slaveowners.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmarch60.html#3.7a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sedition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial condemns Stephen Douglas' attempt to introduce legislation making
                    discussion of slavery in the North seditious.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Faithful Officials</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article praises McClure and Eyster for their work in lowering taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our Representatives</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article praises the local politicians on their work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Hon. A. K. McClure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>Free speech, freelabor, and a free Press will ever have in the Hon. A. K.
                    McClure an unyielding friend and defender.</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article on Sen. McClure's speech at the People's ratification meeting in
                    Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07.05">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Franklin Rail Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn>O. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zellar</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wasson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article notes the activities of the fledgling railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Chapter of Accidents</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summary of a horse accident.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Another horse accident.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Child, choked on cherry pit, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Waynesboro Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article supports movement for a railroad in Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sanford's Opera Troupe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Visiting troupe of negro minstrels from Philadelphia peformed in
                    Chabersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Old Greene Good for 200 Majority for Cameron and Curtin.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>C. T. Maclay, President; A. M. Criswell Secretary</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferree</ln>
                        <fn>Miller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirk</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herchelrode</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pentz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bass</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Town meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Ward Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of ward meetings for the People's party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tedious Trial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note on a U.S. Circuit court trial in Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rev. Peter Cartwright</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of Peter Cartwright's return to Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07.06">
            <pageNote>Fiction and ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07.07">
            <pageNote>All Ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.03.07.08">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. J. B. McClelland married Miss Mary E. Hoke on February 29.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebber</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightcap</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Henry Rebber married Miss Mary C. Lightcap on March 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. George Heller married Miss Barbara A. Jones on March 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Solomon Snyder married Miss Margaret Stake on February 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>N.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pott</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James Pott married Miss Agnes E. Logan, both of Fulton Co., on February
                    22.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John Ebersole married Miss Sarah J. Unger on March 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNew</ln>
                        <fn>Bozel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henrock</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Bozel McNew married Miss Sarah Jane Henrock on March 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geyer</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Henry McGowan of Fulton Co. married Miss Sarah Geyer on February 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Bitner, son of Christain Bitner, died of typhoid fever, age 40, on
                    February 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Over</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Over, age 51, died on March 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
