<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/25/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-04-25">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>8</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="1" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
            <pageNote>Testimony of Ellis B. Schnabel before Congressional Committee investigating
                the Buchanan administration's involvement in Kansas constitutional
            struggle.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="2" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
            <pageNote>Fiction and Ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="3" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
            <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="4" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>State Central Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article lists the members of the the State Central Committee for the
                    People's (Republican) State Party. Alexander K. McClure is listed from Franklin
                    Co. as the Chairman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The "Nigger" Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We leave to the Spirit, . . . to contrast the relative condition of the
                    negro in the North and the negro in the South; but while thus engaged, we would
                    ask them to compare the situation of poor whites in the South with that class of
                    society at the great, industrious North."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The leading article in the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit,</emph> of the
                        11th inst., is upon the question which, above all others, seems to absorb
                        the thoughts of the Nigger democracy. It consists of a long whining cant
                        about the condition of the race which interests its party more than does any
                        other topic. It contrasts the condition of the negro in the South with the
                        circumstances of that class of persons at the North. This is a favorite
                        theme with the orators and press of that party. All their concern is about
                        the "nigger."</p>
                    <p>Because of their continual feasting upon their colored brethren, with
                        "nigger" for breakfast, "darkey" for lunch, "cuffy" for dinner, "woolly
                        head" for desert, and "sambo" for supper, we have arrived at the conclusion
                        that their true name should be the Nigger Democracy. Notwithstanding the
                        nauseating character of the dish, and the frequency with which they thrust
                        the unsavory repast under the noses of their readers, we find that they
                        still rehash the old, mouldy collation.</p>
                    <p>Why cannot these caterers of political food dispense some wholesome diet to
                        their party friends, their willing followers?--Why do not locofoco speakers
                        and locofoco newspapers express themselves sensibly and to some purpose in
                        behalf of WHITE MEN? Why do they disregard the interests of the poor of
                        their own race, and occupy all their attention with the destiny of the
                        negro? We want more sympathy for <emph rend="italic">whites,</emph> poor
                        whites, to fill the minds of our law-makers, than has hitherto been the
                        case, and more real happiness will be the result.</p>
                    <p>Poor white men and their families are the parties who suffer the most, and
                        that too without hope of relief, from the contamination of slave labor. The
                            <emph rend="italic">poor whites</emph> of the South are of all men the
                        most miserable. They have little or no employment; very little if any means
                        of support, and they are compelled to herd with negroes, the slaves of rich
                        whites-- who, imitating the example of their masters, despise, and look down
                        upon "the poor white trash." Such is ever the case where slavery has such
                        unlimited control. And it is to such a treat the slavery-extending,
                        nigger-loving democracy would invite poor white men of the free North.</p>
                    <p>Given the <emph rend="italic">Spirit,</emph> and kindred lick spittle sheets
                        the power and they would fasten slavery, with all its horrors, irrevocably,
                        not only upon the wide-extended plains of our fertile, teeming, western
                        territories, but, <emph rend="italic">upon every free State in this
                            Republic.</emph> There is no demand, however wild, however chimerical,
                        which the hot-heads of the South can make upon the weak-kneed partisans at
                        the North which the latter will not hasten to obey. All their waking
                        thoughts; all their sleeping dreams are upon the one subject--how they can
                        oppress the negro, degrade the poor whites, and increase the power of the
                        Slaveocracy. The organs and leaders of the nigger democracy in the North
                        have no care for, no interest in, the welfare of <emph rend="italic">poor
                            whites;</emph> all they desire is the good will of the dispensers of
                        offices--the oligarchy.</p>
                    <p>What have we of the North to do with the negro question? It gives us, of the
                        Republican party, especially, no uneasiness. We had nothing to do with
                        overrunning the country with the degraded, outcast race, nor are we
                        particularly interested in, getting rid of the burthen. They who have reaped
                        all the benefit arising from the unpaid labor of the poor wretches, who have
                        grown rich, fat and lazy, upon the toil of these helpless, hapless creatures
                        and their willing coadjutors of the North,--the nigger democracy--may devise
                        ways and means to remove the curse of slavery where it exists; all we care
                        about is that it <emph rend="italic">shall not be extended.</emph> We plan
                        ourselves upon the far-famed Mason &amp; Dixon's line, and say to the
                        usurpers: Thus far shalt thou come, but no farther; and here shall thy proud
                        tyranny be stayed.</p>
                    <p>We leave to the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, and locofoco papers, and
                        stump speakers, generally, to contrast the relative condition of the negro
                        in the North and the negro at the South, but while thus engaged, we would
                        ask them to compare the situation of <emph rend="italic">poor whites</emph>
                        in the South with that class of society at the great, industrious North. We
                        would have them tell us, truthfully, the difference upon all classes of
                        whites in those States where unpaid labor prevails--where capitol owns its
                        working men, without disgracing themselves, work, with heads or hands, or
                        both, for their daily bread.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial characterizes the Democratic Party as overly concerned with "the
                    nigger" as an issue in party politics. The article states the Republican
                    position to be only against the extension of slavery, not slavery itself,
                    playing down the party's opposition to Southern slavery.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frapril60.html#4.25a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"No Higher Law"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Is it not a crying shame that we, a professedly christian people, who
                    enjoy to a larger extent that any nation on earth the blessings of a kind,
                    benificent Providence, would be so impious as to compare the feeble offspring of
                    the brain of mortal, erring men with the unerring records of holy writ?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The question is frequently propounded by those who have not kept themselves
                        booked up in political matters, what is meant by "the higher law?" For the
                        information of all such we say that <emph rend="italic">the law which is
                            higher than any human statute</emph> is the law of God--that teachings
                        of the Bible.</p>
                    <p>Some politicians, and their name is Legion, especially in the South, and
                        everywhere among locofocos, pretend to entertain for the Constitution of the
                        United States such profound veneration that they will not admit that any law
                        of the Ruler of the universe--is or can be superior to that instrument; yet
                        they forget to inform us that it (the Constitution) passed through no less
                        than three changes within the first seventeen years of its existence.</p>
                    <p>Is it not a crying shame that we, a professedly christian people, who enjoy
                        to a larger extent that any nation on earth the blessings of a kind,
                        benificent Providence, would be so impious as to compare the feeble
                        offspring of the brain of mortal, erring men with the unerring records of
                        holy writ? How can any man who denies the supremacy of the Bible over the
                        changing, fallible enactments of men ask honest, genuine Christians to vote
                        for candidates who entertain like sentiments; yet every Christian, who votes
                        the locofoco ticket, gives the Bible this indirect blow.</p>
                    <p>The Bible is enable to occupy the sacred position it does in the hearts and
                        affections of the people, because <emph rend="italic">it is inspired;</emph>
                        because it came from the hand of Jehovah. There is no other rule of action
                        for the government and control of mortals which is in any manner to be
                        compared with the Bible--the greatest and most precious treasure ever given
                        to man, by the kind, bountiful preserver of us all.</p>
                    <p>The Constitution of the United States, like all other human productions, is
                        far from being perfect. It is well adapted to the use it was designed to
                        subserve as is the <emph rend="italic">Magna Charta</emph> of any people;
                        but it is little short of gross impiety to set it above and before the
                        precious teachings of God's Holy Word. No reason can be given for the wild,
                        wicket adoration of the locofoco--amounting to idolatry--for the emanation
                        of the minds of men, other than that in the Constitution they profess to be
                        able to see something which conflicts with the plain teachings of the word
                        of life; and, as, with them, the constitution is infallible it must stand
                        though the Bible--the only sources of "higher," purer and holier "law"--is
                        decried and esteemed of no value.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial argues that Southern Congressmen and Democratic Party members are
                    wrong in suggesting that the Constitution is the highest law of the land.
                    Instead, the editorial suggests that God's law is above the Constitution.</summary>
                <note>frbrowswer/frapril60.html#4.25b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="5" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="j">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Secrist &amp; Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bemisdaffer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knode</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dysart</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jack</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Findly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Michael Strock v. Secrist &amp; Carbaugh--Action of Replevin, verdict
                    for plaintiff, one cent. David Bemisdaffer v. Lewis Knode--Action of Replevin,
                    settled by parties. George W. Bitner v. County of Franklin--Assumpsit, judgment
                    for plaintiff by confession in open court for $34.47. Peter Reed v. Samuel
                    Dysart--Action in Assumpsit, plaintiff takes a non-suit. Mary Jack v. Thomas J.
                    Early, Administrator of John Findly, dec'd--Action of debt, verdict for
                    plaintiff for $3,317.98."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Home of Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article on the importance of the Mount Vernon Ladies Association's
                    fund-raising efforts for the preservation of Mt. Vernon. Mrs. R. M. Bard headed
                    the county effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fine Cattle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A prettier sight could not be easily scared up."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Gilmore of Upper Strasburg sold 18 head of cattle weighting 21,775
                    lbs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>School Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElvaine</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. A. McElvaine announces his candidacy for school superintendent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Changed Hands</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKibben</ln>
                        <fn>Chambers</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. K. McClure purchased estate near Chambersburg for $19,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday of last week, the Court considered an injunction to prevent the
                        Town Council of the Borough of Chambersburg, from annexing to said Borough
                        portions of Hamilton and Guilford Townships. The Court decided that the
                        Council had no power to annex tracts of farm land lying within the limits of
                        the survey; and also directed that the boundaries of the survey be so
                        altered as to exclude these tracts of land. These tracts embrace several
                        ares on which there are no buildings, and which if annexed would be a source
                        of heavy taxation to the owners . The Borough, however, will be extended to
                        nearly the limits set forth in the proclamation of the Burgess.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note about the Court's recent decision regarding the expansion of the
                    Borough of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frapril60.html#4.25c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Limits Extended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Chambersburg is permitted to spread herself and keep up with the times."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our town fathers have enlarged our boundaries; making Chambersburg a perfect
                        little inland city. An injunction was prayed the Court to restrain the
                        Council from bringing in the Hamilton township portion, but it was
                        dismissed, by his Honor, Judge Kimmel, and Chambersburg is permitted to
                        spread herself and keep up with the times.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chambersburg wins Court judgment preventing Council from restraining
                    growth.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frapril60.html#4.25d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="6" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
            <pageNote>N. Y. Tribune artile on the Potter-Pryor "duel."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="7" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Hint to Those Who Adopt Children</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There are people who, having no children of their own, resolve to adopt
                    one. This is often well, and often ill, too. Ill--when the self-constituted
                    parent only wants a child as he would a pet dog, and puts it through no higher
                    course of training; when he feeds it from his own plate with choice bits, till
                    it becomes too dainty for the chance wayside bone, and then getting weary of the
                    pastime, opens the door and thrusts it forth to forage again in gutters and ash
                    heaps and street corners."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are people who, having no children of their own, resolve to adopt one.
                        This is often well, and often ill, too. Ill--when the self-constituted
                        parent only wants a child as he would a pet dog, and puts it through no
                        higher course of training; when he feeds it from his own plate with choice
                        bits, till it becomes too dainty for the chance wayside bone, and then
                        getting weary of the pastime, opens the door and thrusts it forth to forage
                        again in gutters and ash heaps and street corners. Such things have been.
                        Let none assume this sacred relation <emph rend="italic">who are not
                            prepared for its sacrifices as well as its pleasures.</emph> Who have
                        not counted on days of sickness, and hours of childish waywardness, and
                        possibly hereditary moral weeds to be rooted out; for these little stray
                        waifs of humanity suffer much from these causes, physically and morally. Let
                        no one, we say, open wide his arms and doors to it unless God's patience be
                        in his soul, God's all suffering, all forgiving love, in his heart, to weave
                        a chord from the child's heart to his own, over which no vibration shall
                        pass unheeded, no more than if it were bone of his bone, and flesh of his
                            flesh.--<emph rend="italic">Fanny Fern</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article suggests that adoption be viewed as a sacred commitment, not one to
                    be entered into lightly or without faith.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frapril60.html#4.25e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="8" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.04.25">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hodgson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf>D.D.</sf>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heysinger</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tindall</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tindall</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf>M.D.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John L. Heysinger of the M.E. Church married Miss Josephine Tindall,
                    oldest daughter of D. M. Tindall, M.D., all of Philadelphia, on Feb. 20.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mountz</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maloy</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William A. Mountz of Chambersburg married Miss Catharine Maloy of
                    Fayettesville on April 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Francis Deal died at the age of 68 on April 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Ann Maria Washabaugh, wife of Upton Washabaugh, Esq., died of cancer
                    in the breast on April 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
