<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-11-28">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania And The South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors discuss one of the South's pretexts for secession--
                    nullification of the fugitive slave law, and they point out that Ohio is the
                    only border state that stands guilty of passing liberty laws that nullify the
                    F.S. law. The editors emphasis the unreasonable expectation of Southerners
                    (while in Pennsylvania) to be exempt from Pennsylvania's laws pertaining to
                    slavery when Pa.'s own citizens are required to comply.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Important From Springfield, Ill.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Description of a celebration of the Republican victory, and a speech by
                    Senator Trumball, in which he argues that the disunionists were just looking for
                    some pretence for breaking up the Union, that they urge quick action before
                    anyone comes to his senses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Southern Secession Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Articles from three separate Southern papers--Fredericksburg (Va.)
                    Recorder, Charlottesville (Va.) Review, and the Memphis Enquirer--all urging
                    Southern states to stay in the Union for different reasons--a Democrat Congress,
                    a simple demand for peace, and the question of whether secession could last any
                    length of time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>A few articles of national news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Future Of The North And South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors suggest that one reason for the disunionists' cry of 'now or
                    never' stems from the present Census' results which will probably reduce the
                    number of electoral votes of Southern states, and increase the number in
                    Northern states and territories-soon-to-be-states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Declaration Of Independence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A humorous imitation of the declaration sent by South Carolina to the
                    President. The imitation is done by Luzerne County of Pennsylvania, giving its
                    reasons for why it wants to separate from the rest of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Articles on travel (sailing) in ice and preparations for winter;
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To The Republicans Of Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An exhortation from Republican Electoral candidates of Maryland to their
                    fellow Republicans in Maryland to stick to the ideals of the Republican party,
                    and to choose to stay part of Lincoln's Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Cupidity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A response to the South's accusation that the North is responsible in part
                    for the existence of slavery in the South. The editors argue that slavery no
                    longer exists in most Northern states, not due to Federal Gov't interference,
                    but because each state decided to outlaw it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There are grave and important questions for the deliberation of that body,
                    without their spending precious time, digusting their constituents, talking all
                    winter about Sambo. We want something done for the Industrial interests of Free
                    Whites. We want the world to see that there are questions worth being considered
                    by men of sense beside the everlasting nigger' question."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reminder to Congress that in their last session they should not waste
                    time on discussing secession, but instead to work on issues such as the building
                    of the Railroad, admission of Kansas, and revision of the Tariff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mr. Secretary Cobb Not So Bad Once As He Now Is</head>
                <origin>The Baltimore Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reference to a speech by Secretary Cobb (presently a disunionist) in 1851,
                    in which he argued that any state that seceded would soon return to the Union
                    when it found how difficult existence outside of the Union was.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>A number of articles either on Lincoln's victory or his abilities, Unionist
                arguments within the South, the famine in Kansas, or general national
            news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28.05">
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death Of An Esteemed Citizen</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupley</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement and short biography of Simon Rupley, Sr., who died on Nov.
                    19th, at age 68, and who was born in Adams county, but after fighting in the
                    campaign of 1814, he lived in Greencastle. The service was done at the German
                    Reformed Curch by Rev. T. G. Apple.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Union Thanksgiving Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of a Union meeting at the Lutheran church on Nov. 29th, where
                    all pastors will participate and the Revs. Harden, Colestock and Philips will
                    speak.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Young People's Union Prayer Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announcement of an evening prayer meeting tomorrow, Nov. 29th, at the
                    Lutheran and Berman Reformed, for all young people.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Large Cabbage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editors thank Mrs. Brough for the 19 lb. cabbage sent to them by means of
                    Mr. B. Cook.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Recommended Books; general news; Help For Kansas; reprint of Pennsylvania
                Presidential election results (due to earlier misprint); Election returns from the
                West--Lincoln still ahead.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28.06">
            <pageNote>National and world news articles; article on the tradition of traveling at
                Thanksgiving; advertisements;</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28.07">
            <pageNote>advertisements; general news and anecdotes;</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.28.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valentine</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creps</ln>
                        <fn>Henry T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpless</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blays</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpless</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johns</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>S. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>Bell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, at the Union Hotel in Greencastle, Rev. J. Rebaugh married
                    William Wolford to Susannah Cunningham, of Washington co., Md. On Nov. 1st, at
                    the bride's father's home, Rev. J. Rebaugh married William Valentine, of
                    Washington co., Md., to Elizabeth Smith, of Franklin co. On Nov. 8th, in
                    Greencastle, Rev. J. Rebaugh married Henry T. Creps to Catharine Switzer, all of
                    Washington Twp., Franklin co. On Nov. 15th, at the home of the bride's father,
                    Henry Blays married Sophia G. Sharpless, both of Washington co., Md. On Oct.
                    11th, Rev. H. Hummelbaugh married Levi Crider to Elizabeth Johns, all of
                    Letterkenny Twp., Franklin co. On Nov. 20th, at the bride's father's home, Rev.
                    J. Smith Gordon married Lieutenant S. O. McCurdy to Bell Witherow, daughter of
                    John Witherow, Esq., all of Fannetsburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummins</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupley</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Struble</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyler</ln>
                        <fn>Elias Fetterhoof</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 24th, in Chambersburg, at his home on West King St., Jesse Cummins
                    died of apoplexy at age 81. On Nov. 19th, in Greencastle, Simon Rupley, Sr.,
                    died at age 67. On Nov. 20th, in Hamilton Twp., John Miller died of apoplexy at
                    age 61. On Nov. 11th, at his home in Amberson's Valley, in Franklin co., Daniel
                    Struble died at age 78. On Nov. 11th, an his home in Guilford Twp., Elias
                    Fetterhoof Oyler died of a lingering illness at age 32.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements; anecdotes; stories.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
