<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-09-19">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Working Men, Read This Article</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extract of an article by E. B. Ward that defends a Protective Tariff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Our Assailants</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Shrinking from a fair discussion of principle, and avoiding every
                    opportunity to meet a Republican candidate before the people, they hope to
                    attract public opinion and contempt from their own questionable and doubtful
                    positions, by directing it against the open and manly action of their
                    opponents."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A comment on the behavior of the Democratic candidates--that they use
                    vicious attacks, instead of open discussions with their Republican opponents, to
                    influence the opinions of the voters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Facts and Fancies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Four anecdotes relating to women: that a girl's best education is done
                    under her mother's supervision; that a girl's studies should be determined by
                    her position in life; that fashionable society ruins a girl's innocent charm; a
                    woman should be happiest in her husband's presence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article on the sinking of the Lady Elgin Steamer; Grand Republican Rally in
                Illinois; Facts and Fancies</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Degredation Of The Country</head>
                <origin>The Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article disdaining the indecent practice of presidential candidates
                    'stumping' for votes, and noting that Lincoln has not stooped to begging for
                    votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Proclamation of the Election in October; advertisements; a story for
            boys.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19.03">
            <pageNote>A Letter from Kansas; an article on the Popery and Mohammedanism;
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Two Forms Of Government</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"That these fat, sleek, lazy nabobs should wish to steep all men in their
                    infamy--living by the unpaid work of slaves, perhaps their own children--is not
                    at all surprising when we reflect upon the old adage that misery loves to have
                    company."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article paints a contrast between the freedom-loving North that
                    respects and upholds the values of Declaration of Independence, whereas the
                    South abuses and persecutes anyone who attempts to promote these concepts, and
                    that it would like to turn the North into a place willing to own human flesh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Breckinridge Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The foes of the "little giant" showed that they were alive and kicking in
                    old Franklin County."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The meeting which the administration, anti-Douglas men of this County held in
                        the Court House on Saturday last, was very much larger than what we had
                        expected to see. The old, tried veterans of the party were here in their
                        strength. The foes of the "little giant" showed that they were alive and
                        kicking in old Franklin County.</p>
                    <p>The meeting assembled about one o'clock and was called to order by the
                        election of Col. James B. Orr, of Orrstown (where they "cannot go <emph
                            rend="italic">white slavery")</emph> President, and the chosing [sic] of
                        a number of Vice Presidents and Secretaries--among the latter of which was
                        another Orr.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Brewer offered a preamble and a series of Resolutions which he read to
                        the meeting. Prominant [sic] among them were two, one endorsing the
                        administration of James Buchanan, and the other endorsing the nomination of
                        Mr. Buchanan's trusty friend, William P. Schell, the nominee of the Nigger
                        Democracy for Congress in this District--both of which the gentleman read
                        with a significant air of triumph.</p>
                    <p>Among the Resolves was one going it strong for the Breckinridge (Cresson
                        fusion) electoral ticket, and another pretending to favor the election of
                        the County ticket of the Nigger Democracy. Everybody understood the meaning
                        of the last-named resolution; if they had dared to rebel against the action
                        of the Douglas nominating convention which placed that ticket before the
                        party for their support, tyrannical though the proceedings of that
                        Convention were, according to their own representations, they knew that the
                        Douglas men would have called a meeting and have read the Breckinridge men
                        of this County out of the party. This was more than they were prepared to
                        encounter. They were satisfied with passing an empty set of resolutions
                        against the action of the recent Douglas Convention, and saving themselves
                        within the pale of the party by promising to support the ticket which that
                        anti-Buchanan Convention put in nomination.</p>
                    <p>After the Resolutions were read a young gentleman from London was called upon
                        and took the floor. He proceeded to discuss the resolutions in a style which
                        was very creditable for one of his years--he having evidently not tarried in
                        Jerricho long enough for his beard to have grown--and which, having been
                        carefully committed, was very well declaimed. If he had given credit to
                        Webster, and other statesman from whom he quoted the most beautiful portions
                        of his sophomorical exhibition, he would not have seemed to be guilty of
                        plagiarism.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Brewer followed in his usual, easy style; but had like to draw tears from
                        "eyes unused to weeping" by declaring that there was danger of Washington's
                        grave being translated to some foreign land if the Cresson fusion ticket,
                        and its candidate, John B. Breckinridge, should be defeated.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Douglas--not the "little giant," but our fellow-townsman--next responded
                        to the calls of the meeting in a short speech, which never touched one of
                        the Resolves, nor enlightened the people on the all-important subject--the
                        object of the meeting.</p>
                    <p>After the last speaker took his seat the Resolutions and preamble were passed
                        in a lump. One of the orators of the occasion asked another of them to call
                        for three cheers, and he asked the third speaker to call for them, but, as
                        neither liked to venture upon so hazardous an undertaking, the meeting
                        dispersed as quietly and solemnly as though they had just been attending a
                        funeral.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schell</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of anti-Douglas supporters who endorsed the present
                    administration and the nominee, William P. Schell, for this district, but they
                    could not come out against the resolutions of Douglas' party, for fear that they
                    might be ousted from the Democratic party.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept60.html#9.19c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our County Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A bit of advice to Republican voters against voting for Locofocos who claim
                    not to want the defeat the entire Republican ticket, but just to win their
                    personal elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Presto, Change</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schell</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A note of inconsistency by the Times (a.k.a. "Shetter Weed") who supports
                    Foster because he was nominated before the Democrats' division, and yet it also
                    supports Schell, from Beford, for the local district, who was nominated after
                    the split.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Tell The Truth, Once</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository accuses the Chambersburg Times for publishing a number of
                    lies in its most recent edition--particularly their description of the Wide
                    Awakes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Town Clique</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "The last few issues of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> have
                    been loud in denouncing certain Locofoco leaders of this place as the "town
                    clique." What caused the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> to break faith with
                    its life-long friends?" </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The last few issues of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> have been
                        loud in denouncing certain Locofoco leaders of this place as the "town
                        clique." What caused the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> to break faith
                        with its life-long friends? The managers of that journal have certainly
                        belonged to the "town clique" for some years themselves. We have been
                        informed that an humble number of their party, residing at Fayetteville, who
                        aspired to fill one of the Court House offices, sent to the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> office, a short time before the meeting of
                        the Douglas convention, his advertisement accompanied with the cash; but the
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit,</emph> and the "town clique," refused to
                        give him a hearing. The bold few who compose the "town clique" had
                        determined to choke off every person in the party who would dare to run in
                        opposition to the present incumbents--all good, true, loyal Douglas men. The
                        course of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> is somewhat strange, while
                        busily engaged denouncing the Douglas men of Chambersburg as being "the town
                        clique" it is industriously engaged assisting the Douglas leaders to elect
                        the Douglas candidates of the "town clique"--Keyser, Toms, Hamsher &amp;
                        Co.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Toms</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository accuses the Valley Spirit of being two-faced towards Douglas
                    supporters and candidates--calling them the "town Clique" (Keyser, Toms, Hamsher
                    &amp; Co.) --and yet not allowing Democratic opponents (of Douglas
                    candidates) to advertise for their elections in the Spirit.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept60.html#9.19a</note>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Good News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "According to a silly article in the <emph rend="italic">Spirit,</emph>
                    our candidate for the Presidency, "honest ole Abe," is so homely that in his
                    infancy his personal appearance frightened all his father's darkies so badly
                    that they ran off from their master; and as he grew larger, and mingled with
                    other boys, he frightened the slaves of his neighbors so that they took to their
                    heels, which caused the owners of human chattles [sic] to beseech him to leave
                    Kentucky." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>According to a silly article in the <emph rend="italic">Spirit,</emph> our
                        candidate for the Presidency, "honest ole Abe," is so homely that in his
                        infancy his personal appearance frightened all his father's darkies so badly
                        that they ran off from their master; and as he grew larger, and mingled with
                        other boys, he frightened the slaves of his neighbors so that they took to
                        their heels, which caused the owners of human chattles [sic] to beseech him
                        to leave Kentucky.</p>
                    <p>If this be true, it is one of the strongest arguments in favor of the
                        Election of Mr. LINCOLN, for if he can be of so much service as to frighten
                        all the darkies in the country to leave, we will have, what we should
                        have--a nation of Free Whites. The <emph rend="italic">Spirit,</emph> then,
                        unless its love for Sambo is too strong, will assist in the consummation of
                        so desirable a result.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A response to a Spirit article, which stated that Lincoln's ugliness chased
                    away all his family's and neighbors' 'darkies.'</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept60.html#9.19b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Strasberg Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of a Republican meeting in Letterkenny Sept. 15th, where Col. F. S.
                    Stumbaugh, L. S. Clarke Esq. and George Eyster Esq. spoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Jack Knife Coming</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors report that Lincoln plans to send the editor of the Spirit a
                    jack knife, since he is even more homely than Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Voters Remember!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A reminder to voters not to vote for D. K. Wunderlich for U. S. Senator,
                    since this is one less vote of support for the principles and planks of the
                    Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Herschel V. Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors remind readers of the pending visit to Chambersburg by Mr.
                    Johnson, and also his pro-slave property rights in the Territories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Reign Of Terror</head>
                <origin>The Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of Texas and other states blaming and lynching negroes and
                    abolitionists for various crimes (some of which they apparently did not commit)
                    ie. murder, insurrection, theft of a slave.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>short articles on politics around the nation.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rotary Harrow</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herst</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of a rotary harrow sent to W. S. Everett, Esq. the Secretary of the
                    Farmers and Mechanics Industrial Association of Franklin Co., who has given it
                    to A. R. Herst, Franklin Hall, who will show it to neighboring farmers. It will
                    be displayed at the fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Wide-Awake Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sleichter</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement by J. H. Criswell, Pres. and S. H. McElroy, Sec. that the
                    Republicans of Scotland have organized a Wide-Awake Club of fifty members.
                    Chosen officers: J. S. Chambers, Captain; B. W. Wallace, 1st Lieutenant; Henry
                    Sleichter, 2nd Lieutenant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Committee Of Reception</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dennerline</ln>
                        <fn>John G. A.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The list of men who will meet Col. Curtin and Carl Schurz, Esq. at the
                    railroad, and escort them to Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Progress Of The Vote Of Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin>The Lancaster Union</origin>
                <commentary>The Vote In All The Gubernatorial Contests</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list, beginning in 1790, that indicates the gubernatorial candidates and
                    their election results.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>biography on Carl Schurz; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19.06">
            <pageNote>Religious and agricultural articles; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19.07">
            <pageNote>Romance stories; articles on Indians and Japan; Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.19.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note of a railroad injury on the Saratoga and Washington train--a man was
                    jolted off the car, and was crushed and mangled.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keesecker</ln>
                        <fn>Cadwalader J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackens</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gossert</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pensinger</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 4th, Rev. F. Dyson married Cadwalader J. Keesecker to Margaret A.
                    Vanderaw, both of Franklin Co. On Sept. 13th, in Fayetteville, Rev. Z. A.
                    Colestock married George Lackens to Amanda C. Gossert, both of Quincy township.
                    On Sept. 13th, Rev. S. McHenry married William R. Pensinger to Louisa M.
                    Wunderlich, both of the vicinity of Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 14th, Mrs. Owen, widow of John Owen and mother of three pastors,
                    died in Lurgan township at age 63. On Aug. 8th, Hugh Crawford died in Green
                    township at age 76.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
