<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-12-05">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"Pennsylvania And The South"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Unionist writes to the editor, expressing his agreement that Pennsylvania
                    is not guilty of nullifying the fugitive slave law; that it is very responsible
                    in following the Constitution's requirements regarding protection of slave
                    property and in fact, it goes beyond what is required, when it--instead of the
                    Federal Gov't--provides jailing for apprehended fugitive slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The National Crisis. The Position Of Maryland. Letter From Governor Hicks.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor Hicks expresses his distaste at the election of Lincoln, but he
                    intends to support the constitutionality of the election; he expresses his
                    displeasure at the Northern states who have passed nullification laws, but he
                    warns that this has been done by the fanatics, and that the conservatives in
                    those states have already introduced repeals for those laws--and the South
                    should not do anything rash that would weaken the actions and words of those
                    conservatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>A Well Deserved Testimonial</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The North American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter to Col. A. K. McClure, from Republican friends thanking him for
                    his efforts during the election and inviting him to a public dinner, the date to
                    be named by him. A response from A. K. McClure, accepting the invitation and
                    choosing Dec. 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Facts And Fancies</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05.02">
            <pageNote>Oil Fever; Stomach of a Shark; Story of a Hero; Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Panic And Its Cause</head>
                <origin>N. Y Independent</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This is the secret of the Panic: The Slave Power undertaking to do through
                    the stock market what it failed to do through the ballotbox."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Independent suggests that the recent panic on the stock market has been
                    intentionally orchestrated by the South, who already are indebted to the North;
                    a secession would dissolve their debts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Anecdotes; news of general interest; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Heavy Bid</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "The recent election went very far toward establishing, beyond further
                    controversy, that there is a great, Free, active, thinking and working North;
                    that the <emph rend="italic">cotton</emph> rope with which nabobs heretofore
                    bound Freemen, enabling them to lead them whither they would, has been torn
                    asunder; that a Northern workingman--although 'a small fisted farmer,' a 'greasy
                    mechanic,' or a 'filthy operative,' in the estimation of Southern lords-of
                    -the-lash--is the equal of any man in Republican America; no matter what claims
                    to superiority the rich owners of human flesh may arrogate to themselves." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Rumor said, a few days since, that the decrepit old imbecile who holds the
                        important position of Chief Justice of the United States--Roger B.
                        Taney--had resigned that high trust. Immediately, longing glances were
                        thrown in the direction of that most coveted post. Among the patriots, whose
                        names we have seen mentioned in connection with that responsible office, is
                        Caleb Cushing. Whether he is anxious to succeed Taney or not we cannot say,
                        from personal knowledge; but the low disgusting speech delivered by him at
                        Newburyport, on Monday evening, the 26th ult., and published in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Press,</emph> of the 30th, is the heaviest bid in that
                        direction that we have yet seen. The labor seems to have been in vain,
                        however, for the old man has not let go his hold upon the judicial
                        robes--nor does he intend to do so.</p>
                    <p>The fact that Taney had not resigned, and had no intention of the sort,
                        however, was not known at the time Caleb Cushing held forth at Newburyport.
                        If diving down deeper, and coming up filthier than any other Northern man
                        could aspire to do will have the desired effect, to win golden opinions from
                        Southern Senators--who can control the appointment--then the claims of Caleb
                        Cushing are far ahead of those of any other sycophant we know of. To read
                        his speech, not being acquainted with the <emph rend="italic">truth</emph>
                        of history on the subject he discusses, one would suppose that slavery was
                        the greatest blessing that could befall a poor man; that our forefathers so
                        regarded it; that the greatest outrage upon the Constitution is in
                        entertaining a feeling hostile to human bondage; and the most dangerous
                        encroachment consists in speaking against the diction of Southern nabobs;
                        and the breaking up of the Union is the only remedy for the unheard of
                        indignities which Northern men inflict upon the South.</p>
                    <p>Everything that is wrong is ascribed to the Freemen of the North; everything
                        right, everything noble, to the South. No language is too severe to be
                        applied to his own neighbors and friends; none too gingerly for the haughty
                        hotspurs of slavedom. Caleb was very unfortunate in not having first beheld
                        the light of day; in not having first breathed God's free air in an humble,
                        obscure cabin on some large plantation--in negro quarters. His admiration of
                        slavery is such that if he had been born a son of bondage his eloquence
                        might have been turned to some account; his master might have given him
                        constant employment convincing his fellow slaves that their "normal
                        condition"--"and the normal condition of poor men everywhere, without regard
                        to color"--"is that of slavery." Doubtless if he had been raised under the
                            <emph rend="italic">beneficial influences</emph> of slavery, his
                        admiration of the "Peculiar Institution" would have prompted him to endeavor
                        to induce all poor men to become slaves--to voluntarily choose masters for
                        life.</p>
                    <p>As it is, however, having been born a white man, in the Free North, under the
                        benign influences of our "Peculiar Institutions": Free Schools, Freedom of
                        Speech, Freedom of the Press, Liberty in its fullest, largest sense, he can,
                        unmolested, pour forth his abominable tirades against the system of social,
                        moral and political sentiments and practice which, when fully developed, as
                        is in the case in the State in which he resides, produce a race of men in
                        every way the equals of any class of human beings in the world-- their Free
                        Schools being the basis of all their greatness. After reading this miserable
                        effort of a would be great man--abusing those of his own section and
                        adulating the owners of slaves--we thought that we would like to hear of a
                        Southern man (it might be the largest slaveowner in that section,) making a
                        speech as strongly against his neighbors, and against slavery, as Cushing's
                        is against freedom, and see how long he would go unpunished by Judge Lynch.</p>
                    <p>The office of Chief Justice, for life, is certainly an enviable position. It
                        is well worthy the noble ambition of any man competent to discharge its
                        duties; it is right and proper for such an one to put forth honorable
                        efforts to obtain the position <emph rend="italic">after having been
                            selected by his fellow men;</emph> but there is no excuse for truckling
                        subserviency in a mad desire to gain even such an honor. What, we would like
                        to know, but the wish of gaining a high place in the estimation of Southern
                        Senators--the men who, with the President, fill the post of Chief Justice
                        when a vacancy occurs--could have induced any man to occupy the bad eminence
                        which Cushing voluntarily assumed in his ridiculous outpouring of slang at
                        Newburyport?</p>
                    <p>There is no position on earth more degrading for a human being to occupy than
                        that of accuser of his nearest relatives and friends of constructive crimes.
                        There is no position less enviable than that of using the Freedom of Speech,
                        which can alone be uninterruptedly enjoyed in the North, in piling up
                        epithets upon the heads of those whose manly defence of the speaker and his
                        rights is his only guarantee of safety while he is abusing them for
                        maintaining the Liberty he so loudly decries. If, therefore, we had not the
                        most indubitable evidence of its truthfulness, we could scarcely believe
                        that a son of New England would demean himself so much, even when desiring
                        to make a heavy bid for a high office; as Caleb Cushing has done--vainly, as
                        he will find, endeavoring to appease the wrath of men who, loving such <emph
                            rend="italic">treason</emph> by his own people as he exhibits in his
                            <emph rend="italic">heavy</emph> bid, utterly despise the <emph
                            rend="italic">traitor.</emph> Caleb Cushing might have well spared
                        himself the trouble, and refrained from heaping this disgrace upon his
                        progeny; for he will not-- nor will any other aspirant who bids so heavy for
                        the place--ever accomplish his wishes by such base attempts at securing
                        Southern favor.</p>
                    <p>The practice of looking only to the South for political assistance, which too
                        many Northern aspirants for office have long indulged in--especially those
                        of the Locofoco school--has so completely absorbed the minds of seekers for
                        place that they do not believe that there is any other power in the land;
                        they forget that there is a North. The recent election went very far toward
                        establishing, beyond further controversy, that there is a great, Free,
                        active, thinking and working North; that the <emph rend="italic"
                        >cotton</emph> rope with which nabobs heretofore bound Freemen, enabling
                        them to lead them whither they would, has been torn asunder; that a Northern
                        workingman--although "a small fisted farmer," a "greasy mechanic," or a
                        "filthy operative," in the estimation of Southern lords-of -the-lash--is the
                        equal of any man in Republican America; no matter what claims to superiority
                        the rich owners of human flesh may arrogate to themselves. The manner in
                        which the Freemen of the North expressed their wishes on the 6th of
                        November, teaches the important lesson that, the day is not far distant when
                        no man can secure office who bids so heavily for exclusive Southern
                    favor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article referring to the rumored resignation of Chief Justice Taney and
                    the pro-Southern Caleb Cushing's bid for the position.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frdec60.html#12.5a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Kansas Sufferers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A fund for people suffering through the Kansas drought was collected at the
                    Lutheran church on Thanksgiving day and is held by John Mull, at the Bank of
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Another Word For Kansas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A merchant, Jacob Hoke, of Chambersburg, has letters describing the
                    sufferings of people in Kansas, and he is sharing them with the Ladies of
                    Chambersburg in order to encourage donations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Complimentary Banquet To Col. Alex. K. McClure, At the Continental.</head>
                <origin>The Philadelphia Daily News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Alex. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Description of the dinner given to honor Col. Alex. K. McClure's efforts as
                    the Chairman of the People's State Central Committee. Morton McMichael welcomed
                    and praised McClure, and then McClure himself spoke. He praised Col. Curtin's
                    efforts, and defended Pennsylvania from the accusation of nullifying the
                    fugitive slave law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The American Bible; The Wolf And The Lamb.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05.05">
            <pageNote>Continuation of Col. A. K. McClure' speech; The Pacific Calamity;
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements; fiction; bigraphy of John G. Leake.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05.07">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Letter To A Southron</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>To the Honorable James R. Chestnut, of Camden, South Carolina, U. S.
                    Senator.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A caustic letter to James R. Chestnut from '43 degrees N. Latitude,' that
                    questions whether 10,000 men and $1,000,000 will be enough should South Carolina
                    actually try to secede.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.12.05.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Thanksgiving Day In Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heysinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A description of the Union meeting held at the Lutheran church on
                    Thanksgiving day for members of all the denominations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fatal Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunwoody</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The conductor of the Cumberland Valley Railroad suffered a fatal accident
                    on Dec. 1st, as the Freight trains were approaching Chambersburg. He slipped and
                    was mangled, and died in spite of the help of two doctors, J. C. Richards and A.
                    H. Senseny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Railroad Conductor Injured</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pickel</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The conductor, John Pickel, of Chambersburg, was caught between two freight
                    cars, during departure preparation from Mechanicsburg, on Nov. 28th. He has
                    recovered enough to come home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bank Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>George R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of people elected to the Board of Directors, and the re-elected
                    officers for the Board.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Singular Cabbage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Walker gave the editors a stalk of cabbage with twelve heads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Military Display</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. P.B. Housum led the Chambersburg Artillery in a display on
                    Thanksgiving Day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keagy</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W. R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baer</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Rachael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zumbro</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Robert M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leitner</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Lemuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Susan E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 4th, Rev. Jacob Steck married Henry Keagy to Maggie Moore, both of
                    Chambersburg. On Nov. 27th, at the home of the bride's parents, in Quincy Twp.,
                    Rev. W. R. H. Deatrich married Jesse S. Baer to Rachael Whitmore, both of
                    Franklin co. On Nov. 29th, in Chambersburg, Rev. W. R. H. Deatrich married
                    Samuel Augustus Zumbro to Sarah A. Deatrich, both of St. Thomas Twp., Franklin
                    co. On Nov. 29th, Rev. S. McHenry married Robert M. Small, of Clay Lick Hall
                    (formerly of Clearspring, Md.), to Rebecca Leitner, of Mercersburg. On Nov.
                    29th, Rev. M. Snyder married Lemuel Kennedy, of Lurgan Twp., to Catharine
                    Bender, of Letterkenny Twp. On Nov. 29th, at the home of the bride's parents,
                    Rev. T. G. Apple married Jacob H. Shank to Susan E. Detrich, both of the
                    vicinity of Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stickel</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heysinger</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 26th, Mrs. Anna Eliza Stickel died at age 41. On Nov. 24th, Adam
                    Heysinger, of Fayetteville, died of consumption at age 22.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
