<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>October 29, 1996</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-05-09">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="09">9</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="1" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09.01">
            <pageNote>Proceedings of the Democratic Party Convention in Charleston, S. C.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="2" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09.02">
            <pageNote>Article on education. Advertisements.</pageNote>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Difference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article tells story about flirting and propriety.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>There is a seduction bill . . .</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notice of a bill in Kentucky which provides that women who wear low cut
                    dresses can be found guilty of seduction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="3" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09.03">
            <pageNote>Includes a letter from Kansas correspondent to Repository which details the
                events surrounding the shooting of a Deputy U.S. Marshall, blames Democratic "slave
                power" for the violence in Kansas.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="4" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09.04">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sectionalism Illuminated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"All the horrors of Disunionism with which the country has been threatened
                    by these locofoco Southern sectionalists, including the outrage upon decency and
                    good morals in Congress, and the wicked cruelties and lawless violence in
                    Kansas, emanated from Southern sectionalism."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have, for years, been aware of the fact that a dark spirit of sectionalism
                        has been brooding over our beloved land, like a gloomy pall, threatening to
                        shut out the genial rays of the sun of Liberty forever from our horizon. We
                        have known whence this forbidding spectre emanated. We have told our
                        readers, time and again, that the aims and objects of the Oligarchy were to
                        obtain complete and entire control of every avenue to the law-making, law-
                        executing and law-defining dapartments [sic] of the general government; that
                        they desired to carry their infamous system of concubinage, and selling of
                        their own progeny, into every portion of our beloved land. All this was
                        denied by the pliant tools of the slave-drivers--the Niggerized Democracy of
                        the North.</p>
                    <p>The impatient hot heads of slavery-extension, however, in their mad zeal for
                        spreading the iniquitous system of unpaid labor over all portions of the
                        country--even into regions where the fell spirit of slavery, the groans of
                        agony from the hearts of helpless females, at being forever separated from
                        their husbands, their natural protectors, have never obtruded their
                        unwelcome society--during the recent sessions of the sectional, political
                        organization at Charleston, have illuminated the sentiments of Southerners
                        and settled, beyond controversy, the question as we have hitherto presented
                        it.</p>
                    <p>The position of the Republican party has been, ever since its organization,
                        such as that no candid man could take exceptions to its creed. They have
                        only contended, as they are bound to do, even with the last drop of blood in
                        their veins, if necessary, as true and loyal sons of heroic ancestors, that
                        this country is the home of the <emph rend="italic">white man;</emph> the
                        place where the poor, oppressed, down-trodden <emph rend="italic"
                        >whites</emph> of other lands may come and find an asylum for themselves and
                        their little ones, away from the overbearing, degrading tyranny of their
                        fellow men--the rich aristocracy and heartless monarchs of the old world.
                        Shall we then, while extending the hand of welcome to the seeker after a
                            <emph rend="italic">home,</emph> and a place where <emph rend="italic"
                            >men</emph> is supposed to be regarded as the fellow man, allow petty
                        tyrants of our own land to over-run America with a baser and darker system
                        of oppression than is known in Europe, thereby debasing the toil of the
                            <emph rend="italic">white</emph> portion of society who earn their
                        living by daily labor? The instincts of a common humanity answer, No. The
                        nobler feelings of our nature prompt us to use our best efforts in behalf of
                        the oppressed of our own race--poor whites. All our endeavors shall,
                        therefrom, be exerted to secure free homes for free <emph rend="italic"
                            >white</emph> men and their families, and not contaminate free whites
                        with negro slave labor.</p>
                    <p>Sectionalism means that which pertains to a particular locality, or section
                        of the country. Slavery, therefore, being limited to certain States--legal
                        only where tolerated and provided for by special law--is purely sectional;
                        altogether local in its character. Freedom is as national, as wide-spread,
                        as the utmost limits of our ocean-bound Republic. Therefore that only is
                        Sectional which is confined within certain local boundaries, and that is
                        National which pervades every quarter of the country. Being National,
                        consequently, is to advocate the spread of principles which underlie the
                        superstructure of our Government; while the supporting of dogmas repugnant
                        to the genius of our institutions, and limited too by certain well defined
                        boundaries in their operations, is certainly Sectional, and nothing but
                        Sectional. The best proof which can be adduced by the Sectionalism of the
                        Democracy is that their principal aid is to <emph rend="italic"
                        >extend</emph> that which is now confined within local bounds--slavery.</p>
                    <p>The conduct of the Northern delegates to the Charleston convention, refusing
                        to submit to the <emph rend="italic">extreme</emph> measures demanded by the
                        Sectionalists, because of their Sectionalism, shows that they, even, are
                        beginning to see who are the real Sectionalists--the troublers of Israel.
                        They too are beginning to learn that the United States Government was formed
                        for some other purpose than to extend tyranny, and oppress the toiling
                        millions. The sectionalists expected to crush out every vestige of liberty
                        at the Charleston convention, and they came very nearly accomplishing their
                        nefarious scheme. If the high ground occupied by the Republican party for
                        the last four years, which has been so very popular with the working
                        classes, because of its sympathy with them, had not started the Northern
                        delegates to Charleston in the face, the Sectionalists would have triumphed.</p>
                    <p>All the horrors of Disunionism with which the country has been threatened by
                        these locofoco Southern sectionalists, including the outrages upon decency
                        and good morals in Congress, and the wicked cruelties and lawless violence
                        in Kansas, emanated from Southern Sectionalism. There never was a greater
                        insult given to the American people than that offered by locofoco who,
                        themselves, sustain the meanest sectionalism in the land, and call others,
                        those who advocate the principles of the Declaration of Independence in all
                        their purity, sectionalists. When the whole history of the locofoco party
                        comes to be summed up, it will all be embraced in one
                    word--Sectionalism.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial lays the blame for sectionalism on the Democratic Party in the
                    South.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.9a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial argues that slavery is inconsistent with democracy and the rule
                    of the people. It suggests that Jefferson's vision for the democratic republic
                    did not include slavery and that Jefferson opposed slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Washington Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from "Nerva," the Repository correspondent in Washington, on the
                    political ramifications of the Charleston convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="5" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09.05">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>School Director's Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zielgler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stine</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacoby</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lego</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pentz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheibley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Osbraugh</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Sacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reichard</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossart</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mish</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Issac R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minehart</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Emmanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Chas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>B. Parker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hysong</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>North</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbaker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shrader</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middower</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kepner</ln>
                        <fn>L. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bomberger</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGarvey</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>P. C.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russel</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoop</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lechron</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clagston</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwaine</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>Philip M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>School Directors elect Philip Shoemaker as Superintendent, 58 votes for
                    Shoemaker to 24 for Andrew McElwaine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Improved</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The internal part of the building has also been much repaired and painted,
                    giving to the property a very pretty and new appearance."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Lutheran congregation of this place, have much improved their Parsonage.
                        The front has been born out and re-built with beautiful pressed brick, on
                        fine red sandstone range work. The internal part of the building has also
                        been much repaired and painted, giving to the property a very pretty and new
                        appearance. It will now be a convenient as well as a handsome residence, and
                        is creditable to the congregation thus to comfortably situate their new
                        pastor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notice of Lutheran church improvements to Parsonage.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.9e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Improvements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are gratified to notice various improvements going on in different
                    parts of our beautiful town. It is an evidence that the building spirit was not
                    exhausted last year by the unusually large number of fine structures that were
                    erected by our citizens."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are gratified to notice various improvements going on in different parts
                        of our beautiful town. It is an evidence that the building spirit was not
                        exhausted last year by the unusually large number of fine structures that
                        were erected by our citizens.</p>
                    <p>D. K. WUNDERLICH, Esq., is now engaged in the excavation of a cellar
                        preparatory to the erection of a very fine two-storied dwelling on Second
                        street, near the M. E. Church. Judging from the plan of the front, (which we
                        had the pleasure of seeing a few days ago,) it will be the most beautiful
                        building, for a private residence in the town. The front will be pressed
                        brick--the window and door sills, the sides of the door, as well as the
                        range work, all to be of red sandstone, with double steps to the front
                        entrance, to be surmounted with iron railing. The whole improvement will be
                        very creditable to the taste and enterprise of our worthy townsman.</p>
                    <p>We understand that Mr. JAMES KING will, in the course of the season, enlarge
                        and remodel the front of his present dwelling, located on East Queen street.
                        It is his purpose to re-build the front with pressed brick, and to use red
                        sandstone for range work, and the entire door frame, as well as window sills
                        of the same material, ornamented. With Mr. KING's known skill as a
                        stonecutter, we have no doubt but that he will make his residence assume a
                        very attractive appearance.</p>
                    <p>MESSRS MYERS &amp; BRAND are also now making arrangements for the
                        building of a large two-storied addition to the rear end of the property
                        which they recently purchased--late part of the estate of Judge Thompson,
                        dec'd. This additional building is intended as an extension of the Store
                        Room, which the above named gentlemen are going to occupy next spring for
                        their Hardware business. It will thus be made one of the largest and finest
                        Store Rooms in the Borough. They also intend, we believe, to let the floor
                        of the front building down to a level with the pavement, and to modernize
                        the front.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editors praise the recent improvements to buildings in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.9f</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Improvements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers &amp; Brand</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Improvements to buildings noted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Capt. Samuel Walker</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowe</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editors relate their conversation with Samuel Walker, a native of Franklin
                    County, and the Sheriff of Douglas County, Kansas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Surveyor General's Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus F.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of Augustus Armstrong's appointment as surveyor in state surveyor's
                    office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Revival of Religion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For four weeks there has been a revival of Religion going on in the church of
                        the United Brethren in Christ, in this place. During that time some twenty
                        five persons have given hopeful evidence of conversion. The Rev. Z. A.
                        COLDSTOCK is the Preacher in charge, and is a most excellent and faithful
                        pastor. May he have many souls for his hire.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coldstock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of religious revival at United Brethren Church in Christ.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.9c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mount Vernon Fund</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Contributions to the Ladies Mount Vernon Association, for the month of April,
                        1860, in Franklin County:</p>
                    <p>Chambersburg......................$53.62 1/2</p>
                    <p>Strasburg.........................10.00</p>
                    <p>Fannettsburg......................2.00</p>
                    <p>Orrstown..........................5.00</p>
                    <p>Waynesboro........................10.00</p>
                    <p>____________________________________________</p>
                    <p>Total.............................$80.62 1/2</p>
                    <p>Manager for Franklin County, of the Ladies Mount Vernon Association.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Accounting of funds raised in April, $80.12, from the treasurer, Mrs. R. M.
                    Bard.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.9b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Mercersburg Classis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of meeting in the German Reformed Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Public Meetings: Central Club</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the People's Party of the Borough of Chambersburg convened at
                        the Public House of Mrs. R. Fisher, on the evening of the 26th ult., for the
                        purpose of nominating candidates for Burgess, School Directors, &amp;c.,
                        prior to adjourning, the following resolution was adopted:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That when this meeting adjourns, it will
                        adjourn to meet at the Public House of Jacob S. Brown, Esq., <emph
                            rend="italic">on Friday Evening, May</emph> 11<emph rend="italic"
                        >th,</emph> 1860, for the purpose of forming a CENTRAL CLUB, of the People's
                        Party of Chambersburg, and that all friends to the formation of such a Club
                        be invited to attend.</p>
                    <p>JACOB HENNINGER, <emph rend="italic">Pres't.</emph></p>
                    <p>G. H. MERKLEIN, <emph rend="italic">Sec'y.</emph></p>
                    <p>In accordance with the foregoing resolution, a meeting of all friendly to the
                        formation of a Central Club of the People's Party of the Borough of
                        Chambersburg, will be held at the Public House of Jacob S. Brown, Esq.</p>
                    <p>On Friday Evening next, May 11.</p>
                    <p>The friends of Freedom, the Constitution and the Union are cordially invited
                        to be present. The young men--especially--our country's hope--will please
                        attend.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merklein</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Public notice of People's Party central club meeting.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.9d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Public Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The friends of Freedom, the Constitution and Union are invited to a
                    meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="6" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09.06">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="7" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="8" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.09.08">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Census of 1860</head>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article projects the results of the latest census on the political
                    representation in Congress and concludes that the South "loses ground largely."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Glowing Extract</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The South want and strive for unlimited Slavery Extension and the
                    subjection of the North. They would fire this temple; but the North had the
                    ability and power to save both it and them."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Hickman (A. L. Dem., Pa.) said that sectionalism had been nursed and
                        animated until it had become the fruitful and commanding parent of all our
                        afflictions. It is not the sectionalism of the North but of the South--not
                        springiug [sic] from the few who understand the Constitution in all its
                        bearings, but from the many, who, feeling their weakness, have united for
                        strength--a sectionalism not created in the atmosphere which cools the
                        laborer's brow, but in the fetid atmosphere of rice swamps and cotton
                        fields--a sectionalism now mild and pursuasive [sic], then fierce and
                        persistent, it is the emblem on the shield of Alcibiades, as a child
                        harmless, but we give it the thunderbolt and make it fierce and destructive.
                        He wished to impress this truth on the public mind, namely, that it is the
                        determination of the South to extend rather than to reduce the limits of
                        Slavery. This arrays the different parts of the country in hostility, and in
                        this connection he spoke of the cringing Buchanan in contrast with the
                        inflexible immovable Jackson. The North will endeavor to preserve the
                        Federal compact in its integrity, and they were fast forming the
                        determination of preventing others from intracting [sic] it. The spoke of
                        the humiliating concessions to the South in the compromise of 1850,
                        including the Fugitive Slave Law, which compels men to leave their fields
                        and shops to run after the fleeing negro while the North are denied equality
                        in the Union. The present Executive has not rendered himself more notorious
                        by his partiality than he has by the disgusting subserviency in his
                        rule.--His deception as a candidate was equalled only by his cynical
                        demeanor to his true friends, and he felt the flattery of sycophants beyond
                        the honest report of disinterested friends. He spoke of the departure from
                        the doctrine of popular sovereignty as enunciated in 1856, because it failed
                        to give Kansas to Slavery. Those who opposed the President's demands had
                        been branded with treason, and trodden down under the iron heel of a fierce
                        tyranny. Certain members of the XXXIIId Congress sowed the harvest, the
                        fruit of which has been reaped at Charleston. In all the bloody history of
                        Kansas the people found the President could be as false as any other man. He
                        spoke of the absurdity of the South in their efforts to preserve not only
                        the territory they now possess, but to acquire Mexico, Cuba, and Central
                        America, as they say, for an outlet to their surplus labor. The South want
                        and strive for unlimited Slavery Extension and the subjection of the North.
                        They would fire this temple; but the North had the ability and power to save
                        both it and them. He proved, he said, the accuser guilty, and sectionalism
                        the accusation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hickman</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article recounts Hickman's statments concerning the sectional attitudes in
                    the South.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.9g</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Marie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitaker</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitaker</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gribble</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gribble</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death notices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F/</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fell</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dullabaum</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hempfield</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowe</ln>
                        <fn>Clarissa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage announcements.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
