<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-09-12">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Speech Of Hon. A. K. McClure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>In the Republican Wigwam, Philadelphia, September 5, 1860</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A speech arguing for support of Col. Curtin, and dissuading support of
                    Henry D. Foster in the election for Pa. Governor. McClure argues that Foster,
                    though he claims to support the doctrine of a tariff, in reality, is a free
                    trade man, and a pawn in the battle between Democratic contenders for the
                    Presidency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Facts and Fancies; a poem</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Just View Of The Case</head>
                <origin>The Philadelphia North American</origin>
                <commentary>Speech of Hon. R. W. Thompson, of Indiana, at Terre Haute, August 4th,
                    1860.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In his speech, the Hon. R. W. Thompson explains that he will continue his
                    support of Bell only if Bell does not sell his supporters to the highest
                    Democrat bidder. He would prefer Lincoln to win, than either Democrat candidate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mr. Lincoln's Eulogy on Henry Clay</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In an excerpt of Lincoln's eulogy on Henry Clay, given at the time of his
                    death, Lincoln praises Clay and states that the country would not be the same
                    powerful, prosperous place without Clay.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Republicanism In Kentucky</head>
                <origin>Correspondent of the N. Y. Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of a speech by an avid Lincoln supporter at a County Court
                    Day in Kentucky--the most interesting note is that the man owned 40 or 50
                    slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>various articles: Toleration of Medicine; Occupations of Emigrants; Cure For
                Hydrophobia; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Campaign Opened</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The political campaign, the bloodless war, has fairly commenced in this
                    County."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The political campaign, the bloodless war, has fairly commenced in this
                        County. On Monday last a committee, consisting of Capt. James M. Brown,
                        Capt. P. B. Housum, Capt. George Jarrett, Sheriff William McGrath,
                        Ex-Sheriff Jacob S. Brown, Mr. N. P. Pearse, Mr. A. D. Caufman, Mr. D. S.
                        Fahnestock, Mr. A. R. Hurst, Mr. J. W. Fletcher and A. N. Rankin, left this
                        place in the afternoon Train of cars and went as far as Shippensburg, where
                        they remained till the evening Train from Harrisburg arrived, which they
                        entered and found therein MORTON McMICHAEL, Esq., of Philadelphia, whom they
                        took in charge and escorted to Chambersburg. Upon the invitation of Col.
                        McClure, Mr. McMichael was taken to the residence of the former and became
                        his guest. In the evening the Fayetteville Band, followed by a number of
                        Carriages, filled with voters, came to town and added very much to the
                        pleasures of the evening's entertainment by their enlivening music.</p>
                    <p>During the afternoon of Monday, according to previous arrangement, the "Wide
                        Awakes" of Chambersburg erected a nice pole, over an hundred feet high, in
                        front of our office--the old temple of Liberty, a name bestowed upon the
                        REPOSITORY building by the lamented Pritts. From the top of the pole floats
                        a small streamed composed of red, white and blue ribbons. About twelve feet
                        from the top there is a pretty blue Streamer with the names of our
                        candidates--LINCOLN, HAMLIN, CURTIN,--thereon, in white letters. Some twelve
                        feet lower down is suspended a handsome national flag. The pole was raised
                        at the first effort, and without any accident.</p>
                    <p>After dark the "Wide Awakes," one hundred rank and file in uniform, commanded
                        by their captain, P. B. Housum, formed a procession and, preceded by the
                        Fayetteville Brass Band, and the Chambersburg Brass Band, proceeded to the
                        residence of Col. McClure and escorted Morton McMichael, Esq., to Franklin
                        Hall, where there was a great throng of people. The meeting was organized by
                        calling Col. McClure to the Chair. The Col. read a letter from the Hon
                        George Chambers, whom a large portion of our citizens desired should
                        preside. The letter is elsewhere in this paper. Mr. M. entertained a large
                        audience for two hours with a style of speech rarely to be met with. When
                        Mr. McMichael finished the chairman of the meeting, Col. McClure, stated
                        that Doc. S. E. Duffield, of Fulton County, was in the Hall, and that, as
                        soon as the Band would play a piece of music, he would all upon the Doctor
                        for a speech. The audience, as soon as they learned that the Doctor was
                        present, began to call loudly for him. While the Bands were playing he made
                        his appearance upon the stage. As soon as the music was finished he was
                        introduced by Col. McClure, and proceeded to deliver an eloquent speech of
                        about thirty minutes in length. The lateness of the hour prevented him
                        speaking longer.</p>
                    <p>The meeting in the Hall having adjourned, "Wide Awakes" re-formed, and,
                        accompanied by both Bands, marched through the principal streets of the
                        town, presenting a beautiful spectacle. A procession of over one hundred
                        persons with caps and capes alike, and each with a torch in his hand,
                        affords a sight which must be seen to be fully realized. The "Wide Awakes"
                        escorted Mr. McMichael to the residence of Col. McClure, where, in response
                        to calls from the "Wide Awakes," short addresses were delivered by Messrs.
                        McMichael and McClure.</p>
                    <p>On next Monday evening the 17th, the Hon. E. McPHERSON, and others, will
                        speak at Quincy, on Tuesday evening, the 18th at Fayetteville, on Wednesday
                        evening the 19th, at Waynesboro' on Friday evening the 21st, at Greencastle,
                        on Saturday afternoon the 22nd, at precisely 3 o'clock, at the Welsh Run,
                        and in the evening of the same day at Mercersburg-- Bradley's Brass Band
                        will be at both the latter-named meetings.</p>
                    <p>On Saturday the 22nd, there will be a Mass Meeting at Chambersburg, which
                        will, without fail, be addressed by the great Wisconsin Orator CARL SCHURZ,
                        Esq., who is said to be the equal of the renowned Hungarian Kossuth. This
                        will be a rare treat. Only once in a life-time, to many of us, will this
                        grand opportunity be presented. No person will fail to attend who can by any
                        possibility be present. In the evening Mr. SCHURZ, will speak in german, his
                        native language, to the citizens of Chambersburg who can understand him. The
                        german portion of our population, who do not fully comprehend the objects of
                        Republicanism, are particularly invited to listen to this great expounder of
                        our political faith; himself a german by birth.</p>
                    <p>Col. A. G. Curtin, our candidate for Governor, has also been announced to
                        speak on that occasion, and we confidently expect him to come; but, owing to
                        the fact that his opponent Henry D. Foster, has mounted the stump, and has
                        signified his willingness to meet Col. Curtin, which the gallant Col. is
                        very anxious should take place, the arrangements for the joint discussion
                        may interfere with his former plan of meeting with the People of Franklin
                        County on that occassion [sic]. He will, however, be in Chambersburg to
                        speak during the campaign; and may be here on the 22nd.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ex-Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearse</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>S. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A description of the Republican campaign's commencement in Chambersburg
                    with the arrival of Morton McMichael, Esq., of Philadelphia, who came to speak,
                    and who was greeted and escorted by a committee partially consisting of Wide
                    Awakes.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept60.html#9.12a</note>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Morton McMichael's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of McMichael's speech given Sept. 10th at Franklin Hall--that
                    McMichael mentioned the topic of slavery only once (when criticizing Douglas)
                    since he feels the topic of industry is more of a concern to the people of
                    Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Waynesboro Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of a meeting of the friends of Lincoln, Hamlin and Curtin, on Sept.
                    8th in Waynesboro, where E. J. Bonebrake and P. Hamman, Esq. spoke</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Culbertson's Row Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Rush</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Master</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Master</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of two meetings: one at Culbertson's Row on Sept. 10th, where "Live
                    Yankee" L. S. Clarke, Esq., Col. F. S. Stumbaugh, and William G. Mitchell spoke.
                    The other took place in Guilford on Sept. 11th, where two young men, Masters
                    Rush Senseny and William Etter, spoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter from Hon. George Chambers declining to appear at the Sept. 10th
                    meeting at Franklin Hall, but that, since he cannot support Bell (because of the
                    improbability of his election), he throws his support to Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Curtin And The Germans: A Base Slander Publicly Refuted.</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Telegraph published the retraction of the German newspaper, Berichter,
                    that had printed accusations that Curtin had spoken with disrespect against the
                    Germans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>What The Republicans Intend To Do</head>
                <origin>New Brunswick (N.J.) Fredonian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Finally, they will not make the 'Nigger' the only object of worship and
                    consideration, but will endeavor to look after and enhance the interests of the
                    WHITE MAN. These are some of the things the Republicans will do when they get
                    into power."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Hon. J. M. Harris, at the Bell meeting held in this city last week, asked the
                        following pertinent questions:</p>
                    <p>"What are the Republicans to do when they get into power?"</p>
                    <p>We propose to reply briefly as to a few things which will be accomplished by
                        the Republicans when they get into power:</p>
                    <p>1. The first work of the Republicans will be to put an end to the disturbed
                        state of the public mind arising from the discussion of the slavery
                        question, by showing that they have no desire to interfere with the
                        institution of slavery where it now exists, and only want to prevent its
                        spread into territories now and always free, and that only by means
                        recognized and provided for in the Constitution of the United States. Then
                        the "bugbear" created by the anti- Republicans will explode, the era of good
                        will and confidence between the North and South will be restored, and peace
                        concord and union prevail.</p>
                    <p>2. The territories being guaranteed to Freedom and Industry, and made fit for
                        the free habitation of free, white laboring men, the Republicans will then
                        "make the land free to all actual settlers," in quantities sufficient to
                        enable a workingman to get a good living from, and raise up and educate his
                        family in a respectable manner. This will be done in preference to the
                        present system of giving them away to schemers of all kinds, or selling them
                        in large quantities to speculators who can afford to keep them without
                        improvement for a long time, and eventually selling them to the hard-working
                        settlers for a large advance upon the original cost.</p>
                    <p>3. Protection to American Industry is one of the cardinal doctrines in the
                        Republican Platform. The Republicans intend to pass a Tariff law sufficient
                        to protect the labor of our free white mechanics and factory operatives
                        against the ruinous competition of the pauper labor of Europe--a tariff
                        which will not only protect the interests of the mechanic, but also create
                        home markets for the products of our soil, and place the whole community
                        beyond the accidents of trade and commercial panics. When such a law is
                        fairly in force in this country, there will be no good reason why every
                        mechanic and laborer cannot earn a good and comfortable living for himself
                        and family, and, if prudent, lay up something for a "rainy day."</p>
                    <p>4. The Republicans intend to afford adequate aid to commerce and navigation
                        on the lakes, rivers, and harbors, by constructing necessary light-houses
                        and break-waters, and removing shoals, snags, and other obstructions to the
                        safe navigation of our public waters.-- The protection to the lives and
                        property of its citizens is an obligation imposed upon all good governments.</p>
                    <p>5. The building of a railroad to the Pacific is one of the "necessities" of
                        this country, and when the Republicans get into power, they will secure its
                        construction at an early period. The great traffic that now and always will
                        be carried on between the Eastern and Western shores of our country demands
                        greater safety and expedition than is now afforded by the tedious and
                        dangerous marches through dreary deserts or long voyages at sea equally
                        hazardous to life and property.</p>
                    <p>6. The Republicans mean to bring back the administration to its original
                        purity and economy, by placing good men into offices of trust, and frown
                        down and punish all attempts at corruption and peculation by any of its
                        agents. The Republicans will act fairly towards the interests of Freedom and
                        Slavery, and will not occupy itself in encouraging fillibusterism, hatching
                        schemes for stealing the possessions of our weak and peaceful neighbors,
                        encouraging the revival of the African Slave Trade, and creating dissensions
                        and ill-feeling between the different sections of our country, as has been
                        done by the present and former administrations. They will not abstract the
                        public money under the guise of "contracts" for the purpose of bribing
                        Congressmen to vote for some administration iniquity, or sustaining a pet
                        organ of the President, or to carry some local election, or supporting and
                        encouraging "third parties" among their political opponents. They will not
                        in a time of profound peace with all the world, run the country into debt at
                        the rate of $20,000,000 annually, as has been done by the present Democratic
                        administration. Finally, they will not make the "Nigger" the only object of
                        worship and consideration, but will endeavor to look after and enhance the
                        interests of the WHITE MAN. These are some of the things the Republicans
                        will do when they get into power.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Bell supporter lists the six main objectives of the
                    Republicans--protection of Industry, construction of railroads, aid to naval
                    commerce, end the slavery discussion, pass the Homestead Act, and purify the
                    administration.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept60.html#9.12b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Hint To Future Biographers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fern</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fanny Fern writes to complain about the title of "The Life of Mr. Jones"and
                    remind that there was a Mrs. Jones who supported her husband--and that there
                    usually is a hidden, supportive wife, without whom the great men would not have
                    been great.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Diseases Of Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list of diseases--gout, pleurisy, dysentary, bowel complaint, sore
                    throat--used as excuses by Douglas to miss discussion or voting of important
                    bills in the House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recount that displays the growing animosity between the Republican Wide
                    Awakes and Democrats; at a funeral for a Wide Awake in Indiana, Democrats
                    inconvenienced the funeral service with a mob and jeering outside the Wide
                    Awakes' Hall from which the funeral procession started.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Humorous and Romantic stories; political articles.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Elwain</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An Announcement of a meeting on Sept. 19th in Scotland at Mr. Dice's store,
                    where C. Long of Shippensburg, P. Hamman and A. McElwain, both of Chambersburg,
                    D. F. Etter, and J. Ditzler will speak.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"Our Flag Is There"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Dewalt</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pew</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>Callie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Description of the construction and mention of the craftsmen of the
                    Republicans' liberty pole in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list of contributions in July and August in Franklin County, to the
                    Ladies' Mount Vernon Association. Chambersburg-$5.50, Loudon-$3.00,
                    Roxbury-$1.25, Strasburg-$1.00.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lurgan In Motion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Morrow R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deardorff</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saltsman</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazlett</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Lincoln and Hamlin club was formed in Roxbury on Sept. 6th. The elected
                    officers include: Morrow R. Skinner, President; Thomas Pomeroy Jr., Secretary;
                    William Deardorff, Assistant Secretary; John M. Saltsman, Corresponding
                    Secretary; Cyrus Hazlett, Treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Barn Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mourer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The barn of George Mourer of Antrim township burned down Sept. 8th; caused
                    by lightning, the fire destroyed his wheat, hay, and oat crops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Whose Fault Is It?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors complain of a hog wallow that occurs in the public square
                    whenever it rains, and requests that the citizen who allows his animals to do
                    this to please stop this.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyer</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Description of a crane--five feet tall and a wingspan of six feet--shot by
                    Abraham S. Oyer, near Monn's mill, north of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter and excerpt from "An Injurious Fertilizer" (in the Philadelphia
                    Century) arguing against the use of fecal matter treated with poudrette as a
                    fertilizer--that vegetables grown in it cause nausea, and possibly consumption.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Rush At New York</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"To this State, then, all eyes are now turned on this last forlorn hope,
                    all efforts are concentrated. Here the traffickers are congregated; and any
                    aspirant who can show a colorable title to a thousand transferable Breckinridge
                    votes may readily barter them for a Congressional nomination, while a hundred
                    such secures a nibble at a Sheriffalty or a tolerable chance for a seat in the
                    Assembly."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Tribune notes that New York could be the deciding state in the election
                    and urges Republicans to rally and help bring about a Republican victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sheriff McGrath posts the notice of Mary Mentzer's application, done by
                    Jacob Good, for divorce from Samuel Mentzer--to be settled Oct. 29th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12.06">
            <pageNote>Articles of politics, crime, and interest from other states;
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12.07">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Familiar Voice To Old-Line Whigs</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Tribune asks the friends of Henry Clay which candidate they will
                    support, and then provides a letter written by Henry Clay that promotes the same
                    objectives as the Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Winan's Steamer</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A witness' description of Winan's steamer boat as it passed by him--that it
                    is an impressive technological feat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various articles: politics in Tennessee; little boy's death; news from
            Europe.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.12.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegerreis</ln>
                        <fn>Michael R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Low</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bridenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreps</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>Nettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>Mathias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 6th, at the bride's mother's home at Philips' Mill, Path Valley,
                    the Rev. William A. West married Michael R. Kegerreis, of Fannettesburg, to Kate
                    Sharp. On Sept. 7th, Rev. T. G. Apple married Philip Low to Sarah Byers, both of
                    Antrim township. On Sept. 4th, Rev. E. Bridenbaugh married Michael Kreps to Miss
                    Nettie Barr, adopted daughter of Mathias and Mary Nead, all of Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorris</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorris</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frederick</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Clara Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sites</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 3rd, in Huntingdon, Elizabeth L. Dorris, a native of Greencastle,
                    wife of William Dorris and youngest daughter of Elias Davidson, Esq. (who died
                    thirty years ago) died of apoplexy at age 42. On Sept. 6th, in Quincy township,
                    Mrs. Elizabeth Frederick died at age 84. On Sept. 5th, in Fayetteville, Clara
                    Belle Etter died at 8 months. On Aug. 30th, in Montgomery township, David Sites
                    died at age 52.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
