<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1863/pa.fr.vs.1863.05.20">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 3/3/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-05-20">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.05.20.01">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements, fiction and humor</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.05.20.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>That "Simple Question" Answered</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Yes, argues the Transcript, but these acts are rendered imperative by
                    'military or public necessity.' Our system of Government knows no such terms....
                    Why look where the monstrous doctrine leads to!... Louis Napoleon became Emperor
                    of France on the doctrine of 'public necessity.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors take up a challenge from the Transcript to explain how they can
                    oppose the administration and support the government. They first argue that the
                    creation of West Virginia from Virginia, the Confiscation bill, the suspension
                    of habeas corpus and the abridgments of freedoms of speech and the press were
                    all unconstitutional. If this is the case, they say, what does it mean to be
                    loyal--to defend the Constitution, or the administration which has violated it?</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Administration vs. The People</head>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors argue that, at the beginning of the war, the Northern public
                    and the army were unified behind the goal of preserving the Constitution as it
                    is and the Union as it was. However, since then both the country and the army
                    have become demoralized because the administration has politicized the war. With
                    abolition as the goal of the war, the only solution would be the extermination
                    of all the whites in the South and the annihilation of its industry. The
                    Northern public outside New England, argues the writer, has rejected the
                    administration's course, as the fall elections demonstrated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Transcript and Repository</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors claim that the Transcript quoted approvingly a report by the
                    Richmond Whig that McClellan did not advance on Munson's Hill and Manassas in
                    1861 because he knew his men were cowards and he wanted to protect his
                    reputation. The editors condemn "this vile slander on our brave volunteers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Erie Observer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Colonel is plainly of the opinion that truth and good sense are things
                    to be ashamed of."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Observer notes the dispute between Colonel McClure and the Spirit and
                    Times over the paper's report of McClure's alleged chastising of Republicans for
                    excessive partisanship and his alleged disavowal of abolition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.05.20.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Coming Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is a source of deep regret that a more general movement, on the part of
                    the citizens, has not been made for their reception."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The 126th Regiment arrived at Camp Curtin, on Thursday last, on their way
                        home, having been relieved from service in the Army of the Potomac. The time
                        of their arrival here is not positively known, but it will not probably be
                        before the last of this or the first of next week, as they will be detained
                        in Harrisburg until they are paid off and mustered out of the service. Many
                        of "the boys" have already paid us flying visits, giving their officers "the
                        slip" for a day or so; and they are all in the finest health and spirits.</p>
                    <p>It is a source of deep regret that a more general movement, on the part of
                        the citizens, has not been made for their reception. The effort to give it a
                        political complexion--which has been made by a few broken down politicians
                        in our town--we can only characterize as the very depth of partizan
                        littleness. It looks more like a movement in glorification of the "Union
                        League" than in honor of the returning braves, who come to us "fresh from
                        the fields of their glory."</p>
                    <p>But we feel confident these tricks of the little politicians will not prevent
                        the people from giving their sons, brothers and friends such a greeting as
                        they deserve. They will receive them in their own good way; and the warm
                        grasp of the hand, and the few trembling and sincere words of gratitude and
                        welcome, will tell those sons, brothers and friends far more than all the
                        noisy professions of selfish politicians. The people will be on hand by
                        thousands, without regard to politics or the politicians, and their
                        reception, although perhaps not so gaudy as that of the "Union Leagues,"
                        will have at least the merit of sincerity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The 126th Reg't Penn. Volunteers has been relieved of service with the Army
                    of the Potomac in Washington, D.C. They will probably not arrive in town until
                    next week, as they will stay in Harrisburg until they are paid and mustered out.
                    However, a number have been visiting town already. The editors complain that an
                    adequate reception has not been prepared for their return.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Broke Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hooker</ln>
                        <fn>Joe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashmead</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two prisoners broke out of the County Jail on Tuesday night. One was the
                    "notorious" horse thief Joe Hooker, and the other was a deserter named Edwin P.
                    Byers. Under instructions from Lieut. Ashmead, Sheriff Brandt had been treating
                    the military prisoners leniently, and Byers was given the freedom of the jail.
                    On Tuesday, Byers' cell was open. He broke the lock off of Hooker's cell, and
                    the two broke through a wall and escaped. Byers was caught and brought back on
                    Friday, but Hooker remains at large.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Military Arrest</head>
                <origin>Mercersburg Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In all candor, isn't it pretty nearly time that this nonsense should
                    cease? It is a very mean way for any man to vent his malice upon his neighbor,
                    by laying secret information against him, and getting him carried away from his
                    home for trial, and then not having the manliness to appear against him."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashmead</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baxter</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors note the arrest in Mercersburg of W. C. Baxter, who was
                    arrested on Thursday and taken to Chambersburg on Friday by the Provost Guard.
                    He was brought before Lieut. Ashmead, and was dismissed because there was no
                    evidence against him. The editors call for an end to such arbitrary and
                    unfounded arrests, saying they bring only ridicule upon the authorities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Election of Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immell</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The stockholders of the "Farmers and Mechanics Industrial Association of
                    Franklin County" of Chambersburg met on Tuesday May 12 to elect officers for the
                    following year. Elected were: President, John Ruthrauff; Vice Presidents, Jacob
                    S. Nixon, G. W. Immell, James C. Eyster, G. R. Messersmith; Secretary, W. S.
                    Everett; Corresponding Secretary, J. P. Culbertson; Treasurer, Emanuel Kuhn;
                    Managers, Wm. Bossert, B. F. Nead, J. W. Craig, W. W. Skinner, H. B. Davidson,
                    Wm. McClure, J. G. Elder, S. Myers, H. C. Greenawalt, A. B. Wingert, A.
                    Davidson, Josiah Besore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Astounding Developments! Unmitigated Treason!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In these strange times, the old rule is reversed, and every man who falls
                    under the displeasure of the powers that be, is judged guilty until proven
                    innocent."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helser</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Lawson of Montgomery Township was arrested for treason and "sent over
                    the lines." His arrest came out of papers found on the person of Solomon Helser.
                    When Lawson was taken to Baltimore for a hearing, it was found there was no
                    evidence against him and he was discharged. The "important note" found on Helser
                    was apparently a note in payment for a horse. Yet, "all the Pharisees" had
                    judged Lawson guilty merely because of his arrest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCollough</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of Company C, 126th Reg't Penn. Reserves, issued a tribute of
                    respect to their compatriot, Nicholas C. Trout, who was killed at
                    Chancellorsville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Paroled</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors report that Lieutenants Fletcher and McCauley, of the 126th
                    Reg't Penn. Volunteers, who were listed as missing after the battle at
                    Chancellorsville, were paroled a few days later and are now at the parole camp
                    near Annapolis. Twenty or thirty privates of the 126th were also captured and
                    paroled, but their names are not available.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Virginia Reilly, daughter of Hon. Wilson Reilly of Chambersburg, and
                    Rev. Thomas X. Orr, pastor of the First Presbyterian Church in Allegheny, were
                    married in the Presbyterian Church in Chambersburg on May 14 by the Rev. Samuel
                    J. Niccolls, assisted by the Rev. Prof. Wilson of Allegheny Theological
                    Seminary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Ready for Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Barnet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The board of enrollment in this congressional district under the
                    conscription bill consists of: George Eyster, Esq., of Chambersburg, Provost
                    Marshal; Dr. R. S. Seiss of Littletown, Adams County, Surgeon; J. S. McIlhenny,
                    Gettysburg, Commissioner. John M. Gilmore and Barnet Early of Chambersburg have
                    been appointed clerks. The board is now ready to commence operation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Editors of Spirit and Times</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Pius D. Zindorf</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zindorf</ln>
                        <fn>Pius Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The writer notes that the editors of the Village Record have called his
                    attention, as borough constable, to a law making it his duty to arrest all hogs
                    running wild. He assures the editor of that paper that he will do so, but if a
                    law exists for arresting jackasses then the editor had better watch out.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheilds</ln>
                        <fn>Wise Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wise Albert Sheilds died on May 8, aged 8 years, 7 months and 20 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheilds</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Sheilds died on May 14, aged 2 years and 4 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Register and Recorder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eichberger</ln>
                        <fn>George P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George P. Eichberger announces his candidacy for the Democratic nomination
                    for register and recorder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes market information and three columns of classified
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.05.20.04">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
