<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1863/pa.fr.vs.1863.03.04">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 2/19/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-03-04">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>The paper resumes publication after a missed issue on February
        25.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Speech of Mr. Harding of Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a speech given in the House of Representatives by Mr. Harding of
                    Kentucky, in which he denounces the Emancipation Proclamation and the suspension
                    of the writ of habeas corpus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified advertisments in two columns</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.04.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Change of Policy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In other words, is not the policy of the administration tending directly
                    and inevitably towards the very consummation the country has poured out her
                    millions of men and money to avoid--a dissolution of the Union? If so, let us,
                    in the name of all our liberties, shift the rudder and steer back again to safe
                    waters, where we will have the same reliable chart to guide us that directed our
                    fathers, through storm and calm, to a haven of peace, prosperity and national
                    greatness."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The debate which recently occurred in the British Parliament, on the delivery
                        of the Queen's annual address, possesses no small degree of interest for the
                        American reader. It was almost wholly confined to American affairs; and,
                        while the general tone of the speeches seemed friendly to the Government of
                        the United states, and averse to anything like interference in our domestic
                        troubles, the "Noble Earls" and "M. P.s," took occasion to tell us some very
                        plain truths. We were never of those who paid great deference to English
                        sentiment, for we have doubted the sincerity of many English statesmen who
                        manifested friendly feelings towards us, believing that some of them would
                        much rather see this great gover[n]mental experiment of ours prove a failure
                        than a success. And yet they sometimes express opinions which demand respect
                        and consideration; especially when we reflect that these men are far removed
                        from the exciting scenes of our great contest and consequently their
                        judgment of the issues at stake is likely to be calm and dispassionate, that
                        they are statesmen of vast experience and world-wide reputation, and, some
                        of them at least, unprejudiced against us.</p>
                    <p>In nearly all these speeches but one opinion was expressed, that "Under the
                        present avowed policy of Mr. Lincoln and his Cabinet there never could be a
                        reconstruction of the American Union." Even those who have been our
                        staunchest friends seemed to concur in this view. And even if all of them
                        were unfriendly to the United States, would it not, under the principle that
                        we should learn wisdom from our enemies, be prudent for the administration,
                        and in fact for the whole American people, to pause, before it is
                        everlastingly too late, and ponder this great issue under the new lights
                        that have been thrown upon it within the last month or so. Are we steering
                        straight for the haven of a safe, permanent and honorable peace; or are we
                        not rather, as Mr. Disraeli feelingly remarked, doing our utmost to make
                        this great country of ours "a different America from that which was known to
                        our fathers, and from that even of which this generation has had so much
                        experience--an America of armies, an America of diplomacy, an America of
                        rival States and manouvering [sic] Cabinets of frequent turbulence and
                        probably of frequent wars?" In other words, is not the policy of the
                        administration tending directly and inevitably towards the very consummation
                        the country has poured out her millions of men and money to avoid--a
                        dissolution of the Union? If so, let us, in the name of all our liberties,
                        shift the rudder and steer back again to safe waters, where we will have the
                        same reliable chart to guide us that directed our fathers, through storm and
                        calm, to a haven of peace, prosperity and national greatness.</p>
                    <p>It was true at the beginning of our national troubles, and is no less true
                        now, that the safest and shortest way to reach the end was to go straight
                        through, without turning to the right hand nor to the left. With the first
                        gun fired upon Sumter we were in a state of actual war; the issue had to be
                        met; the Government could not sign the article of its own dissolution; it
                        had no more right to do so than the suicide has to put the knife to his
                        throat; it was bound to sustain its nationality, and therefore had to take
                        up the gauntlet and resist force by force. It declared war against the
                        rebellion, for the purpose of defending the Constitution and restoring the
                        Union of our fathers. This was a high and holy purpose, and one which, had
                        we gone straight through, would have been well nigh accomplished. But in
                        national politics the crooked byways, full of deep ruts and mire, are
                        generally preferred to the straight, smooth highway of duty and honor. This
                        "mud-road" statesmanship it is that has almost ruined the country. Yes, had
                        the administration traveled in the straight path that lay open before it,
                        refusing to diverge from it one iota to gratify its radical political
                        friends; had the war been prosecuted with the one undivided object of
                        restoring the Union and maintaining the Constitution, we might to-day have
                        been able at least to see "the beginning of the end.: But no, "a Union with
                        slaveholders" had become so unrighteous a thing in the eyes of the radicals,
                        headed by Sumner, Stevens and Lovejoy, that it was determined that slavery
                        must first be killed, the power of the slave interest must be struck down;
                        "Then" said these conditional patriots, magnanimously, "we will talk about
                        reconstruction of the Union." For a while the more moderate Republicans
                        resisted this startling, revolutionary proposition; soon however the weaker
                        minded yielded to the radicals, and the more conservative withdrew in
                        disgust from their councils. Then fanaticism gained control of the
                        Government and ruled the hour. Congress rushed madly on from one wild,
                        impracticable, revolutionary scheme to another, without regard to
                        constitutional obligations or natural, inevitable consequences. The
                        confiscation bill, the bill abolishing slavery in the District of Columbia,
                        the act admitting Western Virginia, the negro enlistment bill, the
                        unauthorized admission of self-elected members of Congress and other kindred
                        measures, whose only effect has been to unite the South and divide the
                        North, were hurried through with frightful rapidity. Then the President,
                        hitherto tolerably conservative, confessed that he had to "yield" to the
                        "pressure," and with one stroke of his pen, drove from his support the
                        conservatives in the Border States and northern tier of seceded States, and
                        made them, if not friendly to the rebellion, at least luke-warm Unionists.
                        They reasoned that they might save their slaves by aiding the rebellion and
                        making it successful, while they could but lose them if they adhered to the
                        Union; and they acted accordingly. And, after, all [sic] no good resulted
                        from this proclamation, for scarcely a single slave within the rebel lines
                        has availed himself of it. Now all these measures have been steps in the
                        wrong direction. Is there an observing man who will say that they have
                        strengthened our cause or weakened our enemies? On the contrary has not the
                        opposite effect attended them all? Are we not weaker to-day, through these
                        ill-advised measures, than we were eighteen months ago; and are not the
                        rebels stronger?</p>
                    <p>But it is not yet too late to save the Republic. A change of policy may even
                        yet drive back the black clouds and give us clear sky. Let the
                        administration and its counsellors [sic] return to their constitutional
                        obligations. The confiscation bill has always been a nullity, let it still
                        "lie on the shelf;" let the President revoke his emancipation proclamation;
                        let negro enlistment be stopped at once, for our brave men in the army are
                        almost universally opposed to it, and their feelings should be consulted and
                        respected in such a matter; let the radicals in the Cabinet be tumbled out
                        heels over head--the people of the country are sick and tired of them and
                        want new, reliable, competent men in their places; and let the original
                        purpose of the war be again declared and adhered to: that it is not waged
                        for any purpose of conquest or subjugation, but simply to restore the Union
                        and maintain the Constitution, with all the rights, privileges and
                        institutions of the several States unimpaired; and, starting in once more on
                        the straight path, with the gallant McClellan again at the head of the army
                        that adores him, and safe men at the head of the nation, victory may again
                        perch upon our banners, and ultimate success attend the unparalleled
                        struggle of a brave people for national integrity and unity. As we are now
                        drifting, such a result seems scarcely within the range of human
                        probability.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors quote from recent speeches in the British Parliament that
                    observe that under Lincoln's present policy the American Union will never be
                    reconstructed. The editors heartily agree with that sentiment and argue that the
                    administration has deviated from the initial war goals. Instead of preservation
                    of the Constitution and restoration of the Union, they argue, the Republicans
                    have shifted the war goals to more radical measures. The confiscation bill, the
                    bill abolishing slavery in the District of Columbia, the admission of Western
                    Virginia as a state, and the "negro enlistment bill" have all served to unite
                    the South in opposition and divide the North. However, the President can still
                    change course, the editors argue, by refusing to use the confiscation bill, by
                    revoking the emancipation proclamation and stopping black enlistment, by purging
                    his Cabinet, and by restoring the original purposes to the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"Aid and Comfort"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial accuses Northern radical newspapers of helping unite the
                    South in opposition. Confederate leaders encourage Southerners to stick to the
                    fight by quoting from abolitionist papers, which accuse Democrats of
                    sympathizing with the rebellion. The editors add that papers like the Transcript
                    and Dispatch are also culpable, as "they scarcely put out an issue in which a
                    dozen such terms as the above can not be found."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Negro Soldiers</head>
                <origin>Hartford (Connecticut) Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates a story about incompetent black troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A New Conscript Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The new conscript bill of Senator Wilson, as it passed the Senate,
                    authorizes the President to call at his option, as many persons between the ages
                    of twenty and thirty-five, for a first draft, and those between the ages of
                    thirty-five and forty-five for a second, as he may see fit."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The new conscript bill of Senator Wilson, as it passed the Senate, authorizes
                        the President to call at his option, as many persons between the ages of
                        twenty and thirty-five, for a first draft, and those between the ages of
                        thirty-five and forty-five for a second, as he may see fit. In furtherance
                        of this authority he is instructed to appoint in each congressional district
                        of each of the several States, a provost marshal and two assistants, and a
                        surgeon, whose duty it shall be to enforce and superintend the details of
                        the draft.</p>
                    <p>An evasion is provided for by the payment of a sum not exceeding three
                        hundred dollars, or the procurance of a substitute. The penalty, of refusal
                        to comply, and the neglect to procure a substitute, are punishable with
                        trial by court martial. Exempts between the ages aforementioned include such
                        as are rejected as physically or mentally unfit for the service; also,
                        first, the Vice President of the United States, the Judges of the various
                        courts of the United States, and the heads of the various Executive
                        Departments of the government and Governor's of the States; second, the only
                        son of a widow, or of aged or infirm parent or parents dependent upon his
                        labor for support; third, where there are two or more sons of aged of infirm
                        parents subject to draft, the father, or if he be dead, the mother may elect
                        which son shall be exempt; fourth, the only brother of children not twelve
                        years old, having neither father nor mother, and dependent upon his labor
                        for support; fifth, the father of motherless children under twelve years of
                        age, dependent upon his labor for support; sixth, where there are a father
                        and sons in the same family and household, and two of them are in the
                        military service of the United States as non commissioned officers,
                        musicians or privates, the residue of such family and household, not
                        exceeding two.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The conscript bill of Senator Thomas, as it passed the Senate, authorized
                    the President to call up men between the ages of 20 and 35 in a first draft, and
                    between 35 and 45 in a second draft. The exemptions to the draft are also
                    listed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Any other policy is absurd, and we can but regard any man who, from any
                    motives whatever, gives his influence against them, as a traitor to the country.
                    His intentions may be good, but his policy is treasonous and traitorous."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This writer urges readers in Kentucky to follow the Democratic party line,
                    insisting that their duty is not to sustain the party of the President. In fact,
                    the writer argues, if Kentuckians act against the Democratic party, they act
                    against the best interests of the country and thus are traitors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Troubles in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The signs are encouraging, and lead us to hope that, at some day not very
                    distant, the co-operation of the true Union men North and South, may
                    re-establish the old order of things."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>If the South is a unit, as the papers in that region would have us believe,
                        it is a very queer unit, to say the least. In almost every quarter there is
                        opposition to the government--not only opposition by speech, but actually
                        armed opposition. It has become so alarming in some sections that large army
                        forces have been detached to put it down. The signs are encouraging, and
                        lead us to hope that, at some day not very distant, the co-operation of the
                        true Union men North and South, may re-establish the old order of things. A
                        contemporary says:</p>
                    <p>The official documents published by certain Governors at the South, and their
                        Generals in command, show that the affairs of Dixie are getting to be
                        desperate in the extreme. The strongest appeals are being made to deserters
                        to return again to the army, and shooting and bucking and lashes are being
                        freely showered upon those who are caught. Their prisons are filled with
                        civilians placed there on suspicion of being favorable to the Union, or
                        complicity in some act against the rebel cause. Colonel Lee, a son of the
                        General of that name, has been sent to the States of North Carolina and
                        Georgia to secure deserters, and to put down the insurrectionary movements
                        taking place in those States. In his general orders, dated Jan. 26, he says:</p>
                    <p>"There are a number of deserters, tories and conscripts resisting the laws in
                        northern and northeastern Georgia and in southwestern North Carolina, and
                        that the Confederate Government has dispatched a force under his command to
                        suppress any insurrectionary movements, to capture deserters, and generally
                        to restore tranquil[l]ity to this part of the country."</p>
                    <p>Governor Shorter, of Alabama, declares that his "invitation to the able
                        bodied men of Alabama, not subject to conscription, did not receive the
                        attention it merited, and then makes a most impassioned appeal for them to
                        offer their services. Officers and privates belonging to the army," he says,
                        "are lingering at home and shirking their duty, and a large number of those
                        subject to conscription are hiding from the enrolling officers."</p>
                    <p>Those who were subject to conscription were evidently already taken from
                        their homes, and the aged and other exempts have not responded to his
                        appeals. Governor Vance details a similar state of things in North Carolina,
                        and promises to deserters, whose name is legion, free pardon if they will
                        deliver themselves up before the tenth of February. It has come to bribes
                        and amnesties. But this is not all--the Charleston <emph rend="italic"
                            >Mercury</emph> of 27th ult. announces the arrival of Gen. Polk in
                        Columbia, who stated that "the tories who had been depredating in Madison
                        county, N.C., had been routed and dispersed. A force of 1,000 men from Gen.
                        Kirby Smith's division, aided by companies collected in North Carolina,
                        attacked them in front and rear, killed many, captured a number and
                        scattered the rest." A similar attack on the "tories," (as the Union men are
                        called,) in Tennessee, is announced by the Richmond <emph rend="italic"
                            >Dispatch</emph>, the result of which is thus given:</p>
                    <p>"The tory cavalry and infantry were parading in a field near the Fish spring.
                        Colonel Folk ordered his men to swim the river and charge them. The tories
                        seeing this, abandoned their horses and took shelter upon the summit of a
                        large ridge. Folk's men were then dismounted and charged up the ridge,
                        completely dispersing the tories. All of their horses were captured. Four of
                        the tories were killed, and a number wounded and captured. <emph
                            rend="italic">The captured were immediately hung</emph>, by order of
                        Col. Folk. Taylor was killed."</p>
                    <p>It is almost charged in direct terms by the press and others at the South,
                        that the Legislature of North Carolina is disloyal--and a correspondent of
                        the Charleston <emph rend="italic">Mercury</emph>, writing from Richmond,
                        gives vent to the feelings prevalent in Jeff. Davis' capital in regard to
                        the loyalty of North Carolina to the rebel cause. The writer says:</p>
                    <p>"We are disturbed about the action of the North Carolina Legislature. Have we
                        not trouble enough with the Yankees, without wrangling at home? Our hope is
                        that the good sense of the people of North Carolina will avert the impending
                        trouble, and keep that powerful and patriotic State in line with her
                        sisters."</p>
                    <p>The Raleigh <emph rend="italic">State Journal</emph> takes the Legislature to
                        task for expressing sympathy with the civilians imprisoned at Saulsbury by
                        Jeff. Davis, and adds:</p>
                    <p>"Do they know that out of the whole number confined there some two or three
                        weeks ago, only one man, out of about three hundred, could be found who was
                        willing to take the oath of allegiance to the Government of the Southern
                        Confederacy? This is a fact which cannot be truthfully denied.</p>
                    <p>"Now we do not charge the Legislature with treasonable purposes or
                        proclivities. We give them credit for all the good intentions they claim.
                        But we do charge them with a purpose to quarrel and conflict with the
                        Confederate Government; and we tell them they are instigated to it by men
                        who are traitors, but who have not the courage to avow their treason.</p>
                    <p>"We call upon the people to watch the movements controlled by such men."</p>
                    <p>From these signs of the times it is very evident that the South is no longer
                        that unit that has been claimed for it; and the people only want the
                        opportunity to throw off the tyranny which is throttling them by means of
                        the military despotism in their midst.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses insurrectionary movements by Union men in North Carolina and the
                    efforts of Confederate officials to suppress them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes miscellanous war and national news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>At Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ass't Surgeon</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Assistant Surgeon George W. Burk of the 46th Reg't Penn. Volunteers is home
                    on a visit. He looks well and is fond of the service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>New Telegraph</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Atlantic and Ohio Telegraph Company are erecting an additional line
                    between Chambersburg and Harrisburg, one line being found to be inadequate. One
                    line will be used for local purposes and the other for through traffic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Colonel Campbell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors regret to inform their readers that reports in letters received
                    last week state that Col. Campbell is in very critical condition. A bullet was
                    extracted from his arm, but he has been sinking ever since.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A New Depot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors have received reports that the Cumberland Valley Railroad
                    intends to start rebuilding its depot within the month. The location has not
                    been decided yet, but it is to be larger than the old building. The company
                    intends to make the new depot both ornamental and useful.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Children's Aid Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors relay a request from the Children's Aid Society of New York
                    that children who have been placed by the agency write them. The editors have
                    decided that since a number of children were placed in Franklin County, they
                    would call this request to the children's attention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Returned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captains John H. Reed and George L. Miles of the 126th Reg't Penn.
                    Volunteers have returned to their homes. Reed has resigned his commission
                    because he is still suffering from the injuries received at Fredericksburg and
                    is barely able to walk. Miles is home on a few days furlough and says that the
                    men of the regiment are healthy and in good spirits, though "up to their eyes in
                    mud."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Paroled</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors note the parole of Lieut. William Burgess, of the 6th Penn.
                    Reserves, from the Confederate Libby Prison in Richmond. He is being held at the
                    parole camp in Annapolis, and they hope he can return to visit his family in the
                    area. Burgess, a Lieutenant in the Ambulance Corps, was captured while
                    supervising the removal of the wounded from the battle field at Antietam.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Snow and Sleighing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Twelve to fourteen inches of snow fell on Saturday night and Sunday, and
                    the editors report the sleighing during the next few days to be "very fine."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mortality in the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of several recent deaths of men in the service, and descriptions of
                    the circumstances surrounding their deaths.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Wild Currency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors defend the Bank of Chambersburg against a charge in the
                    Greencastle Pilot that it is a weak bank and in part responsible for the
                    proliferation of paper money in the area. In fact, the editors note, the Bank of
                    Chambersburg will not redeem notes of worthless banks, and its strength is
                    attested to by the fact that its capital stock is selling $14 above par.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lurgan School District Teacher's Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>David A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Lurgan School District Teacher's Institute met in the Roxbury
                    schoolroom on February 21, with David A. Stouffer giving a two-hour lesson in
                    analyzing and correcting sentences. The Institute also passed a resolution
                    thanking its president, H. A. Thomas, and secretary J. X. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porterfield</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keil</ln>
                        <fn>Anna B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Porterfield of Philadelphia married Anna B. Keil of Chambersburg on
                    February 15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weidmann</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bachmeir</ln>
                        <fn>Paulus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Weidmann and Paulus Bachmeir were married on February 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunkle</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zody</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Zody and Mary E. Dunkle, both of Mt. Hope, were married on
                    February 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Grove, Sr., died on February 23, aged 87 years, 1 month and 19 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie Palmer, only child of George and Mary Palmer, died on Februray 24 in
                    Chambersburg of diphtheria.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kees</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkleman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGarvey</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprints a list of the people authorized by the Board of Relief to receive
                    and pay over relief for drafted soldiers. They include: George W. Zeigler,
                    Antrim Township; W. S. Amberson, Washington Township; John Kees, Quincy
                    Township; J. B. Cook, Fayetteville; J. Wallace, Greenvillage; John Orr, Sr.,
                    Orrstown; William McClelland, Strasburg; Thomas Pomeroy, Roxbury; Robert Moore,
                    Hamilton; H. McKnight, Guilford; P. Kunkleman, Peters; P. McGarvey, St. Thomas;
                    W.S. Harris, Metal; James Ferguson, Fannett; James M. Bradley, Montgomery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.04.04">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
