<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1863/pa.fr.vs.1863.01.07">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 2/17/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-01-07">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Four-page edition with seven columns per page; see editorial on page
        2</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.07.01">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements, fiction and humor</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.07.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To our Patrons--Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors thank their subscribers for paying their bills and announce
                    that instead of raising the price of the paper, they will temporarily reduce its
                    size to four pages from eight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Emancipation Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "We may say, however, that we regard this <emph rend="italic"
                        >pronunciamento</emph>, to use the language of the President himself, as
                    impracticable as the 'Pope's bull against the comet.' It is unwise, ill-timed,
                    outside of the Constitution and full of mischief." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Emancipation Proclamation.</p>
                    <p>The President has issued the promised emancipation proclamation declaring the
                        slaves of certain States and parts of States "henceforth and forever free."
                        It will be found in another column of our paper to-day.</p>
                    <p>Our views upon the policy of emancipation are well known to our readers and
                        we do not deem it necessary to reiterate them at this time. We may say,
                        however, that we regard this <emph rend="italic">pronunciamento</emph>, to
                        use the language of the President himself, as impracticable as the "Pope's
                        bull against the comet." It is unwise, ill-timed, outside of the
                        Constitution and full of mischief. Its effect will be more thoroughly to
                        unite and exasperate the whites of the South in their resistance to the
                        National Government, and to make the war still more prolonged, bloody and
                        bitter.</p>
                    <p>But the radicals have told us that it would end the war in thirty days; that
                        it was the great remedy for the evils afflicting the country; and the
                        Harrisburg <emph rend="italic">Telegraph</emph> of Saturday last, exclaims:
                        "The deed is done. The heart of the rebellion has been struck and the Union
                        is saved."</p>
                    <p>Well, we will now see this emancipation policy tested practically, and learn,
                        from experience, the value of abolition philosophy. The country expects them
                        to redeem their promises and with one tremendous blow struck at the "heart
                        of the rebellion" crush it at once, and give peace to the country.</p>
                    <p>Drive on, "<emph rend="italic">Massa Linkun,"</emph> we are anxiously
                        awaiting the result.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note the issuance of the Emancipation Proclamation. While they
                    do not comment on it extensively, the editors observe that Lincoln's
                    proclamation will have little effect but to prolong the war and exacerbate the
                    conflict.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Disturbed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Forsaken and despised by the sensible and intelligent portion of its own
                    party, it is left to wallow almost alone in the slough and mire of fanaticism
                    into which it has dragged itself. Its condition is pitiable indeed. Afflicted
                    with an incurable disease--nigger on the brain--it deserves the commiseration of
                    mankind."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors suggest that the reason that the Dispatch is upset with the
                    Spirit and Times's coverage of Fredericksburg is because of mental infirmity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How Richmond was not Taken</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Now it is an established and admitted fact that Abraham Lincoln alone is
                    responsible for this interference with Gen. McClellan's plans and for defeating
                    his success . . ."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Citing testimony from the court martial of General McDowell, the author
                    argues that if McDowell's corps had not been withdrawn from McClellan's command
                    during the approach to Richmond, McClellan would have been able to take the
                    city. Therefore, the author concludes, the blame should be laid at the feet of
                    President Lincoln, who split the armies and gave McDowell a separate command.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bloody Beecherisms</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The craving of these monsters--these vampyres in human shape--for blood
                    cannot be satisfied. It grows with what it feeds upon."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer quotes several speeches by Henry Ward Beecher, in which the
                    minister argues that the blood being shed in the war is for a noble cause and
                    that God should be thanked that there are more men who can be sacrificed. This,
                    says the writer, is evidence that abolitionists are willing to sacrifice all in
                    a fanatical quest for their goal of emancipation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Emancipation Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints President Lincoln's order to emancipate the slaves in the
                    rebellious states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Important from the Army of the Cumberland--A Great Battle at Murfreesboro'</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a partial report of the battle at Murfreesboro, Tennessee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes war news from Vicksburg, as well as market information.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Worthy of Commendation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note that the management of the Cumberland Valley Rail Road has
                    settled with about seventy-five members of the Corn Exchange militia regiment of
                    Philadelphia, who were wounded in the accident last year. The editors believe
                    this is a highly honorable gesture by the company. While the management does not
                    acknowledge any responsibility, they are nonetheless devoting part of their
                    profits to help relieve the suffering of those wounded in the accident.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>Adam R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinkley</ln>
                        <fn>W., W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowen</ln>
                        <fn>Dallas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownson</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of the 126th Reg't Penn. Volunteers issued a resolution
                    commemorating their fallen comrades.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Donation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The German Lutheran congregation of Chambersburg presented their pastor,
                    Rev. Mr. Wolff, with a new suit of broadcloth, and his wife with a new bonnet,
                    dress, and cloak, made of "the best material." The editors note that it speaks
                    well of the "liberality" of the congregation and the popularity of Rev. Wolff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Carriers Address to the Patrons of the Valley Spirit and Times</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reprint of the poem read by the carrier to subscribers, recounting the
                    events of the year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zacharias</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fetter</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Gillan and Mary A. Fetter, both from the vicinity of Orrstown, were
                    married on December 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kadel</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Kadel and Elizabeth Heller, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    December 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williamson</ln>
                        <fn>Johannes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seger</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Johannes Williamson and Elizabeth Seger were married on January 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creamer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jonathan Creamer died in Upper Strasburg on December 30, aged 31 years, 11
                    months and 11 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brendel</ln>
                        <fn>Melchia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Melchia Brendel died near St. Thomas on December 28, aged 96 years, 10
                    months and 11 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardley</ln>
                        <fn>Wilhelmina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardley</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardley</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wilhelmina Hardley, daughter of Catharine and Henry Hardley, died on
                    December 27, aged 4 years, 6 months and 15 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>William Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>Emma E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Augustus Flack, aged 6 years and 5 days, and Emma E. Flack, aged 1
                    year, 9 months and 15 days, children of Samuel and Lydia Flack, died on January
                    1 near Jackson Hall of diphtheria.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>Charles B.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles B. D. Coffroth died in New York City on December 21 of a heart
                    attack at the age of 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin>Shippensburg News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The subject of this notice was a young man of bright promise, possessing
                    social qualities which endeared him to all who knew him. Esteeming it a duty he
                    owed his country, he freely offered his services in her defense, and on this
                    hard fought fields of Antietam and Fredericksburg nobly did a soldier's part."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLean</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George J. McLean died at "Harewood Hospital" in Washington D.C. on December
                    22, of wounds sustained during the battle of Fredericksburg, at age 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Certificates for Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A notice to people who have been before the Commissioners (D. O. Gehr and
                    Samuel Reisher) and have had their claims adjusted for the impressment of
                    horses, saddles, bridles, hauling, forage, blacksmithing, services, etcetera,
                    that they should call on Gehr or Reisher to receive certificates by leaving the
                    vouchers they now hold.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Four and a half columns of classified advertisements, including legal
            notices</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.07.04">
            <pageNote>Fiction and five columns of advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
