<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1863/pa.fr.vs.1863.07.15">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 3/3/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-07-15">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.07.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Unquestioning Support</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Had the Democratic party pursued a similar policy in the days of its
                    power, there would not only not be an Abolition administration, directing the
                    government today, but there would not be a vestige of Republicanism left--The
                    fathers of Abolitionism would years since have expiated their offenses on the
                    gallows, or be languishing in prisons, and one-half the Republican party been
                    banished to some penal colony far off in the ocean."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer challenges the Republican argument that attacks on the
                    administration are tantamount to attacks on the government. If the Democrats had
                    applied the same standard when they were in power, particularly under Buchanan's
                    administration, Republicans would have been as freely arrested as Democrats are
                    now.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the Democratic State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A summary of the activities of the Democratic State Convention held in
                    Harrisburg on June 17. George W. Woodward was nominated for Governor on the
                    ninth ballot, while Walter H. Lowrie was nominated for Chief Judge by
                    acclimation. A number of resolutions were also passed, pledging the Democrats of
                    Pennsylvania to a war policy of "The Constitution as it is, and the Union as it
                    was" and condemning, among other things, the deportation of Vallandigham from
                    Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes miscellaneous news and fiction.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.07.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>What is Franklin County Doing?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors call for a reorganization of the 126th Regiment to defend the
                    town from future attacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We must throw additional vigor into this war, and endeavor to bring it to
                    a speedy and successful end for the Union . . .The present wasteful system of
                    raising troops for an emergency must cease."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors urge that a permanent militia be organized in each state. If
                    there had been such a body to throw against Lee, they claim, he could have been
                    easily defeated. The present system of raising troops is inadequate, and
                    something new must be done to prevent further invasions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Democratic Nominees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Seldom, if ever, within our recollection, have the representatives of the
                    Democracy of Pennsylvania, in Convention assembled, discharged their duty in the
                    selection of good and unexceptionable candidates, more honestly,
                    conscientiously, and faithfully, and more satisfactorily to the masses of the
                    people, than did those who met in Harrisburg on the seventeenth of June last,
                    and gave us the Hon. George W. Woodward and Hon. Walter H. Lowrie as our
                    standard-bearers during the coming campaign."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors discuss the two candidates nominated by the State Democratic
                    Convention. Hon. George W. Woodward was not originally a nominee for the
                    position, but his name was put in as the "unusual interest and anxiety" over the
                    nomination produced a series of deadlocked ballots. Woodward was a framer of the
                    current State Constitution, and was the first Democratic nominee for Supreme
                    Court when the office was made elective. His decisions, along with Chief Justice
                    Lowrie, who was renominated for election, are among the most cited from the
                    bench. It is fitting, say the editors, that he be nominated as a man of law to
                    help safeguard civil liberties before they are "irrevocably swept away."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have always been struck with the wisdom of this strategy. The South
                    took up arms because they apprehended slavery was in danger. Destroy slavery and
                    they will have no object to make war about. Who is so shallow that he can't see
                    the wisdom of that?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer argues that attempting to defeat the Confederates who are
                    fighting to save slavery by abolishing slavery makes no sense.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. S. Stenger</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>District Attorney W. S. Stenger writes to deny reports in the Lancaster
                    Express that he had tried to shake hands with the Confederate commander Jenkins
                    during the raid, only to be rebuffed by Jenkins. He also goes on to defend
                    Franklin County Democrats of charges of welcoming the Confederates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Incidents of the Great Battle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of the battlefield and aftermath of Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes news of the capture of Vicksburg.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.07.15.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors report on the movement of troops, both Confederate and Union,
                    through Franklin County in the aftermath of Gettysburg. Several cavalry
                    engagements took place in the vicinity of Funkstown and Boonsboro. Union
                    commanders are now stationed in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Riot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors note that some of the militia from New York who came to defend
                    Franklin County have been behaving badly. Their actions included an assault on
                    Captain Doebler on the grounds that he was a coward, which extended into a
                    general melee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Serenade to General Couch</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"His charges against the loyalty of the community are beneath contempt and
                    known to be utterly false by every honorable and fair-minded man who remained at
                    home and is cognizant of the facts. His information was, no doubt, obtained from
                    some valiant 'skedaddler.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Couch, headquartered in the Franklin Hotel, was serenaded in his
                    quarters on Friday by the Chambersburg Brass Band. The General responded with a
                    short speech promising to drive the enemy from the border. He was followed by
                    Col. McReynolds of New York and Major McVey, of Chester County, Pennsylvania.
                    The editors criticize McVey's speech as partisan, and he apparently imputed the
                    bravery of the community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>L. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of citizens left Chambersburg last week for Hagerstown, thinking
                    that there would be a battle here. The Confederates captured a number of them
                    and sent them to Richmond on the grounds that they were spies. Among the
                    captured were Dr. James Hamilton, L. W. Tritle and George Kauffman (several
                    other names are listed but are obscured by a tear in the paper).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A doctor in Chambersburg (whose name is obscured by a rip in the paper) has
                    been appointed Assistant Surgeon and assigned to the 20th Regiment State
                    Militia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Brave Cavalry Dash</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors relate the capture of a party of Confederate cavalry in
                    Greencastle by a squad of Federal cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"The Franklin Repository"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We wish the gentlemen every pecuniary success in their new enterprise, and
                    know we shall always find in them honorable competitors for public patronage,
                    while, politically, we feel confident we shall meet in them 'foeman worthy of
                    our steel.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors note the publication of the Franklin Repository, the product of
                    the purchase by Col. A. K. McClure and Henry S. Stoner of the Repository and
                    Transcript, and the Dispatch.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Dirt and Filth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors report that the streets of the town need a good cleaning after
                    their occupation by the Confederates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Copperhead Heroism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors report an anecdote that when a Confederate requested of a
                    female resident an axe with which to cut down the liberty pole in the Diamond,
                    she refused, even when the soldier threatened her with his pistol. That woman,
                    note the editors, "is one of the most 'malignant copperheads' in town."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>An Act of Vandalism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This was an act of disgraceful vandalism, which speaks well for the
                    boasted chivalry of the Southern army."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During the Confederate occupation, several Confederate soldiers broke into
                    the Columbus Lodge of Odd Fellows, cut to pieces the regalia, and "mutilated
                    everything they could lay their hands upon."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Card of Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of Company C of the "First Coal" or 4th Regiment Pennsylvania
                    Militia write to thank Mrs. Maria Eyster of Chambersburg for the breakfast she
                    furnished them, free of charge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Soldier Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>During an altercation Thursday evening between two members of the 1st NY
                    Cavalry, one of the combatants was stabbed and died almost immediately. Dr.
                    Richards was called in but found the man dying when he arrived. The other party
                    was arrested by military authorities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The 56th Reg't NY Guards were presented with a "magnificent stand of
                    colors" by several gentlemen connected with the Brooklyn Navy Yard, who came to
                    Chambersburg for expressly that purpose.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Telegraph</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>W. Blair</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The telegraph between Chambersburg and Loudon has been reconstructed, under
                    the supervision of W. Blair Gilmore. Communication with Pittsburgh was
                    established last Saturday. Work is also being done on the line between
                    Chambersburg and Carlisle, "so that during the present week we will again be in
                    telegraphic communication with the civilized world."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Provost Marshal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General Couch appointed Lieutenant Palmer Provost Marshal for the area. The
                    editors have confidence that "he will do his utmost to preserve peace and order
                    in the community."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Latest News</head>
                <origin>Baltimore American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report on the cavalry engagement near Funkstown and Boonsboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Republican Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republican State Convention has been postponed until August 5. The
                    writer suggests that, if they are sincere about their condemnations of
                    partisanship, they should show a unified vote for Woodward for Governor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appel</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appel</ln>
                        <fn>Wilhelm</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appel</ln>
                        <fn>Johannes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wilhelm Appel, son of Barbara and Johannes Appel, died on July 11 near
                    Grindstone Hill, aged 1 year, 7 months and 8 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>General Orders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>By order from the Dept. of the Susquehanna, all U.S. Government property
                    captured from the Confederates now in the hands of private citizens is to be
                    turned in to the Provost Marshal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>A rip in the bottom left corner destroyed part of the list of the people
                captured by the Confederates, as well as another unknown article at the bottom of
                the second column. This page also contains three columns of classified
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.07.15.04">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
