<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.11.23">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-11-23">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">23</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.11.23.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.11.23.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Still More Plundering</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper quoted the Chambersburg Valley Spirit in arguing that several
                    developing scandals revealed the true character of the Republican leadership.
                    The article highlighted cases of fraud at the New York Custom House, the Whiskey
                    Ring, and gold speculation at the Treasury Department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Enquirer and Examiner</emph> says that after such a
                        conflict as was waged for four years in this country -- a conflict no less
                        remarkable for its development of power than of passion -- that after such a
                        conflict, we say, the general views of the conquering portion were to
                        prevail was what reason and experience alike would teach; but surely it will
                        be a matter of amazement to posterity that, after a war waged for the defeat
                        of Secession, for the preservation of the Constitution, and the integrity of
                        the Union, the party who had, after an arduous struggle, achieved a complete
                        victory under a banner with these inscriptions, should, for four years, and,
                        perhaps, for an indefinite period, falsify their own declarations, and
                        practically vindicate the cause and course of their defeated opponents by
                        refusing to admit the Southern States to a Union from which it had been
                        contended they could not secede, and by the mutilation and utter destruction
                        of the healthy spirit of a Constitution they had sworn to preserve intact.</p>
                    <p>What a distinguished writer says of the prototypes in England may be applied
                        with greater force to the imitators in this country: "In truth their
                        proceedings are as little to be reconciled to policy as to humanity and
                        justice. -- The key to their conduct must probably be sought in their
                        ambition. Having tasted the sweets of power, they can no longer endure the
                        thought of a superior, or the presence of even an equal. The same lust of
                        sway which they denounced at the outset has taken possession of their minds,
                        and they believe, as despots always will, that no power can be safe in any
                        hands but their own. Having converted themselves into an irresponsible, and,
                        as they fondly trust, an irremovable oligarchy, they seek to complete the
                        usurpation by rendering themselves absolute."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Enquirer and Examiner found it ironic that, after a war waged over the
                    question of a State's right to leave the Union, the victors would reverse their
                    position and prevent Virginia from taking her place in the Union. Also ridiculed
                    the fact that the Radical party swore to protect the Constitution, but now they
                    claimed to do so by overriding and destroying it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The End of the Stay Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is a great deal of needless apprehension entertained in this State,
                        respecting the effect of the expiration of the Stay Law, which ceases with
                        the acknowledgment by Congress of the new constitution. The opinion prevails
                        that about one-fourth, or a very large portion of the real estate of
                        Virginia will then change hands, at a ruinous sacrifice to the present
                        owners. -- Those who take this gloomy view of the subject lose sight of the
                        fact that the courts can, to a great extent, control this matter, and
                        interpose to protect the interests of the property-holders. In all cases,
                        except where deeds of trust exist, sales of real estate must depend upon a
                        decree of court; and no sales will be permitted if the proceeds of annual
                        rental for a term of years will liquidate the claim on account of principal
                        and interest. But in any case, it is competent for the courts to have
                        property appraised, and to set aside any sale where the value of the
                        property, or something nearly approximating it, has not been secured. This
                        power of the courts is ample to secure landholders against a ruinous
                        sacrifice of their property; and further, we have no doubt that the
                        Legislature will, by appropriate legislation, under the Constitution, see to
                        it that wholesale ruin be not thus inflicted upon the debtors of the
                        Commonwealth. -- The sharpers, therefore, in and out of the State, who are
                        expecting to get land for a mere song, may find themselves egregiously
                        mistaken. It is the interest of the property-holders who are not involved in
                        debt, to see to it that the value of real estate in Virginia is not reduced
                        to a merely nominal sum, that would, in that event, seriously affect
                        themselves; and we trust that they will combine, if necessary, to protect
                        their own interests. In a word: we would advise those who want land to buy
                        now; for, in all probability, it is lower than it ever will be again, in
                        Virginia. With the success of reconstruction and the restoration of general
                        prosperity to the South, all values of this kind will be enhanced. The State
                        is not going to be put under the hammer, as many people believe, and there
                        will never occur a better opportunity to buy lands at reasonable figures
                        than that afforded now. -- <emph rend="italic">Lynch. Virginian.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator claimed that the fears of widespread property confiscation
                    after the repeal of the Stay Law are groundless, and predicted that the courts
                    and legislature would prevent creditors from abusing their new power. Advised
                    people to buy land now before the law is repealed and prices rise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.11.23.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Academy of Medicine passed resolutions of sympathy and respect
                    upon the death of Dr. Samuel R. Hendren.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James F. Taylor of Staunton and Miss Mattie A. Jordan, daughter of Albert
                    Jordan, were married at the residence of the bride's father near Warm Springs,
                    Bath County on November 18th by the Rev. S. Rider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>T. Bullett</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Boykin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>David R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. Bullett Harrison and Mary Boykin Williams, daughter of David R. Williams
                    and formerly of South Carolina, were married at the residence of the bride's
                    father near Staunton on November 16th by the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauver</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Hettie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James H. Fauver and Miss Hettie E. Hanger, both of Augusta, were married on
                    November 11th at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phelps</ln>
                        <fn>E. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carrington</ln>
                        <fn>Jane W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herr</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>N. I. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. E. P. Phelps of the Virginia Conference, M. E. Church, and Mrs. Jane
                    W. Carrington of Texas were married at the residence of William L. Herr in
                    Staunton on November 16th by the Rev. N. I. B. Morgan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. H. Evans and Miss Mary A. Sibert, daughter of Lorenzo Sibert of Augusta,
                    were married at Siberton on October 19th by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.11.23.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
