<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.07.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/07/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-07-27">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">27</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.07.27.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.07.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Look Out for a Carpet Bag Exodus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Wilmington (N.C.) Star calls attention to the fact that the
                        carpet-baggers in Virginia are packing up preparatory to a raid on
                        Mississippi, Texas, or some other place where they can make their salt. But
                        it don't take a carpet-bagger long to pack up. His wardrobe consists of one
                        shirt, marked "John Smith," one pair pants, one pea-jacket, one old hat, one
                        second-hand tooth-brush, one dozen Sumner's speeches, and one hundred copies
                        Ritual Union League. Carpet-baggers never wear drawers nor socks. This is an
                        infallible method of distinguishing them from white folks.</p>
                    <p>What the "miserable vermin" who have so long infested Virginia will now do we
                        cannot imagine. Possibly, they may get a job in Mississippi or Texas. We
                        have no room for them, says the Star, in North Carolina. All the offices are
                        already filled, and when a vacancy occurs, a carpet-bagger stands no chance
                        whatever for the place.</p>
                    <p>The Star begs its Virginia friends to keep a sharp look out after their
                        spoons until the carpet-bag exodus is completed. It says the "vermin" will
                        all want some "relics;" and they will find spoons very convenient for
                        stowing away in their carpet bags.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Wilmington Star predicted that the carpet-baggers in Virginia will soon
                    leave the State, sarcastically saying they may pursue jobs in Texas or
                    Mississippi.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals have not ceased to lie, even since the election, to the more
                        ignorant colored men. For some days they had a number very uneasy, by
                        telling them that they would be put back into slavery, and that all who
                        voted for Walker, would be sent to work on public works at Washington. We
                        cannot imagine what they expect to gain by such stories now, and presume it
                        is but the old habit strong in death. -- Lying has become chronic.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claimed that the Radicals, even after the election is over, continue to lie
                    to the Freedmen by telling them that they will be returned to slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter to the editor advocates construction of a Market House in
                    Staunton, where citizens can purchase their "daily table supplies."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.07.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Staunton's Southern Methodists have been worshipping in the Baptist Church
                    due to the courtesy of that congregation. The Rev. George Kramer, pastor of the
                    M. E. Church South, will preach next Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>American Hotel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The public house near the railroad depot is being renovated under the
                    management of M. P. Bledsoe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clinedinst</ln>
                        <fn>B. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Photographer B. M. Clinedinst has returned to Staunton and once again taken
                    charge of his art gallery on Main Street.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Tuesday last, two negroes, calling themselves John Adams and Tom Henry
                        were arrested at Dearfield and brought to this place by three colored men,
                        James Stewart, Lewis Hunter, and Madison Brown, on the charge of rape and
                        murder made against them by another colored man named Jim McDowell. They
                        arrived here on Tuesday night and had a hearing before Justice J. F. Maupin
                        and he committed them to jail to await further investigation.</p>
                    <p>On Wednesday morning, Mr. Geo Harlan, jailor, and Mr. J. T. Parent, C. P.,
                        informed them that they were suspected as the parties who had <sic>broke
                            jail</sic> from Lexington, which they confessed as being true, and said
                        their names were Lee Morrison, Wm. Alexander and Jim McDowell. They had been
                        confined in Lexington in jail on charges, respectively, of waylaying and
                        attempting to kill young Devier, of burglary and attempted rape, and robbing
                        a church. They were sent back to Lexington jail.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Tom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Madison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Jim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Jim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Three Freedmen are arrested on suspicion of murder. During the
                    investigation, it is found that they are fugitives from the Lexington jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William T. Jackson and Miss Annie Shelton, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Summerdean on July 1st by the Rev. Mr. Lantz.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Kate E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Kate E. Hanger, infant daughter of Dr. David W. and Sallie Hanger, died on
                    July 20th. She was 4 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.07.27.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
