<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.01.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/05/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-01-05">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">5</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.01.05.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.01.05.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Condition of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Christmas day a communication signed "Senex" appeared in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Richmond Whig</emph>, advocating a change of policy by the
                        Conservatives of this State. The writer, who is understood to be a gentleman
                        of distinction and influence, takes the ground that the Underwood
                        Constitution will probably be forced upon us unless we avert the calamity by
                        agreeing to universal suffrage. He thereupon proposes that a Constitution
                        unbodying "universal suffrage and universal amnesty" be presented to the
                        Congress with a request that it, as well as the other instrument, be
                        submitted to the vote of the people of Virginia. Another correspondent of
                        the <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>, who signs himself "Augusta," expresses
                        the belief that a majority of the people of this county will approve the
                        scheme proposed by "Senex." In the absence of the editor of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spectator</emph>, we do not feel at liberty to say more
                        than that we think "Augusta" is mistaken in regard to the sentiment of our
                        people. The Washington correspondent of the Baltimore Gazette, in his letter
                        of the 29th, says:</p>
                    <p>"The condition of Virginia, beyond peradventure, is critical, and there are
                        some gentlemen now here whose conservative status and general intelligence
                        are unquestioned, who seem inclined to think that the people of that State
                        have it in their power to prevent greater wrongs by anticipating some of the
                        certain and unavoidable demands of their oppressors. The immediate
                        concession of negro suffrage by the Legislature, it is thought by these
                        gentlemen, (whose views are fairly represented by the writer of the recent
                        editorials upon this subject in the <emph rend="italic">Intelligencer</emph>
                        -- himself a Virginian,) would mollify the bitterness of Radical hatred.
                        Alas! the history of the past three years furnishes indubitable evidence
                        that <emph rend="italic">concessions</emph> but whet the edge of Radical
                        vengeance.</p>
                    <p>The case of Georgia is in point. The people there complied with <emph
                            rend="italic">every demand of Congress.</emph> They adopted a
                        Constitution recognizing negro suffrage to the fullest extent, and carrying
                        but literally and equitably the whole infernal Congressional system of
                        "reconstruction." The Constitution as adopted was submitted to Congress, and
                        adopted by it without a syllable of objection. Yet the State did not bow
                        down to heathen gods, and what do we see! Arkansas even went further. She
                        not only did all that was required by the <emph rend="italic">legislation of
                            Congress</emph>, but (if the election returns are to be credited) <emph
                            rend="italic">actually voted the Radical "national" ticket.</emph> Did
                        this subserviency save her from the deliberate inauguration of a<emph
                            rend="italic">system</emph> of robbery, arson, murder and wholesale
                        rape, committed by negro troops under the auspices, if not under immediate
                        command of Federal military satraps!</p>
                    <p>But it may be imagined that an utter abandonment of the last vestige of
                        manhood might operate favorably upon what is termed here the "Conservative"
                        wing of the Republican party in Congress. Vain hope! These men are the mere
                        echoes of Northern hate, fanaticism and revenge."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A response to a letter to the editor of the Richmond Whig, which urged the
                    Conservatives of Virginia to concede the issue of universal suffrage in hopes of
                    gaining universal amnesty. Claims that the experience of Arkansas and Georgia
                    show that such concessions are unlikely to dampen Radical misrule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Was there ever before in the world such a party as the present Radical party
                        of this country? Mr. Van Wyck makes a report to Congress upon the subject of
                        frauds committed upon the Government in the matter of collecting the revenue
                        or evading the payment of the same, and can find no one to blame but the
                        President. Mr. JOHNSON is the cause of "all our woes." Congress has passed a
                        tenure-of-office law which deprives him of the power of removing incompetent
                        and dishonest officials, or of appointing competent and honest ones; yet Mr.
                        Van Wyck censures him because he has not collected as much revenue as he
                        would have collected if he had been left untrammeled.-- This is the Radical
                        idea of justice and fair dealing. -- <emph rend="italic"
                    >Dispatch</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An editorial from the Dispatch denying the Radicals' criticism of President
                    Johnson's ineffectiveness. Says such criticism is hypocritical because the
                    tenure of office act prevents Johnson from effectively running the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Richmond Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held in Richmond to discuss ways to prevent the proposed
                    constitution from being adopted. The group decided to accept suffrage for
                    African-Americans but to modify the constitution if possible. "If we adopt the
                    Constitution, our condition will be intolerable, because we will be under the
                    absolute domination of adventurers and the worst classes of our population. If
                    we reject it, we shall probably be regarded as contumacious, and be subjected to
                    a harsh and coercive provisional government."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The New Stay Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following order, issued on 22d. ult., by General Stoneman, so fully
                        explains itself that no comments upon it seem to be needed.--So that real
                        estate remains as free as before, whilst personal property is not in any
                        event to be sold <emph rend="italic">before</emph> the 1st of July, and not
                            <emph rend="italic">afterwards</emph> in case the owner can provide for
                        the payment of interest upon his debt.</p>
                    <p>"HEADQUARTERS FIRST MILITARY DIS.</p>
                    <p>"STATE OF VIRGINIA,</p>
                    <p>"RICHMOND, VA., Dec. 22, 1868.</p>
                    <p>"<emph rend="italic">General Orders No.</emph> 149.</p>
                    <p>"In view of the pecuniary distress and difficulties which must necessarily
                        ensue throughout this military district upon the termination of the stay law
                        on the 1st of January next, and in the absence of any Legislature or body
                        competent to devise the appropriate remedy therefor, it is ordered:</p>
                    <p>"1. That the stay of executions against personal property, so far only as the
                        same exists under laws now in force, and which by the provisions thereof
                        expires on the first day of January, 1869, shall be, and is hereby, extended
                        until the first day of July, 1869; and if, on or before the said last named
                        day, the debtor shall have paid all the interest then due and owing thereon,
                        execution shall be further stayed until other orders from these or superior
                        headquarters.</p>
                    <p>"2. If, during the existence of this order, any debtor shall be eloigning any
                        property which but for the existence of this order would be liable to said
                        executions, or shall dispose, or attempt to dispose of the same to the
                        prejudice of his creditor, it shall be lawful and right for such creditor to
                        apply to any circuit court, or to any judge thereof in vacation, giving
                        reasonable notice of such application to the debtor, and said court or judge
                        thereof in vacation, upon the statement under oath of the parties, and such
                        legal evidence as they may adduce, may make an order to the clerk to issue
                        said execution for the entire debt, interest, and costs, or else dismiss
                        such application, with costs to either party, as the said court or judge
                        shall seem right.</p>
                    <p>"3. General Orders No. 24, of March 12th, 1868, are hereby continued in
                        force, and the military commissioners and circuit judges entrusted with
                        their execution are enjoined to observe and give effect to the same.</p>
                    <p>"4. It is intended by this order that, whilst affording relief to the debtor,
                        not to impair the rights of the creditor, but to preserve and enforce the
                        same by subjecting the whole personal estate which is now exempt by the stay
                        law to the lien of the creditor's execution, and at the same time enforce a
                        prompt payment of a part of the debt, and an early payment of the remainder.</p>
                    <p>By command of Brevet Major General</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Stoneman</emph><lb/> S. F. CHALFIN,</p>
                    <p>Assistant Adjutant General.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reproduces a military order, issued by General Stoneman, extending the
                    protections of the recently revoked stay law on debts until July 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.01.05.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Churchville raised $185 at their fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plume</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. George Plume will hold a soiree at the American Hotel on January 7th.
                    Tickets are $1.00.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that on Christmas Day " a slight row occurred" in
                    Staunton "between the negroes and whites, in which the negroes came out second
                    best. Some half dozen negroes were knocked down and severely handled. No one was
                    seriously injured. It threatened to become a row of considerable proportions,
                    but was promptly quelled by the energetic action of the regular and special
                    police."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peterson</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruth</ln>
                        <fn>Mary F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruth</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peterson</ln>
                        <fn>P. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. E. M. Peterson of the Virginia Conference, M. E. Church South, and
                    Miss Mary F. Ruth, daughter of Samuel Ruth of Richmond, were married on December
                    30th by the Rev. P. A. Peterson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallhelm</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William T. Bowers and Catherine A. E. Sheets, both of Augusta, were married
                    on December 24th at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. H. Tallhelm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fudley</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammack</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Hogshead and Lydia O. Fudley, both of Augusta, were married on
                    December 19th by the Rev. C. B. Hammack.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mrs. Louisa Wilson died at Spring Hill on December 12th. She was 53 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolen</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary A. Bolen died at Mt. Solon on December 26th. She was 26 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>Polly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Polly Matheny died at Mossy Creek on December 29th. She was 70 years
                    old. "The deceased had been a strict member of the Methodist Episcopal Church
                    for forty years."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.01.05.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
