<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.12.07">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-12-07">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.12.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.12.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Proposed "Walker Party"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We regret to learn that some of our more ardent politicians about Richmond
                        have set on foot a movement, for the purpose of establishing a new political
                        party, to be called the "Walker party."</p>
                    <p>We think the movement unwise and premature. The people of Virginia are in no
                        condition now to participate in partisan politics. -- We think, with Com.
                        Maury, that, for the present at least, "it is the policy of Virginia to
                        eschew politics." Our attention should be directed to the improvement of our
                        material interest. It will be time enough to talk of political parties when
                        we are restored to our full rights in the Union, and are in a condition to
                        back our opinions by our votes. At present, we have no recognized right to
                        participate in the political contests of the nation, and it seems to us,
                        therefore, that it is rather an idle thing for us to be vaporing and saying
                        what we would do if we had the power to do it.</p>
                    <p>But we would regard any movement of the kind as premature, even if we were in
                        the full enjoyment of our rights. At present, every thing is in a transition
                        state. We have not the information that is necessary to enable us to form an
                        intelligent opinion as to what will be best for us in the future. We have
                        but little knowledge of what Gen. Grant's policy will be, and still less as
                        to Gov. Walker's. We must await further developments. In the mean time, we
                        should occupy a position of armed neutrality. We must meet every issue as it
                        arises, and deal with it as best we can. The whole people of Virginia should
                        stand together as one man. There should be no splitting up into separate
                        parties. By maintaining this kind of compact organization, we have, thus
                        far, been able to ward off the deadly blows that were aimed at Virginia. Let
                        us preserve that organization intact, at least until we are fully restored
                        to the Union. After that is accomplished, we must expect party divisions.
                        Such divisions are incidents to free institutions. They spring out of
                        differences of opinion on questions of public policy, and are inevitable in
                        all governments in which freedom of opinion and discussion are tolerated.</p>
                    <p>As for ourselves, we are free to confess that we are not prepared now to take
                        any definite position in regard to political parties. We want more light
                        before we can determine what our political relations may be in the future.
                        We are in a state of anxious expectancy. Our purpose is, to co-operate, in
                        the future, with that party which may seem to us to have most at heart the
                        interests of the country, and more especially, the welfare of Virginia. But
                        with the lights now before us, we are not prepared to say what party will
                        come nearest to our standard. We are now in a condition of political
                        independence, and, for the present, we mean to maintain that position. We
                        are untrammeled by any party affiliations. We are neither republicans nor
                        democrats. We owe no fealty, and but little gratitude to either of those
                        parties. We think they are both corrupt, effete, worn out. We should be glad
                        to see both of them set aside. We should like to see a new organization
                        spring up, which would cast aside the dead issues of the past, and represent
                        the living ideas of the present day -- a party which would respect the
                        rights of the States, on the one hand, and faithfully fulfill the duties of
                        the general Government on the other. We want a party which, while it would
                        reject the narrow dogmas of nullification and secession, would at the same
                        time, steer clear of the more dangerous heresy of consolidation.</p>
                    <p>We are not among those who believe that the organic law of our country has
                        been changed by the war -- we do not think that the sword is the best
                        expounder of the Constitution. Nor are we advocates of the fashionable
                        doctrine of "unification." We believe that the war has settled the question
                        of the indissoluble character of the Union -- we agree to that. Further, we
                        know that the war has abolished slavery, and given to citizens of African
                        descent the rights of citizenship -- we acquiesce in that. -- But, we
                        maintain, that, in other respects, our government remains now, what it was
                        before the war began.</p>
                    <p>We mean to take no leap in the dark. We wish to know where we are going,
                        before we commence our journey. At present, we know so little of the policy
                        of Gen. Grant and Gov. Walker that we cannot decide whether we shall support
                        or oppose, either, or both. We shall be gratified if the course of both
                        shall be marked by that wisdom and patriotism that shall draw us to them by
                        hooks of steel. We should deplore the necessity of opposing either. We
                        earnestly hope that no such necessity will arise. Their future conduct will
                        determine that question. Our first duty is to our country. We shall endeavor
                        to fulfill that duty faithfully. But we can give no bonds for the future,
                        except of a conditional character. We shall form no entangling alliances in
                        advance. We shall wait and watch. If Gen. Grant's and Gov. Walker's
                        administrations be wise and patriotic, we shall sustain them -- if they be
                        not of that character, we shall reluctantly, but firmly and respectfully,
                        oppose them to the best of our ability. But, as we before remarked, we have
                        not the requisite information to decide that question now.</p>
                    <p>Hence we conclude this article, as we commenced it, with the declaration
                        that, in our judgment, it is unwise and premature for the people of
                        Virginia, at this time, to entangle themselves with any party organization
                        whatever.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator reported that some Richmond politicians were seeking to form
                    a "Walker party," in support of the recently elected Republican governor. The
                    Spectator argued that it would be unwise to form parties and enter alliances
                    before the elected officers took office. Recommended a wait-and-see strategy to
                    determine if President Grant's and Governor Walker's policies were acceptable to
                    Virginians or not.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Organization of a Walker Party</head>
                <origin>Enquirer and Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Enquirer and Examiner printed a call for the formation of a Walker
                    Party and a list of the Central Committee consisting of some Augusta County
                    citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.12.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seneker</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cornelius Koiner and Mary S. Koiner were married near Waynesboro on
                    November 24th by the Rev. J. E. Seneker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Susan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seneker</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus B. Conner and Mrs. Susan M. Jones were married near New Hope on
                    November 29th by the Rev. J. E. Seneker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hicks</ln>
                        <fn>Robert M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert M. Hicks of Waynesboro and Miss Annie E. Harper, daughter of Richard
                    Harper, were married in Maryland by the Rev. Mr. Henderson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrish</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tyler</ln>
                        <fn>Ella D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>S. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John F. Parrish of Augusta and Miss Ella D. Tyler of Albemarle were married
                    near Hillsboro on November 16th by the Rev. S. P. Huff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsay</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goodloe</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>S. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William S. Ramsay of Augusta and Miss Lucy C. Goodloe of Albemarle were
                    married near Afton Depot on November 24th by the Rev. S. P. Huff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellyson</ln>
                        <fn>James Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellyson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Lora E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>N. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Taylor Ellyson, son of Henry K. Ellyson of the Richmond Dispatch, and
                    Miss Lora E. Hotchkiss, daughter of N. A. Hotchkiss, formerly of Augusta and now
                    agent of the Richmond and York River and Chesapeake and Ohio Railroads, were
                    married in Albemarle at the residence of the bride's parents on December 2nd by
                    the Rev. John C. Long.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownlee</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Brownlee died of neuralgia of the heart on November 8th. He was 61
                    years old and a member of the A. R. P. Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.12.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
