<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.09.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/09/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-09-21">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">21</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.09.21.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.09.21.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Toleration--Charity--Harmony</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The late war naturally called into action the worst passions of our nature.
                        During the terrible struggle, men looked at every subject from their own
                        peculiar stand-point, and few were willing to accord to those who differed
                        from them, even the merit of sincerity. Men were drunk with passion, and
                        impatient of all differences of opinion. This intolerant spirit prevailed,
                        not only in regard to matters of political character, but extended even to
                        questions of morals and religion. And, strange to say, that many professed
                        disciples of the religion of peace, were more bitter towards those who
                        professed, in the main, the same faith, but differed from them in matters of
                        form, rather than of substance. They could tolerate those who did not
                        profess to belong to any church much more readily, than those who agreed
                        with them on all the fundamental doctrines of christianity, and yet differed
                        from them on some of the forms of worship, or minor questions of faith.</p>
                    <p>The war has now ended. The cause of fearful excitement has been removed. The
                        passions of men are beginning to subside. But still some of the old feeling
                        of acrimony remains. The greatest of all christian virtues -- charity -- has
                        not yet asserted its full dominion over the minds of men. But we trust that
                        it is making rapid advances to that end.</p>
                    <p>The public sentiment of the North is becoming much more ameliorated. The
                        recent action of the federal government, is a concession to the improved
                        public opinion of the Northern masses. And, as Providence seems to have
                        ordained that, in the future, the people of the United States shall live
                        together as one people, having common interests, and a common destiny, it is
                        manifestly proper that we should cultivate an enlarged feeling of toleration
                        and charity. If we cannot forget, we can, at least, forgive. Having such
                        constant occasion to invoke forbearance for our own short-comings, we ought
                        to endeavor, at least, to practice the divine attribute of forgiveness
                        towards others. We should remember, too, that owing to the diversity of
                        human minds, and the opposite stand points from which men view subjects,
                        differences of opinion are inevitable. We should remember our own frailty,
                        and in judging of the conduct of others, we should, at least, accord to them
                        honesty of purpose.</p>
                    <p>We trust we are on the eve of an era of better feeling, and we should do all
                        in our power to cultivate it, and place it on a firm basis.</p>
                    <p>In view of these facts, may we not invoke, on the part of the Southern
                        people, the exercise of a spirit of toleration on all the important
                        questions of the day -- toleration in politics -- toleration in religion --
                        toleration towards the people of the North, who have been misguided by
                        mischievous demagogues -- toleration towards the freedmen who have been
                        cheated and deluded by selfish office-seekers.</p>
                    <p>Religion is a matter between man and his God. It is a matter which affects
                        himself and his relation to his Creator, much more than it concerns his
                        fellow-men. And yet, strange to say, it is upon questions of this kind, that
                        men are most apt to intermeddle with the affairs of their neighbors, and to
                        extend the smallest measure of toleration.</p>
                    <p>All this is wrong. Let us cultivate a feeling of Catholic charity. Let us
                        dismiss, as far as we can, all narrow and partisan feelings in matters of
                        religion and politics. Let us allow every man to worship God according to
                        the dictates of his own conscience. Let him attach himself to what church he
                        pleases, and adopt such forms of worship and discipline as best suit his
                        taste and judgment. Let him join what political party he pleases, and vote
                        for the men and measures most acceptable to him. If we will extend this
                        charity to others, they will soon be obliged to extend the same to us. In
                        this way, the jars which sometimes disturb society will be prevented.
                        Intolerance, test-oaths, and disfranchisements are contrary to the genius of
                        this age. They are the fruits of a narrow spirit of bigotry in religion and
                        politics. And yet how many are there, who, while they are loud in their
                        denunciations of those things, indulge towards their fellow-men the very
                        feelings which give birth to these enormities.</p>
                    <p>The time is at hand when the events of the last eight years should be
                        obliterated, as far as possible, from the minds of the American people, and
                        when, recognizing no North and no South, no East and no West, they should
                        all unite in a common effort to advance the interests and honor and
                        prosperity of a common country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator publishes an editorial in favor of religious and sectional
                    toleration. Blames test-oaths and disfranchisement on feelings of intolerance
                    and urges everyone to forgo sectionalism in favor of promoting common interests
                    across the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.09.21.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Schools in Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A large number of students have arrived in Staunton, and the town's schools
                    will be filled to capacity this year. The paper praised the quality of
                    Staunton's male and female schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shea</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trippe</ln>
                        <fn>E. T. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Shea and Miss Rebecca Jane Coiner, both of Augusta, were married on
                    September 15th by the Rev. E. T. H. Trippe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>Lucretia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Lucretia Cox died in Staunton at the residence of her husband on
                    September 14th. She was 43 years old. "The deceased was an impressive
                    illustration of the influence of true piety, as seen in the bearing of
                    afflictions, in the training of children, and in the happiness of home! Her
                    bereaved family circle has the sympathies and prayers of many."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.09.21.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
