<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/26/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-08-20">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Address of the Democratic State Central Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This address sums up the position of the Pennsylvania Democratic party on
                    the causes of the Civil War. They lay the blame for the onset of the war
                    squarely on the abolitionists. Without them, claim the authors, the
                    secessionists in the South would never have risen to power. Moreover, claim the
                    Democrats, the abolitionists are intent on changing the focus of the war from
                    restoring the Union to releasing the slaves, and they will not stop until the
                    white race in the South is "exterminated or held in subjugation." The address
                    also notes rumors that black regiments have been formed. The Democrats argue
                    that this is not only a waste of uniforms, since blacks in their view will make
                    worthless soldiers, but is also dangerous. Thus, argues the address, responsible
                    citizens should vote for the Democratic party, particularly the Democratic
                    candidates for state auditor general and state surveyor general, who will stand
                    in the path of the abolitionists in Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20.02">
            <pageNote>Literature and classifieds</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20.03">
            <pageNote>Literature and classifieds</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We believe that the power granted to the government under [the
                    Constitution] are amply sufficient to crush out this wicked rebellion in the
                    South, without restoring [sic] to measures that, besides being unconstitutional,
                    are perilous within themselves."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial argues that the Constitution is to the citizen as the Bible
                    is to a Christian, and that loyalty to the Constitution, rather than to a
                    political party, is the only measure of loyalty. Abolitionists who argue that
                    secession justifies the abolition of slavery are making an "absurd and
                    fallacious" argument, and such a view proves that they are not loyal to the
                    Constitution. Lincoln's inability to resist the abolitionists indicates his
                    weakness. The editors lament the lack of a political leader like Andrew Jackson,
                    who could resist radicals on both sides of the spectrum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Even-Handed Justice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We could have no sympathy with any parties who would be guilty of
                    discouraging enlistments, and if we felt convinced that the parties arrested had
                    any such design we would say they deserved the severest punishment commensurate
                    with the crime. But we must confess our inability to see anything of the kind in
                    the transaction which caused the arrest of these men."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Messrs. Barrett and M'Dowell, Proprietors, and Forster and Jones, Editors of
                        the Harrisburg <emph rend="italic">Patriot</emph> and <emph rend="italic"
                            >Union</emph>, were arrested a short time since, by order of the Provost
                        Marshall of Washington and taken to that city under charge of a military
                        guard and imprisoned in the old capital prison. The cause of this arrest and
                        imprisonment was the issuing of a hand-bill from the office of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Patriot</emph> and <emph rend="italic">Union</emph>, by
                        two printer boys, announcing that Jim Lane was in town, and would enlist
                        colored recruits for the war.</p>
                    <p>The issuing of this hand-bill was held to be discouraging to the enlistment
                        of white men. Now, if enlisting, or advocating the enlistment of negroes is
                        calculated to discourage the enlistment of white men, why, we ask in all
                        seriousness, has not Jim Lane himself been arrested under the late order of
                        Secretary Standon [sic]? He, we are told, has gone to Kansas to enlist two
                        full regiments of negroes. Or why have not the Editors of the NY <emph
                            rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, of the Harrisburg <emph rend="italic"
                            >Telegragh</emph> [sic] and other kindred abolition sheets been
                        arrested, who have been advocating the enlistment and arming of negroes for
                        months past? It's a poor rule that wont [sic] work both ways. But it would
                        seem that what is taken for the highest degree of loyalty and patriotism in
                        Jim Lane and abolition Editors and orators, instantly becomes treason, when
                        proposed by a couple of irresponsible printer boys belonging to a <emph
                            rend="italic">Democratic</emph> newspaper office. Is this impartial and
                        even-handed justice? We think that every honest and fair minded man must say
                        that it is not.</p>
                    <p>We could have no sympathy with any parties who would be guilty of
                        discouraging enlistments, and if we felt convinced that the parties arrested
                        had any such design we would say they deserved the severest punishment
                        commensurate with the crime. But we must confess our inability to see
                        anything of the kind in the transaction which caused the arrest of these
                        men.</p>
                    <p>The following just and sensible remarks on this subject we find in the
                        Northampton County <emph rend="italic">Journal</emph>, the organ of the
                        Republican party in that county, Would to God, there were more such
                        honorable and fair-minded men editing Republican newspapers. In speaking of
                        the late order of the Secretary of war and the arrest at Harrisburg, the
                        Editor remarks:</p>
                    <p>But we hope that in the execution of this order, the govnment [sic] will
                        pursue a course of even handed justice. There should and there must be no
                        favor shown on account of political party affinities. The editors lately
                        arrested at Harrisburg for publishing incendiary hand-bills, no doubt,
                        deserved what they got, but in the judgment of many their offence was not
                        half so grand as that of Wendell Philips and the whole radical faction of
                        the North. The former lately delivered an address, in which, by heaping up
                        abuse and ridicule upon the President and some of our Generals, he has done
                        more to weaken confidence in the government and to discourage enlistments
                        than any other one man in the North. The order should not only reach and
                        punish known sympathizers with secession, but also that large class of
                        radical abolitionists who are most fond and hearty in their denunciation of
                        the government because it does not adopt and carry out their plans for
                        suppressing the rebellion. Unless the order is thus impartially executed,
                        sparing none however high, or whatever their political creed, it will do
                        more harm than good. It is just the thing now needed to enable the
                        government to prosecute the war, if it be executed without fear or
                    favor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The proprietors and editors of the Harrisburg Patriot and Union (a
                    Democratic paper often excerpted by the Valley Spirit) were arrested recently on
                    order of the provost marshal of Washington, and taken to Washington City under
                    military guard and imprisoned. The cause of the arrest was the publication of a
                    handbill announcing that Jim Lane was in town recruiting black troops--printed
                    apparently in jest by two printer boys. The publication was deemed to have a
                    harmful impact on recruiting white troops, and the two owners and two editors
                    were arrested. The Valley Spirit and Times argues that this happened simply
                    because they were Democrats. In contrast, Republican papers are free to publish
                    the most incendiary material that they choose without any repercussions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Wendell Phillips</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes from a speech recently given by Wendell Phillips in Abingdon,
                    Massachusetts, in which Phillips argues that it would better to let the South go
                    and to form a new republic based on the political equality of all men. Such
                    sentiments, argue the editors, are far more treasonous than the incident for
                    which the Patriot and Union editors were arrested.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Correspondence from 'the Army of Virginia'</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Here we are, at last, encamped on the sacred soil, on one of the Arlington
                    Heights, five miles from Washington City, two and a half miles from Alexandria,
                    and some two miles from the mansion of the Rebel General Lee."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Near Arlington Heights.</p>
                    <p><lb/>Saturday, August 16th, 1862</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Correspondence of the Spirit and Times</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Editors: Here we are, at last, encamped on the sacred soil, on one of
                        the Arlington Heights, five miles from Washington City, two and a half miles
                        from Alexandria, and some two miles from the mansion of the Rebel General
                        Lee. Our regiment was formed on Wednesday last, consisting of eight
                        companies from Franklin and two from Juniata county James G. Elder, of St.
                        Thomas, was chosen Colonel; D. W. Rowe, of Greencastle, Lieut. Colonel, and
                        James C. Austin, of Chambersburg, Major.</p>
                    <p>On Thursday evening we received orders to strike our tents at three o'clock
                        the coming morning, and be ready to march, with two days cooked rations. The
                        orders were promptly obeyed, but it was nine o'clock before we were marched
                        to the railroad, where a long train of cars was in waiting for us; after
                        remaining seated in the open cars for nearly three hours, we started for
                        Baltimore on the Northern Central Railway, after innumerable unpleasant
                        delays, we arrived at eight o'clock. We took supper at the "Union Relief
                        Association," and immediately left for the Federal Capital, which we reached
                        about three o'clock, this morning; here we were likewise indebted to the
                        Washington "Ladies Retreat" for our breakfast. After breakfast, the boys
                        were allowed an hour or so to see the sights of the town; and you may well
                        imagine they made very good use of their time. Unlike some regiments and
                        companies we have seen, they did not rush as soon as dismissed, to the
                        hotels and grogeries, but wended their way to the Capitol, President's
                        House, Public Departments, Smithsonian Institute, and other buildings and
                        places of note and interest. At about twelve o'clock, the one hundred and
                        twenty fourth regiment, Col. Bell, and the one hundred and twenty sixth,
                        (our's) took up their line of march over the Long Bridge. The day was
                        exceedingly warm, the road dusty, and the march about five miles long. You
                        may know it was the most fatiguing half day's duty many of us had ever
                        performed. There was but little shade along the road, and still less water;
                        and with a heavy knapsack weighing forty or fifty pounds together with a
                        musket and accoutrements, a haversack with rations and a canteen, many of
                        the men were almost exhausted. If our march had been much longer some of us
                        would most assuredly have been left behind. It was a very strong march for
                        raw recruits, but although greatly fatigued, we all escaped without any
                        serious consequences. The location of present camp is a pleasant one. It is
                        situated on a hill overlooking the Potomac and the Valley stretching away to
                        Alexandria, a small brook runs through it and several wells of good water
                        are in the immediate vicinity.</p>
                    <p>The day before we left Camp Curtin, Major General Wool paid us a vit [sic].
                        He was greeted with the most enthusiastic cheers by the men; and intimated
                        that the nine months volunteers would be ordered into active service as soon
                        as possible.</p>
                    <p>It is rumored in camp that last night a party of ten guerillas [sic] were
                        captured within two miles of our camp. Two of them were shot in the
                        encounter and the remainder were taken prisoners. Scouting parties are out
                        after them nightly; to-morrow we expect to go ourselves. They will receive
                        but little quarter, if any of our parties succeed in entrapping them.</p>
                    <p>A portion of McClellan's army has already arrived below Alexandria, and
                        everything seems to indicate that the second advance upon Richmond will be
                        made from the direction of Fredericksburg and the Rappahannock. By extracts
                        from Richmond papers received here, it would seem that the Rebels really
                        begin to fear for the safety of their Capital. If such be the case they
                        will, in all probability, make another demonstration, before many of the new
                        recruits can get to this side of the river. We have no desire to participate
                        in any serious engagement until we become tolerably well drilled, but after
                        that we want to do our whole duty. Our present camp is surrounded with forts
                        on all sides, at distances varying from one to three miles. Forts Runyan,
                        Albany, Scott, North Blencker and Corcoran, all within the range of the
                        naked eye, can be seen to turn their bristling parapets towards the foe, and
                        are each within shelling distance of the others.</p>
                    <p>With the exception of some little sickness occasioned by change of water and
                        climate, all still continue to enjoy excellent health, and are in the
                        liveliest spirits.</p>
                    <p>We were the first Pennsylvania nine months regiment, which reached the
                        Federal Capital; but now they come pouring in by thousands. Thus far we have
                        all been thrown into one camp; but it is to be hoped that different camps
                        will be established, as it becomes very uncomfortable when thirty thousand
                        men are massed in a single camp.</p>
                    <p>Our reception in Baltimore was very cordial--flags and handkerchiefs were
                        fluttering from hundreds of windows, while many followed us along our route,
                        cheering and encouraging us. I saw regiments passing through the streets of
                        Baltimore last winter, but their reception did not bespeak as healthy a
                        union sentiment as our's did. At least, one thing is certain, the union men
                        are now much bolder in the expression of their sentiments than they formerly
                        were.</p>
                    <p>Henceforth, our movements are very uncertain. But I shall try to keep you
                        advised as to our whereabouts. For the present letters for Capt. Doebler a
                        company should be directed to Company A, 126th Regiment Pennsylvania
                        Volunteers, Washington City, D.C.</p>
                    <p>The companies of the Regiment run as follows:</p>
                    <p>A--Capt. Doebler. <lb/>B--Capt. Austin. <lb/>C--Capt. Brownson. <lb/>D--Capt.
                        Reed. <lb/>E--Capt. W.W. Walker, (Waynesboro). <lb/>F--Capt. Wharton.
                        <lb/>G--Capt. Miles. <lb/>H--Capt. John H. Walker. <lb/>I--Capt. Martin.
                        <lb/>K--Capt. Davison, (Greencastle).</p>
                    <p>I hope this letter will reach you in time for next week's issue. I must now
                        close as the mail will soon leave for town.</p>
                    <p>K.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wharton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A report from the newly-formed 126th Regiment of Pennsylvania Volunteers,
                    made up of eight Franklin County companies and two Juniata County companies,
                    encamped at Arlington Heights, five miles from Washington City. The author
                    describes the regiment's trip through Baltimore and arrival in Washington, and
                    then the hot march out to Arlington. He also notes that James G. Elder of St.
                    Thomas was elected Colonel of the regiment, D. W. Rowe of Greencastle as Lt.
                    Colonel, and James C. Austin of Chambersburg as Major. The company commanders
                    are: A, Capt. Doebler; B, Capt. Austin; C, Capt. Brownson; D, Capt. Reed; E,
                    Capt. W. W. Walker (Waynesboro); F, Capt. Wharton; G, Capt. Miles; H, Capt. John
                    H. Walker; I, Capt. Martin; J, Capt. Davison (Greencastle).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Five or six prisoners under guard passed through town on Monday, on their
                    way to Fort McHenry. They were apparently citizens of Hagerstown and Lellersburg
                    "who had been too freely indulging their Secesh proclivities."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Small Change</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note that the scarcity of small change is unprecedented. If the
                    government does not hurry up its production of postage stamps to use as
                    currency, business operations will be impaired.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Their First Charge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A visitor to the 126th Penn. Volunteers reports that the regiment, on their
                    march to Washington, spied in the field what was thought to be an enemy battery.
                    They charged, only to find that it was a field of watermelon. The editors note
                    that they regained their position without the loss of a man, and wish them the
                    same luck in future encounters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Improvement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that "our friend" Spangler, the druggist, has rearranged the interior
                    of his store, and repainted and repapered it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A New Tobacco and Segar Store</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. C. H. Bush, formerly of Winchester, Virginia, has opened a new tobacco
                    and cigar store on the southeast corner of the Diamond, between the Mansion
                    House and the Repository and Transcript Building. He was compelled to leave
                    Virginia due to his Unionist sympathies, and he lost everything he owned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Not as large a crowd attended the most recent court session. The only cases
                    tried were on the criminal calendar, and most were of a "trifling" nature. The
                    people engaged in "flooding our county with counterfeit money" received a light
                    sentence, but severe enough, the editors hope, to deter others from doing the
                    same. The editors urge the public to continue to examine all bills offered them,
                    as there are still a number of counterfeit notes in circulation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Franklin County Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the election of officers to the 126th Regiment (see letter above).
                    Capt. John T. Dick of Mercersburg, now a captain in the 107th Regiment, had been
                    elected Lt. Colonel, but the secretary of war prohibited officers currently
                    serving from being elected to positions in new regiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Drafting--How it is Done</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Governors of the States are ordered forthwith, to proceed to furnish
                    their respective quotas of the 300,000 militia called for by the President, and
                    to appoint commandants and designate rendezvous."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Governors of the States are ordered forthwith, to proceed to furnish
                        their respective quotas of the 300,000 militia called for by the President,
                        and to appoint commandants and designate rendezvous. They are also ordered
                        to <emph rend="italic">cause an enrollment to be made forthwith</emph>, by
                        the Assessors of the several counties.</p>
                    <p>When the enrollment is completed, it is to be filed in the offices of the
                        Sheriffs of the several counties. The Governor is then to appoint a
                        Commissioner for each county to superintend the draft and decide upon
                        exemptions. These cases are specified. Exemptions for physical disability
                        will not be allowed, unless it unfits the claimant for service for a period
                        of more than thirty days, and it must be certified by a Surgeon to be
                        appointed in each county for the purpose. Within <emph rend="italic">ten
                            days</emph> of the filing of the lists of enrollment the draft is to be
                        made by the Sheriff of the county, who is to publicly place in a Jury wheel
                        a separately folded ballot for each name on the list; and when they are all
                        in, a person to be appointed by the Commissioners is to draw, blindfolded, a
                        number of ballots, equal to the quota for the county.</p>
                    <p>Subsequent paragraphs of the regulation provide for the publication of the
                        list, furnishing substitutes &amp;c., and the assembling of drafted men
                        within five days after they are drawn.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the procedure and exemptions for the upcoming draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Messrs Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Guilford</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacoby</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The letter writer suggests Jonathan Jacoby of Antrim Township as a nominee
                    for state representative, to be considered by the upcoming Democratic County
                    Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Messrs Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Colonel served the people faithfully some years ago in the same
                    capacity, and he came out without even the smell of corruption on his garments."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Constitution</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This writer puts Col. James B. Orr of Orrstown in as a candidate for the
                    state legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Further of the Battle of Culpepper, Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three and a half columns of information of the recent fighting near
                    Culpepper between Generals Pope and Banks of the Union and Stonewall Jackson.
                    The stories focus on Stonewall Jackson's retreat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>President</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hines</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carper</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ray</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heineman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDonough</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mehaffy</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heist</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seylar</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCumsey</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A synopsis of the cases tried at the "several Courts for the County" on
                    Monday August 11. President Nill and Judges Orr and Carson were on the bench.
                    All civil cases were carried over until the next term, and the reporter notes
                    that "the cases tried and disposed of were generally trifling and unimportant."
                    Commonwealth vs. William H. Hines--Larceny; defendant plead guilty, sentenced to
                    a fine of one cent plus costs of prosecution, and given six months in the County
                    Jail. Commonwealth vs. Jacob Carper--Surety of the Peace on the oath of James
                    Ray; case dismissed, Ray instructed to pay costs. Commonwealth vs. Henry
                    Heineman--Assault and Battery; verdict guilty, sentenced to a fine of one cent
                    plus costs, given two months in the County Jail; Commonwealth vs. Michael
                    McLaughlin--Assault and Battery; verdict guilty, sentenced to a fine of one cent
                    plus costs, given thirty days in the County Jail. Commonwealth vs. Henry
                    Morgan--Assault and Battery; verdict guilty, sentenced to a fine of one cent
                    plus costs, given two months in the County Jail. Commonwealth vs. James
                    McDonough--Passing Counterfeit Bank Notes purporting to be issued by the Bank of
                    Chambersburg; verdict guilty, sentenced to a fine of one dollar plus costs,
                    given one year in the Eastern Penitentiary. Commonwealth vs. Ephraim
                    Mehaffey--Indecent assault; verdict guilty, sentenced to a fine of five dollars
                    plus costs, given seven months in the County Jail. Commonwealth vs. William H.
                    Heist--Passing Counterfeit money; defendant pleads guilty, sentenced to fine of
                    one dollar plus costs, given one year in Eastern Penitentiary. Commonwealth vs.
                    Samuel M. Seylar--three indictments of passing Counterfeit Coin, having
                    counterfeit Coin in his possession with intention to pass, and with issuing and
                    selling counterfeit notes; defendant pleads guilty, sentenced to a fine of three
                    dollars plus costs, given three years in the Eastern Penitentiary. Commonwealth
                    vs. Rebecca Lightner--Larceny; verdict not guilty. Commonwealth vs. William
                    Cunningham--Assault and Battery; verdict guilty, sentenced to fine of one cent
                    plus costs, given one month in County Jail. Commonwealth vs. Elizabeth
                    Cunningham--Adultery; not a true bill. Commonwealth vs. Lewis
                    Gelwicks--Seduction, Fornication, and Bastardry; jury was unable to agree and
                    was discharged. Commonwealth vs. Jesse McCumsey--False pretenses; verdict not
                    guilty, but defendant ordered to pay two-thirds of costs, accuser Joseph Allen
                    ordered to pay one third. A number of Surety of the Peace cases of no importance
                    were also disposed of. Court adjourned until September 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burd</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parks</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Crider and Susan Parks, both of St. Thomas Township, were married
                    on the "27 inst." [indicating August 27, but probably meaning July 27].</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>Arthur Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Arthur Franklin McKnight, only son of H. C. and A. E. McKnight, died in
                    Marion on August 13 at the age of 2 years, 6 months and 12 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James S. Ross, Esq., died in Chambersburg on August 11, aged about 50
                    years. He was a member of the Chambersburg Bar and was highly esteemed for his
                    honesty and character.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brindle</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brindle</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Brindle, wife of Michael Brindle, of St. Thomas Township, died on
                    August 6 at age 94.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haas</ln>
                        <fn>Gertrand</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gertrand Haas died on August 7 at the age of 1 year, 1 month and 22 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But her Heavenly Father had ordered those [happy] days to be few, and the
                    latter portion of them were days of peculiar physical pain and suffering."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yoe</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin R.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddle</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddle</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Riddle, widow of William M. Riddle of Chambersburg, died at the
                    home of her son-in-law, Benjamin Yoe, Esq., in Baltimore on August 12 at the age
                    of 57 years. A lengthy obituary follows, which notes her unobtrusive manner and
                    the strength with which she passed through the emotional trial of widowhood, and
                    the physical trial of the sickness that finally killed her.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Chambersburg Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf>Dr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>J. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An advertisement announcing the improvements made at the Chambersburg
                    academy, as well as the retention of J. K. Shryock as a teacher of classics and
                    of J. R. Kinney as an instructor in higher mathematics and natural sciences. The
                    Trustees, noted above, urge the community to support the institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Borough Ordinance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn>Caleb</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The town council (Flack, Brown, Shafer, Myers, and Atherton) announce the
                    appointment of Emanuel Kuhn as "Regulator" of Chambersburg, who will grade all
                    pavements and number all buildings to be erected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20.06">
            <pageNote>Miscellaneous war news, fiction, and five columns of classifieds</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20.07">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.08.20.08">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
