<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/25/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-07-09">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="09">9</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The War News--The Very Latest from General McClellan's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The entire front page is occupied with reports of the fighting near
                    Richmond during the "Seven Days" engagement, with reports of Union losses of
                    15,000 to 20,000 men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09.02">
            <pageNote>Literature</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09.03">
            <pageNote>War news from Virginia previous (June 26) to the Seven Days engagement, and
                five columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Army Surgeons</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is manifest that the enemies which the soldiers of the Union have most
                    to fear, are not the armed rebels who are to face them in battle, but the
                    commissioned gentlemen whose duty it is to take care that they be supplied with
                    everything which their health requires."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A medical board arrived in Harrisburg to examine candidates for admission
                    into the army as surgeons. The editors speculate that what happened was a
                    familiar routine: many good doctors signed up but then refused to take the
                    examination, as their knowledge of peripheral fields has faded. The editors
                    predict that the only people who could pass the test were medical students
                    without any practical experience. The editorial goes on to criticize the
                    understaffing of the medical corps, especially in light of the unanticipated
                    need generated by the number of men getting sick in the camps. The efforts of
                    the voluntary Sanitary Commission have not been backed up by the government, the
                    editors claim.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>State Line</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If it is wrong for the church to meddle in politics, it is equally wrong
                    for political newspapers to meddle in church affairs."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints part of a letter to the Valley Spirit, which attacks an article
                    published in the Transcript regarding a local church. The letter gives a veiled
                    threat to the editor of the Transcript, noting that if the editor ever visits
                    State Line, Pennsylvania, where the letter was written, "he can have it fully
                    demonstrated that the 'boys' are not only his superior morally, but physically."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The delegates departed Harrisburg with the highest hopes for the future of
                    the country and the determination to spare no exertions to secure the triumph of
                    constitutional principles at the October election as the last hope of a
                    distracted and bleeding nation."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Directs the reader's attention to a report elsewhere in the paper from the
                    Democratic State Convention held in Harrisburg on July 4. The Spirit claims that
                    this year's convention was unmarked by personal rivalry and exhibited the unity
                    and patriotism of the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Democratic State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Resolved, that this is a Government of white men, and was established
                    exclusively for the white race; that the negro race are not entitled to and
                    ought not to be admitted to political and social equality with the white race,
                    but that it is our duty to treat them with kindness as an inferior and dependent
                    race...."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A summary of the proceedings of the Democratic State Convention held in
                    Harrisburg on July 4. F. W. Hughes of Schuykill County was elected president of
                    the convention; vice presidents from every county and district were elected as
                    well, including John Orr from Franklin County. Isaac Slenker of Union County was
                    nominated as the candidate for the office of Auditor General, and James P. Barr
                    of Allegheny County was nominated for Surveyor General. Resolutions adopted
                    included: support for the federal government for the restoration of the Union
                    and the Constitution; statement that the object of the war is only those goals,
                    and none other; criticism of the extravagant expenditures of some federal
                    departments; condemnation of the release of Southern slaves into Northern
                    society and into competition with white laborers; statement that abolitionism
                    and secessionism are equivalent; statement that abolitionism will prevent
                    restoration of the union due to its purely sectional nature; criticism that the
                    suspension of habeas corpus is dangerous; statement that the government is
                    exclusively for white men and any effort to equalize blacks with whites is
                    condemned; and a statement of support for the troops in the field.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Rebel Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another trainload of Confederate prisoners passed through Chambersburg on
                    Sunday, and they seemed to the editors less distinguished than those who passed
                    through previously.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Tall Timothy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fickes</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A new stock of timothy grass which reaches five feet tall can be found
                    growing on the farm of Josiah Fickes in Lurgan Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Counterfeiters About</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Counterfeit notes of the Bank of Chambersburg are in circulation, though
                    the editors claim that the parties circulating the notes have been determined.
                    The notes are in $5 denominations, and are described as such: the vignette is
                    larger than in the genuine; a sheaf of wheat is in front of the vignette; the
                    title of the bank is scratchy and blurred; a male portrait, rather than a
                    portrait of Franklin, is in the upper right corner; the signature is different
                    and the paper is lighter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Franklin County Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>J. A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A member of the 77th Reg't Penn. Reserves writes that he encountered a
                    Franklin County resident, Capt. J. A. S. Mitchell, now in command of a company
                    of troops from Indiana. Mitchell was a former law student in the office of the
                    Hon. Wilson Reilly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Fourth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "Unless something is soon done for the morals of this community--and that
                    speedily--a catastrophy [sic] like that which befell Sodom and Gomorrah may be
                    looked for almost every day. Reform is demanded and let those <emph
                        rend="italic">who are most interested</emph> move in the matter--it wont
                    take much looking around to find out where to begin." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Fourth passed off in this place with rather an unusual amount of
                        enthusiasm, and rather an unusual amount of something else too that had as
                        well been left out of the programme. We never knew as much rioting and
                        drunkenness on one night as was put through on the night previous to the
                        Fourth. In fact to such an extent was it carried that some of our divines,
                        who are not apt to tread on the toes of our fashionable vice, were
                        constrained to notice it in their sermons on the following Sabbath. Unless
                        something is soon done for the morals of this community--and that
                        speedily--a catastrophy [sic] like that which befell Sodom and Gomorrah may
                        be looked for almost every day. Reform is demanded and let those <emph
                            rend="italic">who are most interested</emph> move in the matter--it wont
                        take much looking around to find out where to begin.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial condemns the drunken behavior of townspeople the night
                    before the Fourth of July, and warns of dire consequences if the morals of the
                    town are not improved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Capt. Easton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Hezekiah Easton, of the First Pennsylvania Artillery, was killed on
                    Friday (presumably during the Seven Days battle) after fighting all day. He was
                    shot in the bowels that evening with a Minnie ball and died several minutes
                    later. Because the enemy took the ground where he fell, his body was not
                    recovered. Easton's worth as a citizen and soldier was known by all, and he
                    leaves a family of a wife and eight children in the town of Loudon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Meeting of George Washington Lodge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At a meeting of the George Washington Masonic Lodge (No. 143, A. Y. M.), a
                    resolution of commemoration was passed for their deceased member, Hezekiah
                    Easton. The resolution was reported to the press by secretary John Mull.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>300,000 Troops to be raised</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of a letter from Union governors to Lincoln, advising him of their
                    willingness to raise more troops to replenish depleted units (Gov. Andrew of
                    Massachusetts did not sign the letter). Lincoln's reply thanks them, asks for
                    300,000, and leaves a space for each state's quota.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Disgraceful</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article attacks civilian political leaders who are criticizing the
                    policies and tactics of General McClellan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew Detrich and Nancy B. Shatzer, both of St. Thomas Township, were
                    married on July 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes market information from Chambersburg and Baltimore, and a synopsis of
                the early fighting in the Seven Days battle.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09.06">
            <pageNote>Literature and classifieds</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09.07">
            <pageNote>Literature and classifieds</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.09.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Great Meeting in New York--Protest Against Negro Agitation</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting was held at the Cooper Institute for people who supported
                    fighting the war only for restoration of the Union and who opposed "continued
                    agitation of the negro question." Hon. Mr. Wickliffe of Kentucky and Hon.
                    William Duer of New York spoke in favor of the position, and the few people who
                    objected were shouted down by the crowd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Three columns of classified advertisements and legal notices</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
