<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-02-19">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News--Glorious News from North Carolina</head>
                <origin>Various Richmond papers</origin>
                <commentary>"All the Southern papers received are unanimous in admitting a complete
                    victory by our troops, and that the loss of the island is a very serious one."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A series of reports describing the victory by General Burnside's expedition
                    in North Carolina, culminating in the capture of Roanoke Island.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Latest News From Fort Donnelson!</head>
                <origin>St. Louis Democrat, Chicago Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A compilation of reports from the Union victory at Fort Donelson,
                    Tennessee, through February 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Abolition is Secession</head>
                <origin>Boston Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Because Abolition is Secession, let patriots keep clear of it; and because
                    the Constitution is the Union, let them cling to it as the mariner clings to the
                    last plank."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points to Andrew Johnson of Tennessee as an example of a border state
                    unionist caught between his love for the Union and his hatred of abolition. The
                    article criticizes abolitionists because they place their duty to "fanatical and
                    revolutionary demands" above the Constitution. Abolitionists are thus tantamount
                    to the secessionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The Valley Spirit changed its typeface to include a greater number of
                sub-headlines in a variety of typesets. The first article takes up nearly half of
                the front page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Growl at the President</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The truth is that the Abolitionists begin to realize the fact that they
                    have played and lost, and that their counsels are not to be heeded in the White
                    House. We predict before long that they will be in open opposition to the
                    Administration, and that the President will look to the Democrats and moderate
                    Republicans to support the conservative policy of his administration."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pokes fun at the criticisms of the president by Horace Greeley's New York
                    Tribune. The article asserts that Lincoln has rejected the abolitionists'
                    demands, as can be gauged by their protests against him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes fiction, humor, and miscellaneous human interest news
            items.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19.03">
            <pageNote>Fiction and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Lincoln Dynasty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The history of the present Administration has yet to be written, but we
                    may supply a chapter in anticipation of the volume of startling disclosures that
                    is to astound the world with the recital of the grossest bribery, corruptions,
                    defalcations, plunderings, extravagance and profligacy that has ever disgraced
                    or overthrown a government."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial takes Lincoln to task for portraying himself as "Honest Abe,"
                    while at the same time setting himself up as an aristocrat in the White House.
                    It includes a long quote describing how the White House has been redecorated "in
                    imitation of the residences of the crowned heads of Europe." The editorial also
                    singles out Mrs. Lincoln for the extravagant dress she wore to a recent White
                    House ball, and generally criticizes the Lincolns for extravagance at a time of
                    national emergency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Hon. Edgar Cowan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"One of the most deplorable signs of these most deplorable times, is the
                    utter disregard of law evinced by the Republican party in general."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> has twice vindictively assailed
                        Senator COWAN for opposing the expulsion of JESSE D. BRIGHT from the Senate
                        of the United States. In its issue of the 5th inst. it said it supposed "he
                        intended to darken his career in the Senate with the encouragement of
                        treason;" and on the 12th it said: "Mr. COWAN has most surely dug his own
                        grave. His political life will evidently end at the expiration of his
                        present Senatorial term. He has positively refused, knowingly, according to
                        his own expressions, to represent his constituents properly in the Senate of
                        the United States. He has committed an outrage upon the old Keystone, and
                        the Legislature should very politely request him to resign his seat, so that
                        it can be filled by one more worthy of its honors," &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>We care nothing for JESSE D. BRIGHT, and Senator COWAN is neither a personal
                        nor political friend of ours. But we put in an indignant protest against the
                            <emph rend="italic">Transcript's</emph> coarse denunciation of one of
                        the ablest and most honest representatives that Pennsylvania has for a long
                        time had in the Senate of the United States. The man who takes a seat in
                        that august body should discard the low partisanship that disgraces our
                        State Legislature. This Mr. COWAN has done; and because he has done it, and
                        sunk the partisan in the statesman, he is assailed in unmeasured terms by
                        certain members of his own party, who have not the elevation of mind to
                        appreciate the dignity and the justice of his official conduct.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> compares the course of Mr. WILMOT
                        with that of Mr. COWAN, and eulogizes the former as warmly as it denounces
                        the latter. The very quotations it makes from the debate between these two
                        Senators of Pennsylvania, shows the rank injustice of its attack upon Mr.
                        COWAN. When Mr. WILMOT said, in answer to Mr. COWAN's inquiry, that "he was
                        frank to admit that if he were sitting <emph rend="italic">as a
                        juror</emph>, there are those doubts hanging about the case (of BRIGHT) that
                        would make him <emph rend="italic">hesitate to pronounce a verdict of
                        guilty</emph>," he gave up the whole case in favor of Mr. COWAN. As a
                        Senator sitting in judgment upon a fellow-citizen, he committed a horrible
                        outrage by rendering a verdict which he would not have rendered if he had
                        been sitting as a juror.</p>
                    <p>One of the most deplorable signs of these most deplorable times, is the utter
                        disregard of law evinced by the Republican party in general. Not only do
                        Cabinet officers exercise powers never conferred upon them by the
                        Constitution and laws--not only do members of Congress and of the State
                        Legislature openly proclaim their want of respect for the sacred instrument
                        which this gigantic war is waged to maintain--but the town and township
                        leaders of the Republican party take under their special protection the
                        degenerate statesmen and politicians who thus trample upon and deride all
                        that a true American holds dear.</p>
                    <p>And worse than all, when an eminent lawyer like Senator COWAN, unable and
                        unwilling to unlearn all that he has ever learned about the Constitution and
                        laws of his country, refuses to follow the path marked out by the blind
                        malice of such men as SUMNER and WADE, the cry for vengeance upon him goes
                        forth at once from mouths that but a single year ago were sounding his
                        praises.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph>, which tenderly consigns Senator
                        COWAN to a grave of his own digging, and calls upon the Legislature to
                        request him to resign, has not a word of condemnation for State Senator
                        LOWRY, whose remarks on his resolutions of instruction were a burning
                        disgrace to Pennsylvania. LOWRY, who knew very well that his views on legal
                        and constitutional questions were not worth a rusty nail in comparison with
                        COWAN's, appealed to the mob spirit of the North and declared that there was
                        "too much disposition shown to conduct this war on legal and constitutional
                        grounds." For saying less than this, Democrats have been whisked off to
                        forts and other military prisons, on the unlawful order of a Cabinet member
                        or military officer, with the full approval of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Transcript</emph> and other Republican journals.</p>
                    <p>It is such men as these political gods of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Transcript</emph>, WILMOT and LOWRY, who have brought the country to the
                        verge of ruin. It is such men as COWAN who will yet save her, if she is not
                        beyond the reach of salvation. There is not now in the whole country a man
                        who has done more than DAVID WILMOT to estrange and imbroil the two sections
                        of the Union. From the day when he offered his celebrated <emph
                            rend="italic">proviso</emph> in Congress, fourteen or fifteen years ago,
                        the country has known no peace on the slavery question. That firebrand,
                        wantonly lighted in the Capitol of the nation, has gone on burning with ever
                        increasing fury, till it has enveloped the whole country in the frightful
                        conflagration we are now struggling to suppress. LOWRY is but another WILMOT
                        on a smaller scale. He has less ability, but even more malice. He has no
                        capability for doing good in any sphere of life, and under ordinary
                        circumstances he could do but little harm; but he is a dangerous light to
                        follow in times like these, and the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph>
                        incurs a heavy responsibility by holding him up as a guide to the public.</p>
                    <p>Senator COWAN's general course in the Senate, so far as it has attracted our
                        attention, has been that of an able, resolute, safe and honest man. The
                            <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> will find itself mistaken in
                        predicting that he has dug his grave. It may cover him with abuse and slaver
                        WILMOT with praise, but the honest people of patriotic old Pennsylvania will
                        have no difficulty in distinguishing between the enlightened statesman and
                        the mischievous demagogue. As long as EDGAR COWAN stands by the
                        Constitution, Pennsylvania will stand by him--for it is <emph rend="italic"
                            >not</emph> the sentiment of this glorious old State that the
                        Constitution can be <emph rend="italic">saved</emph> only by being <emph
                            rend="italic">violated</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Edgar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This editorial takes the Transcript to task for its criticism of Senator
                    Edgar Cowan's opposition to the expulsion of Senator Jesse Bright from the U.S.
                    Senate. The Valley Spirit contrasts Cowan's behavior to that of Senator Wilmot,
                    who was supported by the Transcript, and argues that Wilmot's vote to remove
                    Bright from the Senate was not made in good conscience, and that significant
                    doubt existed as to whether or not Bright should have been removed. The editors
                    cite Wilmot's vote as further evidence of the disregard of Republicans for due
                    process and the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Secretary Stanton With the Congressmen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a day spent with Secretary of War Stanton as he met with
                    congressmen and senators requesting favors from him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Conspiracy Against McClellan</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Evidences of a conspiracy among the 'On to Richmond' tribe of New York
                    editors and marplot Congressmen, like Gurley, are becoming more and more
                    abundant every day."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends General McClellan against accusations of being unpopular among his
                    troops and attacks his adversaries for warmongering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>County Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is not an office in the county more directly beneficial to the
                    people than that of the County Superintendent, and none so poorly remunerated,
                    when we take into consideration the amount of labor required to be performed by
                    the incumbent."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P.M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Takes issue with unnamed critics of the salary of the Superintendent of
                    County Schools, P.M. Shoemaker, Esq. The editors defend not only Shoemaker's
                    performance, but also make a case for the existence of the office itself, which
                    some people had questioned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Correction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"None can feel more rejoiced than we do to make known this gratifying fact,
                    and remove any injurious impressions our notice may have occasioned. We don't
                    know after all but some good may result from our blunder."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors apologize for a mistake made in the previous week's editorial,
                    which called for more local activity on behalf of the poor. They had stated that
                    the Visiting Sick Society was defunct, when in fact it was in active operation.
                    They urge citizens to support the Society in its work among the poor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Enterprise Extraordinary!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have always felt considerably put out by the one-sided accommodation of
                    the Telegraph office here...."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pokes fun at the Dispatch, the "semi-weakly" as the Valley Spirit calls it,
                    for celebrating the use of the railroad to obtain army intelligence reports
                    ahead of the telegraph service; the editors note that the railroad is not
                    exactly a new innovation. The editorial also claims that the Dispatch gets
                    preferential treatment by the telegraph office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Health of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our town was never in a more healthy condition."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Exaggerated reports of sickness prevailing in this place have been circulated
                        in some parts of the county. There is not a word of truth in these reports.
                        Our town was never in a more healthy condition. Two or three cases of
                        Varioloid have occurred but there are no fears entertained of the disease
                        spreading and no alarm is felt about it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes claims of widespread sickness in the city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Recruiting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the War Department has consolidated all recruiting in
                    Pennsylvania under a single officer. The article warns enlistees to make sure
                    they are signing up with an authorized recruiting officer before joining.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Turned Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Brotherton of Waynesboro, recently released by the Confederates,
                    reports that he was in prison in Richmond with a man named McLaughlin, who was
                    taken prisoner with a number of other Franklin County men. McLaughlin was
                    rumored to be killed or to have deserted, and he wished to notify an uncle in
                    Franklin County of his whereabouts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Sad Casualty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wentling</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGarvey</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stratiff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hicks</ln>
                        <fn>Albertis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGlaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John West, a laborer, was found dead on Tuesday at the lime kiln of Solomon
                    Wentling, on the farm of F. Gelwicks. A jury of inquest was summoned by P.
                    McGarvey Esq., and ruled that West had died of suffocation from coal gas. The
                    jury consisted of Jacob Stratiff, Albertis Hicks, David McGlaughlin, Frederick
                    Gelwicks, Peter Small, and James G. Elder, Esqs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rejoicing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bells were rung in Chambersburg upon receipt of the news of the capture of
                    Fort Donelson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that every man in Captain McKesson's company (attached to Col.
                    Stumbaugh's regiment in Kentucky) sent home money on the last payday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Robbed</head>
                <origin>Shippensburg News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thrush</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The room of D.W. Thrush, Esq., in the Black Horse Hotel in Shippensburg,
                    was broken into and $180 dollars in money and promissory notes, as well as a
                    dress coat, was stolen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>An Old Citizen Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Radebaugh died on February 18 after a short and painful illness. He
                    was one of Chambersburg's most affluent citizens and held the position of
                    Director of the Bank of Chambersburg at the time of his death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Franklin County Boy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beam</ln>
                        <fn>Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beam</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jackson Beam, son of John Beam of Loudon, is an Orderly Sergeant in one of
                    the companies of the 84th Illinois Regiment, encamped at Mumfordsville,
                    Kentucky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Letter From Col. Stumbaugh's Reg't</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have had once or twice some crackers that were rather hard but they
                    were an exception. In fact I can say that we have much better living than I
                    expected when I entered the service."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>CAMP WOOD, 77th Reg't, <lb/>P. V., Munfordville KY., <lb/>February 10, 1862</p>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: Having seen a request for communications from the Army, I will
                        try to give you a few items that perhaps <emph rend="italic">may</emph> be
                        acceptable to some of your readers although you cannot expect much from a
                        poor soldier. There has been nothing exciting here in this division of the
                        army since that famous communication to the Cincinnati <emph rend="italic"
                            >Gazette</emph> from this place. The Pennsylvania boys of this Reg't
                        were very much pleased with your notice of it in the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Valley Spirit</emph>. All we ask is a chance at the enemy and we will
                        try to earn our laurels. I saw an extract from a letter from this Reg't, in
                        your paper in regard to rations issued to this Reg't which I was sorry to
                        see. The writer carried the idea that we were not very well provided for. I
                        think this Reg't has been well supplied with provisions with one or two
                        exceptions. When the bridge over the Rolling Fork River was washed away we
                        lived on a very short allowance for a few days. We have had once or twice
                        some crackers that were rather hard but they were an exception. In fact I
                        can say that we have much better living than I expected when I entered the
                        service. We of course do not fare as well in regard to delicacies from our
                        friends as we would if encamped near home, which I presume is better for us,
                        as I have noticed whenever the <emph rend="italic">boys</emph> have received
                        boxes from home they are apt to get on the sick list. There is no prospect
                        of a forward movement here at present, but we never know before an order
                        comes. We are all in hopes to see a forward movement soon. Mr. EDITOR if our
                        friends at home would only write us letters oftener and give us all the home
                        news they would often raise our drooping spirits. If this should prove
                        acceptable you may hear from the Bloody 77th again.</p>
                    <p>CORPORAL</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Corporal</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter describing the state of provisions at the camp and the general
                    consensus that no forward movement is likely in the near future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We had the pleasure of witnessing the tieing of the above knot and
                    partaking of some of the good things prepared for the occasion. We wish our
                    friend Isaac long life and much happiness in his new relation, and though he
                    married a Whisler [ital], we trust he may never have to deny[?] he paid to dear
                    for his whistle [ital]."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whisler</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac P. Grove of Lurgan township married Martha Whisler of Letterkenny
                    township on February 13.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michaels</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisel</ln>
                        <fn>Lena B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Michaels and Lena Weisel, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    February 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>ippy?</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W.H.C. ippy? and Caroline Smith, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    February 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>N.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sipes</ln>
                        <fn>David V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Binkley</ln>
                        <fn>Angeline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKillip</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David V. Sipes of Licking Creek township married Angeline Binkley of Summit
                    Ridge at the house of John McKillip.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Houck died on February 9, near St. Thomas, age 82 years, 11
                    months and 11 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>?</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth ? died in Loudon on January 24, age 39 years and 10 months. She
                    leaves a husband and six small children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hannah Wingerd died near New Guilford on February 6, age 62 years, 10
                    months and 2 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Radebaugh died on February 17, after a short but painful illness, at
                    age 68. His funeral will take place at his residence on Wednesday at 12 o'clock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aegle</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Fanny Aegle died near Chambersburg on February 16, age 70 years and 15
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes market reports and classified advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19.06">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19.07">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.19.08">
            <pageNote>Repeat of public financial information, plus classified
            advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
