<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/1/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-10-29">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The London Times on the Battles in Maryland</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"For the first time in the war, a Federal General has challenged the
                    Confederates to fight a pitched battle and has won it."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report from the London Times of October 2, relating the details of the
                    battle at Sharpsburg. The correspondent describes the Federal victory as a
                    surprise and credits it to McClellan's willingness to engage the enemy. Until
                    now, the Confederates had outfought superior Union armies, but the fight now
                    seems to be about equal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Penalty for Refusing to Serve When Drafted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Much curiosity is evinced to know the penalties under State and national
                    laws for refusing to serve when drafted."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors relate the penalties for evading the draft, which are a fine of
                    not more than one years pay and not less than one month's pay, and, on refusing
                    to pay, an imprisonment at the rate of one month for every five dollars owed.
                    The penalty was set out in an act of Congress in 1795.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes a speech from September commemorating the 75th anniversary of
                the signing of the Constitution.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29.03">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Democrats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"That they deserve severe retaliatory measures may be true, but let your
                    forbearance be the scorpion that shall sting their consciences continually, as
                    the severest punishment that could be inflicted upon them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors claim that the Democratic party has been more "traduced and
                    vilified" than any other. Now that the Democrats have triumphed in the recent
                    elections, the editors urge them not to retaliate against those who have
                    persecuted them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Infamous Proscription</head>
                <origin>Constitutional Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This, says the Constitutional Union, is the way in which white men are
                    treated by the leaders of the Abolition faction."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors claim that all employees of the Philadelphia Arsenal who did
                    not vote Republican in the election were fired, and they argue that abolitionist
                    leaders are willing to discard white workers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Hurra for the People!</head>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Southern people will see, in fact, that they have no rights they need
                    fight for; and that if the contest be kept up, it will be done after the people
                    in the South have no interest in it."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors interpret recent Democratic victories as an indication that
                    Northern voters have endorsed the Democratic policy of "the Constitution as it
                    is and the Union as it was." Such a policy should be encouraging to the average
                    citizen of the South, the editors believe, as it promises a return to the Union
                    with all their rights intact. However, the editors conclude, Confederate leaders
                    are still determined to fight, and a strong show of force will be necessary to
                    discredit these leaders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Recent Election: Will Abraham Lincoln Listen to their Teachings?</head>
                <origin>Constitutional Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The policy and acts of President Lincoln and his party have been scattered
                    to the winds by the fury of popular indignation, for in the choice of the
                    members of Congress, the Democratic party have made most unprecedented gains."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer takes issue with the Philadelphia Inquirer's interpretation of
                    the election as an endorsement of President Lincoln. In the Pennsylvania
                    congressional delegation, Democrats gained nine seats, with fifteen Democratic
                    congressmen and nine Republicans. Democratic control of the Pennsylvania House
                    of Representatives gives Democrats a majority on the joint ballot, which will
                    give them enough power to name David Wilmot's replacement in the Senate. A
                    number of prominent Pennsylvania abolitionists were defeated at the polls. Ohio
                    and Indiana show similar results. Voters have "peaceably notified" Lincoln that
                    they are tired of emancipation, tired of "Abolition treason," tired of criticism
                    of McClellan, and tired of the suspension of habeas corpus. The editors wonder
                    if Lincoln will hear the voters' message.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Election--Official</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives the county-by-county breakdown of votes for auditor general and
                    surveyor general, the breakdown of votes within the
                    Adams-Franklin-Fulton-Bedford-Somerset congressional district, the breakdown of
                    votes within the Adams-Franklin-Fulton state senatorial district, and the
                    breakdown of votes within the Franklin-Fulton legislative district. It also
                    includes a roll of the Pennsylvania Senate and House of Representatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Drafted Militia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We think that we never saw a finer body of men, physically, than the
                    drafted men that appeared in our town on Tuesday last."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We think that we never saw a finer body of men, physically, than the drafted
                        men that appeared in our town on Tuesday last. They are much superior, as a
                        general thing, to the volunteers, and judging from appearances will make as
                        good, if not better, soldiers, than any that this County has already sent to
                        the "tented field." Universal good humor prevailed amongst them and every
                        man we conversed with expressed a determination to "pitch into" the Rebels
                        as soon as they got a chance.</p>
                    <p>It is highly probable that the drafted men of the border counties, will go
                        into camps, near the state line, for the protection of the Old Commonwealth
                        from future incursions of horse thieves under Stuart and Hampton. The
                        government should, by all means, establish a camp near this place and send
                        here several batteries of artillery, so that if the enemy again makes an
                        inroad, in this direction, we may be able to give him a warm reception.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors praise the quality of the recently drafted soldiers from
                    Franklin County and claim that they are of even higher quality than the
                    volunteers from the area. They editors believe the draftees will most likely be
                    stationed within Pennsylvania, and they ask for a detail to be placed in
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>List of Deaths in Hospitals in Chambersburg, since October 4</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Academy Hospital: Sgt. George D. Robertson, Co. A, 1st NY Cavalry, d. Oct.
                    12; Corp. John Kellam, Co. C, 88th PA, d. Oct. 15; 2nd Lieut. Charles W. Bean,
                    Co. H, 5th NH, d. Oct. 19. School Hall Hospital: Private Patrick Mulligan, Co.
                    K, 1st CA, d. Oct. 4; Private J. Danforth, Co. C, 19th MA, d. Oct. 5; Private
                    Stephen H. Ellis, Co. H, 137th PA, d. Oct. 8; Lieut. J. Finch, Co. A, 124th PA,
                    d. Oct. 20. Franklin Hall: Private Charles A. Trask, Co. K, 13th MA, d. Oct. 1;
                    Private C. H. Wellington, Co. K, 13th MA, d. Oct. 1; Capt. Zechariah Dakins, Co.
                    K, 95th NY, d. Oct. 7; Corp. A. G. Edwards, Co. A, 125th PA, d. Oct. 9; Private
                    Isaiah S. Hartman, Co. C, 132nd PA, d. Oct. 20; Private Edward H. Kunkles, Co.
                    I, 4th MD, d. Oct. 22.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Depot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors visited the burned-out railroad depot and warehouse of
                    Wunderlich and Nead. They complimented both the Cumberland Valley Railroad and
                    Wunderlich and Nead for their efforts to rebuild.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus Knepper of Quincy Township was badly hurt when he was thrown from the
                    top level of an omnibus as he rode it from Greencastle to Waynesboro. Knepper
                    fell when the omnibus crossed a railroad track, and the wheels passed over his
                    head.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is as little good judgement as good sense exercised in the matter."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors complain that the gas streetlights are often unlit on the
                    darkest and rainiest nights, while on the brightest nights they are lit when
                    they are not needed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Camp on the Potomac</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The enemies shells and bullets came towards them thick and fast, but they
                    still advanced boldly over rough roads and newly furrowed fields, climbing rocks
                    and high fences and pushing through almost impenetrable woods."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">For the Spirit and Times.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Battle Field of "Antietam," <lb/>October 20th, 1862.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs Editors:</emph> I have thought it due my my [sic]
                        company to give some expression of my regard for them, and state some
                        matters connected with our movements, through the public prints. The company
                        designated "G" in the 126th Regiment, Penna. Vols, was among the first
                        reported at Harrisburg, for the Nine Months service. We left Harrisburg on
                        the 15th of August and crossed the Beng Bridge at Washington into Virginia
                        the following day. Since that period we have occupied various camps near
                        Washington and Alexandria and this section of Maryland. We have marched
                        fully two hundred miles afoot, and a portion of our late principal march,
                        namely, from beyond Frederick, to Antietam Battle Field about 27 miles over
                        two mountains, and by night, in 14 hours was certainly one of the most
                        remarkable of this war. It is now nearly three months since we were mustered
                        into the U.S. Army, and I am proud to say that at this date I have every man
                        of the original number yet in my command. A few are sick in the hospital and
                        from the same cause one or two are absent with leave. None, however, are
                        seriously ill. Not one of my men have "deserted," or been arrested for any
                        dishonorable act or for any flagrant violation of the Regulations of the
                        Army. I accept their past conduct as a guarantee for the future in this
                        respect. At this time the roll of my company exhibits as many men for active
                        duty as any other in the Regiment.</p>
                    <p>It affords me no little pleasure to be enabled to speak in commendatory
                        language of the general conduct of my company. I can say frankly and
                        candidly that they are always prompt and faithful in the discharge of any
                        duty assigned them. To the officers they are respectful, courteous, and
                        obedient. In their intercourse with one another, on and off duty, they are
                        kind, generous and forbearing. Their persons they keep as clean as it is
                        possible to do in camp, and their quarters evidence order and neatness. They
                        have given proof that they are ready at any time to engage actively in the
                        business of their organization, namely fighting for the Stars and Stripes
                        and the glorious cause of their country. Arriving on the day following the
                        battle of Antietam, but before it was certain that that sanguinary contest
                        had ended, they were full of enthusiastic ardor, and ready to march into
                        position with the rest of the army at the word of command. Again, when
                        notified by Gen Tyler, the brave Commander of this Brigade, on the next
                        Saturday, that they would certainly face the enemy in conflict within a very
                        short time, they were ready without flinching for the order to move. On the
                        late reconnaissance over and several miles beyond the Potomac into the
                        enemy's country, and which was fraught with danger at every step they
                        proceeded bravely and determinedly. The enemies shells and bullets came
                        towards them thick and fast, but they still advanced boldly over rough roads
                        and newly furrowed fields, climbing rocks and high fences and pushing
                        through almost impenetrable woods. They did all this without a murmur or
                        faltering in the least.</p>
                    <p>I make this record of my command after three months intimate association with
                        them for the simple purpose of indicating to their relatives and friends,
                        their past conduct and what we may all hope for in the future. I have spoken
                        of them with no intention to disparage the claims of my fellow officers and
                        their companies, in this regiment, or to undervalue their services, for we
                        are all associated and united in a common purpose and a sacred cause.</p>
                    <p>It may be of interest to the families of my men to know that the 31st of the
                        present month is the date fixed for the appearance of the Paymaster, when
                        each man will be paid the amount due him for three months services.</p>
                    <p>George L. Miles, <lb/>Capt. Co. G. 126th Regt., Pa. Vols.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Capt. George L. Miles</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. George L. Miles reports on the activities of Company K of the 126th
                    Reg't Penn Volunteers, which he commands. He reports that every man who mustered
                    into the company is still present, save for several sick in the hospital. He
                    also praises the company for its courage and eagerness to fight, even though
                    they reached the battlefield of Antietam a day after the battle had finished.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of a proclamation issued by Gov. Andrew Curtain, recommending that
                    the people of the Commonwealth set aside Thursday, November 27, as a day of
                    "Solemn Prayer and Thanksgiving to the Almighty." He adds a prayer for God to
                    aid the leaders to have "right judgement" in things, and to grant military
                    leaders "zeal and vigor in action, that the fire of rebellion may be quenched."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Hasting</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Mary F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hasting Gehr of Washington City married Mary F. Smith, daughter of the late
                    Frederick Smith, Esq., of Chambersburg, on October 23.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deck</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Witman of Harrisburg married Kate Deck of Franklin County at the
                    house of the bride's father on October 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karper</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin Grove and Margaret E. Karper, both of Franklin County, were married
                    at the house of the bride's father on October 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Lizzie McFadden, daughter of D. S. and Elizabeth McFadden, died of
                    diphtheria in Chambersburg on October 18 at age 3 years, 11 months and 17 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blankney</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susan Blankney died in Greenvillage on October 23 at age 81.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie E. Dixon, only daughter of Capt. William D. Dixon and Martha Dixon,
                    died in St. Thomas on October 18 at the age of 3 years, 11 months and 2 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Cook died in Chambersburg on October 23 at the age of 71 years and 12
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Isabella Marshall died in Upper Strasburg on October 21 at the age of
                    71 years and 12 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gebhardt</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gebhardt</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gebhardt</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Gebhardt, son of George J. and Anna Gebhardt, died on October 24 at
                    the age of 10 months and 24 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Falkenstein</ln>
                        <fn>Michael H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Falkenstein</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Falkenstein</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michael H. H. Falkenstein, son of George M. and Elizabeth Falkenstein, died
                    on October 27 at the age of 10 months and 12 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes miscellaneous war news and reprinted news items</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29.06">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29.07">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.10.29.08">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
