<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-05-21">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Shall Constitutional Liberty Survive the Restoration of the Union?</head>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"For this reason we hold all men, instrumental in passing unconstitutional
                    laws, such as confiscation of property, without due process of law, the
                    emancipation of slaves in the States, but acts of Congress or individuals in the
                    army, the nullification of the fugitive slave law, or any other Constitutional
                    law, as aiders and abettors of treason and rebellion."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that either radical abolitionists or the Constitution must give way,
                    and hints that it would be better to "bloodily suppress" abolition sentiment
                    rather than allowing what the authors see as a violation of the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Emancipation and its Consequences</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Supposing emancipation to be an accomplished fact, supposing the
                    Constitution to be violated and the four millions of slaves in the Southern
                    States declared forever free, and this decree executed by military power, how
                    much better off are we than with slavery as an existing institution?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, since the separation of the races is in accordance with
                    natural law, the emancipation of the slaves would only worsen social problems.
                    The North could not handle the influx of free blacks, who if they stayed in the
                    South would simply relapse into slavery, and colonization is too expensive an
                    option.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes an article in dialect about Lincoln and emancipation, as well as
                brief humorous articles.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21.02">
            <pageNote>Humor and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. John W. Forney</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks Forney's support for a Union movement with Republicans in the
                    Pennsylvania legislature. Forney noted that Senator Wilmot supported the idea,
                    which the authors of the article see as a sure sign of its worthlessness. The
                    authors lump Forney, Wilmot and Sumner together as supporters of the
                    "treasonable theory" that the southern states had given up their rights as
                    states and should revert to territories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Five columns are classified advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democratic State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Democratic State Convention will be held in Harrisburg
                    on Friday, July 4, to nominate candidates for Auditor General and Surveyor
                    General.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democratic County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. Y. Hamsher, chairman of the Franklin Democratic County Committee,
                    announces a meeting on June 3 at Montgomery's Hotel, to elect delegates to the
                    state convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Under Abolition Rule</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The South was about returning to her allegiance when LINCOLN'S
                    emancipation message, the abolition of slavery in the District of Columbia, and
                    the pronunciamientos of abolition military chieftains, started the war afresh,
                    smothered out nearly all Union feeling in the South, and no one will now venture
                    to predict where the war will end nor how much more blood will be spilt since it
                    has degenerated into a crusade against slavery."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Lincoln has turned the war into one solely to free the slaves,
                    and that his abolition of slavery in Washington D.C. has turned the city into a
                    haven for runaway slaves. The article states that former slaves are being
                    supported in idleness by the federal taxpayer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Hero Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But our Republican friends must not despair--they have two chances yet.
                    General FREMONT is reinstated to command the mountains, and General HUNTER is in
                    the field with his nigger brigade, and who knows but the Republican party may
                    yet succeed in manufacturing a Hero out of one or other of these redoubtable
                    Generals?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks the leaders of the Republican party, arguing that every figure the
                    Republicans have tried to celebrate as a hero has fallen short of the
                    mark--Cameron, Fremont, and finally, Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Transcript and the Democratic Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks the Transcript for its criticism of the recently published speech
                    by certain Democratic members of Congress. The Transcript said that the
                    Democrats neither praise the soldiers nor denounce the rebels in their
                    anxiousness to attack the Republicans. The Valley Spirit responds that
                    Republican sentiments for the Union are weakly held, and that if abolition were
                    repudiated, the abolitionists would be as likely to go into rebellion as the
                    southern states were.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>General Hunter's Order</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of General Hunter's order freeing the slaves in South Carolina. The
                    Spirit criticizes it for its failure to distinguish between loyal and disloyal
                    owners, and notes that it is in direct violation of the purposes of the war as
                    declared by Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Surveyor General</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Levi L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Valley Spirit notes its support for Col. Levi L. Tate, the editor of
                    the Columbia Democrat, for the position of Surveyor General. The Colonel, they
                    note, is a "'rock-water' Democrat."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Two additional columns of reprinted editorials</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Capt. Wishart in Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Captain led his company into battle at Pittsburg Landing, at 6 o'clock
                    on the morning of April 7th, and remained with it in the thickest of the fight
                    until 1 o'clock in the day, when he was promoted to the position of Surgeon of
                    the regiment--"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Capt. H.S. Wishart, Company F., 77th regiment Pa. Volunteers, made a short
                        visit to our town on Friday last. The Captain was obliged to return home on
                        account of the condition of his health, which has somewhat improved, since
                        his return, and he hopes to be able to join his regiment in a few days. The
                        Captain led his company into battle at Pittsburg Landing, at 6 o'clock on
                        the morning of April 7th, and remained with it in the thickest of the fight
                        until 1 o'clock in the day, when he was promoted to the position of Surgeon
                        of the regiment--Previous to going into battle Gen. McCook desired that all
                        the medical men, no matter what office they might hold, be detailed to take
                        charge of the wounded. Col. Stumbaugh communicated this order to Capt.
                        Wishart, who is a regular physician, and desired him to act as Surgeon of
                        the 77th. The regiment was then about entering battle without a Surgeon--Dr.
                        Irish the Principal Surgeon was back with the ambulances, and did not arrive
                        upon the field until the battle was over, and his Assistant, Dr. Potter, had
                        been left in charge of an Hospital at Columbia. Capt. Wishart,
                        notwithstanding the position in which the regiment was left in regard to a
                        Surgeon, requested to be allowed to remain with his company, to which the
                        Colonel reluctantly agreed, and he continued in command of the company until
                        1 o'clock, when the first man shot down in the regiment was a member of his
                        own company. Capt. W still continued with his company for over one hundred
                        yards in advance of where the man was shot, when he received a peremptory
                        order from the Colonel to take charge of the wounded and perform the duties
                        of Surgeon of the regiment for the remainder of the day. In obedience to
                        orders, as well as promoted by a feeling of humanity, and knowing too that
                        his 1st Lieutenant was a brave and skilful [sic] officer, and would lead the
                        company gallantly through the battle, Capt. Wishart transferred his command
                        to Lieut. West and assumed the duties of Surgeon, which he performed
                        skilfully [sic] and humanely until the regular Surgeon arrived and took
                        charge of the wounded. Capt. Wishart speaks in the highest terms of praise
                        of Lt. West, as well as of all the men under his command. We have the
                        principal facts in the above statement not from Captain Wishart, but from
                        Colonel P.B. Housum who would take pleasure in corroborating them over his
                        own signature was he not prostrate on a bed of sickness.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wishart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Wishart of Company F, 77th Reg't Penn. Volunteers, made a short visit
                    to Chambersburg last Friday to recover from a health problem. Wishart, a doctor,
                    was promoted to surgeon of the entire regiment during the battle at Pittsburg
                    Landing. He requested to remain in command of his troops, which he did until a
                    man in his own regiment was shot and the Colonel ordered him to take charge of
                    the wounded. Colonel P. B. Housum related this incident, and would have written
                    about it himself had he not been "prostrate on a bed of sickness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>From the Wars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Nip Scott an individual of the kullered persuasion, who held the
                    distinguished position of private commissary to the colonel of the 77th
                    Pennsylvania regiment, returned from the wars last week covered all over with
                    glory."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Nip Scott an individual of the kullered persuasion, who held the
                        distinguished position of private commissary to the colonel of the 77th
                        Pennsylvania regiment, returned from the wars last week covered all over
                        with glory. Nip is quite a lion among the wolves of Wolfstown while fighting
                        his battles o'er again and recounting his hair-breadth escapes on field and
                        flood. Nip called to see us and gave a "gleamy" account of our boys in
                        Tennessee. He considers the 77th the crack regiment of the army--that it did
                        all the fighting, took all the prisoners and killed all the rebels at
                        Pittsburg Landing he is quite sure. It would excite Nip's belligerent
                        propensities to a very unsafe degree to say anything against the 77th in his
                        presence. Nip has one trait about him that we admire--<emph rend="italic"
                            >his modesty</emph>, and it would be worthy of imitation by all who have
                        seen the elephant. We inquired of Nip if he was in the battle?</p>
                    <p>"No sa I warn't."</p>
                    <p>"How near were you to the fight?"</p>
                    <p>"Well you see de Colonel, in de afternoon you see, sent for me you see, to
                        bring him somthin to eat you see. I slung de habbersack ober my back and
                        started for de field on de double quick you see, and got up whar de balls
                        war wizzen and den--"</p>
                    <p>"Well, what then Nip?"</p>
                    <p>"I'd radder you wouldn't ax me anything more 'bout dat."</p>
                    <p>"You did'nt [sic] retreat I hope?"</p>
                    <p>No S-ar. Dat is not de word we use out dar--I <emph rend="italic"
                        >retired</emph>, sa in good order."</p>
                    <p>"Did the Colonel get nothing to eat all day?"</p>
                    <p>"No sa, muffin by dis individual nigger."</p>
                    <p>"Were you afraid of being shot?"</p>
                    <p>"No, sa, but I didn't want to be."</p>
                    <p>Discretion is evidently the better part of valor in Nip's estimation, and it
                        would be as well for all those who have a <emph rend="italic">natural
                            aversion</emph> to smelling powder to "acknowledge the corn" as frankly
                        as Nip Scott.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Nip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nip Scott, a black resident of Wolftown, returned from service as a
                    commissary in the 77th Reg't Penn. Volunteers. The Valley Spirit accuses him of
                    cowardice in the face of fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Farmer's and Mechanic's Industrial Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruttrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immell</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graig</ln>
                        <fn>J. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An election was held on Tuesday May 13 for officers of the Franklin County
                    Farmer's and Mechanic's Association. They are: President, John Ruttrauff;
                    Vice-Presidents, J. S. Nixon, G. W. Immell, D. K. Wunderlich, James C. Eyster;
                    Secretary, W. S. Everett; Corresponding Secretary, Samuel M. Armstrong;
                    Treasurer, Emanuel Kuhn; Managers, William Bossert, William Cline, B. F. Nead,
                    J. Watson Graig, W. W. Skinner, H. B. Davison, William McClure, James G. Elder,
                    Samuel Myers, H. C. Greenawalt, A. B. Wingerd, Andrew Davison.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Seventy-Seventh</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Col. Stumbaugh had the satisfaction of receiving the sword of Colonel
                    Batteles, of the Twentieth Tennessee, who surrendered to him as a prisoner."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>General M'Cook, in his official report, tells what part Colonel Stumbaugh's
                        regiment took in the great battle of Shiloh. He says:</p>
                    <p>"Colonel Stumbaugh, with the 77th Pennsylvania Regiment of Pennsylvania
                        Volunteers, early in the action, being ordered to watch the enemy on my
                        left, was, at a later period ordered to engage. His regiment, partially
                        isolated from the rest of the division, steadily moved over an open field in
                        its front under a heavy fine. While here the enemy's cavalry charged this
                        regiment twice, but was each time repulsed with heavy loss. Col. Stumbaugh
                        had the satisfaction of receiving the sword of Colonel Batteles, of the
                        Twentieth Tennessee, who surrendered to him as a prisoner. Lieut. Col.
                        Housum and Major Bradford ably seconded the efforts of Col. Stumbaugh.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Quotation from General McCook's report on the "great battle of Shiloh,"
                    which praises the action of the 77th Reg't Penn. Volunteers and singles out Col.
                    Stumbaugh, Lt. Col. Housum, and Major Bradford for compliments for their
                    efforts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A collection of dispatches on the war, including rumors of the capture of
                    Richmond, a report on the repulsion of Federal gunboats south of Richmond,
                    reports on the situation in the west and southwest, and notice of the lifting of
                    the embargo on Beaufort, NC, Port Royal, SC, and New Orleans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>From Banks' Command</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A brief report of encounters with Confederate cavalry near Strasburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ripper</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ripper</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine Ripper, "relict" of the late Peter Ripper, died on May 16 in
                    Chambersburg after a prolonged illness. She was 84 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Polmer died on May 16 at the age of 86.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes market news and one column of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21.06">
            <pageNote>Humor and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21.07">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Union Must Be Saved Constitutionally</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If the destruction of property rights in slaves, and the disregard of
                    constitutional provision, is the medicine necessary and justifiable to cure a
                    rebellion after it has broken out, how clear it is that the hanging of a few
                    abolitionist lecturers by way if precaution is necessary and justifiable as a
                    preventative!"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, by making abolition a war goal, the Republicans seem to want
                    to destroy the Union in order to save it. No circumstances, they argue, justify
                    the violation of constitutional guarantees of the right of states to determine
                    the fate of slavery within its own borders. For people to advocate a federal
                    plan of abolition is tantamount to advocating revolution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Five columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.05.21.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Proclamation of General Butler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of the orders of Major General Butler regarding the occupation of
                    New Orleans. Butler declares martial law, makes it a punishable offense to show
                    disrespect to the American flag, prohibits publications from describing the
                    movement of American troops, and dissolves the municipal authority of the city
                    with the exception of the fire companies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Four and a half columns of classified advertising.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
