<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/25/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-07-02">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Speech of Hon. S. S. Cox of Ohio</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A speech in the U.S. House of Representatives that discusses the
                    ramifications of free blacks moving to the North. Cox, a Congressman from Ohio,
                    claims his district has the highest percentage of blacks in the state, and yet
                    the districts that are most prominently abolitionist hardly have any.
                    Abolitionists would not be so anxious about their cause if the blacks moved into
                    their counties, Cox claims. He also argues that, if freed, blacks will not work
                    in agriculture, and where they do work they will displace the whites who have
                    paid taxes and fought to free them. The Congress that frees the slaves, he
                    concludes, will go down in history as hated by both whites and blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Speech takes up five columns.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02.02">
            <pageNote>Literature</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02.03">
            <pageNote>Literature and classifieds</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Affairs at Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are led to believe that we have not been making that progress in our
                    advance to the rebel Capital that we hoped to chronicle this week."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sketchy news reports indicate that McClellan has been forced back to the
                    James River, and though the editors note that it may be a tactical move, they
                    decline to speculate very far. A number of Pennsylvania reserves have been
                    involved in the fighting and have suffered heavy losses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Union Men of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commentary on the reprint of a letter written by Gen. J. B. Cochrane of
                    Kentucky, a Unionist slaveholder and former legislator. It is the slaveholders
                    of Kentucky who are Unionists, claims Cochrane, and the non-slaveholders who
                    fear the effects of abolition who are the secessionists. Thus, the letter and
                    the article claim, attempts by Congress to punish secessionists by freeing
                    slaves will only alienate slaveholding Unionists in the border states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Who Are the Partizans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We know it is idle to expect fairness and honesty on the part of the
                    Dispatch towards a political opponent."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reply to the Dispatch's criticism of an earlier Valley Spirit editorial
                    that claimed that the Democrats were less partisan than the Republicans. The
                    Dispatch disputed this claim and made allusions to the Spirit's partisanship. In
                    response, the Spirit cites its editorials from April 17, 1861, and April 24,
                    1861, both of which urge its readers to forgo partisanship and unite to defend
                    the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Short Reply</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Every man in this community knows, and every honest man will say, that the
                    Valley Spirit was the first paper in this place to run up the Stars and Stripes,
                    and that too without any demand, or under any threat or forcework about it, but
                    from a sense of right and duty. These negro-worshiping abolition traitors must
                    not think that because they hide the meanest political bigotry under the mask of
                    patriotism, other men do the same."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is not often that we notice the productions of anonymous scribblers and
                            <emph rend="italic">never</emph> when our paper is the target at which
                        they aim their malicious and cowardly shafts. We invariably allow all such
                        assassin like scribblers to simmer down in their own malice, after ridding
                        themselves of their superfluous froth and foam, without being in the least
                        annoyed by their spiteful ebullitions. We depart from our usual rule in this
                        respect to notice briefly a writer in the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Transcript</emph>. This veracious correspondent in an effort to establish a
                        reputation for truth telling lets off the following:</p>
                    <p>"But Mr. Editor, it does not surprise me that the <emph rend="italic">Valley
                            Spirit</emph>--a sheet notorious for its traitorous proclivities--should
                        attempt to screen rebel sympathisers by a suppression of facts, in order to
                        cast odium upon the brave soldiers of the Union army, for if I have been
                        correctly informed, compulsory measures had to be used before the publishers
                        of that <emph rend="italic">vile sheet</emph> would hoist the Stars and
                        Stripes at the commencement of the rebellion."</p>
                    <p>We fear the above extract might seriously damage the writers reputation
                        unless he is very careful to keep it in the dark. Should he let himself be
                        known his character must suffer some from such a dubious statement. If the
                        writer intended that this community should believe his balderdash about Mr.
                        Hanstine's Flag he was most unfortunate in introducing the above item into
                        his article about the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit's Flag</emph>.
                        Nobody in this community ever heard of the "compulsory measures" that this
                        writer prates about so knowingly. People are not so easily deceived as this
                        anonymous scribbler imagines and when they detect one deliberate falsehood
                        in an article are apt to look upon the balance of the production in the same
                        light. In this instance they would be taking a very correct view of the
                        writers "<emph rend="italic">facts</emph>" for a more dastardly tissue of
                        lies was never penned. His entire statement about Mr. Hanstine's disloyalty
                        is on a par with his assertion that "compulsory measures had to be used"
                        before the Stars and Stripes adorned our office. We have in this community
                        some very rabid sympathisers with abolition treason, like the writer in the
                            <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph>, who will assert almost anything
                        about a Democrat, but we defy one of them to say that there is a single
                        circumstance upon which to found such a report about the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Valley Spirit</emph>. It is a lie manufactured out of the whole cloth,
                        and the writer who penned it and the printer who published it <emph
                            rend="italic">knew it to be such</emph>. Every man in this community
                        knows, and every honest man will say, that the <emph rend="italic">Valley
                            Spirit</emph> was the first paper in this place to run up the Stars and
                        Stripes, and that too without any demand, or under any threat or force-work
                        about it, but from a sense of right and duty. These negro-worshiping [sic]
                        abolition traitors must not think that because they hide the meanest
                        political bigotry under the mask of patriotism other men do the same. They
                        are mistaken and it is time they should know it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanstine</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>While the editors claim that their policy is never to reply to anonymous
                    criticism, they take issue with a letter printed in the Transcript, which
                    accuses the Valley Spirit of having to be forced to fly the Stars and Stripes at
                    the moment of the rebellion. This allegation is absolutely false, the editors
                    reply, and the writer is casting doubt on the honesty of all the Transcript's
                    writing by the publication of this obvious falsehood. The issue is connected to
                    an ongoing argument over the cutting down of a flagpole raised by Michael
                    Hanstine, a Democrat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>That's What's the Matter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"That pole was bound to come down. No abolitionized Republican could look
                    at it and not become enraged--it was enough to give them fits."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Star-Spangled Banner that Mr. Hanstine, of Waynesboro, hoisted upon the
                        Union pole at his residence, had inscribed on it "Democracy and the Union
                        Now and Forever." That is where the treason was smelt--better a thousand
                        Unions perish than that Democracy should endure forever! That pole was bound
                        to come down. No abolitionized Republican could look at it and not become
                        enraged--it was enough to give them fits.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanstine</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The flag on Mr. Hanstine's pole in Waynesboro which was cut down read
                    "Democracy and the Union Now and Forever." The editors claim that it was bound
                    to come down, due to the fanaticism of Republican partisans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Fool Answered</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanstine</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Transcript's accusation that Hanstine was not a supporter of the Union
                    is false, because at the time of the rebellion Hanstine was occupied putting up
                    Union poles and trying to "encourage a spirit of patriotism" in Waynesboro. He
                    has a better record, the editors claim, than many Republicans who are trying to
                    make money off the war by "robbing the Government as a contractor by selling
                    them worthless horses."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Management of the War</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Patriot and Union cites the Philadelphia Union, a Republican paper,
                    which blames Secretary of War Stanton for the recent reverses in the Virginia
                    theater. It was not McClellan's fault, but the disorganization resulting from
                    four different generals commanding troops in the region. While soldiers die
                    needlessly, the article claims, Stanton tries to play soldier. The Patriot and
                    Union notes that if a Democratic paper had said such things, they would have
                    been branded traitors. The tone of the article, overall, is very pessimistic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Delightful Entertainment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We do not remember of witnessing so brilliant an array of talent at any
                    former exhibition of this kind in any place."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The pupils of the Chambersburg Female Seminary gave a "Grand Vocal and
                    Instrumental" concert in Franklin Hall on Thursday. The editors praise both the
                    performers and the director of the school, Rev. Dr. Reeves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie Burns died in Fayetteville on June 23 at the age of 5 years, 1 month
                    and 14 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Hannah Cook died in New Guilford on June 28, aged 65 years, 4 months
                    and 12 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahaffy</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Mahaffy died near Marion, aged 54 years, 9 months and 14 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Local news is brief; most of the page is taken up with war and foreign news,
                including the removal of General Fremont from his command and reports of advances
                toward Richmond. The page also contains the market reports from Chambersburg and
                Baltimore.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Draft at Savannah--Georgia Patriotism at a Low Ebb</head>
                <origin>Charleston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a scene in which a Confederate colonel attempted to raise
                    volunteers for the army in Savannah with very little luck. Most men tried to use
                    excuses to avoid volunteering, and they didn't join the army until they were
                    faced with the threat of a draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Five columns of classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02.07">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.07.02.08">
            <pageNote>Legal and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
