<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1862/pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-02-05">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Charge to the Grand Jury by Hon. James H. Graham</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>H.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Address of Hon. James H. Graham to a grand jury in Cumberland County. His
                    remarks reflect on the war, and focus, by the end, on the folly of the policy of
                    Northern abolitionists to make emancipation a central war aim. He implies that
                    abolition sentiment may even slip toward treason, as abolitionists agitate
                    against the protections for slavery in the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The speech occupies half of the front page. This page also includes
                Congressional reports and general war news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction and poetry</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Indefinitely Postponed</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the State Committee of the "People's Party," a Republican
                    effort to attract Democratic voters to its ticket, met and decided not to call a
                    State Convention at the present time. Dissension between those who wished to
                    maintain a pure Republican party and those who wished to attract Democrats
                    caused party leaders to postpone the convention until unity could be assured.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also contains classified advertising</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Legislative Corruption</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The people will decide these matters for themselves--nay, they have
                    decided them--and the fact that but one member of our Legislature, who was
                    suspected of corruption, has been returned to his seat by the people is a
                    sufficient 'handwriting on the wall' to warn unfaithful legislators of their
                    doom for all time to come."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial addresses the appointment of a legislative investigating
                    committee to examine the passage of an act commuting the tonnage tax in the
                    previous session. While suspicious generally of the legislature's ability to
                    investigate itself, the editors hope that the "ventilating" of the issue will
                    answer some questions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Libel on Pennsylvania Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Cincinnati Gazette article claimed that, in an engagement in Kentucky on
                    January 19, Pennsylvania soldiers in the 77th and 79th Regiments panicked and
                    fled the field without even sighting the enemy. The editors of the Valley Spirit
                    condemn this accusation as "calumny" and cite a Louisville Journal article
                    refuting the charges.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Congress</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have endeavored to keep our readers posted on the doings in Congress by
                    giving a summary of its daily proceedings. Was anything of importance
                    transpiring we would give it in more detail. The present Congress has convened
                    at a time when the country, more than any other period in its existence,
                    demanded calm and safe counsels, but instead of this we have had nothing but
                    wrangling about the negro, the most frivolous debates, and nonsensical
                    dilly-dallying that has ever disgraced any deliberative body."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The present Congress, in the view of this editorial, has become sidetracked
                    by debates over the future of African-Americans when more important matters,
                    such as how to keep the nation financially solvent, are in need of attention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Letter from the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Our camp here seems to be but a temporary one; at all events, it is very
                    evident that we will not tarry long in this heaven-forsaken place."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Treher</ln>
                        <fn>H.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Treher</ln>
                        <fn>John.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from H.R. Treher, son of John Treher of Loudon, stationed at
                    Patterson's Creek, near Cumberland, Maryland. The letter does not specify the
                    regiment, although it mentions that the commander is General Lander. The bulk of
                    the letter focuses on marching and camping in the rains and the mud.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Letter from Camp Pierpont</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joe. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Joseph Miller, a solider formerly stationed at Camp Slifer, now
                    at Camp Pierpont in Virginia with the "11th Reg't P.R.C." He writes to thank the
                    ladies of Chambersburg who set a "box of fine edibles" to the camp. He also
                    recalls the hospitality of Chambersburg during the time he was stationed there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Good Move</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is a sacred duty we owe towards those who have sacrificed their health
                    in defending their country's flag, and there is no avoiding it unless we come
                    down--away down--to heartless selfishness and disloyalty to our country."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several collection boxes for relief of sick and wounded soldiers have been
                    placed at the Post Office and the railroad ticket office, and the Valley Spirit
                    urges all to contribute.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Turn Them Out</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Curtain's Cabinet needs overhauling, and these incompetent officers set
                    adrift."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the discrepancies between the state auditor's and the state
                    register's reports and calls for the removal of the state auditor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Superintendent's Salary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Spirit omitted the salary of the superintendent of common
                    schools in last week's listing of moneys received from the state. His salary of
                    $600, the editors feel, could be justly doubled, due to the excellent job he
                    does.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Shocking Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kupfender</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Kupfender of Chambersburg was killed on Friday in a train collision
                    while tending several railroad freight cars belonging to Messrs. Wunderlich and
                    Nead on the North Central Railroad near Baltimore. His body was severed in two,
                    and it was returned to the city where his funeral was held on Sunday. He left a
                    wife and several small children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The 'Poor House'</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Everything about the establishment presented an air of neatness,
                    cleanliness and order, which speaks well for the present management of the
                    institution, and must conduce much to the health and comfort of the inmates."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday last, we paid a flying visit to the Alms House. We arrived there
                        just in time to partake of the many good things prepared for the occasion,
                        and served up in the shape of a <emph rend="italic">magnificent</emph>
                        dinner. After dinner we were ushered into the business room of the
                        establishment, where we found the Directors--Messrs. Spencer, Latshaw and
                        Harris--in session, than whom, three more gentlemanly and courteous men, we
                        venture to assert, are not to be found anywhere. Afterwards, with the
                        Directors, we passed through the various rooms and cells of the poor <emph
                            rend="italic">unfortunates</emph>, and found everything in <emph
                            rend="italic">apple-pie</emph> order, under the judicious management of
                        the present obliging and efficient Steward--James Chariton, Esq. Everything
                        about the establishment presented an air of neatness, cleanliness and order,
                        which speaks well for the present management of the institution, and must
                        conduce much to the health and comfort of the inmates.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latshaw</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chariton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors visited the Poor House last week, dined with Directors Latshaw,
                    Harris, and Spencer, and met Steward James Chariton, Esq. They reported that
                    conditions there were excellent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Recruiting Station</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieutenant William Burgess, of Captain Dixon's company of the 6th Regiment
                    of Pennsylvania Reserves, has set up a recruiting station at the Franklin Hotel.
                    Volunteers may choose the regiment they will serve in and will be furnished with
                    transportation and sent off immediately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Boys in Trouble</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We do not believe the young men arrested would be guilty of committing
                    such an act. They have always borne good characters while among us, and some of
                    them have respectable connections in this place."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some four or five of the members of Capt. Brand's company have been arrested
                        in Harrisburg for robbery, and sent to prison to answer for the offence in
                        default of $500 bail. A man by the name of Charles Gray alleges that he was
                        robbed by the party, of some thirty dollars, while crossing the Harrisburg
                        bridge after night. We do not believe the young men arrested would be guilty
                        of committing such an act. They have always borne good characters while
                        among us, and some of them have respectable connections in this place.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Four or five members of Capt. Brand's company have been accused of robbery
                    in Harrisburg. The Spirit protests their innocence and notes that they are from
                    respectable families in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Clark died suddenly on Thursday. He was about 60 and had been in
                    attendance in court the day before his unexpected death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes reviews and advertisements for magazines. Local news and
                national editorials seem to have been combined onto page 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05.05">
            <div type="j">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings, Second Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Polly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dearmine</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dearmine</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Braver</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Divilbiss</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tenly</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lytle</ln>
                        <fn>J. Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lytle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tankersly</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phraener</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNair</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ery?</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ery?</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summary of the second week of trials; Judge Nill recused himself, as he was
                    counsel on many of the cases, and Judge Graham of Carlisle stood in for him.
                    Cases tried were: Keystone Mutual Life Insurance Company vs. William
                    McLellan--action to recover promissory notes; defendant claimed he had been
                    induced to become a member of the company through misstatements of the company;
                    verdict, $174.80 for plaintiff. Polly Piper vs. James Dearmine and his wife
                    Catharine--account rendered; referred to auditor at defendant's request. William
                    Crist vs. John Snider--action to recover a tract of land in Montgomery township;
                    Crist bought the property at a sheriff's sale, but Snider claims to have deeded
                    the land to somebody else before the sale; verdict for plaintiff. William
                    McGrath vs. John Braver--Ejectment to recover 70 acres of mountain land; verdict
                    for plaintiff. Fred. Divilbiss vs. James Tenly--action for rents of 13 acres of
                    land; verdict, $27.50 for plaintiff. Adam Carbaugh vs. J. Milton Lytle, executor
                    of David Lytle--action to recover part of purchase money of a farm; verdict,
                    $208.89 for plaintiff. Commonwealth for the use of J.R. Tankersly and Wife vs.
                    Hezekiah Easton and Martin Newcomer, Executors--Action on guardian bond;
                    verdict, $869.48 for plaintiff. G.W. Brewer vs. Administrators of Benjamin
                    Phraner, deceased--Action on book account; verdict, $110 for plaintiff. William
                    Forbes vs. James and Elizabeth Patterson--Action on "assumpsit"; verdict,
                    $127.68 for plaintiff. J. and S. Eye? vs. Andrew McNair--action on book account
                    of $23.10; verdict of $10.28 for plaintiff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cashman</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reuben Cashman and Susan M. Palmer, both of the vicinity of Chambersburg,
                    were married at the Lutheran Parsonage on January 30. Miss Palmer is the
                    daughter of Daniel Palmer, Esq.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham A. Price and Elizabeth Stover, both of Waynesboro, were married on
                    January 30 at the Lutheran Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin C. Snyder and Elizabeth West, both of Hamilton township, were
                    married on the 21st of January.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Forney, of St. Thomas township, married Mary McCleary, of Hamilton
                    township, on January 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Muma</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Muma and Mary Myers, both from the vicinity of Fannetsburg, Path
                    Valley, were married on January 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Clark died suddenly in Chambersburg on January 30, age 61 years and
                    11 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fetter</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Fetter, died near Orrstown of palsy on January 29, at age 88
                    years, 3 months and 10 days. She was a long-time member of the Lutheran church
                    at Orrstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Nancy Flickinger, daughter of Joseph Flickinger of Fannetsburg, died
                    on Sunday last at age 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page also includes accounts of the Poor House, the statement of finances for
                Franklin County from January 6, 1861 to January 11, 1862, and accounts of the county
                with the state. Also includes classified advertising.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05.06">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05.07">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1862.02.05.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Burnside Expedition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[General Burnside] is confident of the ultimate success of the expedition
                    and has the respect of every man under his command."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A glowing report on the arrival of the Burnside expedition at Hatteras
                    Inlet, despite the loss of a number of ships along the way.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes statement of aggregate tax assessments of the county, as well as
                classified advertising.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
