<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.10.08">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/20/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-08">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.08.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; miscellaneous anecdotes, columns 4 and
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democrats on the Union Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Refutes the claim made by the Valley Spirit that the Democratic men on the
                    Union ticket are "old office hunters who have been boring the public for office
                    for years past."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Is He Competent?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A mind so illy balanced as to be opposed to the infliction of capital
                    punishment or the crime of wilful and deliberate murder, and to be capable of
                    stultifying itself by being in favor of any war, is certainly illy adapted to
                    the necessities of the Judge's office."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Mr. Reilly is not fit for a judgeship because in open court he
                    declared himself against capital punishment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every intelligent voter will understand the importance of sending true Union
                        men to the Legislature. If the Breckinridge Democracy should succeed in
                        deceiving the honest voters of Pennsylvania and thereby securing a majority
                        of their kind of <emph rend="italic">patriots</emph> in that body,
                        Pennsylvania will be dishonored by having her Senators in Congress
                        instructed to vote for Peace and Compromise with the Rebels, and it must not
                        be forgotten that Compromise with the Rebels upon any other terms than an
                        unconditional surrender to the authority of the Government is Treason to the
                        Constitution and the Union, and a virtual surrender of every principle that
                        makes us proud of our Country and her institutions.</p>
                    <p>See to it, then, by ever honorable effort that you can exert, that John Rowe
                        and W. W. Sellers is [sic] triumphantly elected. The larger their majority,
                        the greater will be the rebuke you will administer to the enemies of the
                        Union. Lag not in your efforts this day while the polls are open and there
                        is a vote to be cast. Exert yourselves to secure that vote for Rowe and
                        Sellers--for the whole Union Ticket--and for Freedom. One vote, this day,
                        may be of the most momentous importance, and might decide the political
                        complexion [sic] of the next Legislature, and upon the action of the
                        Legislature may hang the fate of the Union! Who can tell? For our country's
                        sake, then--for the sake of humanity, and for Freedom here as well as for
                        the oppressed, struggling masses of the Old World, who are gazing with
                        trembling anxiety as to the result of the struggle in which Freedom and
                        Slavery are now engaged in our midst--for these reasons and for every other
                        consideration that should be cherished by Freemen, we conjure you to a
                        faithful, unwearied, unflagging discharge of your duty.</p>
                    <p>The despots and enemies of Freedom throughout the world are rejoiced at the
                        wicked rebellion which is now so severely testing the strength of the Union,
                        and which they fondly expect will ultimate in the destruction of the
                        Republic. Let no vote of yours, then, either contribute to their
                        gratification of the more inexcusable and detestable enemies in our midst. A
                        political victory may result in more beneficial consequences with regard to
                        the perpetuity of our Union than the most sanguinary battle-field; then let
                        to-day's sun set upon a triumph of the entire Union Ticket.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Implores voters to go to the polls and vote for "true Union men" so that
                    Breckenridge Democrats do not take control of the legislature, in which case
                    they would vote for peace and compromise with the rebels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Union Ticket!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges voters to vote for the Union ticket, because only in this way can
                    "the open traitor" be kept out of the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Test of Female Heroism</head>
                <origin>Louisville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"To the young wife, we would say, better far is a widowhood of honor than a
                    long life union with a craven who would not defend his home; glorious the solemn
                    garb which denotes your bereavement, when you can pay visits to the grave of
                    your dead warrior-husband and over it mingle your tears in common with those of
                    the mourning friends of our country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Appeals to the women of the North to do their part in the Union cause by
                    allowing their men to go off and fight to preserve the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Union ticket, column 1; reminders to voters to examine their tickets closely,
                and to vote for the Union ticket, column 4; anecdotes concerning the war, column 4;
                news from Fortress Monroe and Washington, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Col. Stumbaugh's Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Colonel Stumbaugh's regiment left Camp Slifer the previous day
                    for Pittsburgh. Speculates that the regiment will be sent to the West as its
                    "field of operations."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Growing Crops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that in at least five or six townships in the northern part of the
                    county there are indications that in the next season there will be a good
                    harvest produced.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of Maj. Hollar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the death of Major Joseph Hollar in Greencastle after an illness of
                    several weeks. Hollar was the proprietor of the Union Hotel in Greencastle since
                    moving there shortly after his marriage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Isaac W. Skinner and Miss Elenor A. Bowers, both of Mercersburg,
                    Pennsylvania, were married on October 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reprint of the list of jurors to serve at court in Chambersburg on Monday,
                October 28, column 1; anecdotes and incidents from the war, columns 2 and 3;
                advertisements, columns 3 and 4; story concerning a battle in western Virginia, news
                from Fortress Monroe, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.08.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
