<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.07.16">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/1/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-16">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="16">16</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.16.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; poem, column 4; proceedings of Congress, columns
                4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Message from Jeff. Davis</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the dispatch supposedly from Jefferson Davis demanding that the
                    North surrender cannot be authentic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Chivalry Returning Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If they are half as chivalrous and brave as they would have the world
                    believe them, let them return to the field and seek earnestly to meet the
                    Northern 'mud sills,' as they have contemptuously styled our working men, and
                    whose courage they have so persistantly [sic] impugned, or for ever after hide
                    their faces."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We see it stated that two South Carolina Regiments, who were in Virginia,
                        have returned to their homes, their term of enlistment having expired. If
                        the rebel soldiers from any of the seceding States ought to see the fight
                        through with, it is those from S. Carolina. After striving for 30 years to
                        produce a collision between the Northern and Southern sections of our
                        country, and when at last they have succeeded, they should at least have
                        manliness enough not to desert their friends, whom they have dragged into
                        the conflict, right in the midst of their difficulties. We should be glad to
                        hear form them when they re-inlist [sic] for of all others of the rebel
                        troops those of South Carolina we desire most to see thoroughly thrashed. If
                        they are half as chivalorous [sic] and brave as they would have the world
                        believe them, let them return to the field and seek earnestly to meet the
                        Northern "<emph rend="italic">mud sills</emph>" as they have contemptuously
                        styled our working men, and whose courage they have so persistently
                        impugned, or for ever after hide their faces. As the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Valley Spirit</emph> has been the peculiar defender of South Carolina,
                        we hope it will institute an inquiry as to this mean, dastardly conduct of
                        its friends, and report.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Dispatch scoffs at members of two South Carolina regiments who returned
                    home after their enlistment expired. The editor remarks that South Carolinians,
                    largely responsible for starting the war, should not abandon "their friends."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Col. Kelley</head>
                <origin>Wheeling Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Colonel Kelley is recovering from his injuries and will be
                    able to resume at least some of his military duties shortly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Is It Right?</head>
                <origin>Knoxville (Tenn.) Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is enough for us to know that this whole thing is in violation of law,
                    of the Constitution, and of every principle of right; that it was conceived in
                    sin, and shapen in iniquity; that is controlled, and urged forward by the very
                    worst class of men South of Mason and Dixon's Line."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes the argument that because certain former Unionists have come out
                    in favor of secession, it is futile to oppose it any longer. Asserts that the
                    question should be whether secession is right or not.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Synopsis of the Secretary of War's Report</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes the speech of Secretary Cameron, in which he pointed out that
                    instead of being embarrassed for lack of forces to put down the rebellion, the
                    government is in the position of being overwhelmed with volunteers. Over 188,000
                    volunteers have enlisted, making a total of 230,000 men when the regular army is
                    included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>War news from Virginia, Missouri, Washington, and Maryland, columns 3 and 4;
                advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.16.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Rebel Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that five rebels were conveyed through Chambersburg via rail the
                    previous morning on their way to Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Resigned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Honorable</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the resignation of the Honorable Wilson Reilly of his commission
                    as captain of the McClure Rifles due to health reasons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a regiment of the reserve corps of Pennsylvania volunteers
                    passed through Chambersburg to Greencastle, where they have camped. A second
                    regiment passed through the same night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Mr. Jason C. Woolslare, a volunteer from Pittsburgh
                    and member of Company I of the Second Regiment. Woolslare was in the care of Mr.
                    Trostle since the hospital was moved to Hagerstown. He died of brain fever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Trophies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Captain Girard, Lieutenant Enright, and fifteen men of the
                    Seventh Regiment captured three men, three horses, two rifles, one musket, two
                    revolvers, one horse pistol, and other items when they went on "a scouting
                    expedition" from their quarters near Martinsburg, Virginia. Notes that one of
                    the revolvers, a clasp off a sword belt, and an inkstand were left at the office
                    of the Dispatch so that anyone who wishes might examine them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article on skirmish in western Virginia, column 2; book column, column 2;
                advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.16.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Trogan [sic] Horse in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commends Congress for admitting loyal members from the states that have
                    declared their secession. Remarks that this policy offers added incentive to
                    Southerners to remain loyal to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Niggerless Individuals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The preponderance of the slaveholding interest of Missouri is decidedly for
                        the Union. The large slaveholders seem to realize a great truth which Col.
                        Frank Blair recently announced to one of them. He was in his quarters at the
                        Arsenal, when a gentleman from Lexington came in, and was introduced to him.
                        "I am a Union man," remarked the visitor, "but I'm pro-slavery; I own
                        niggers." "Well, Sir," replied Col. Blair, with a faint suggestion of a
                        smile upon his grim face, "You have a right to be. If a man likes negroes,
                        we don't object to that; but if you gentlemen who own negroes attempt to
                        take the State of Missouri out of the Union, in about six month you will be
                        the most 'niggerless' set of individuals that you ever heard of!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Anecdote involving Colonel Frank Blair, in which Blair tells a slaveholder
                    from Missouri that the federal government doesn't object to slave ownership. If
                    slaveholders attempt to take Missouri out of the Union, however, they will
                    shortly find themselves without their slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article involving the illness of the Pope, column 1; current prices, column 2;
                advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
