<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.11.12">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/24/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-11-12">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="12">12</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.12.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; poem, details of the capture of Lieutenant
                Colonel John H. Price of the rebel army, anecdote, column 4; article reporting that
                a new iron-clad ship is being built for the Union, which will be launched in
                December, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Election in Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"With but, probably, one exception--we believe that a decided majority of
                    the people of every Southern State was decidedly in favor of the Union--of the
                    Government, pure and simple, as it was before the rebellion was precipitated."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The result of the recent Election in Maryland, (held on Wednesday last,) is
                        most gratifying to the loyal men throughout the country. The result shows
                        that the Union sentiment predominates largely throughout the State, and even
                        in the city of Baltimore, the principal hot-bed of treason in the State, the
                        result is overwhelming in favor of the Union.</p>
                    <p>With all the eighteen Free States solid for the Union, backed by a tremendous
                        loyal sentiment in Missouri, Kentucky, East Tennessee, Western Virginia,
                        Delaware, and now by a fair expression of the sentiment of Maryland, there
                        seems to be but little hope for the success of the rebellion, and but little
                        to cause the patriot to fear for the ultimate result. It is but a question
                        of time--treason must be, will be crushed out, and our glorious Union will
                        again stand before the world more powerful, more grand, more beautiful, from
                        being abscurred [sic] by the cloud that now hangs over it, than she has ever
                        before been regarded by the world.</p>
                    <p>No effort--from cold-blooded murder to perjury--was left untried by the
                        Rebels of Maryland to drag her into the slough of secession, but all failed,
                        and to-day her voice, as expressed at the ballot-box, rings out over the
                        country, in stentorian tones, for the Constitution, the Union, and the
                        enforcement of the Laws. All honor to the intelligent freemen of Maryland.</p>
                    <p>With but, probably, one exception--we believe that a decided majority of the
                        people of every Southern State was decidedly in favor of the Union--of the
                        Government, pure and simple, as it was before the rebellion was
                        precipitated. And even now, if they could be permitted to express their
                        honest sentiments, we doubt not it would be in favor of the Union of their
                        fathers. This was never permitted, however. Force, violence, lynch-law,
                        governed and over-awed, and the ambitious, the bad, and turbulent men
                        assumed the control and proclaimed the several States out of the Union, and
                        thus forced upon the country, against the better judgment of their people,
                        the present unfortunate civil contest. It is a severe ordeal through which
                        our loved Republic is called to pass, but the future will demonstrate, that
                        the trial was for her good, as she will come out of the firey-furnace
                        disrobed of her impurities. The preservation of our Government is worth all
                        the blood and treasure and suffering that may be demanded for that purpose,
                        not only for ourselves, but for our posterity, and as an asylum for the
                        oppressed of other lands.</p>
                    <p>The result of the Election in Maryland is another assurance to the world,
                        that the people are loyal, and that the Republic is safe.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Maryland expressed a strong sentiment for the Union in the
                    recent elections. Argues that even in the Southern states that have rebelled,
                    the predominant sentiment is probably for restoring the Union, but that the
                    people are prevented from expressing this view by those who are in power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Review of the Losses</head>
                <origin>New York Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italic">Advertiser</emph> has a careful review of
                        the various skirmishes, battles and important reconnoissances, from the
                        bombardment of Sumpter to the late battle at Romney, with the most accurate
                        returns of the losses that could be obtained, the result, as figured up from
                        the table, is:</p>
                    <p>Killed. Wounded. Prisn'rs. Total. <lb/> Union forces. 969 2,041 5,384 <lb/>
                        Rebel forces, 4,049 1,604 2,808 8,461</p>
                    <p>But this shows greatly to the disadvantage of the Union side, since the
                        losses of the Rebels in many important actions are unknown, while the
                        prisoners on the Union side are largely made up of the troops surrendered by
                        Twiggs' treachery in Texas.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Statistics revealing the number of men from both Union and Confederate
                    sides who have been killed, wounded, or taken prisoner since the firing on Fort
                    Sumter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Late Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the results of the recent elections in New York, Massachusetts, New
                    Jersey, Maryland, Wisconsin, and Kansas. The vote in New York, Massachusetts,
                    and Maryland was heavily in favor of the Republican or the Union party, while
                    the vote in Kansas and Wisconsin was almost evenly divided between Democrat and
                    Republican. New Jersey was carried by the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Background of General Hunter, the successor of General Fremont, column 2;
                resolutions announced by the East Pennsylvania Eldership of the church of God
                offering its loyalty to the Union and its prayers that the Union might be restored,
                column 2; particulars of the fight at Belmont, near Columbus, Missouri, column 3;
                chronicle of the dissatisfaction caused by the removal of General Fremont, columns 3
                and 4; report that the effect of Fremont's removal has been "much exaggerated,"
                columns 4 and 5; more news from Missouri, columns 4 and 5; news from Fortress Monroe
                of the naval expedition, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The State</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Pennsylvania will pay 27 cents per pair of "good knit woolen
                    socks" that are delivered to Harrisburg. Recommends that they be gray and that
                    the socks have double heels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the resignation of Mr. J. R. Gilmore of his position as
                    superintendent of the government telegraph to enlist in Colonel Patterson's
                    Regiment of Philadelphia. He has been made a First Lieutenant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General Robert McAllen of Fannettsburg in Franklin County has
                    been authorized to form a regiment of volunteers, which will be quartered at
                    Camp Slifer until they are sent to Harrisburg sometime in the coming two weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mittens for the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides directions from the Ladies' Aid Society of Philadelphia for the
                    knitting of mittens for the soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Danfeldt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the child of a German man named Danfeldt was severely burned
                    so that recovery is unlikely. The child, along with another child, was left
                    alone briefly while his father attended church and his mother was upstairs in
                    their residence on Broad Street when the child upset a candle and his clothes
                    caught on fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From Negley's Brigade.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have been permitted to make the following extracts from a letter received
                        by the wife of an officer in Col. Stumbaugh's Regiment, now on duty in
                        Kentucky:</p>
                    <p>Camp of Negley's Brigade, P. V., <lb/> Hardin Co., (Ky.,) Oct. 24, 1861.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Dear Wife</emph>:--Well, here we are, in the midst of
                        secession, 50 miles South of Louisville, on the Louisville and Memphis Rail
                        Road. We arrived in Louisville on Monday night, remaining on the boats until
                        morning, when we disembarked and marched through the city to our Camp, at
                        Oakland, a most beautiful spot, about one mile from the city. Louisville is
                        one of the most beautiful of American Cities. The streets are very wide and
                        clean, and many of the private residences are magnificent. We were received,
                        while passing through the city, with shouts of joy, and welcomes to the "Old
                        Pennsylvania Boys." We went to camp, pitched our tents, when our Regiment
                        marched back to town, where the citizens had prepared a substantial supper.
                        Everybody appeared to do their utmost to make us comfortable. After supper
                        we returned to camp, and next morning the whole Brigade--3000--marched back
                        to the city, and were again treated to a good warm breakfast, provided by
                        the citizens.</p>
                    <p>At 4 p. m. we took the cars and moved off, no one knew whither. We traveled
                        about 50 miles and disembarked at this, our present camp. There is now,
                        within 2 1/2 miles of us, 30,000 men, and 15 miles further there is another
                        camp of some 4000 men, all good and true to the Government of our fathers.</p>
                    <p>Kentucky, we find, is largely for the Union; but before the loyal troops came
                        here the Union men wee compelled to keep quiet. Now, however, they are
                        flocking around their country's standard--the glorious old Stars and
                        Stripes--by thousands. * * *</p>
                    <p>Our pickets were within 1 1/2 miles of the Rebel camp, and saw them drilling.
                        You will thus see that we are in close proximity to our enemies. We have no
                        fears of an attack, as they are entrenching themselves, and of course expect
                        us to attack them, which we will do not until we have a sufficient force to
                        insure an easy victory.</p>
                    <p>We have been getting along finely, having had no accident since we left
                        Pittsburg. The health of the Brigade is good--there is not a severely sick
                        man in the entire command.--We have a very fine set of Staff officers, who
                        endeavor to make things as comfortable as possible.</p>
                    <p>Direct your letters to the care of Col. Stumbaugh, Negley's Brigade, P. V.,
                        Louisville, Ky.</p>
                    <p>There goes tattoo, and all lights must be extinguished. Good night.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>J. R. F.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beidell</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John M. Beidell, from near Fayetteville, and Miss Jane Durff of
                    Cleversburg in Cumberland County were married on November 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Abraham Barnhart and Miss Hannah Mary Keehner, both of Washington
                    County, Maryland, were married on November 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas Benson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Benson Seibert, 32 years of age, died on November 9 in Chambersburg.
                    He was the son of William Seibert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Continuation from page 2 of report on the naval expedition, column 1; report
                that the federal forces had taken Beaufort in South Carolina, column 1; report of
                the election and of a fire on the prairie in Kansas, column 1; advertisements,
                columns 3-5; report from Washington that federal troops have arrived at
                Coosawatchie, which is 20 miles north of Beaufort and 60 miles west of Charleston,
                column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.12.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A New Pennsylvania Cavalry Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Seventh Cavalry Regiment, which is the eightieth regiment
                    formed in Pennsylvania, is nearly ready for the field. Almost a thousand men
                    have enlisted in the regiment, which is commanded by General Wynkoop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poem, article from the New Orleans Picayune concerning the predictions of
                Nostradamus, column 1; prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns
            1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
