<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.10.11">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/20/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-11">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="11">11</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.11.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; poem, column 3; article concerning the
                capture of Mississippi City by the Union army, column 3; news from Washington
                involving the capture of an army transport by the rebels and a grand review of
                cavalry and artillery exhibited in the capital city, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that in the preliminary election returns, Mr. Nill is projected
                    to have won a majority of about 600 in Franklin County and that his overall
                    majority should be about 500 or 550 in the entire district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Voting in Camps</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Now that the election is over, we can urge a matter which we have heretofore
                        refrained from urging, lest our motives might be misconstrued: that is, the
                        repeal of the law providing for the holding of elections in the camps of the
                        Pennsylvania volunteers, on the regular election days. As it has been
                        claimed that a majority of our volunteers were Democrats, it might have been
                        pretended that we opposed the law because its operation might favor the
                        Democratic cause. The reverse proves to the be fact; for, so far as can be
                        ascertained, the Democrats, although actively canvassed, polled a much
                        smaller vote than the People's Party's men, at the election held yesterday.</p>
                    <p>But no matter who may be in the majority, the effect of the law is bad.
                        Soldiers engaged in the service of the country, with an enemy almost within
                        sight, should not be disturbed by electioneering politicians. It is evident
                        that they think so themselves, for in some regiments no polls were opened,
                        and in those where they were opened, scarcely half the men voted. This
                        proves that when men go to fight, they do not care to vote, and probably not
                        one volunteer in twenty would consider himself injured by being deprived of
                        the right of sufferage while in the army. The officers of the army, we know,
                        from the Commander-in-Chief down, condemn the law, and it was contemplated,
                        at one time, to forbid voting in the camps. But is was propably [sic]
                        thought well to try a single experiment, the opportunity being thought
                        favorable, as there was no danger of an attack from the enemy. But as it has
                        been proved that the soldiers do not set a very high value on the privilege
                        of voting while in active service, we trust that the law will be repealed at
                        the next session of the Legislature, or else that the opening of the polls
                        and the introduction of politicians into the camps will be forbidden by the
                        General in command. The effect of carrying party politics into the army
                        cannot foil to be most demoralizing.--Phila. Bulletin.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Voices an objection to allowing soldiers in camps to vote in elections,
                    because voting disturbs soldiers who are engaged in fighting for their country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of a freight train accident on the Ohio and Mississippi Railroad,
                column 2; story of a skirmish at Hatteras Inlet, column 3; news from Missouri and
                Fortress Monroe, columns 3-5; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Election Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that election day was marked by no particular incidents, and that
                    the weather was chilly in the morning, but "the sun came out very warm," causing
                    the day to be a pleasant one.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Wagon Stolen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the theft of Mr. Alexander Martin's one-horse spring wagon from the
                    alley outside his stable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cool</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that one warm day during the previous week, Mr. J. Geo. Wolf hung
                    his coat and vest on a stake while working in one of his father's fields. His
                    coat was subsequently stolen, with the thief taking care to place the papers
                    that had been in the pockets of the coat into the vest before leaving.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Suicide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that D. Watson, a middle-aged man who had previously failed in his
                    attempts to secure a position in the army, committed suicide on Sunday at the
                    Jones' House in Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Patriotic Firemen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>The firemen "risk ease and comfort, health, life and limb in their
                    disinterested efforts to save property from the devouring flames; and they are
                    among the most ready to bare their breasts to the enemies of their country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the Hope Fire Company turned out four officers and thirty
                    privates for three months' service and four officers, fifteen privates, and a
                    telegraph operator for three years' service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>An Example</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out Mr. John Monn, Sr., of Quincy township as an example to all
                    Northern men. Mr. Monn, 91 years of age, turned out at the ballot box the
                    previous Tuesday to cast his ballot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>More Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Men who do not wish to fight, should not go under either [of the men], for
                    we have an idea that both are that kind of men who would seek the place where
                    danger is the thickest."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. Jack</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoskinson</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Mr. A. Jack Brand is attempting to raise a company of
                    infantry and that Mr. J. T. Hoskinson, clothier of Chambersburg, is raising
                    either a Zouave or a Rifle company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Departure of the Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Col. F. S. Stumbaugh's Regiment left this place on Monday evening last, for
                        Pittsburgh. Owing to bad management somewhere, the soldiers were marched
                        from their encampment about four o'clock, P. M., at which time they were to
                        take the cars, but were detained at the depot in the midst of a drenching
                        rain, for two hours. The soldiers had supplied themselves with mean whisky
                        before they left, and consequently, many of them became intoxicated,
                        producing a great deal of confusion and fighting. Through the efforts of the
                        officers, a partial quiet was restored, when the cars left, bearing them
                        towards their Western destination.</p>
                    <p>A soldier named Myers, from Luzerne County, connected with this Regiment, but
                        to what Company we have not been informed, was run over by the cars when
                        near Carlisle, and terribly mangled. It is supposed that he jumped from the
                        train, when the accident occurred. He was discovered the next morning by the
                        Freight train, which passed over him, and on going back to pick him up, he
                        was found to be cold, which is evidence that he met his death the evening
                        before. His remains were taken to Carlisle and interred.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the soldiers from Colonel F. S. Stumbaugh's Regiment left
                    Chambersburg on Monday evening, bound for Pittsburgh, but after marching from
                    their encampment around 4 o'clock, they waited for two hours in the pouring rain
                    before their train arrived. Some of the soldiers became intoxicated, and one was
                    "terribly mangled" when he was run over by the cars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Not True</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The report that Col. Knipe was shot by a soldier, turns out to be a hoax,
                        which probably owes its origin to the following:</p>
                    <p>A supposed young man, of feminine manners and appearance, belonging to the
                        regiment, was detailed as hospital nurse, where, having control of the
                        supplies, he become [sic] somewhat addicted to an indiscriminate use of the
                        wines, and in an unguarded movement divulged the fact that she was a female,
                        the wife, it is said, of one of the privates. Finding her sex discovered,
                        and learning that she was to be discharged, she managed to obtain the
                        countersign, passed the guard, and made her way, still in male attire, to a
                        neighboring farm-house. She had her hand bound up with a handkerchief, and
                        begged some camphor to put upon it. She then stated that she was the son of
                        Col. Knipe, that he had been assassinated by a private, a friend of Lanagan,
                        and she had received the wound in attempting to save the Colonel's life. She
                        wanted a horse and buggy to pursue the murderer to Rockville, where she knew
                        he had gone. The unsuspecting farmer conveyed her to Rockville, upon promise
                        of remuneration; but on arriving there she gave him the slip, and has not
                        since been heard of, except, perhaps, by the reporter who so ingeniously
                        furnished the press with the information referred to.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that the rumor concerning the shooting of Colonel Knipe was a
                    hoax, probably perpetrated by a woman on the run from the authorities of Colonel
                    Knipe's regiment. The woman had pretended to be a man in order to be near her
                    husband, but was discovered and ran away.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Curt. Lowry and Miss Lydia Myers, both of Quincy township, were married
                    on October 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Henry Gushart and Miss Sarah M. Swartz, both of St. Thomas township,
                    were married on October 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.11.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
