<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.10.01">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/19/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-01">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="01">01</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Issue number 41, printed September 27, 1861, is missing.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The End of Breckinridge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In himself he is of no consequence, but the shameful defection of a man so
                    petted and caressed by public favor will bring a pang of regret to thousands of
                    honest Northern hearts, as they recall the delusion under which they were led to
                    give him their suffrages in last November.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is reported, we presume on good authority, says the N. Y. <emph
                            rend="italic">Tribune</emph> of Saturday last, that John C.
                        Breckinridge, of Kentucky, has at length gone over to the enemy, and joined
                        the Rebels who are seeking to destroy the Republic, and who, from the
                        beginning of their treasonable movement have had his secret sympathy and
                        countenance. To the country and to the Government his departure is no great
                        loss. To the great majority of loyal citizens the name of John C.
                        Breckinridge is the symbol, not of a great or eminently able man, but of a
                        small and commonplace politician, a mediocre lawyer, and of a soldier who,
                        while in service in Mexico, never faced any other enemies than the opposing
                        counsel in the prosecutions which he assisted the redoubtable Gen. Pillow in
                        bringing against his associate and superior officers.--Born with a gold
                        spoon in his mouth, of one of the most opulent and influential families of
                        Kentucky, of pleasing manners and appearance, and of insatiable ambition, he
                        has been pushed forward in public life more rapidly than any other man in
                        our history. Before the age of forty, an age earlier than which high public
                        position is rarely attained in this country, he has been twice a Member of
                        the House of Representatives, had been Senator and Vice President of the
                        United States, and at length the candidate of a great party for the
                        Presidency itself. In all these posts, with all these opportunities he has
                        done nothing, literally nothing. Outside of his native State no man
                        remembers, no man can recall a speech or an act of Mr. Breckinridge which
                        was striking or important enough to take a hold, however feeble, of the
                        public mind. The act by which he will be hereafter best known and longest
                        remembered, is the act of open treason which he has just committed. In
                        himself he is of no consexuence [sic], but the shameful defection of a man
                        so petted and caressed by public favor will bring a pang of regret to
                        thousands of honest Northern hearts, as they recall the delusion under which
                        they were led to give him their suffrages in last November.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the news that John C. Breckenridge of Kentucky has gone over to
                    the enemy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; article describing the siege of Lexington,
                column 1; news from Kentucky, reports of skirmishes in Virginia, column 4; other war
                news, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Nill vs. Mr. Reilly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Endorses Mr. Nill for the position of President Judge while questioning the
                    loyalty of Mr. Reilly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Judgeship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 19th ult., the Conferees, representing the <emph rend="italic">Day
                            Book</emph> Democracy of the Sixteenth Judicial District, composed of
                        the Counties of Franklin, Fulton, Bedford and Somerset, met in Bloody Run,
                        and placed in nomination Wilson Reilly, Esq., of Chambersburg, as their
                        candidate for the President Judgeship.</p>
                    <p>On Tuesday last, the 24th ult., the Conferees of the Union Party of the same
                        District nominated the Hon. James Nill, of Chambersburg, as Mr. Reilly's
                        competitor.</p>
                    <p>The Conferees of Somerset failed to meet the other Conferees, but they
                        acquiesced in the action of the Conference, and Mr. Nill and Mr. Reilly now
                        stand before the voters of the District as candidates for President Judge
                        for the next ten years, and it requires no prophet to foretell who will be
                        the choice of the people.</p>
                    <p>We presume it is unnecessary for us to draw a comparison between these two
                        gentlemen, as to their qualifications for the position for which they have
                        been selected, or as regards their merits and demerits. They are so well
                        known to the people of the District, and especially to those residing in
                        Franklin and Fulton Counties, that an attempt on our part to do so, would
                        seem almost as foolish as would the act be of introducing members of a
                        community to each other who are in daily communication and engaged in daily
                        business transactions.</p>
                    <p>The people are deeply interested in having the right kind of man to preside
                        over their Courts. A President Judge is only chosen every ten years, unless
                        a vacancy should be created by resignation, death, or otherwise, and to have
                        a man fastened upon the Bench for the next ten years, who, in many ways, may
                        be unfitted for the position, would be a blunder which the people might have
                        great reason to regret.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Nill is a man of fine legal attainments, and is an experienced Lawyer,
                        having had a most extensive practice at our Bar for the last thirty years.
                        He possesses a cool head and a well balanced judgment, and is not moved to
                        rashness and excitement by every trivial cause or obstacle. He is not
                        capricious or whimisical [sic]. He is a man of dignified mien and of the
                        most correct moral deportment. The Bench and other similar positions, should
                        be filled by just such men as Mr. Nill. While the duties of the position
                        would be ably discharged, there would be no detraction from the dignity that
                        should be, and is, accorded by the people to the wearer of the judicial
                        ermine.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Nill is the man for the place, and the voters of the District should see
                        to it that he is elevated to the Bench beyond a preadventure. The people
                        have a deep interest in the kind of man who is to dispense Law and Justice
                        in their Courts the next decade of years, and while we would not detract
                        from his opponent, we feel assured that the people will very readily
                        indicate by their votes on <emph rend="italic">next Tuesday</emph>, that
                        James Nill is the man of their choice for President Judge. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the qualifications of James Nill to be President Judge without
                    calling into question the qualifications of his competitor, Wilson Reilly, Esq.,
                    for the job.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Voters Should Remember</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds voters that the ballot for President Judge must be placed in a
                    separate box. Relates that the Dispatch has printed the ticket with the name of
                    judge at the bottom so that it may be easily detached.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Under His True Colors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that Breckenridge, who defected to the South, was the candidate
                    endorsed by the Valley Spirit for President in the previous election. Expresses
                    little surprise at Breckenridge's defection.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Next Tuesday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let every voter who feels an interesting the stability of the Government,
                    the perpetuity of the Union and the maintenance of the Constitution, go to the
                    Polls and support the Union ticket."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds voters that Tuesday is election day and urges them to vote for the
                    Union ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>What Are We Waiting For?</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Many among the uninitiated--and this class is in the great majority--echo the
                        question which we use as a caption. In view of the great armies sternly
                        regarding each other at Washington, the Rebel progress in Missouri, and the
                        movements in Kentucky, the curiosity becomes sharpened almost to madness;
                        the suspense lies like an incubus upon the mind. What are we waiting for?
                        Why is not some movement made from Washington?</p>
                    <p>Let us give a few answers to this manifold question. We are waiting to
                        recover entirely from the disaster of Manassas; to re-inspirit the new
                        troops there panic-struck, and to try them in <emph rend="italic"
                        >affairs</emph> and reconnoissances, such as that of Lewinsville, before
                        they are again subjected to the "leaden rain and iron hail" of a great
                        battle. "We must have no more Bull Run affairs."</p>
                    <p>We are waiting to discipline a vast army, before improperly organized,
                        lacking bone and muscle; lax for want of a system of <emph rend="italic"
                            >army-corps</emph>, divisions and brigades, with permanant [sic]
                        commanders. This is to be done, now that the proper appointments have been
                        made, by constant drills of the company as skirmishers; of the battalion, by
                        the new and rapid French system embodied in the United States Infantry
                        Tactics; by the army corps, under the Brigadiers, in <emph rend="italic"
                            >evolutions of the line</emph>. This is being done, silently but
                        vigorously, everywhere, under the immediate direction of experienced and
                        indefatigable Generals.</p>
                    <p>We are waiting to increase our artillery and and [sic] perfect the practice;
                        to place heavy guns in the beautiful chain of forts stretching from
                        Alexandria to the Chain Bridge; and to multiply light batteries until they
                        literally swarm in the battalion intervals.</p>
                    <p>We are waiting for cavalry--at first under-valued--at all times requiring
                        toil, time and expense to provide. We were without that expense to provide.
                        We were without that arm; McClellan's eye saw at once the great disparity
                        and the great want. The Rebels abound in a superior cavalry--a true modern
                        Centaur, intelligent men on superb horses; Manassas told the story of their
                        value. We must have cavalry equally good, as soon as possible. We are
                        waiting for it.</p>
                    <p>We are waiting to let diversions on the Southern coast operate magnetically
                        in Virginia. They are now being felt; and those secretly projected on a
                        greater scale, with the blessing of Providence, shall echo like thunderbolts
                        between the Rappahannock and the Potomac. Add to this the coming frosts,
                        with the rigors of a Northern winter; their want of supplies--Virginia is
                        nearly eaten up--their want of clothing; their home-sickness, which will be
                        another evil laid at the door of <emph rend="italic">States'
                        Rights</emph>;--we are waiting for these, and we see the incipient signs
                        already. In a word, we are using every moment of the passing time with the
                        utmost diligence; and those who cannot see the workings of the intricate
                        machinery must be content to hope and to put their faith in the genius,
                        industry, valor and endurance of General McClellan, whose plans are forming
                        and formed, and who will move when we need wait no longer, with secrecy,
                        celerity and success.--<emph rend="italic">Phila. Inq.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers answers to those people who ask what the government is waiting for
                    to unleash its military forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Union ticket, column 1; anecdote, column 4; advertisements, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.01.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Fast Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments that the day of fasting declared by the President for the previous
                    Thursday was "universally observed" by residents of Chambersburg, who refrained
                    from conducting business and attended church services.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Terrific Storm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Daum</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that a "terrific" wind and rain storm passed through Chambersburg
                    the previous Friday evening, causing a chimney and a tree to fall on the
                    property of Mr. Jacob Daum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the arrival in Chambersburg of more detachments of troops, which
                    are to be incorporated into Colonel F. S. Stumbaugh's regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>J. Allison Eyster, Esq., Released</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have the gratification to announce, that our respected townsmen, J. A.
                        Eyster, Esq., whose arrest by the rebels we announced at the time it
                        occurred, and who has been held a prisoner at Richmond, Va., ever since,
                        during the early part of last week was released, and arrived at home on
                        Saturday last.</p>
                    <p>While in Richmond he was imprisoned in a large Tobacco Warehouse for some
                        five weeks, with Messrs Kurtz, Walker, McCumsey and Brotherton, of
                        Waynesboro', whose capture we also announced. He was then removed to the
                        County Prison, where he was detained up until the hour of his release.</p>
                    <p>Mr. E. looks about as natural as ever, but somewhat thinner in flesh. He says
                        he was treated kindly, as are all the prisoners, as far as his knowledge
                        goes, that are detained at Richmond, of whom it is supposed, there must be
                        some 2500. Many of them are now being transferred to points farther South.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Eyster was arrested and detained as a spy, and would have been discharged
                        long ago could he have obtained a hearing before the proper authorities. It
                        was a mere accident that he finally did succeed in having his case brought
                        up, and no evidence being adduced against him, he was discharged on the
                        spot. He was furnished a pass to Norfolk, from whence, under a flag of
                        truce, with a number of other discharged prisoners, he was sent to Fortress
                        Monroe. From there he embarked for Baltimore, and is now at home, where he
                        has received the congratulations of hundreds of his fellow-citizens, at his
                        fortunate escape from the philistines.</p>
                    <p>The other parties we have named above, were not so fortunate as Mr. Eyster.
                        It appears they are charged with furnishing the federal troops with supplies
                        while on the "sacred soil" of Virginia, and they, doubtless, will be
                        obtained until the close of the troubles.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that J. Allison Eyster was released from prison in Richmond, where
                    he was being held by the rebels under suspicion of being a spy, and returned
                    home the previous Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>I. O. O. F.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monat</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Grath</ln>
                        <fn>T. J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earhart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClenegan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the election of officers by the Chambersburg Lodge of the I. O.
                    O. F. W. S. Everett will serve as Representative to the Grand Lodge, as
                    Secretary, and as Lecture Master; Jno. Monat was elected N. Grand; T. J. C.
                    M'Grath will serve as V. Grand; Assistant Secretary will be G. W. Bitner;
                    Treasurer is John Earhart; Hall Keeper will be William Robison; William
                    McClenegan was appointed Conductor; and William Kennedy, Esq., serves as the
                    Sitting Past Grand of the Lodge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bad Orthography</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Errors in spelling, therefore, amount to nothing, and like other great
                    men, we may be, and doubtless are, very deficient in this respect. But our bad
                    spelling does not relieve the editor of The Times from the inconsistant [sic],
                    inexcusable position he occupies with regard to his professed Union sentiments
                    and the support he is giving to candidates of doubtful loyalty."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Dispatch editor defends the paper against charges by the Times of bad
                    spelling by arguing that spelling is not very important.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michaels</ln>
                        <fn>Willliam B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William B. Michaels of Chambersburg and Miss Ann Catharine Thompson of
                    Williamsport, Maryland, were married in Chambersburg on September 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William Keller and Miss Annie Ward were married on September 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Adam Yost and Miss Elizabeth Kahler, of Cumberland County were married
                    on August 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Talbert</ln>
                        <fn>Tilman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bohn</ln>
                        <fn>Rosanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Tilman Talbert and Miss Rosanna Bohn, both of Franklin County, were
                    married on August 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Alrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Alrick Fletcher, aged 8 months, died on September 27 in Chambersburg.
                    She was the daughter of Mary V. and J. W. Fletcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Daniel Knepper, 70 years of age, died in Quincy township on September
                    20.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2, 3, and 5; war news from Washington, column
            4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.01.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
