<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.07.23">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/2/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-23">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="26">26</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>The first part of the address given by the Honorable Joseph Holt that concludes
            in this issue is printed in the issue published July 23.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.26.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; continuation of the address given by Joseph
                Holt at Louisville, Kentucky, columns 3-5; proceedings of Congressional extra
                session, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.26.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The First Reverse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that the battle at Manassas Junction on July 20 was not a
                    defeat, but was the first time the federal army has been compelled to withdraw
                    their forces. Commends federal troops for the small losses of men compared to
                    those lost by the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Major General Patterson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It appears to be rather unpopular in certain quarters, for newspaper editors
                        to criticize the actions, or rather the want of action, of any of our
                        Military gentlemen, and whenever one of the aforesaid know-nothing-about
                        -war editors presumes to the audacity of venting his thoughts upon such
                        subjects, some others who "acknowledge the corn," quickly open their
                        batteries upon him. At the risk of being "blown up" we also must have our
                        little say, and will preface it with a telegram which appeard [sic] in
                        several of the Philadelphia papers, as follows:--</p>
                    <p>"It is vaguely reported that General Patterson's Division arrived in the
                        vicinity of Manassas this morning, and commenced an attack on the rebel
                        force. He was within twenty-five miles of the battle-ground yesterday, and
                        the exhausted condition of his men prevented him from coming to the aid of
                        General McDowel."</p>
                    <p>Now, we do not intend to contradict this nonsensical telegram, nor to ask why
                        he was not there. The first has been done already, and we can answer the
                        other by saying that he had no business there. But we do ask, why did he
                        allow Gen. Johnson to go there? Is this the 'bloodless victory' he told his
                        men he should achieve? Gen. Johnson left Winchester with 30,000 men leaving
                        5,000 behind. Why did not General Patterson harrass [sic] his retreat, as
                        any good General could have done, and thus either so engaged him as to have
                        compelled his presence at Winchester, or at least cut off the communications
                        of a large portion of his army? A review of the pranks of this
                        take-part-in-the-chase-at-Cerro-Gordo General, looks to us very much like
                        either cowardice or sympathy with the rebellious cause. The Philadelphia
                            <emph rend="italic">Inquirer</emph>, a few days ago, asked its readers
                        to look at what General Patterson had done, and then, in most bitter irony,
                        we suppose, told them. </p>
                    <p>Had a written agreement, drawn up by Jeff. Davis himself, between Gen.
                        Patterson and Gen. Johnson, been regularly signed, sealed and delivered,
                        containing full stipulations respecting the method to be pursued by both,
                        allowing Patterson the eclat of having served as a General in the Union
                        cause, acted bravely in battle, retired at the expiration of his time with
                        honor, &amp;c., &amp;c., and at the same time avoid cutting off Gen.
                        Johnson's communications with Gen. Beauregard at Manassas Junction, and
                        permit him to slip through his fingers and unite with Beauregard at the
                        proper time, such an instrument could not have been drawn by Mr. J. Davis
                        more to his own liking than the farce enacted by this
                        forced-to-show-his-colors General. May the race of such Generals be very
                        soon extinct.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Dispatch questions the wisdom, the bravery, and the loyalty of General
                    Patterson for failing to cut off the lines of communication between General
                    Johnson and General Beauregard at Manassas Junction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Breckinridge Journals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> devotes nearly the whole of one
                        of its columns to us, thirteen lines of which is original, and which we do
                        not consider worth noticing, except to say that, if the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Spirit</emph> had desired to make an honest statement it would, with
                        our article of the 12th have quoted that of the 23d, having the same caption
                        in which we quote part of a letter from Mr. Cessna himself, or not have
                        published anything about it. After quoting our article the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> copies about half a column from the Bedford
                            <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph>, another sheet of about the same
                        calibre and patriotic sentiments, which, as their article appeared before
                        our explanation, we will answer very briefly:</p>
                    <p>1.--The article in our columns was handed to us for publication, and was
                        written by a reliable gentleman who received the information, respecting Mr.
                        Cessna, from a <emph rend="italic">Breckinridge Democrat</emph> of Fulton
                        County, who, with curses upon Mr. Cessna, related the substance of the
                        article, in the presence of this gentleman and several others. </p>
                    <p>2.--We love truth-telling, clean-worded journals, and of course the <emph
                            rend="italic">Gazette</emph> professes to belong to that class, and in
                        "Nailing our Falsehood," has shown due zeal, f not any brilliant acquirement
                        of knowledge. We profess to hold the principles of the Republican Party. We
                        believe them right. </p>
                    <p>3.--The resolutions of that convention were strictly in accordance with the
                        Breckinridge Party Platform, with the present views of Mr. Breckinridge, and
                        just what Jeff. David &amp; Co. desire all parties and conventions in
                        the North to pass. They agreed with the doctrine of "Let us alone."</p>
                    <p>4.--Mr. Cessna was a member of the Democratic Party, and held to the
                        doctrines of Mr. Douglas, honestly, we suppose; he was, therefore, right in
                        supporting him.--We, as honestly, opposed those doctrines, and therefore, as
                        rightly opposed those doctrines, and therefore, as rightly opposed the
                        election of Mr. Douglas. Where mere opinions of political policy are
                        concerned, we oppose the coercion of any man.</p>
                    <p>5.--Respecting the minding of our own business, that is what we are trying to
                        do; and part of that business is, to expose, and hold up for general
                        condemnation, all traitorous acts and influences, of individuals, assemblies
                        and public journals, within the limits of our knowledge, and to the extent
                        of our sphere.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Dispatch defends itself against charges by the Valley Spirit that the
                    Dispatch issued false statements with regard to Mr. Cessna and the Bedford
                    Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen. Patterson's Column</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our issue of the 21st, we gave the organization of Gen. Patterson's
                        column. Since that time several important changes have been made, as
                        follows:</p>
                    <p>Gen. Patterson's term having expired, the position is to be occupied by Maj.
                        Gen. Banks.</p>
                    <p>A 3d Division has been added, Maj. General C. W. Sandford commanding,
                        comprising two Brigades, the 7th, Col. Stone acting Brig. General,
                        consisting of</p>
                    <p>1st. Reg. N. H. Vol., Col. M. W. Tappan;<lb/> 9th " N. Y. S. M., " G. W.
                        Stiles; <lb/> 26th " Pa. Vol. " H. S. Cake; <lb/> 17th " " " (Artil.) " F.
                        E. Patterson, besides a New York State Militia Battery, and one Company of
                        Dist. of Columbia Volunteers. </p>
                    <p>The 8th Brigade, Col. D. Butterfield commanding, consisting of</p>
                    <p>5th Reg. N. Y. S. M., Lieut. Col. L. Berger; <lb/> 12th " " " " " W. G.
                        Ward;<lb/> 19th " " Vol., Maj. Ladlie; <lb/> 28th " " " Col. D. Donnelly;
                        <lb/> 2d " Mass. " Col. G. H. Gordon. </p>
                    <p>The 2nd Division, under Gen. Keim, has been reformed into three Brigades
                        instead of two, as before, each Brigade comprising but three Regiments. The
                        new Brigade is numbered 6th, Col. J. J. Abercrombie commanding, consisting
                        of the 11th Pa., 1st Wis. and the 11th Ind., Col. Wallace. The 14th, 15th
                        and 24th Pa. Regiments, form the 5th Brigade.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes changes in the organization of General Patterson's column, which has
                    been taken over by Major General Banks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Sabbath</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>While we do not hold to non-resistance upon the Sabbath, or any other day,
                        nor believe that, the Sabbath can be observed with the same quietude and in
                        the same manner in the army as when in our own peaceful homes, we do
                        believe, that the Sabbath might be observed as becomingly in the army as out
                        of it, and that, but few circumstances can be found to justify an attack
                        upon an enemy upon that day. Whether it necessarily follows, that the
                        attacking party is generally worsted, or not, certain it is, that our forces
                        attacked the rebels on Sunday at Bull's Run, and if not worsted, not only
                        did they fail to gain their point, but lost the position they had gained the
                        day before. We are not inclined to be superstitious, but we firmly believe
                        in the overruling hand of a Divine Providence, who will not suffer iniquity
                        to go unpunished. Our cause is just and righteous, and must finally prevail;
                        but we shall be scourged for past national sins, and it behooves us to guard
                        well, that the continued commission of others does not protract the scourge.
                        God has said, "Him that honoreth me, I will honor," and upon this, we would
                        have all; and especially all in authority, everywhere to reflect.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Union army for attacking the enemy at Bull Run on a Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Latest News by the Mails!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the battle as it continued on Sunday, July 20.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Particular incidents that occurred during the battle at Bull Run, taken from
                the Washington National Republican, columns 3 and 4; brief articles from Kansas City
                and Baltimore, column 5; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Return of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that five or six Pennsylvania regiments have passed through
                    Chambersburg in the previous day or two. They are on their way to Harrisburg
                    because their three months of service has expired. Most are expected to
                    re-enlist after a visit at home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Oats Crop</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that lack of rain will cause the early sown oats not to be over an
                    average yield. However, the recent rain, according to the opinion of farmers,
                    should make the crop heavier than usual in Franklin County. In addition, unless
                    a sustained drought occurs, the corn should yield a fine crop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Passes the word from the Harrisburg Telegraph that the clothing recently
                    furnished to Pennsylvania troops was of excellent quality. The Dispatch commends
                    the improvement and expresses the hope that the state's volunteers will "go
                    forth equally well equipped in all other respects."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Glad to See Him</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the visit to the Dispatch office on Wednesday of Mr. James L. Gaff,
                    who was previously reported to have been hanged by the rebels in Virginia. Gaff
                    said that he had feared many times for his life while a captive in rebel hands.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Extraordinary Yield!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Estimates from the yield of one small farmer that wheat crops could yield
                    the "astonishing quantity" of 201 bushels to the acre.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>Lillie Allice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lillie Allice McElwain, aged 2 years and 6 months, died on July 23 after a
                    painful and lingering illness. Lillie Allice was the daughter of Andrew and Mary
                    Jane McElwain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullenberger</ln>
                        <fn>William Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Henry Sullenberger, aged 5 months, died on July 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.26.04">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>John Brown and the Traitors</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Evening Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reader puts forth the theory that Southerners looking to unite the South
                    against the North and overthrow the government put John Brown up to the raid on
                    Harper's Ferry. The letter credits Henry Wise in particular for urging Brown's
                    action to show the South that Northerners wanted to compel their slaves to rise
                    up against them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-5; prices current, column 2</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
