<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.09.17">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/17/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-09-17">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="17">17</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.17.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Drunken Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New Orleans <emph rend="italic">True Delta</emph> of the 27th has these
                        two paragraphs in its "Home Department:"</p>
                    <p>"We know not why it is so, but the fact cannot be disputed that drunken women
                        are now more plentiful in this city than we ever knew them to be before. An
                        evening or two since, we saw three fearful cases within the cases within the
                        course of as many hours. The first one was taken to the Second District
                        lock-up, and report said that, when sober, she bore the reputation of being
                        a decent woman. She was so completely powerless that every muscle was
                        ralaxed [sic] and her will had no more control over them than over inanimate
                        matter. The sight was truly disgusting, and in her drunken idiocy an infant
                        was not more helpless.</p>
                    <p>The second case was in the Third District, and the victim was a young and
                        really beautiful woman. Her dress was neat and clean. When brought in she
                        was placed on the floor of the lock-up, and so completely insensible was she
                        that we felt her pulse in order to be assured that the object before us was
                        still "breathing clay," and at the time a thought arose that she had been
                        plied with some deadly drug in order to the accomplishment of some fearful
                        wrong."</p>
                    <p>A correspondent of a Northern paper says:--I "know why it is." The simple
                        truth might well be told. Secession debauches both males and females
                        wherever its infection spreads. Women who can't respect their country can't
                        respect themselves. Fair woman and tender babies, in the atmosphere of that
                        loathsome treason which now pervades the South, unless fortified against it
                        by the antidote of better teaching, become morally rotten. If the present
                        state of things continue a year longer, women and children will be picking
                        each other's pockets and cutting each other's throats in the once refined
                        Crescent City. Secession change angelss [sic] into demons. It would make a
                        man murder his mother.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints part of a story from the New Orleans True Delta stating the
                    opinion that there have been more drunken women in New Orleans at present "than
                    we have ever known them to be before." The Dispatch argues that it is secession
                    that causes women, and men, to "become morally rotten."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; war news from Washington, Louisville,
                Chicago, Fortress Monroe, St. Louis, Baltimore, and Sandy Hook, columns 4 and
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.17.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Dilema [sic]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We should first know whether we have a Government, and when that is
                    certain--when peace is restored and the Union saved--it will be time enough for
                    us at least, to assume our party position, but not before; and we think no lover
                    of this country would encourage party organizations an hour sooner."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our somewhat amiable friend of <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph>, is in a
                        dilema [sic]. He is just now engaged in the interesting effort of trying to
                        "carry water on both shoulders," and like many others before him, who have
                        tried to please every body by a similar course, in the end he will find that
                        he has <emph rend="italic">wet himself</emph>!</p>
                    <p>The editor of <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph> makes great pretentions
                        [sic] of devotion to the Union, and yet is found in communion with its
                        enemies.--We judge him out of his own mouth. He attempts to rebuke us for
                        denouncing a portion of the Democracy of the County as <emph rend="italic"
                            >Day-Book</emph> Democrats--advocates of Compromise and Peace with the
                        Rebels; and in the same issue he lampoons them quite as severely as we ever
                        did. Listen to him: </p>
                    <p>"Of all the quacks and humbugs of the age, these Peace men take the lead. * *
                        * This cry of 'Peace, Peace' then means the recognition of the Southern
                        Confederacy.--The man who asks this Government to lay down its arms, * * *
                        is either a <emph rend="italic">very great</emph> traitor, or a <emph
                            rend="italic">very cowardly fool</emph>!"</p>
                    <p>In view of the terrible dangers that threaten the very existence [sic] of our
                        Government, the Republicans of Franklin County--although in the
                        majority--magnanimously came forward, as they did elsewhere, in States and
                        Counties, and proposed to obliterate, for the time being, all party lines
                        and distinctions, and unite with the Democracy in forming Tickets to be
                        composed of men who have heretofore acted with the different parties. While
                        we rejoice to say, that a large number of the truly loyal men of the
                        Democratic party heartily embraced the proposition, and, with the
                        Republicans, have formed such a ticket, the editor of <emph rend="italic"
                            >The Times</emph> has given the <emph rend="italic">lie</emph> to his
                        professions of love for the Union and the maintenance of the Government, by
                        refraining to co-operate with the movement the real object of which is, to
                        heal divisions and unite the whole people in the support of the objects
                        which he professes to cherish so dearly. He not only does not fraternize
                        with the Union party of the County, but he is found to be supporting the
                        regular Democratic Ticket, composed in part at least, of men whom he <emph
                            rend="italic">knows</emph> to be open, avowed and uncompromising enemies
                        of the War--men who are crying "Peace, "Peace," and who, per consequence,
                        according to this very editor of <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph>, must
                        be "very great traitors, or very cowardly fools!" </p>
                    <p>There is an inconsistency in the course pursued by the editor of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Times</emph>. If he is unconditionally for the Union, he
                        must not support "Peace" candidates, whom he styles "very great traitors" or
                        "very cowardly fools"--he must come out from among "the foul party." He
                        cannot blow hot and cold with the same breath. From a pure spring does not
                        issue forth both pure and salt water. He must cease his prating about the
                        wickedness of the rebellion and the glories of the Union, or he must turn
                        his battery against the common enemy, wherever found, in the vicinity of
                        Washington or on the Democratic Ticket at the head of his paper. In
                        characterizing these "Peace candidates" of <emph rend="italic">The
                        Times</emph> as "<emph rend="italic">Day Book Democrats</emph>," the editor
                        charges us with making "a wholesale onslaught" "upon the Democratic party of
                        Franklin county." We deny the charge. We have heretofore asserted, as we now
                        believe, that the Douglas wing of the Democratic party, not only in this,
                        but in every other county, with but few exceptions, are quite as loyal in
                        their devotion to the great cause as are the Republicans, and will continue
                        to be if they are not misled by such timid, partizan sheets as <emph
                            rend="italic">The Times</emph>. It will not do for our neighbor to point
                        to the course of "M'Clellan, Dix, Butler, and hundreds of other leading
                        men," or endeavor to hide himself and his Compromising, Peace candidates
                        under their mantle, until he and they give evidence of as pure a patriotism
                        as they exhibit. These men have, unlike the editor of <emph rend="italic"
                            >The Times</emph>, discarded party organizations, party lines and party
                        candidates and for the purpose of harmonizing the people in a common effort
                        to save the country, council a union of all parties in one, for the time
                        being, or until the danger is passed. Only on Thursday last, Gen. Butler,
                        one of the very men to whom <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph> refers us,
                        in a speech at Lowell, Mass., used the following language.</p>
                    <p>We have a country torn at the present hour by intestine war, and until the
                        country is put in peace, in quiet, there must be NO PARTY and NO THOUGHT OF
                        PARTY. No Compromise, no yielding, nothing but the strong arm, until the
                        glorious flag of the Union floats over every inch of territory which belongs
                        to the United States of America.</p>
                    <p>We agree with Gen. Butler. This is no time for "party." We should first know
                        whether we have a Government, and when that it certain--when peace is
                        restored and the Union saved--it will be time enough for us at least, to
                        assume our party position, but not before; and we think no lover of his
                        country would encourage party organizations an hour sooner.</p>
                    <p>We commend the sentiments of the following eloquent burst of true patriotic
                        devotion which fell from the lips of another prominent Democrat, Hon. Daniel
                        S. Dickinson of N. Y., which are the concluding remarks of a speech he
                        delivered in Ithaca, N. Y., a few days ago.</p>
                    <p>"For myself, I am enlisted for this great war--rage how it may--terminate how
                        it will. Give me poverty, stripes and chains, give me abject misery and
                        distress, give me bereavement, let my heart be wrung by every emotion that
                        can torture and agonize man, make me a wanderer in the earth, and give me an
                        ignoble death rather than permit my country to perish. Sooner than that
                        should be done, in the language of Emmet, I would raze every house, burn
                        every blade of grass, and the last entrenchment of Liberty shall be my
                        grave. No, my fellow-citizens, let our watchword be, our county, our beloved
                        country!</p>
                    <p>If the heart and soul of the editor of <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph>,
                        and those with whom he now cooperates, were imbued with such feelings and
                        sentiments, it would be an easy matter for him to discard, at this time, all
                        party organizations and distinctions, and to unite heartily in the great
                        Union movement that is now cementing all real loyal men in one solid
                        phalanx.</p>
                    <p>But we are pained to say, that does not appear to be the case. His watchword
                        is not that of the patriotic Dickinson--"our country, our beloved
                        country"--but "our party, our beloved party." Until <emph rend="italic">The
                            Times</emph> forsake its evil company, it must partake of the odium
                        which naturally attaches to that company. "Birds of a feather flock
                        together." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rebukes the Times for denouncing those Democrats who want peace, but then
                    refusing to support the Union party and backing candidates who advocate
                    compromise with the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Fight near Lewinsville, Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the government's reconnoitering force was fired upon,
                    including the 79th Regiment, and that two men were killed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Impressment of Women in Memphis</head>
                <origin>Memphis Appeal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the Common Council of the city of Memphis considered
                    impressing women into service in hospitals, because there exists a severe
                    shortage of nurses to care for the soldiers there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Pecuniary Advantage of Enlisting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Congress has raised the pay of volunteers to $13 per month,
                    or $156 per year, plus a $42 allowance for clothing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The National Finances</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that from the figures listed in the North American, it is clear
                    that the expenditures of the United States government will not exceed by much
                    the ordinary peace-time expenses of some European governments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports from Baltimore the arrest of the mayor of the city, an editor of
                    the Exchange newspaper, the editor of the South newspaper, a state senator, and
                    eleven delegates from the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Union ticket, column 1; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.17.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Healthy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that of the 8,000 soldiers stationed at Camp Curtin, Harrisburg,
                    "scarcely a single one" is undergoing medical treatment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Promoted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the promotion of Lieutenant-Colonel Campbell of the Pennsylvania
                    Artillery Regiment to Colonel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Battle at Hand</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a telegraph dispatch indicates that a "fearful and bloody"
                    battle at Washington is expected any hour.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Arrived</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the arrival in Chambersburg the previous Friday of a company of
                    soldiers from Fulton County. The soldiers marched to Camp Slifer. They will be
                    connected with the regiment that is currently being formed by Colonel F. S.
                    Stumbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Property Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the sale of property from the estate of C. Shoup, deceased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Goods for the Rebels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges the citizens of Waynesborogh, Greencastle, and Mercersburg to look
                    out for merchandise moving in wagons from Baltimore to Virginia. Suggests that
                    committees be appointed at these locations to search all suspicious wagons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Blankets and Stockings for the Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>R. C. Hale, Quartermaster General of the State, issued an order at
                        Harrisburg, under date of the 10th, inst., in which it is said that Blankets
                        and Stockings for 30,000 soldiers are needed for the coming winter.</p>
                    <p>He requests that all Factories, capable of making even a single Blanket,
                        should be put in operation, and to whom liberal contracts will be given.</p>
                    <p>Blankets should be wool, grey; 7 ft. long by 5 ft. 6 inches wide, and weight,
                        full five pounds, with the letters V. P. in black, four inches long, in the
                        centre of each blanket.</p>
                    <p>Here is a chance for the Factories of our County to obtain employment, for
                        which they will be fairly compensated,</p>
                    <p>Stockings will also be needed the coming winter--half hose or socks, good
                        size, one-fourth of a pound each. Let every wife, mother and sister knit one
                        or more pairs.</p>
                    <p>The Quartermaster suggests that associations be formed in each county, with a
                        treasurer at the county-seat, with whom the stockings can be deposited, and
                        forwarded to the military store at Harrisburg. The United States contract
                        price, twenty-five cts. per pair, will be paid to each county treasurer, and
                        thus a fund can be raised to supply the wants of the volunteer families, to
                        which every patriotic woman in the State can contribute her share.</p>
                    <p>This would be a praiseworthy and laudable undertaking, and we are pleased to
                        hear that a number of ladies of Green township are engaged in it. We would
                        suggest, however, that a meeting of the ladies of Chambersburg be held for
                        the purpose of maturing plan, appointing officers, and thus secure
                        organization and concert of action.--Ladies, take the matter in hand.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that by order of the Quartermaster General of Pennsylvania,
                    blankets must be manufactured and stockings must be knitted for the soldiers for
                    the coming winter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Honor Conferred</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the conferment of an honorary degree from Washington College upon
                    the Honorable George Chambers of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Levi Shuman of Strasburg and Miss Elizabeth Shuman of Hamilton township
                    were married on September 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelsheim</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. George Hummelsheim of Chambersburg and Miss Caroline Manspeaker of
                    Bedford County were married on September 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Ann C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William Bell and Miss Ann C. Miller, both of Franklin County, were
                    married on September 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-4; war news from western Virginia, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.17.04">
            <pageNote>Anecdotes, column 1; prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns
            1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
