<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.07.30">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/2/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-30">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="30">30</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.30.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; Congressional proceedings, columns 3 and
            4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.30.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Warfare with Savages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"And now if the war is to be a war to the knife, without regard to the
                    usages of civilized warfare, traitors will find that there is such a thing as
                    retaliation; . . . that in determining for such a war, they pronounce the
                    sentence of their own extermination."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condems the rebel forces at Manassas Junction and elsewhere for their
                    "barbarity" and warns them that the "villainy" displayed by Southern troops will
                    bring about their own destruction at the hands of the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Evidence of Statistics</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Estimates that the cost of operating the ports and maintaining
                    fortifications in the South over the previous six years exceeded the amount of
                    revenue collected for the federal government at Southern ports by more than 10
                    million dollars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Officers Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A politician, or a good fellow, or a clever speaker, or a man of wealth
                    may be of use in organizing a regiment or a company; but when an actual fight
                    has proved that he is not also a soldier, he must be made to resign."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that mistakes made on the field of battle arose from the
                    inexperience of many of the officers leading the men. The Dispatch urges that
                    officers who have proved themselves incompetent at Bull Run should resign their
                    posts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Major General Banks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses full confidence in Major General Banks, who has assumed the
                    command of the Department of the Shenandoah at Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Rebel Loss at Manassas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the rebel loss at Manassas as 3,000 killed and 6,000 wounded. In
                    contrast, the number of killed and wounded from the Northern troops was 1,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Further Particulars of the Late Battle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGraw</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Arnold</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports among other items that Messrs. Harry McGraw and Arnold Harris, with
                    a livery stable keeper from Chambersburg, were captured by rebel forces when
                    they went to retrieve the body of Colonel Cameron.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Latest News by the Mails!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Repeats an account of the battle at Bull Run given by a Union sympathizer
                    who resides near Manassas Junction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Flag Presentation at Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details a ceremony at Harper's Ferry at which the ladies of the town
                    presented a flag to the Massachusetts Second Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, bottom of column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.30.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>What is an Ambulance?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes for the Dispatch's readers what an ambulance looks like.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Eleventh Indiana Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the passage of the Eleventh Indiana regiment through Chambersburg
                    the previous Friday evening. A number of the city's residents turned out at the
                    train station with baskets of food for the men, which were well received by
                    them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Held a Prisoner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Mr. J. Allison Eyster, prominent Chambersburg merchant, was
                    captured by rebel troops when he was visiting the encampments of the federal
                    army in Virginia and is being held prisoner at Winchester.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Returned Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Sunday evening, the Chambers Artillery, Companies A &amp; B, returned
                        safe to gladden the hearts of their families and friends. It is said that
                        they have not lost a single man, although there are several in ill health at
                        present. They have been detained for about a week in Harrisburg, awaiting
                        their pay, having drawn "nary red" in the three months of their service. We
                        are glad to hail the safe return of these men, who in the hour of emergency,
                        threw themselves into the breach for the preservation of their country, and
                        whether one of them re-enlists or not they all deserve a soldier's welcome
                        and a soldier's honors.</p>
                    <p>Although many of the three months men have not been in actual battle, they
                        have experienced all the hardships of the soldier's life, prevented the
                        ravages o the enemy upon our soil, and stood ready to meet the threatened
                        invasion with proper spirit and energy. Let all who desire to cavil at the
                        return of our men, just remember their own anxiety when these men first
                        enlisted for their defence. Their own hearts will then answer their own
                        questions.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Company A and B of the Chambers Artillery arrived safely in
                    Harrisburg, where they are awaiting their pay before returning home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gebhart</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nickey</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Isaac Gebhart of Newburg and Mrs. Mary C. Nickey of Shippensburg were
                    married in Chambersburg on July 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mich</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte E. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mich</ln>
                        <fn>Fredrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 25, Mr. Benjamin S. Huber, son of Abraham Huber of Letterkenny
                    Township, and Miss Charlotte E. C. Mich, daughter of Fredrick Mich of Hamilton
                    Township, Franklin County, were married.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.30.04">
            <pageNote>Letter from a member of the New York Fire Zouaves to his parents, column 1;
                anecdote concerning General Lyons and his German body guard, column 1; prices
                current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
