<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.05.10">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>4/24/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-10">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="10">10</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>No paper was printed between April 19 and May 10.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.10.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Through Baltimore!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Poem about the Pennsylvania volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>War Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the locations and recent accomplishments of different divisions of
                    government troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Capt. Roger Jones</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the presence in town of Capt. Roger Jones, a much-decorated
                    officer in the Union army, who is staying with his "friend and relative, Mr.
                    Campbell."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Bandages for the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines the directions for making bandages for the army so that the women
                    who have volunteered to do so will make them properly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Treason of South Carolina</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Clipper</origin>
                <commentary>"The following, from the Baltimore Clipper, of July 5th, 1851, will
                    exhibit to our readers the fact, that the present attitude of South Carolina
                    towards our Government, is strictly in accordance with their sentiments, as
                    expressed at that time:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of an article from 1851 in which South Carolinians at the
                    anniversary of the battle of Fort Moultrie declared their anti-Union sentiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"The following remarks of the N. Y. Tribune, we have no doubt, express
                    the sentiments of the vast body of the Union-loving people of our country--"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since the country has lost more than $500,000 because of the rebellion, the
                    matter must be settled forever, not given up with any "half-way arrangement."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.10.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Border State Mediation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>"This pretense of Border State mediation and Border State neutrality must
                    soon come to an end."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial arguing that acceptance of Kentucky governor Magoffin's offer to
                    mediate between the government and the rebels would only lend credence to the
                    idea that there in fact are two governments between which to mediate and border
                    states would then all depart the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Men and Arms from England</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that England's flattering offer of troops and arms must be rejected
                    because the U.S. is not fighting a war against a foreign power, but must put
                    down the rebellion on its own soil itself.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>No Mediation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns those of the "Southern Rebellion" for stealing and robbing, and
                    for firing on a fort with a hundred men who lacked provisions. At the same time,
                    the government is praised for its competent attempt to restore order and peace
                    without resorting to negotiation, which would be treasonous.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Southern Errors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The traitors of the South committed a very grave error, when, because a few
                        northern office-holders held sympathy with them, in the incipiency and even
                        more progressive stages of the rebellion, they supposed the North could be
                        divided against itself, and thus fall an easy prey to their rapacious
                        villainy. The mistake was to many of them a natural one, and shows, most
                        emphatically, their gross ignorance of the Northern people. Their own
                        masses--rude, ignorant, coarse, and in many cases, desperate and
                        semi-barbarous--are easily led on by artful men, to consummate almost any
                        wicked folly in the name of Southern Rights. Having such a population at
                        home, they, measuring Northern intelligence and patriotism by their own
                        standard, supposed that a few energetic leaders here could, as YANCY said of
                        the South, fire from the heart and precipitate a revolution.</p>
                    <p>There was the rock upon which they split; this blunder of their own
                        ignorance, led them to commit the greatest of all blunders--<emph
                            rend="italic">Secession</emph> itself. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that the South made the mistake of thinking that the North would
                    be divided against itself when the South seceded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gov. Letcher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The document . . . stamps Gov. Letcher as a traitor to GOD, his Nation,
                    and his own State."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the governor of Virginia is calling out troops against the
                    U.S., even though the secession act of the state convention has not been
                    ratified.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Noble Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Pennsylvania's volunteer companies are ahead of those of every
                    other state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Re-enforcement of Pickens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Fort Pickens has been reinforced successfully.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Right Doctrine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Mr. Seward has instructed the U.S. minister to France that
                    there has not been, nor will there ever be a dissolution of the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Proclamation by the Governor of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor Letcher gives the commanding general of the military forces of
                    Virginia the power to muster into service as many volunteers as the state may
                    require.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.10.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Home Guards</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hershberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Home guards under Major Hershberger's direction are making rapid
                    improvement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Capt. Housum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler&gt;</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that both men are home on furlough.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Flag Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An American flag made by a group of ladies from Chambersburg was presented
                    to the 8th Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lieutenant Roger Jones was issued a commission from Hon. Simon Cameron,
                    Secretary of War.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Good Idea</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that picket guards are stationed each night at several approaches
                    to the town, and ladies of Chambersburg have been giving them baskets. The
                    editor expresses the hope that all the guards will be provided for in this
                    manner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Life in Camp</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A few days ago, we had the pleasure of visiting Camp Slifer. Everything about
                        it has a military air. The troops are drilled regularly, and are rapidly
                        improving. The quarters, which are board shanties, put up under the
                        supervision of Mr. Joseph Frey, and experienced mechanic of this place, are
                        comfortable, so far as we could learn; and although considerable rain has
                        fallen since the formation of the camp, have leaked but little. There seems
                        to be a disposition in all concerned to do the best for all others, and but
                        one complaint seems to exist. This is a sad one, and we feel sorry it is so.
                        It appears, that a great deal of the bread is of very poor quality, and in
                        many cases, the men have not enough, even of that. How it occurs, we know
                        not, but have heard quite a number of the men express, how different was
                        their treatment at camp Curtin, (Harrisburg,) and say, that if there was not
                        an alteration they should return to their homes whenever their three months
                        of enlistment are up. At the Western Camp, we were informed both by officers
                        and men, that their provisions were both good and plentiful, and we cannot
                        see any good reason why it should not be so at Camp Slifer. Wherever the
                        defect exists we hope it may be speedily remedied. For to have good
                        soldiers, they must be well cared for both as regards food and clothing, but
                        especially that of food. It must be wholesome, or there will be sickness;
                        there must be a sufficiency, or there will be weakness, or perhaps
                        insubordination. Our soldiers deserve well of us. Many of the men here
                        encamped, have left good homes to uphold our liberties, to guard our
                        hearthstones from desecration, and protect us, our wives, and our little
                        ones from the invasion of our foes. Such men should be held in honor by us.
                        They should not want for any comfort be given them while in the service of
                        their country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that in Camp Slifer, many of the men have complained that the bread
                    is of poor quality and that the portions of bread are small. The editor urges
                    that soldiers should be well cared for, especially as regards to food.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Secession in Kentucky</head>
                <origin>Louisville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>More votes were cast for Union in Louisville than the largest number of
                    aggregate votes ever polled in an election there before.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stine</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>Margaretta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Adam Stine of Pittsburgh and Margaretta Bowers of Chambersburg were married
                    on the 6th of May.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhamer</ln>
                        <fn>Blanche</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhamer</ln>
                        <fn>George O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhamer</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Blanche, aged 3 months, infant daughter of George and Jennie Seilhamer,
                    died on the 5th of May.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinstry</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died in Mercersberg on the 24th of April at the age of 93.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died after a lingering illness at the age of 66.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strike</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strike</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel F. Strike, aged 10 years, died near Chambersburg on the 4th of May.
                    He was the only son of John Strike.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. White, infant son of George W. and Charlotte A. White, died on
                    the 24th of April at the age of 7 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Annie Thompson, aged 18 years, died in Camden, N.J., on the 9th of April.
                    She was the youngest daughter of the late Judge Alexander Thompson of
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.10.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
