<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.12.03">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/30/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-12-03">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="03">3</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Issue number 59, which would have been published on November 29, is
        missing.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.12.03.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; poem, column 3; incident from the war in
                western Virginia, columns 3 and 4; anecdote concerning Colonel Berdan, international
                news items, column 4; article reporting that the expedition launched by Generals
                Grant and McClernand down the Mississippi River will soon be underway, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.12.03.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Future Triumph</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that the advantageous positions occupied by Union troops on
                    several fronts at present will mean victory in the future for the government
                    forces over the rebellion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Important Movements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the strategies currently being employed by the navy to enforce
                    the blockade of Southern ports and to wage a campaign on the Mississippi River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Reconnoisance to Drainsville</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that while returning to Langley from a reconnaissance mission to
                    Drainsville, members of the First Pennsylvania regiment were ambushed by a force
                    of Southern soldiers. The regiment made a retreat, but only after 29 men had
                    been killed, wounded, or captured.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Losing Railroad Cars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the war has broke [sic] out the freight cars of the different railroads
                        have been used freely upon one another's roads. The result is that none of
                        them know where their cars are. It is no unusual thing to see cars of the
                        New Jersey Central, or Williamsport and Elmira and Pennsylvania Railroad
                        standing about the sidings at Washington. The Balt. and Ohio Railroad have
                        lost over forty that they cannot find, and have, accordingly, sent out men
                        all over the country wherever a railroad runs to hunt them up and get them
                        home. The freight coming into Washington every morning would make one
                        continuous string for two and a half to three miles long. To-day, a train
                        nearly half a mile long, loaded with wood, came in. Before the war, wood
                        along the road was poor sale, little or none being sent over the road; now
                        the trade is immense, and prices have again gone up for woodland to almost
                        fabulous rates.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that railroad companies do not know where many of their cars are,
                    since their freight cars have been used freely on one another's roads since the
                    war began.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We take the following extract from a letter written by a lady in
                    Charleston, S. C., to the Philadelphia Inquirer. It speaks for itself."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We take the following extract from a letter written by a lady in Charleston,
                        S. C., to the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Inquirer</emph>. It speaks
                        for itself:</p>
                    <p>"Disguise the truth as we may, all thinking men here feel their position
                        peculiarly unsafe; and those who are surrounded by female relatives, have
                        their anxiety increased a thousand fold. We do not fear for the clash of
                        contending armies, though that is sufficiently terrible to excite much
                        apprehension; but even amid the carnage of war, the veriest boor within the
                        armies would respect women; though traitors try to teach us that the
                        Northern war cry is "Beauty and Booty;" but we do dread lest at midnight the
                        fearful sounds of servile insurrection shall salute our ears. You know the
                        negroes are far superior in number to the whites, and now that there are so
                        many absent in the army their majority is greatly increased. <emph
                            rend="italic">If they rise we are in their power!</emph> Do you know
                        what that means? Remember the history of all servile insurrections, and
                        recall the horrors enacted by the race whom oppression has helped to
                        brutalize. Of course the masters would fight desperately; but how could the
                        small number of male whites defend their helpless wives and daughters
                        against a tenfold force of maddened slaves, whose strength and ferocity are
                        well known."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of a letter that indicates the fear of slave insurrection now
                    present among whites in Charleston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News items from Fort Pickens, "news and gossip" from Washington, news of the
                battle of Pensacola, the latest from General Bank's column, columns 2 and 3;
                information from a deserter of an Alabama regiment, column 4; advertisements,
                columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.12.03.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Chaplaincy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that reverend Charles T. Steck, the brother of Reverend J. Steck,
                    who is the pastor of the Lutheran congregation of Chambersburg, will leave for
                    Kentucky in a day or two to assume the position of chaplain of Hambright's
                    Regiment, which is connected with Negley's Pennsylvania Brigade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Thanksgiving Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"All secular employment was suspended, and our town wore all the quiet and
                    order of a Sabbath day.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the day of Thanksgiving was observed in a respectful manner in
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Under Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that two soldiers connected with Chambersburg were among those who
                    participated in the reconnaissance mission towards Drainsville. The two were Mr.
                    George W. Fisher, brother of Mr. John Fisher, Mr. David Newman, son of Mr. A. H.
                    Newman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Thanksgiving Sermon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that at the request of a number of members of the community from
                    different denominations, the Thanksgiving sermon given by Reverend Samuel J.
                    Niccolls will be repeated next Thursday evening in the Methodist church of
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>More Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Dr. J. A. Carmon of Harrisburg has been authorized to raise a
                    company of volunteers for Colonel R. W. McAllen's regiment, which is currently
                    encamped at Camp Slifer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From One of Our Own</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>T. W. M.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from a member of Company C of Harlan's Cavalry, who have recently
                    arrived at Fortress Monroe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinneard</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 27, Mr. David Croft, from near St. Thomas, married Miss Ellen
                    W. Kinneard of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Araminto</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Araminto Weaver, aged 5 years, died near Marion on November 16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sackman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Sackman, aged 70 years and 11 months, died at St. Thomas on
                    November 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhoads</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Lydia Rhoads, aged 67 years, died at Smoketown on November 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports from Port Royal, Martinsburg and Winchester, and Fairfax Court House,
                columns 2 and 3; advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.12.03.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Instructions to Gen. Sherman</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the instructions of General Sherman that the crops in Beaufort be
                    seized and that the slaves be used to gather those crops and to erect the
                    defenses at Port Royal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Incident of bravery on the part of officers and soldiers in Virginia, column
                1; prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
