<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.10.04">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/18/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-04">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Flood in the Susquehanna--$1,000,000 Worth of Logs Adrift</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the previous Saturday, "one of the greatest floods that has
                    occurred" since 1846 has flooded the streets of Lock Haven and Williamsport and
                    has destroyed the booms in those two cities, allowing one million dollars' worth
                    of logs to escape. As a result, a line of the logs fifty-six miles long and a
                    hundred yards wide floated past Harrisburg on Sunday morning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Wanton Destruction of Property</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laments the destruction of property that took place in Fall's Church the
                    previous Sunday. Blames commanding officers for not "shooting down" any of their
                    men who disobey orders and participates in the unnecessary destruction of houses
                    and other property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; news items from Washington, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.04.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Union Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every patriot, every local citizen and every lover of good Government, should
                        support the Union ticket. The situation in which our country was placed
                        imperatively demanded that party strife should cease until the storm which
                        threatened the very existence of our Government, had passed and we were
                        assured that we had a Government to be transmitted to our children. It was
                        an act of magnanimity on the part of Republicans, so far as the spoils of
                        office were concerned, to propose and adopt the Union policy. Yet any other
                        action on their part, at such a time, would have been utterly unworthy the
                        character of a patriotic people. They rose above all selfish feelings and
                        with them, a noble band of their fellow-citizens of the Democratic party and
                        formed a ticket of the very best material: a ticket on which the Democratic
                        party was fully and fairly represented. Democrats in other days were proud
                        to vote for such men as James Nill, John Rowe and D. K. Wunderilch. These
                        men have all been nominated and supported by their party for important
                        offices at different times, and have but recently discharged the duty of
                        their respective offices to the entire satisfaction of their party. But what
                        gave them a peculiar fitness for the position assigned them on the Union
                        ticket was their energetic support of the Union cause, both in word and
                        action. We hold, then, that a ticket so formed, at a time so critical,
                        should have been supported by men of all parties. This Union policy should
                        have superceded [sic] the necesity [sic] of any party ticket. What, if some
                        of the Democratic nominees had never been nominated? Is it so important to
                        the community or the country that the loyalty of such men as Augustus
                        Duncan, Christian D. Lesher or Dr. Wm. H. Boyle should be endorsed, on a
                        ticket which of course will be defeated, by a party action? We hope good and
                        loyal Democrats will join us in supporting and electing men whose loyalty
                        "is seen and read of all men."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges that at this time of crisis, people of all parties must support the
                    Union ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>C. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Asserts that Wilson Reilly is not the man for the judgeship because, in
                    part of the company he keeps with men who would be pleased if a peace with the
                    rebels were negotiated--men such as Augustus Duncan, C. D. Lesher, or Dr. Wm. H.
                    Boyle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fatal Mistake Near Fall's Church, Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the story of a clash between Union regiments, each believing that
                    the other was the enemy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Union ticket, column 1; report of the Republican convention in Massachusetts,
                column 1; advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that "Divine Services" will be held at the United Presbyterian
                    Church the following Sunday morning at eleven o'clock and that Reverend Bruce
                    will officiate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Left</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the departure of the forty men who had been encamped at Camp
                    McClure. The soldiers are on their way to Harrisburg, but the cause of their
                    departure is unknown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Take Command</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Negley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brigadier-General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hambright</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sirwell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Governor Curtin has ordered Brigadier-General Negley to
                    assume command of the regiments of Colonel H. A. Hambright, Colonel F. S.
                    Stumbaugh, and Colonel William Sirwell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Not True</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Lanahan, the soldier who shot Major Lewis, has not committed
                    suicide, but is still awaiting the action of the authorities at Washington.
                    Lanahan served as a private under Captain McCasey and was stationed for a time
                    at Camp Slifer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"Camp Slifer"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"All the tents have been pitched, and 'Slifer' appears more like a camp
                    than it did, in times past."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that supplies have arrived at Camp Slifer, and that as companies
                    are organized, they will be uniformed and otherwise made ready "to do duty for
                    their country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Errata of the Chambersburg "Times"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It has not been our custom heretofore, to parade ourselves before the
                    community as a literary critic; but on the lex talionis principle, we would
                    kindly assist the great man of the Times in entertaining the public in that
                    way."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out numerous minor spelling and typographical errors found in the
                    Times recently.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Stockings</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Evening Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary>"Those patriotic ladies who have determined to knit stockings for our
                    army would do well to make a note of the following directions, furnished to the
                    Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, by a lady of much experience:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides instructions for women wishing to knit stockings for men in the
                    army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>List of Jurors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Webster D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deehert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Mathew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creighbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanagan</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists jurors drawn for court sessions to be held at Chambersburg on Monday,
                    October 28. Elias Hoke, A. J. Miller, and Samuel Ott from Chambersburg will
                    serve as grand jurors, while Webster D. Diehl, Jacob L. Deehert, Henry
                    Greenawalt, William Heyser, Jr., Daniel Trostle, Samuel Greenawalt, and Mathew
                    Gilian, all of Chambersburg, will serve as traverse jurors in the first week of
                    the court session. William L. Chambers, Peter Creighbaum, Joseph Frey, and John
                    E. McLanagan, all of Chambersburg, will serve in the second week as traverse
                    jurors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. David Baker of Franklin County and Miss Catharine R. Avey of Washington
                    County, Maryland, were married on October 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Maxwell, aged 22 years, died in Jackson Hall on September 28. He was
                    the son of Dr. Thomas and Sarah Maxwell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.04.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
