<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.11.22">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/29/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-11-22">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="22">22</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Affairs at Norfolk</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details of the situation at Norfolk, Virginia, reported by Mr. Henry Davis,
                    who had lived in Norfolk for the past ten months and just arrived with other
                    refugees in New York.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Pillaging of Beaufort</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the pillaging of homes in Beaufort by slaves and the general
                    state of disarray with the content of houses on the sidewalks and their
                    interiors were in "a chaos of broken furniture, torn books and engravings, old
                    letters, &amp;c."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; various news items from the South, column 4;
                letter to the Cincinnati Gazette from a correspondent in Pike County, Kentucky,
                column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Justification in a Nutshell</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the seizure of the "would-be" Confederate ministers to France
                    and England was entirely within the rights of the United States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen. Wool</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that federal operations at Fortress Monroe have become more
                    efficient and disciplined since General Wool took over the command.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News from Maryland, Fort Pickens, Memphis, Washington, Fortress Monroe,
                columns 2 and 3; article detailing the particulars of the arrest of Slidell and
                Mason, columns 3 and 4; article from the Richmond Dispatch expressing the dangers
                involved in accepting peace, column 4; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Pleasant Weather</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments that the weather has been unusually pleasant. Reports that aside
                    from the rain of a few weeks ago, the weather has been "remarkably fine" and
                    just cold enough to make outdoor activity pleasurable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>False Representations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Several days ago a colored man called at the Grocery of Mr. John Schofield,
                        and inquired if he had any Hams on hand, remarking that he was sent by a
                        certain Hotel-keeper whom he named, to get a couple. Several being shown, he
                        picked two and left, remarking that the landlord, just being out of change,
                        would call in the evening and pay for them. The time having passed at which
                        payment was to be made, suspicion was aroused that all was not right, and
                        inquiry was made of the landlord, who said he had sent no one to his Store
                        for Hams. Mr. Schofield by that time commenced "smelling a large mice." He
                        was confident of being minus two Hames, for which he had received no pay,
                        and on looking around for the colored man who had got them, discovered that
                        he had left in the next Train.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that an African-American man represented himself falsely as having
                    been sent by "a certain Hotel-keeper whom he named" to the grocery of Mr. John
                    Schofield to acquire two hams. It was later discovered that the man had not been
                    sent by the hotel keeper and that instead he had left town on the next train
                    without paying for the hams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Camp Slifer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is an abundance of the right material in the County for the
                    formation of a crack Regiment."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoskinson</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that parts of two companies are now encamped at Camp Slifer and
                    that another company is to arrive today from Cumberland County. In addition,
                    Captain J. T. Hoskinson of Chambersburg is busy raising his company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates an accident that occurred the previous week when the horse of Mr.
                    Jason Robison, resident of Washington township, became frightened while pulling
                    Mr. Robison's buggy and kicked him on the leg, fracturing it badly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Torchlight Procession</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a torchlight procession held the previous Friday evening by the
                    Union men of Hagerstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died from Exposure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>Alexandria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of an Irishman, Alexandria Speer of Chambersburg, who
                    became drunk several evenings previous and was left lying on the road, but was
                    unable to make his way home and died the next morning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Jane M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Jane M. Reed of Chambersburg, who was 73 years of age, died at the
                    home of her son in Westmoreland County, Pennsylvania, on November 19. Mrs. Reed
                    had been a resident of Newville, Cumberland County, for many years and will be
                    interred there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Emma E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Elisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emma E. Young, aged 11 years, died on November 17 in Antrim township,
                    Franklin County. She was the third daughter of Jacob and Ann Elisa Young.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.22.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
