<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.06.04">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/27/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-04">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.06.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Jeff Davis in Richmond</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of an article from the Richmond Enquirer describing the journey to
                    and arrival of Jefferson Davis, his aid Colonel Wigfall, and the Honoroble
                    Robert Toombs of Georgia in Richmond. Recounts the warmth of President Davis's
                    reception at the stops his train made along the way from Montgomery to Richmond
                    and the enthusiastic greeting he received when he arrived in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Excitement at Wheeling</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts movement of troops from "Camp Carlisle" toward Grafton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Listing of national, state, and local officeholders, column 1; prospectus of
                the Semi-Weekly Dispatch, column 1; advertisements, columns 1 and 2; poem, column 3;
                reprint of an article from the Savannah Republican that says the Confederacy does
                not want Maryland if the people of Maryland will not give their full consent to
                support the Confederacy, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.06.04.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Baltimore--Chief Justice Taney</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts an article that reports an alleged plan by the rebel forces to
                    capture Baltimore and slaughter the unarmed Union men and their families
                    residing in the city. The Dispatch predicts, though, that "Gen. Scott will not
                    be caught napping" but will manage to "nip the design in its incipiency." The
                    Dispatch also calls for the resignation of Chief Justice Taney because of the
                    decision he issued in the Dred Scott case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fugitive Slaves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As our readers are aware, numbers of slaves have been escaping from their
                        masters, and taken refuge with Major General Butler, since his occupation of
                        Fortress Monroe. In many cases their reputed owners have asked their
                        delivery under the Fugitive Slave Law. The invariable answer of Gen. Butler
                        has been, in all such cases, that the slaves would be promptly returned to
                        their owners, provided they would take the oath of allegiance to the
                        Government of the United States.</p>
                    <p>The Secretary of War has issued the following letter of instructions:</p>
                    <p>"Washington, May 30, 1861.</p>
                    <p>"SIR: Your action in respect to the negroes who came within your lines, from
                        the service of the rebels, is approved. The Department is sensible of the
                        Embarrassments which must surround officers conducting military operations
                        in a State, by the laws of which Slavery is sanctioned. The Government
                        cannot recognize the rejection by any State of its Federal obligation,
                        resting upon itself, and among these Federal obligations, however, no one
                        can be more important than that of suppressing and dispersing any
                        combination of the former for the purpose of overthrowing its whole
                        Constitutional authority. While, therefore, you will permit no interference,
                        by persons under your command, with the relations of persons held to service
                        under the laws of any State, you will, on the other hand, so long as any
                        State within which your military operations are conducted, remain under the
                        control of such armed combinations, refrain from surrendering to alleged
                        masters any persons who come within your liens. You will employ such armed
                        combinations, refrain from surrendering to alleged masters any persons who
                        come within your lines. You will employ such persons in the services to
                        which they will be best adapted, keeping an account of the labor by them
                        performed, of the value of it, and the expenses of their maintenance. The
                        question of their final disposition will be reserved for future
                        determination.</p>
                    <p>"SIMON CAMERON, Secretary of War.<lb/> "To Major General BUTLER."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints the instructions of the Secretary of War to General Butler
                    directing him to "refrain from surrendering to alleged masters any persons who
                    come within your lines." The Dispatch points out that thus far, the policy of
                    General Butler has been to announce that slaves who take refuge in Union
                    fortresses will be promptly returned to their owners if those owners have taken
                    an oath of allegiance to the United States government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Rebel Troops at Martinsburg, Va.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the Confederate troops stationed at Martinsburg, Virginia, as
                    "drunk when they please," disorderly, and lacking in discipline. Small pox and
                    diarrhea, the paper reports, are widespread.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gov. Curtin Seeks an Investigation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a dispatch declaring that the governor is prepared to meet any
                    charges against his administration for corruption in the distribution of
                    supplies to the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Alleged Frauds in Contracts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Governor Curtin has ordered an investigation into the charges
                    of fraud in supply contracts for the army. The governor has also ordered "good
                    and substantial clothing" to be distributed to Pennsylvania volunteers stationed
                    in Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Union Meeting in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a meeting held be Unionists in Martinsburg, Virginia, in which
                    participants denounced secession and the presence of the Southern army on
                    Virginia soil.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article applauding the appointment of Colonel John C. Fremont and N. P. Banks
                as Major Generals, column 2; listing of the number of troops in the army of the
                Union by location, column 2; short item from the Cincinnati Enquirer about the
                journey of Jefferson Davis from Montgomery to Richmond, column 2; summary of the
                minor battle at Acquia Creek, column 3; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.06.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Still They Come!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Fourteenth and Fifteenth Regiments arrived in Chambersburg
                    the previous night. The number of regiments in and around the town now total
                    thirteen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Run Over</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the previous afternoon a soldier slipped from a government
                    wagon and fell. The wheels of the wagon passed over his head and arm, compelling
                    the soldier to go to the hospital.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Arrival of Gen. Patterson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the arrival of General Patterson and his staff in town on the
                    previous Sunday evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Soldier Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Samuel Patterson of Company B, the Tenth Regiment, died the
                    previous morning of typhoid pneumonia after a sickness of five days. Patterson
                    was 35 years of age and had served in the entirety of the Mexican campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Scriptures, &amp;c.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pleads for the Bible Society or some of the women of the town to provide
                    "scriptures, tracts, and other appropriate reading matter" to the soldiers in
                    hospitals and camps in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Independent Rangers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Captain M'Mullen's Independent Rangers arrived in Chambersburg
                    on Sunday afternoon, acting in the capacity of bodyguards to General Patterson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Fracas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a scuffle between members of the German Rifles and their officers
                    the previous Saturday afternoon when the officers were attempting to convey
                    their men to camp. One man was wounded in the face with the officer's sword, and
                    three of the men were conveyed to jail "in order to regain their senses."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Hospitality--Opinions of the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the comments soldiers from Philadelphia and Camp Scott have made
                    about the "kindness and hospitality" of the people of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Disgraceful and Bloody Affray</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday last, our town was the scene of a most disgraceful affray, which
                        resulted in the death of a mullato resident, named Frank Jones, and the
                        wounding of three soldiers stationed here. The particulars, as nearly as we
                        could learn, were as follows:--</p>
                    <p>On Saturday afternoon, a party of soldiers went to the house of Frank Jones,
                        a mulatto residing in Wolffstown, a suburb of this place, and wanted
                        admission. They found the door fastened, and were informed by Mrs. Jones
                        that they could not come in, when one of them threw a boulder at her head,
                        which she dodged, and called her husband, who was in the garden
                        transplanting cabbages. The men attempted to force the door, and fired a
                        shot through the window, while Jones, in order to defend his own house,
                        seized his double-barrelled gun, which was charged with buckshot, and
                        warning them not to force the door, stood with it ready when the door was
                        burst in, and after retreating to the wall, fired at one wounding him in the
                        thigh about six inches above the knee. A scuffle ensued in which Jones was
                        floored, and while down, his wife begged them not to kill her husband, when
                        one of them struck her a severe blow in the face, others knocked the
                        children about, when Jones recovering his feet, wrested the gun from the
                        soldiers' hands, and, as they were beating a retreat, fired the contents of
                        the other barrel, which took effect in the leg of another of the soldiers.
                        The news of the occurrence spread immediately; a crowd collected, and the
                        sight of the wounded men, who had been conveyed to a neighboring house, so
                        exasperated a number of the soldiers, that a rush was made for Jones' house.
                        He fled, was hotly pursued by the crowd, shouting, "kill the nigger," and
                        other similar expressions. He ran about three-quarters of a mile, and
                        finding no escape, made for the house of Geo. Eyster, Esq., Prosecuting
                        Attorney, and secreted himself in the chimney. His pursuers, representing to
                        Mrs. Eyster that they wished to convey him to jail, obtained permission to
                        take him from the house. As they were taking him away, Lieut. Bryan came up
                        saying, "stand aside, men," when he fired his revolver at Jones, wounding
                        him in the side. A second shot by Bryan, struck him in the other side, when
                        some other person fired into his back, the ball passing through the shoulder
                        blade, and wounding him fatally. He then became a mere target for pistols,
                        bludgeons and bayonets, he at the same time begging piteously for his life.
                        While he was yet moaning, it was stated, this lieutenant stood over him and
                        thrust his sword nearly through his body. In the promiscuous firing, a
                        soldier, who had just arrived, a member of the 2d regiment, Comp. G,
                        received a wound in the hip, the ball glancing down to the thigh.</p>
                    <p>A post-mortem examination was held, when it was ascertained that Jones had
                        received five shots in the back, several in his head, one passed directly
                        through his heart lengthwise, and, at a coroner's jury held yesterday
                        morning, it was testified that there were several wounds each of which would
                        have produced death. The cause of the assault, as stated before the jury,
                        was, that a neighbor of Jones has been keeping whiskey, and wish to purchase
                        in such quarters, and that Jones a few days ago, fearing disturbance from
                        it, entered complaint against him for selling liquor without license. The
                        frequenters of the "hotel," finding their supply cut off, swore vengeance
                        against Jones, and came with the intention, it was supposed, of carrying
                        heir threats into effect, with results as have been stated.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Recounts a shoot-out between a local mulatto, Frank Jones, and several
                    soldiers at Jones's home in Wolffstown. Jones escaped a mob of townspeople who
                    began to pursue him after he had shot two of the soldiers, but then the attorney
                    who had given him refuge released him to the crowd, who shot him repeatedly,
                    even after he had died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--It is indeed with pleasure and gratification that I offer,
                        through your columns, the most deep and heartfelt thanks of the officers and
                        members of the "Juanita Rifles," to the Ladies of the neighborhood in which
                        we are at present quartered, the Parsonage of the German Reformed Church,
                        situated near the head of Main street. Those ladies have stepped forward in
                        our behalf, exhibiting all the patriotism and philanthropy of their
                        illustrious Revolutionary mothers. At the present time, when the good city
                        of Chambersburg is completely overrun with the military of our land,--and at
                        a time, too, when it behooves her citizens to exercise the greatest caution,
                        as well as economy, in order to protect them against the evil designs and
                        characteristics of this multitude of strangers--these kind-hearted Ladies
                        have freely and voluntarily provided for our every want, regardless alike of
                        trouble and expense. We have been abundantly supplied with everything the
                        most fastidious taste or yearning heart could desire. Luxuries such as our
                        anxious eyes have heretofore been strangers to, have been, and still are,
                        freely lavished upon us; and Mr. Editor, it is with deep and heartfelt
                        gratitude that I tender to those kind Ladies, the grateful acknowledgements
                        [sic] of every man in the company, accompanied by our sincere wishes for
                        their happiness and prosperity.</p>
                    <p>I desire also, in this connexion, to tender thanks to Mrs. J. H. Eyster for
                        her untiring devotion to her country's cause, by way of numerous favors
                        supplied the worn out soldier. In gratitude we place ourselves subject to
                        these truly philanthropic Ladies. They have but to command, and their
                        slightest wish shall be our command, and their slightest wish shall be our
                        command, and their slightest wish shall be our law. For the sake of such
                        noble-hearted lady friends no danger can be too great for us to dare, no
                        feat too daring for us to accomplish. May the righteous God cherish and
                        protect such truly noble hearts.</p>
                    <p>In behalf of Comp. H., Capt. A. M. Lloyd, Third Reg., P. V.<lb/> Wm. I.
                        Blain.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Wm. I. Blain</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers praise from Company H of the Third Regiment for the generosity of
                    the women of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laudenslager</ln>
                        <fn>Benena</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John Snyder and Miss Benena Laudenslager, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on May 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Rosa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>Emma L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rosa McDowell, two years of age, died of the croup on May 30. She was the
                    only child of J. McDowell and Emma L. Sharpe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article about the capture of a cannon at Sistersville, Virginia, column 3;
                prices current, column 3; advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.06.04.04">
            <pageNote>Article recounting the feelings of President Lincoln toward Colonel Ellsworth,
                column 1; article about how to take care of the hair from Hall's Journal of Health,
                column 1; description of the diploma given to every man serving in the army or navy
                of the United States, column 1; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
