<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.11.15">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/29/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-11-15">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="15">15</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Horrors of Bull Run--Feeling at Richmond, Virginia</head>
                <origin>Montreal Witness</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Depicts the scene at Richmond when the wounded returned from the battle at
                    Manassas, "or Bull Run as it is somewhat pointedly styled by the Northerners."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; poem, column 4; anecdotes, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Naval Expedition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Of all the rebellious States, South Carolina deserves the severest
                    treatment, and no punishment that can be meted out to her by the General
                    Government, would be considered too severe by the loyal people of the country,
                    though that punishment should sweep over her entire length and breadth as with a
                    besom [sic] of destruction, leaving neither root nor branch, house nor hamlet,
                    master or slave, man or woman."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses the opinion that South Carolina deserves to be severely punished
                    for its history of rebellion and its current disloyalty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Regulars and Volunteers</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Washington correspondent of the New York Herald says:</p>
                    <p>The members of Congress who are here are also discussing the propriety of
                        wiping out the distinction between the regulars and volunteers, by declaring
                        the volunteers to compose the army of the United States. Unless something is
                        done to legally obliterate the distinction now maintained, and to do away
                        with the tyrannical rule of the regular department, the volunteer system
                        will be utterly destroyed.--As it is now, no officer, however capable or
                        meritorious, can obtain any position or consideration with the heads of the
                        army bureaus, and nothing is conceded to the volunteers that can possibly be
                        withheld. For their arms, clothing, equipments, transportation, &amp;c.,
                        the volunteers must dance attendance, day after day, upon men who openly
                        deride and malign them, and who never treat them with decency, and never
                        speak of them except with contempt. It is astonishing the extent to which
                        this feeling is carried.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points to the ill treatment of the volunteer segment of the army by members
                    of the regular army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Naval Expedition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Gen. Sherman has hundreds, perhaps thousand, of negro laborers at his
                    command to work on the new entrenchments. It is said they were wild with joy and
                    revenge. They have been shot down, they say, like dogs, because they would not
                    go off with their masters."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Confirms and provides details on the taking of Beaufort by federal troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reprint of a speech in which General Burnside highly recommends General
                McClellan as a worthy and capable commander of Union forces, column 2; news of
                battles and skirmishes at Pikesville, Kentucky, and near Kansas City, Missouri,
                column 4; news of attacks by rebels at Guyandotte, Virginia, and near Alexandria,
                Virginia, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.15.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the child who had been severely burned, as reported in the
                    previous issue of the Dispatch, has died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ministerial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Reverend Charles T. Steck of Philadelphia will preach in
                    the Lutheran Church in Chambersburg on the coming Sabbath and the one following.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fatal Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that a son of Mr. Joseph Linn, who lives near town, accidentally
                    struck himself a "severe blow" with a hay fork, causing his death a few hours
                    later.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fun!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Just as we go to press, we observe that Sanford, the inimitable negro
                        delineator, has posted his bills, announcing a Concert to come off on
                        Tuesday and Wednesday evenings of next week. Upon the recent successes which
                        have attended our arms in the West and South Carolina, we doubt not but that
                        we could be induced to take a hearty laugh--even at Sanford's expense.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Sanford, "the inimitable negro delineator" will give a concern
                    on Tuesday and Wednesday evenings next week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Kemmerer's</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the Grand Juvenile Concerts and Floral Exhibitions that were
                    presented on Monday and Thursday evenings at Franklin Hall "gave universal
                    satisfaction and delight to crowded houses." Notes that a final performance will
                    be given on Saturday evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Scoundrel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A man by the name of James Klink, a merchant of Newville, Cumberland County,
                        arrived in this place on Saturday last, accompanied by a young lady whom he
                        represented as his wife, and put up at one of our Hotels for several
                        days.--Klink has a wife and several children in Newville; was an elder in
                        the Church, and occupied a respectable position in that community. The girl,
                        whose ruin he has accomplished, was from a rural district, and became
                        acquainted with Klink by dealing at his store. The elopement was not
                        immediately discovered; but when the face became developed, they were
                        tracked to this place, and on Tuesday last the brother-in-law of the girl,
                        accompanied by Klink's wife, arrived here in pursuit of the guilty pair. By
                        that time, however, the respected merchant had left for parts unknown,
                        having sent the foolish and disgraced girl back--from whence he decoyed
                    her.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that James Klink, a merchant from Connecticut, brought a girl into
                    town the previous Saturday. Klink has a wife and children and by staying with
                    her at a hotel in Chambersburg for several days has accomplished the "ruin" of
                    the girl involved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seihart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Copies the resolutions of the Friendship Fire Company pertaining to the
                    death of Thomas B. Seihart, a member of the company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reprint of a speech by Colonel Mulligan, commander of the Irish Brigade at
                Lexington, given upon his arrival in Chicago, column 2; account by the Charleston
                Mercury of the capture of Beaufort, column 3; advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.11.15.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
