<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.05.17">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>4/28/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-17">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="17">17</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.17.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The American Race</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Nationality, customs, language, race, must all be lost in the Union of
                    multitudinous descendants of distinct peoples."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The present census reveals the astonishing fact that the population of the
                        United States has increased thirty-three per cent, within the last ten
                        years. The Roman Empire, approaching the culmination of its power, increased
                        about thirty per cent each hundred years, but no nation in recorded times
                        has afforded any parallel to the advancement of our own. Spain has been
                        depopulating for a thousand years; England is not three times more populous
                        than three centuries ago, and Italy is no more important numerically than
                        she was in the days of Pliny; but within three quarters of a country the
                        population of the United States has risen from three to thirty millions. It
                        is a common error to attribute this vast increase to immigration from
                        foreign countries; but of the twenty-three millions enumerated in '50, not
                        three millions were of foreign birth. Vast as the annual immigration is, it
                        bears no proportion to the yearly increase by birth, which in itself,
                        independent of immigration, averages thirty per cent, every ten years of the
                        present century. This wonderful fecundity is not unexplained by physical
                        law; it is observed that in populous countries of Europe where the same
                        people continually intermarry, the increase is comparatively insignificant;
                        on the same principle the aristocracy of England is observed to diminish
                        rather than multiply, because interest and pride confine people to
                        intermarriage to people of the same race, and often within the circle of
                        consanguinity. But in the United States various races amalgamate; the stock
                        becomes more vigorous, there is less of disease and early death, and the
                        population consequently increases with a prodigious ratio. Whatever hatred
                        the Celtic Teutonic people may bear towards the Anglo-Saxon race, because of
                        ancient oppression and spoliation, it is not to be denied that the hated
                        Anglo-Saxons are the masters of the world, giving new language to strange
                        people, and destroying every impediment in their progress. It is computed
                        that at least one-third of the population of the U. States are descendants
                        of the Puritans, who were Anglo-Saxons; this strong-willed, enterprising and
                        indomitable race, intermingling with others, has preserved ascendancy and
                        produced a people superior in physical strength and in those attributes of
                        mind most required in the rapid development of the great Empire of the West.
                        Humiliating as the institution of any analogy may appear to man of the
                        immortal mind, he must submit to the laws governing the rest of animal
                        creation in which the union of distinct stocks produces improvement. Some of
                        the finest examples of physical beauty have resulted from the intermarriage
                        of Europeans and North American Indians; and, indeed, instances are not
                        wanting where the offspring has been endowed with wonderful intellectual
                        strength. If the laws of nature require the marriage of separate kindreds,
                        why may not corresponding improvement result from the intermingling of
                        distinct nations? It does so happen, and the American nation, surpassing all
                        others in indomitable enterprise and in ratio of increase, is a clear
                        demonstration of the fact.</p>
                    <p>From this representative union of nations another greater, more powerful, and
                        partaking of the physical and mental qualities of all, will demand
                        recognition in the family of races--the "American race," combining the
                        courage of the Saxon, the patient industry of the Teuton, the reflection of
                        the Celt, and the impetuous unrest of the Frank. That race exists now in the
                        increased millions revealed by the census of the complete decade. The ten
                        thousands of intelligent, strong-limbed children who beseige [sic] our
                        schools may proudly claim to belong to that separate people of the West who,
                        a century hence, will outnumber the population of ten European kingdoms and
                        empires, and will be in strong conflict with the conquering Saxon. Celt and
                        Saxon and Teuton have become confused at the altar and the font, and,
                        borrowing a language from the strongest, are correctly pronounced a new
                        race, eclectic, composite, but none the less distinct. Nationality, customs,
                        language, race, must all be lost in the Union of multitudinous descendants
                        of distinct peoples, as rivers running into the great ocean become deep.
                        Whatever may have been their pride and power when dashing through the
                        mountain gorge or overflooding the plain, their strength becomes mightier,
                        their anger more terrible, their roaring more sublime, when, with united
                        power, they smite the unyielding rock and lift their hoary crests to
                    heaven.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reasons that America's population has increased by one-third in the past
                    ten years because of the intermarriage in the United States of the races of
                    Celts, Teutons, Anglo-Saxons, and North American Indians. This mixing of the
                    races has made the "stock" more "vigorous" and will ultimately produce a
                    peculiar "American race," which will exhibit the different positive
                    characteristics of all these distinct peoples.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>More Volunteers</head>
                <origin>Newville Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bentzel</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillen</ln>
                        <fn>Thos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>Jos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rousch</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butts</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Givler</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholson</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minor</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists new volunteers from Newville who enlisted at Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin>Newville Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. E. Jones of Lower Path Valley, Franklin County, was killed when struck
                    in the head by a stake which had caught in the wheel of a sulkey in which he was
                    riding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, column 1; poem, column 2; Southern items, column 3</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.17.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Slavery Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The question of Slavery, at present, is not a question for the North but for
                        the South. Let it be our business to preserve our own liberties, by
                        sustaining our Constitutional Government, and let the adjustment of the
                        Slavery Question be an after consideration, or find its own adjustment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editor comments that the North should simply concentrate at this point on
                    preserving their own liberties by fighting to sustain the Union. The slavery
                    question should be secondary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Occupancy of Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The government now occupies Baltimore. The editor points out that General
                    Butler has vowed not to interfere with the "occupation of any citizen" except
                    with those citizens of Baltimore who are aiding the rebellion. In those cases,
                    munitions of war and other property will be seized.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Out of Place</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The man who would sow discord in the ranks of our army, is quite as much
                        guilty of treason as he who gives aid and comfort to the enemy; and a
                        pretended friend, in time of war, is worse than a hundred open enemies.
                        Treason is the more dangerous when disguised; and he who, under pretence of
                        loyalty, takes occasion to upbraid the defenders of the cause, and bring
                        them and their cause into disrepute, must be regarded as a traitor. We have
                        been called upon to make these remarks by noticing in several of our
                        exchange papers, articles calculated to stir up strife and discord among the
                        loyal people of the country, by invidious slurs upon the Republican party,
                        and holding us responsible for the war now forced upon us. The Republican
                        party, as a party, has, for the time at least, dropped the discussion of the
                        question, as to who or what has endangered our liberties and forced us into
                        a civil war. The respectable, responsible and influential portion of the
                        great Democratic party has done the same, and we notice, and rejoice at it,
                        that but few northern papers are found so low as to attempt to stir up such
                        a spirit of vile partizanship, and as truly glad to find the few attempts of
                        the kind which have been made, sternly frowned a display of the Stars and
                        Stripes, or in hypocritical speech profess a love of country which they
                        cannot feel.</p>
                    <p>The North is united, and although an occasional Arnold may be found, we
                        firmly believe in the integrity, intelligence, and patriotism of the great
                        mass of our fellow citizens, and as confidently expect them to resist all
                        attempts at introducing the firebrands of party crimination into the ranks
                        of our people, and force the public press into an attitude at least of
                        decency.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial responds to papers that have attempted to blame the Republicans
                    for the war. The editor argues that in most cases, both Democrats and
                    Republicans have put aside the question of who or what has forced the country
                    into war. Expresses satisfaction that few Northern papers have attempted to
                    "stir up such a spirit of vile partisanship."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>One Thing at a Time</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are many persons in the world who, with good abilities and intentions,
                        fail to accomplish anything by attempting too much. They have no faith in
                        the doctrine of "a half loaf being better than no bread," and with them it
                        is all or none; if they cannot save the ship, the cargo must be suffered to
                        sink also. Such persons always are on a hobby, and no matter what the
                        occasion, hobby must always go along. In the present crisis of our country
                        we see cases of this kind, not only of private individuals but of public,
                        and even of the press itself. The hobby to which we now particularly refer
                        is the question of Slavery. To all interested, we commend a careful and
                        thoughtful perusal of the following, taken from the editorial columns of the
                            <emph rend="italic">N. Y. Tribune</emph>.</p>
                    <p>"Many persons seem anxious to complicate the struggle now making for and
                        against the integrity of the Union with questions concerning the
                        perpetuation of Slavery.--Some require the war for the Union to be a War for
                        the extinction of Slavery; while others would have pledges given by the
                        Unionists that Slavery shall in no case suffer from our triumphs. Each of
                        these demands is in our eyes ultimately and unreasonable. This War is in
                        truth a War for the preservation of the Union, not for the destruction of
                        Slavery; and it would alienate many ardent Unionists to pervert it into a
                        War against Slavery. And on the other hand, no pledges can be given that
                        Slavery shall receive no damage from a Union triumph, because (among other
                        reasons) no one can foresee how the Slaveholding interest will behave
                        itself. Our own judgment confirms the testimony of cool observers that the
                        conspiracy against the life of the Nation is rather that of the political
                        aspirants than the slaveholders of the South--that, as a general rule, the
                        slaveholders have been but reluctant backers of Secession, ninetenths [sic]
                        of whose noisiest champions are as destitute of slaves as of loyalty or
                        patriotism. If the slaveholders as a class would only speak and act as they
                        think and feel, we should have the head conspirators before Grand Juries
                        within three months. That the South, and especially the slaveholders, whose
                        property is visible an tangible, are destined to be ruined by Secession, is
                        plain. This rebellion found good field-hands worth $1,000 to $1,200 each;
                        they can now be bought for half the money: and will be sold for a fourth of
                        it before the war is ended. If the slaveholders do not interpose to stop the
                        strife, the day predicted by John Randolph, when the masters would run away
                        from the slaves to escape ruin, may be much nearer than is imagined.</p>
                    <p>Hitherto the armies of the Union have observed, and are disposed to observe,
                        a scrupulous respect for all rights of property as defined by law. As yet,
                        every solicitation that negroes should be allowed to engage in the War of
                        the Union, has been unhesitatingly rejected. As yet, every fugitive slave
                        who has run for protection to the Federal troops whether in Florida or
                        Maryland, has been returned to his legal master. On the other side, money
                        has been squeezed out of negroes to fill the ever-yawning treasury of
                        Secession, and we are threatened in various quarters with the arming of
                        negroes to fight against the Union.</p>
                    <p>We believe the general inclination of the Unionists is to let Slavery alone
                        provided it lets <emph rend="italic">them</emph> alone. We believe that
                        Slavery has nothing to fear from a Union triumph unless it should throw
                        itself across the way of that triumph. But if Slavery should insist on
                        making up an issue between itself and the Union, then we are sure it would
                        do so to its own peril. Whenever the issue shall be--"Shall the American
                        Republic," "be destroyed or shall Slavery perish?"--we believe the
                        overwhelming response of the patriots--Democrats quite as generally and
                        heartily as Republicans--will be, "The Republic must live, "even though
                        Slavery should have to die!" It rests with the Slaveholders--especially
                        those of them who are rich and powerful--to say whether that question shall
                        be so raised and so pressed to a decision. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints an editorial from the New York Tribune stating that there is
                    disagreement over whether the war is to be a war to end slavery. The editor
                    believes that declaring the war for Union a war to end slavery would alienate
                    many Union supporters at the North. On the other hand, it is impossible to
                    guarantee that the war will not affect slavery, since no one can foresee how the
                    slaveholders themselves will act.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports minor actions of the army--movement of troops, etc.--column 4.
                Advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.17.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Outrageous</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday afternoon, a pair of drunken negroes entered the confectionary
                        store of Mrs. Jane Booth on South Main street, and after purchasing a few
                        nick-nacks, proceeded to make themselves quite familiar in their remarks,
                        when the woman requested them to leave the store. They refused to go,
                        stating that in these times every one expressed their opinions, and they
                        would express theirs. They became so outrageous as to draw a pistol and
                        threaten her life. Calling in one of the neighbors, the rascals were driven
                        off, making threats against her, and swearing that they had a right to cut
                        whosoever throat they pleased. A warrant has been issued for their
                    arrest.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Booth</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that two drunken African Americans went into the confectionery
                    store of Mrs. Booth, purchased some "nick-nacks," and then made some "quite
                    familiar" remarks to the storekeeper. They then proceeded to threaten Mrs. Booth
                    with a pistol before being driven off by a neighbor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossart</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Snively</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emmanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>P. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists officers elected for the coming year at a meeting on May 14 of the
                    Farmers and Mechanics Industrial association. James Orr was elected president;
                    Jacob Nixon, James Davidson, Henry Keefer, and William Bossart, vice-presidents;
                    W. S. Everett, recording secretary; Snively Strickler, corresponding secretary;
                    Emmanuel Kuhn, treasurer; and John Ruthrauff, H. B. Davison, J. W. Craig, P. C.
                    Duffield, James G. Elder, John Gillan, Samuel Myers, D. K. Wunderlich, Josiah
                    Besore, A. B. Wingert, H. C. Greenawait, and D. O. Gehr, managers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Regimental Parade and Flag Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stinger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rippey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes a parade through Chambersburg on the previous Wednesday by the
                    7th and 8th regiments station at Camp Sliver. William S. Stinger, on behalf of
                    the ladies of Chambersburg, presented a national flag to the 7th regiment, Col.
                    Rippey also gave a speech, and the band played.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>I. O. of O. F.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Chambersburg and Columbus Lodges were visited last Tuesday by the
                    secretary of the Grand Lodge of Pennsylvania and other high-ranking Lodge
                    officers. The article reports that the Order of Odd Fellows is growing daily
                    more popular, has removed many of its "objectionable features," and is doing
                    good work everywhere.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Brave Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have just been informed of a circumstance which, if true, and our
                        informant is a man of veracity, is not calculated to throw great credit upon
                        either the morals or bravery of some of the troops stationed here.</p>
                    <p>It appears that a few evenings since an old gentleman of our place, having
                        some tenants in the portion of the town known as Wolffstown, went over,
                        accompanied by his son. In one of the houses he found four soldiers to whom
                        he gave some good advice, for which they thanked him. On his return home,
                        the four were standing on the bridge, and as he passed by, one of them made
                        some insulting remark; upon which he turned about and told them they would
                        be much better in camp than there at that time of night. Turning away he
                        received from one of them a blow upon the jaw, which the old gentleman
                        returned under the fellow's chin. After two or three passed of the kind, the
                        brave fellows concluded it best to leave, which they did at a quick march.</p>
                    <p>Soldiers, whose bravery allows them to strike a man old enough, for their
                        grandfather ought to be scarce. What few are here ought to be taught
                    better.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that an older man of Chambersburg was accosted on a bridge in
                    Wolffstown by four soldiers, one of whom insulted him while another struck him
                    "a blow upon the jaw." After a short fight, the soldiers left.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cree</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. S. Everett and Jennie E. Cree, both of Chambersburg, were married on the
                    16th of May.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cobaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James King of Chambersburg and Mrs. Rebecca Cobaugh of Shippensburg
                    were married on the 28th of April.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Wm. D. Senseny, son of Dr. A. H. Senseny, died this morning in
                    Chambersburg at the age of 23, following a lingering illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.17.04">
            <pageNote>Poem, column 1; advertisements, column 2, 3, 4, and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
