<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.10.29">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/23/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-29">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="29">29</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.29.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; article giving the "full particulars" of the
                battle of Ball's Bluff, columns 3-5; article on the federal naval expedition in
                progress, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Speakership</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe&gt;</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proposes that "the current seems to be setting strongly in favor of" the
                    Honorable John Rowe of the Franklin and Fulton district for the next Speaker of
                    the Pennsylvania House of Representatives. Quotes the Reading Journal on the
                    political merits that Rowe would bring to the job.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From Edwards' Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"To attempt to cross a body of 7,500 troops over a river to hostile shores
                    in two or three ordinary flat boats, with every probability of meeting a enemy,
                    in uncertain numbers, whose policy has been sufficiently demonstrated to be that
                    of ambuscades and masked batteries, seems to us little less than
                    fool-hardiness."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the "deplorable mismanagement and reckless and inexcusable
                    carelessness" committed by those who formulated the strategy for transporting
                    the troops involved across the Potomac.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Emancipation</head>
                <origin>Albany Journal</origin>
                <commentary>"The question of emancipation is being discussed by exchanges from all
                    parts of the country at present."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes the Albany Journal as saying that "no man can contemplate violent
                    emancipation without shuddering," but that the government should let the South
                    know that if the Union can be saved by emancipating the slaves, then slavery
                    "must be thrust aside."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Sealed Orders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that orders are now being sealed, so that the members of a regiment
                    do not know their destination when they leave a brigade. This change in policy,
                    the Dispatch speculates, indicates that the General in charge of the Army of the
                    Potomac is preparing for an important campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the new Senate in the Pennsylvania Legislature, according to
                    the Harrisburg Union, will house 23 Republicans and 10 Democrats, and the House
                    will contain 53 Democrats and 47 Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article reporting the completion of the telegraph line to San Francisco,
                column 1; report of the repulse of Zollicoffer and his rebel soldiers by Union
                forces at Camp Wild Cat, column 1; accounts of the battles at Santa Rosa and at the
                mouth of the Mississippi River, columns 3 and 4; news from Missouri, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.29.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Enlarged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Town Council has commissioned an extension to the
                    Friendship Engine House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Beef Contract</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Benjamin S. Kunkle and John L. Metzger of Harrisburg have
                    received a contract for four thousand cattle, "with the privilege of sixteen
                    thousand," from the government. The cattle are to be delivered either at
                    Chambersburg or at Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Reinforcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the arrival in Chambersburg the previous morning of 276 Indiana
                    volunteers. They are on their way from Baltimore to join the 12th Indiana
                    Regiment in the Grand Army of the Potomac.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ripe Strawberries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stokes</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that the garden of Mrs. Elisabeth Stokes has produced a bunch of
                    ripe strawberries of a variety that bears monthly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The First Ice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The first ice of the season, in this locality, was formed on the night of the
                        25th inst. Winter, with all its rigors, is at the door, and although our
                        country is blessed with an abundance of breadstuffs, who can tell the amount
                        of hunger and suffering that will be indured [sic] by the poor before the
                        ear is again saluted by the song of the Spring birds! Owing to the disturbed
                        condition of our national affairs, and the scarcety [sic] of employment
                        resulting therefrom, the approaching winter, doubtless, wears a more
                        terrible appearance to thousands of the children of want than many others
                        did, that are past. Let all, therefore, be as liberal to the deserving poor
                        as their means will permit, and thus prevent want from pressing too
                    heavily.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the first frost of the year formed on the night of October
                    25. Urges readers to be generous to the "deserving poor," since the winter
                    promises to be a difficult one for them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Negley's Brigade</head>
                <origin>Louisville (Ky.) Democrat</origin>
                <commentary>"To keep our readers informed on the whereabouts and doings of this
                    Brigade we take the following from the Louisville (Ky.) Democrat of the 22d
                    inst.:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the arrival of Negley's brigade in six steamers at Louisville and
                    describes the men in the brigade as "finely uniformed and armed," disciplined,
                    and well taken care of.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Another Requisition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the war department has asked Governor Curtin for five
                    companies of heavy artillery, to be commanded by Colonel Anganthe of
                    Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baer</ln>
                        <fn>Ann R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Jacob E. Wingert of Quincy township and Miss Ann R. Baer of New
                    Franklin were married on October 15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiser</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mehaffey</ln>
                        <fn>Susan A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Jeremiah Kiser of Cashtown and Miss Susan A. Mehaffey of Chambersburg
                    were married on October 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-5; brief news items from Missouri and Virginia,
                column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.29.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Rebels Discouraged by Inaction, and Expect a Long War</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A suspicion is gaining ground, that the advantages of our position have
                    not been profited by, as they might have been; that the war has not been
                    prosecuted with the vigor and energy demanded by the emergency."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Indicates that the Confederates are experiencing a crisis of confidence and
                    suggests that the South begin to look for "terms of submission." Argues that a
                    satisfactory treaty cannot be made until the South has destroyed the
                    strategically advantageous position that the North presently occupies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports from the South that its supplies are giving out, column 1; opinions
                from various newspapers about the charges levied against General Fremont, column 1;
                prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
