<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.06.25">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/29/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/24/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-25">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="25">25</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.06.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sunday School Address by the Hero of Fort Sumter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a speech by Brigadier General Anderson to a Sunday school at
                    Cincinnati. Anderson credits God for preserving his safety at Fort Sumter and
                    for directing his actions there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Unemployed at Their Own Door</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Slaves walk the street whose masters can find work neither for hire nor
                    for clothing."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Dispatch points out that Secessionists have repeatedly predicted that
                    war would bring unemployment to northern cities. Yet the article excerpted from
                    the Richmond Examiner reports that five Richmond contains at least five thousand
                    African Americans who lost their employment when the tobacco factories closed or
                    cut their production.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>List of federal, state, and local government officials, column 1;
                advertisements, columns 1 and 2; poem, columns 3 and 4; anecdote about the loyal
                actions of Captain Armstrong's daughter, column 5; anecdote concerning the action
                off Pig's Point, column 5; article from the Cincinnati Gazette concerning the
                "farce" of an election in Tennessee on the secession question, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.06.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>No Tampering with the Tariff</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Congress not to modify or repeal the Morill Tariff at the upcoming
                    special session. Argues that the tariff should be tested in a time of peace
                    before its merits can be examined.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Maryland and Her Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Thus they fume, and fret, and spit their venom round, like their
                    villainous emblem, (the snake) when caught between a forked prong and held
                    secure, and will in the issue sink their poisoned fangs into their own flesh."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Maryland legislature has declared that the state is not
                    responsible for the debt incurred in fighting the war. The legislature has also
                    prevented Governor from disposing of state funds and has formally recognized the
                    Confederacy by a vote of 47 to 4. The Dispatch declares that the legislature of
                    Maryland can do what "villainous" deeds they will, because the governor of the
                    state will keep Maryland safe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Coming Anniversary</head>
                <origin>Forney's Press</origin>
                <commentary>"We notice, in quite a number of our exchanges, articles relating to the
                    coming 4th of July, but none which accords so well with our own inclinations and
                    sense of propriety as an editorial in Forney's Press, of the 22d instant."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"If we are to celebrate this Fourth of July, let us do it by . . . entering
                    into our new and trying period of national existence, determined that before
                    another year, with its changes and its seasons, shall have come and gone, we
                    shall be once more a free, united, and powerful republic."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpt from Forney's Press affirms the decision that no appropriation be
                    made for the celebration of the Fourth of July this year. Argues that Americans
                    should spend their funds and their energy on settling the question of whether
                    the experiment that their ancestors fought to create in 1776 will endure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Secretary Cameron on the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a speech given by the Secretary of War at a dinner of the St.
                    Andrews Society the previous Wednesday. Cameron denounced states' rights,
                    pointed out the foolishness of the South in supposing that the North and West
                    would divide over the question of preserving the Union, and championed the
                    federal government as "the strongest Government to-day in the world."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Brief items of news concerning the war, column 1; short report of a skirmish
                at Independence, Missouri, column 1; articles from Hagerstown (Maryland), Wilmington
                (Delaware), Baltimore, St. Louis, and Cincinnati, columns 4 and 5; proceedings of
                the Wheeling convention, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.06.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the First and Second regiments have left Hagerstown for
                    Frederick, and that the Third is expected to leave today.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Captain Finch of the Eighth Regiment, Company F, wounded his
                    leg by stepping on the butt of a bayonet while drilling his company. The bayonet
                    flew up and struck the calf of his leg, causing a somewhat serious flesh wound.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Capt. Campbell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Captain Charles T. Campbell has formed another company of
                    artillery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>No State Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the State Agricultural Society has decided not to hold a state
                    fair this season because of "the war excitement" and difficult economic times.
                    The Dispatch dismisses state fairs as "extensive humbugs" that benefit only
                    managers and speculators.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Hospital</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that nearly all the people who had been in the hospital at
                    Chambersburg have recovered and that the hospital was moved to Hagerstown the
                    previous day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Martin Smith, Printer, died in Aberdeen, Ohio, on June 10 after a
                    lingering illness. Mr. Smith was a native of Chambersburg and was 59 years of
                    age when he died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheuerman</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Geo. M. Scheuerman, 53 years of age, died on June 20 in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbet</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbet</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Nancy Sibbet died on April 20 near Lexington, Ohio. Mrs. Sibbet was
                    the wife of Samuel Sibbet, Esq., formerly of Funkstown, Franklin County,
                    Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.06.25.04">
            <pageNote>Article relating anecdotes concerning the search for contraband at the Relay
                House, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
