<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.06.28">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/29/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/24/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-06-28">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="28">28</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.06.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Inaugural Address of Mr. Pierpont, the New Governor of Loyal Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We, I repeat, have been driven to assume this position; and now we are but
                    recurring to the great fundamental principles of our fathers, that to the local
                    people of a State belongs the law making power of that State."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints the speech of the governor elected in western Virginia. The
                    governor notes that those who have previously governed Virginia have believed
                    the propertied, educated classes should make the decisions in the state. It is
                    these leaders, the "usurpers of the South," who have driven Virginia to secede.
                    Now, Pierpont asserts, loyal Virginians are reclaiming the power of all the
                    people to make the law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Gen. Scott's Plan</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts the opinion of the Washington correspondent for the New York
                    Tribune, who believes that General Scott has no long-range plan for winning the
                    war. Presently, the correspondent argues, the troops around Washington are there
                    simply to defend the capital. But he thinks the present plans will be modified
                    before the fall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>List of national, state, and local government officials, column 1;
                advertisements, columns 1-3; poem, column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.06.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Items of News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Various news briefs concerning the war, including information that Hugh
                    Brenan, a private in company F of the 24th Pennsylvania regiment, was arrested
                    and "will probably be shot" for attempting to shoot the day officer, Captain
                    Thomas Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Peace Propositions</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"That no such infamous scheme, as that contemplated in the first dispatch,
                    be permitted to be carried into effect, demands the most watchful care of the
                    loyal people of the nation."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints two dispatches from Washington. The first reports that the
                    "Rebels" have advanced a proposition for peace that requires recognition of the
                    Southern Confederacy by the federal government, along with a treaty of commerce
                    and friendship. The second denies that the South has offered any such
                    proposition and that "the traitors intend to push the war to the bitter end."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The McClellan-McMagoffin Treaty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The time has come, when the dignity and power of the General Government
                    must be asserted and maintained as supreme over all State Governments."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints the agreement made between General McClellan and General Buckner
                    of Kentucky, whereby Kentucky will enforce the laws of the United States on its
                    soil. By the agreement, Kentucky will be compelled to remove Southern troops
                    from the state if they manage to occupy it. If Kentucky is unable to accomplish
                    the removal of Southern forces, they must call on the United States government
                    to do so. The Dispatch is in accord with President Lincoln's decision to
                    repudiate this agreement, because the Dispatch believes that the government
                    should not be required to ask permission to enter a state. In addition, the
                    editor states Governor Magoffin of Kentucky is attempting to fool the government
                    with this stance of neutrality. The editor fears that, once Magoffin has
                    gathered troops, he may well declare that "Kentucky has changed her mind" and
                    has decided to join the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Proclamation of Gen. McClellan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Take nothing, destroy nothing, unless you are ordered to do so by the
                    general officers. . . . Show to the world that you differ from our enemies in
                    these points of honor, honesty and respect for private opinion, and that we
                    inaugurate no reign of terror where we go."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints orders by General McClellan to his troops that they should bring
                    into battle the "highest and noblest qualities of soldiers' discipline--courage
                    and mercy." The soldiers under his command should remember that they have the
                    upper hand morally over those they will fight, and, therefore, they should show
                    mercy to their disarmed foe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Contrabands to Go to Hayti</head>
                <origin>Washington Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is probably that Congress, at its approaching session, will place means in
                        the hands of the President for the colonization in Hayti, and elsewhere, of
                        such of our colored people as may desire to emigrate. Such a measure seems
                        to be demanded by the new exigencies. As it would only contemplate the
                        aiding of voluntary emigration, it would quiet any sensitiveness in relation
                        to a too sudden and great increase of our free negro population. No question
                        of constitutionality can be raised, as the war power covers the case.</p>
                    <p>Of course, large discretion must be left to the President as to the place or
                        places, to be colonized. Available places are numerous and not remote. Hayti
                        alone would perhaps be able to receive all the colonists who would offer
                        themselves.</p>
                    <p>The expense would'nt [sic] be formidable. From military "lines" established
                        near Charleston, Savannah, Mobile, New Orleans, &amp;c., into which the
                        contraband negroes would flock, they might be "sluiced off" to St. Domingo
                        or Central America, with great rapidity and economy.</p>
                    <p>This is upon the supposition that it becomes necessary to carry this war to
                        the Gulf, as must be the case if the traitors continue obstinate. But even
                        if the war terminates with the pacification of Virginia, the number of
                        negroes desiring to be colonized must be large enough to require national
                            interposition.--<emph rend="italic">Washington Republican</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speculates that Congress will give the president the means to send to Haiti
                    any African Americans of the North who wish to go.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Proceedings of the Wheeling convention, column 3; report of destruction of
                property by the South at Baltimore, column 3; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.06.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lieut. Col. Bowman and Mr. Chase</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Bowman and Chase are rumored to have been taken to Richmond
                    and that they will soon be released on parole. Their friends have made efforts
                    to have them exchanged.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Drowned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the death of James Mifflin of Shippensburg, an government teamster
                    who drowned in the Potomac River near Williamsport.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Serious Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a farmer, Powell Leap, living near Chambersburg was riding
                    atop the load when hauling hay and fell off backward by a sudden jolt. The
                    Dispatch reports that "his chest was represented to us as twice its natural
                    size." Though Leap was still alive when the paper went to press, he was not
                    expected to live.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of Another Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A volunteer from Pittsburgh, a member of the 3d Regiment, died on last
                        Tuesday evening, of Typhoid fever, at the house of Mr. F. Deatrich of this
                        place. The deceased was a German, 19 years old, named Charles Sitzler. His
                        mother arrived on last Saturday and remained with him untill [sic] his
                        death. Being very poor the railroad companies granted her a free pass both
                        ways, and on Tuesday morning she left for her home taking with her the
                        remains of her son. The funeral arrangements were attended to be Mr. J.
                        Hoke. The poor woman, upon leaving, could not express in words her gratitude
                        to him, and as the car was starting, she, with tears in her eyes, signaled
                        to him and pointed upward. The sight was affecting, and the meaning not to
                        be misunderstood.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of a German soldier from Pittsburgh, Charles Sitzler of
                    the Third Regiment. Sitzler died of typhoid fever in the house of Mr. F.
                    Deatrich of Chambersburg. The funeral arrangements were made by Mr. J. Hoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Retreat from Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A man from this place, who had been impressed in the Southern army, and who
                        was in the retreat from Harper's Ferry, has made his escape, bringing his
                        Southern uniform and the sight off his rifle, as trophies. His account of
                        the retreat we give in his own peculiar style. He says:</p>
                    <p>"When the news came that a large force was coming against us, we were all in
                        confusion, and then you ought to have seen the boys <emph rend="italic"
                            >gitting</emph>. While on the retreat word was brought that the enemy
                        was not following us and had gone back again; then, said he, we all came
                        back to the Ferry again. Word was again brought us that they were coming
                        again in still larger numbers than before. You should have seen them <emph
                            rend="italic">git then!</emph>" </p>
                    <p>It would appear from this statement, that the peace policy of Jeff. Davis was
                        rather involuntary on his part.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of the retreat from Harper's Ferry given by a Chambersburg
                    soldier who had been impressed into the Confederate army and had recently
                    escaped.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William McLellan, Esq., of Chambersburg and Major John Rowe of Greencastle
                    have distributed clothing to the soldiers encamped at Hagerstown to replace the
                    inferior clothing furnished by the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Religious Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Reverend James Mackey of Shippensburg will preach "in
                    the Bethel" at the corner of Queen and Water streets the following Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Capt. Doubleday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Captain Doubleday has been promoted to Major.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Grass Cutting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Grass cutting season is here, and our farmers are busily engaged in
                        making hay. The weather is highly propitious and it is thought the yield
                        will be plentiful and good. Wheat is begining [sic] to put on a golden
                        appearanc [sic]. Soon will the Harvest Home be celebrated in Franklin
                        County, and never perhaps, with greater cause for thankfulness for an
                        abundant crop.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarks that the grass cutting season has arrived and that farmers are busy
                    making hay.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fire in Greencastle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a fire on the previous Monday afternoon in Greencastle
                    completely destroyed the foundry building and nearly all its contents. In
                    addition, the blaze consumed two houses, causing a total of $12,500 in damages.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Hospital Cases</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Saml.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyster</ln>
                        <fn>Chas.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfkill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrick</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that several citizens took into their homes people still remaining
                    in the hospital on the previous Monday. Samuel Myers, Judge Chambers, Mrs.
                    Wolfkill, D. Trostle, and F. Deatrich each took in one, while Charles Oyster,
                    Jr., took in three, and A. H. McCulloh took in two. Dr. A. H. Senseny was the
                    attending physician.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.06.28.04">
            <pageNote>Reprint of an ordinance for the reorganization of Virginia's state government,
                column 1; prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
