<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.07.12">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/1/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-12">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="12">12</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.12.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, column 1; poem, column 2; proceedings of Congress, columns
            2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Hon. John Cessna</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the recent nominating convention of the Bedford County
                    Democratic party for failing to make clear declarations of loyalty to the Union.
                    The Honorable John Cessna, reports the Dispatch, was voted out of the party
                    after introducing resolutions that tried to breathe "a spirit of patriotism and
                    loyalty to the Union" into the convention. The Dispatch commends Cessna for
                    being a "patriotic and honest man" and denounces the convention for voting down
                    his resolutions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Philadelphia Inquirer and the Secretary of War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rebukes the Philadelphia Inquirer for reporting incidents of corruption in
                    the War Department. The Dispatch remarks that Breckenridge Democratic papers
                    have quoted these charges as true without questioning them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gov. Pierpont's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summary of the message of Governor Pierpont of Virginia, in which he "takes
                    high and patriotic ground" by promoting the war against the rebellion. Pierpont
                    maintains that there has long existed a secret organization in the South whose
                    object was to overthrow the federal government. He suggests that "the cry of
                    danger to the institution of Slavery has been a mere pretext to rouse and excite
                    the people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Army Not Marauders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces new orders issued by General Patterson that prescribe death to
                    any soldier "who shall quit his post or colors for the purpose of plunder and
                    pillage."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"Malice"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under the above caption the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> copies,
                        and thus endorses, a very dirty little article from the Carlisle <emph
                            rend="italic">Volunteer</emph>. We do not refer to this fire-cracker
                        article because there is any common sense in it, but merely to show the kind
                        of mental food the readers of these papers are supplied with; and, if
                        possible, induce the publishers to issue something a little more edifying
                        and truthful. We could not think of inserting the whole piece into our
                        columns, but, as a sample, give the following comments upon a quotation from
                        Mr. Forney, who is able to take good care of himself:</p>
                    <p>"Good lick, John--'cute,' and no mistake. We think this will secure you a
                        re-election. But what malignancy! Mr. Buchanan--a man with more patriotism
                        in his big toe than is possessed by the entire Lincoln Administration, the
                        'Kitchen Cabinet' included--to be accused of having entertained a design to
                        destroy the Government he loves so well!"</p>
                    <p>The traitor we despise, the dupe we pity; but whether most to despise or pity
                        the authors and circulators of such consummate hypocrisy and spleen, is
                        rather undecided with us. Under ordinary circumstances, we could make
                        allowance for the blinding effect of party zeal, but when such flings are
                        uncalled for by any consideration and entirely out of place, we feel
                        indignant at the malevolence it betrays. And when we reflect that our
                        present political troubles have been brought upon us by the intimate friends
                        and advisers of this same Buchanan; winked at and screened by him until a
                        whole nation were ready almost to seize him and drag him by force out of the
                        Presidential chair; who, while sworn to preserve inviolate the public
                        property of the United States, permitted State after State to proclaim their
                        withdrawal from the Union, steal forts and arsenals, mints and treasuries;
                        and whose damning guilt is now proclaimed over the entire civilized
                        world;--we then realize how stupid the intellect or how base the designs of
                        such rodomontadors.</p>
                    <p>The publication of such articles is insulting to the common sense of the
                        readers of these papers, and afford a very strong commentary upon the
                        suspected patriotism of the authors as well as retailers of such miserable
                        twaddle.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chastizes the Valley Spirit for printing an article criticizing the Lincoln
                    Administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of a "desperate battle in Missouri," column 3; brief articles of news
                from Baltimore, Washington, and Georgia, columns 3 and 4; advertisements, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that two more regiments passed through town the previous Wednesday
                    night, on their way to "the seat of War."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Noble Harvest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that farmers in and around Chambersburg have been harvesting the
                    heaviest wheat crop in memory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Chambersburgers Visiting Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the men from Chambersburg listed above are on a trip to
                    Washington and are visiting various camps around the city. They plan to follow
                    the army into the interior of Virginia if the troops depart on a campaign before
                    the men return home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Habeas Corpus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the counsel for George Heckerdorn filed and lost a writ of
                    habeas corpus before Judge Kimmel the previous Tuesday. Heckerdorn was charged
                    as a principal in the killing of "the negro Jones" some time ago.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Camp Followers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "certain" people, some "from our own neighborhood," have been
                    following the Union army into Virginia. The Dispatch passes on the information
                    that these people are being closely watched and will be "dealt with" according
                    to the standard procedures of war if they are caught stealing anything.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Knights of the Golden Circle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a portion of an article from the Harrisburg Telegraph that repeats
                    a rumor claiming that a lodge of the Knights of the Golden Circle, a
                    "treasonable order," exists in Harrisburg. The Dispatch urges an inquiry
                    throughout the state into whether there are members of this order in
                    communication with Southern "co-conspirators."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the condition of Chambersburg troops stationed at Martinsburg as
                    "excellent." Reports that the troops have enlisted for three months and would
                    like to return to Chambersburg after that time, but will probably re-enlist for
                    three years after a short stay at home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Contrabands in Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A letter from Fortress Monroe says: "The ebony 'contrabands' are everywhere
                        to be seen, and make themselves generally useful. General Butler has
                        seventeen to wait upon his table (so the story goes), and they are liberally
                        attached to the various departments. The one to whom skill my boots owe
                        their extravagant polish says his master left him, and he had no alternative
                        but to come to the fortress. He thinks the cause of the North eminently
                        just, and agrees with one of his dark companions in expressing an earnest
                        desire that Jeff. Davis may be roasted alive. The contraband women and
                        children occupy an old house near the fortress and laugh and sing away the
                        long warm days in blissful ignorance of the magnitude of the contest of
                        which their race is the innocent cause."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpt from a letter written from Fortress Monroe giving an account of the
                    presence of slaves who have run away to the fort, referred to as "contrabands."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.12.04">
            <pageNote>Proceedings of Congress continued from page 1 printed in column 1; prices
                current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
