<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.07.19">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/2/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-19">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="19">19</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.19.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; proceedings of extra session of Congress, columns
                4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Free Speech and a Free Press</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that free speech must not be curtailed in hopes of stopping public
                    pronouncements of support for the rebellion in the North. The Dispatch maintains
                    that it was not the exercise of free speech, but the poor choice of elected
                    officials that led to war. To preserve the Union, it is necessary to protect
                    freedom of speech and freedom of the press, not to "make words treason."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rapid and Effective</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The country is beginning to realize some of the good fruits of placing the
                        right men in the right places in the rapid and effective movements of Gen.
                        G. B. M'Clellan. Within less than one week he has met and vanquished, a
                        rebel force of at least 10,000 men under Gen. Garnett, putting his
                        detachments to rout in three several engagements, capturing at one time two
                        or three hundred prisoner, forcing the unconditional surrender of about six
                        hundred men under Col. Pegram at another, and winding up with an other
                        engagement where Gen. Garnett heads the rebels, in person, in which Garnett
                        is killed, over one thousand prisoners taken with all the cannon, camp
                        equipage, besides a great number of horses, leaving not even the stump of an
                        army remaining to the foe. His triumphant message to head quarters is, "Our
                        success is complete, and Secession is killed in this part of the country."</p>
                    <p>Such are the men, and such the movements which are destined to re-establish,
                        throughout the broad expanse of our beloved land, the sacred principles of
                        Human Rights and Human Equality, and we verily, begin to feel more than ever
                        confident that "when this war shall be brought to a close, that, no cause of
                        war shall exist." After our army of Liberty shall have performed its
                        mission, Statesmen from North and South shall meet in days past, but without
                        the haughty insolence displayed, which for years past has been the wont of
                        many Southern Congressmen towards the Northern, who scracely [sic] dared
                        oftimes to call himself the peer of him whose servants said "my master."</p>
                    <p>These days are gone. The Northern Statesman no more shall bow his neck to
                        such disgrace. They will henceforth meet as equals, acknowledged, and as
                        such respected.</p>
                    <p>Push then the battle forward. Let no back step be taken until no traitor
                        dares to pollute the common atmosphere with the poison of his
                        influence--until the Snake, Secession, stings itself to death.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that, because of the great leaders the country has chosen in men
                    like General McClellan, statesmen will meet in Congress as equals once the North
                    has won the war and the Union has been preserved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Apprehension of Danger to General Scott</head>
                <origin>Knoxville Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is recklessness enough among them to perpetrate worse crimes than
                    even the assassination of General Scott."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Dispatch offers agreement with a prediction given by the Knoxville Whig
                    that General Scott will be assassinated because he is so adept at military
                    strategy. The Dispatch expresses little surprise that members of the rebel army
                    might attempt such an action.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Are the Rebels Cowards?</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary>"The above from the Phil. Bulletin, is full of truth, justice and common
                    sense."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The soldiers of the rebel army have run at Philippi, at Romney, at Falling
                        Waters, at Rich Mountain and everywhere else. It really looks as if they
                        were all cowards and not fit to fight with brave men. General McClellan was
                        not far wrong when, in one of his proclamations, he expressed regret that
                        his soldiers would not find "foemen worthy of their steel." It has been
                        suggested here that the mystic letters of the Virginians, F. F. V., really
                        mean Fast Flying Virginians.</p>
                    <p>But we cannot allow that the Southerners are cowards. It would be a reproach
                        to our own blood, and to the race from which we and they have sprung. In a
                        good cause they have fought and will always fight as bravely as any men in
                        the world. Some of them are perhaps sincere in their faith in the excellence
                        of their cause. But we know that many are not; that thousands of their men
                        have been impressed, or have enlisted for fear of injury if they did not
                        enlist. When an army thus composed finds itself face to face with a body of
                        loyal troops, and is called on to fight against the glorious Stars and
                        Stripes, is it any wonder that the hearts of the men fail them, and that the
                        enormity of the crime they are engaged in is for the first time felt to such
                        a degree, that they fly or surrender? Let us not jeer at the rebels as
                        cowards. The weakness they show may be the first sign of returning loyalty.</p>
                    <p>The above, from the Phil. <emph rend="italic">Bulletin</emph>, is full of
                        truth, justice and common sense. History doe not write Americans as Cowards
                        whether of Northern or Southern birth, and had it not been for the
                        vainglorious boasting of certain braggadocio Southern papers, and speakers,
                        their own bravery would never have been called in question.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes the idea that rebel soldiers are cowardly, even though they have
                    run on a number of occasions when faced with the Union troops in battle. The
                    Bulletin argues that a substantial number of Southern soldiers have been
                    impressed or have enlisted for fear of sustaining injury if they did not, and
                    therefore what seems cowardice may simply be their hidden loyalty to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Havelocks a Failure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Includes an excerpt from the Harrisburg Daily Telegraph complaining that
                    the head gear presently worn by Pennsylvania soldiers renders them conspicuous
                    to the enemy and interferes with their hearing and their. The Dispatch adds that
                    these "havelocks" are uncomfortable, and the wearer is "made to resemble an
                    overgrown monkey." Suggests a hat with a stiff brim and ventilation holes are
                    around as a replacement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Revival of Trade in Philadelphia</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Evening Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The leading editorial in the Philadelphia Evening Bulletin of the 6th
                    contains information of a cheering character, respecting the revival of trade in
                    that city."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The leading editorial in the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Evening
                            Bulletin</emph> of the 16th contains information of a cheering
                        character, respecting the revival of trade in that city. The writer says:</p>
                    <p>"The signs of recovery from the paralysis produced by the first shock of war
                        are multiplying. Business of every kind is reviving, stocks are going up;
                        manufacturers are stirring themselves with a view to more active operations;
                        some branches are more busily employed than ever, owing to the necessities
                        created by the war; the farmers are all busy gathering in a splendid crop;
                        there are signs of a pretty good fall trade in our mercantile circles,
                        partly the result of this great crop--these, and the exhilerating [sic] news
                        of victories to the Federal arms and demoralization and disaffection in the
                        ranks of the rebels, are restoring public confidence, and, confidence once
                        restored, half the mischief of a business panic is undone and repaired.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines areas in which the economy has been seen to be prospering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>End of Congressional proceedings, column 1; report of union victory at
                Huttensville in western Virginia, arrival of troops at Fairfax courthouse, column 4;
                other minor news items pertaining to the war, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.19.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Funeral of a Volunteer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfkill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death on Tuesday morning of the soldier who had been lying sick
                    of typhoid fever at the home of Mrs. Wolfkill. His name was George W. Cressinger
                    of Derry, Westmoreland County. Due to the rapidly decomposing state of the body,
                    he was buried in Chambersburg the following morning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Got a Prize and Off for Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A uniformed individual, of the colored persuasion, passed through our place
                        on last Sunday, riding a very fine horse and bearing with him a carbine and
                        holster pistol, exciting considerable curiosity among our people. On being
                        questioned it was found that he had been with the 8th regiment in the
                        character of a servant to one of the officers; that when the "Chivalry" took
                        prisoners those 43 Union men who mistook them for friends, he was about: and
                        seeing a ready saddled horse with a carbine strapped to him, "lying around
                        loose," concluded, a horse was no use without a rider, and so, jumped upon
                        him and was making for home as fast as possible.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that an African-American man dressed in uniform passed through
                    Chambersburg the previous Sunday. The man had been a servant to one of the
                    officers of the Eighth Regiment and was on his way home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How the Rebels Obtain Information</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces criticism made of Northern papers for publishing the "earliest
                    intelligence" about the movement of Northern troops. The Dispatch argues that
                    these papers are not the means by which rebels learn of Northern strategy. In
                    fact, they learn through spying, as dispatches from Baltimore indicate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branthaver</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susannah Branthaver, aged 60 years, died near Jackson Hall on July 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diener</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Barbara Diener, aged 47 years, died near Grindstone Hill Church on
                    July 10.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.19.04">
            <pageNote>Anecdotes from the Chicago Journal and Harper's Drawer, column 1; prices
                current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
