<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.05.21">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>4/30/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/23/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-21">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="21">21</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.05.21.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Patriotic Speech of Maj. Gen. Butler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Butler's speech extols the loyalty and patriotism of citizens from
                    Massachusetts. Residents of the Commonwealth love the Union as well as they do
                    their state, and they are willing to risk bloodshed to preserve the Union whose
                    independence their fathers fought to gain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>How Sumter Was Provisioned</head>
                <origin>Milwaukee Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes how the "traitor Floyd" arranged for Fort Sumter to be
                    defenseless against the South Carolinians, making it also dependent on supplies
                    from Charleston every few days. But Colonel Gardiner managed to provision the
                    fort from Fort Moultrie without Floyd knowing about it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.05.21.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Work of God</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The mighty uprisings of the people, and tremendous outburst of patriotism
                        throughout the entire North, can only be explained upon the hypothesis, that
                        agencies more than human are at work amongst us. Love of country has burst
                        so suddenly and sublimely upon us, that the most sanguine have been
                        surprised and amazed. Where was supposed to exist one patriot, a host has
                        sprung up. The weak and sickly man has become a very Ajax; and even of the
                        stones, God has raised up children unto Abraham. There is no fear manifested
                        as to the result of the conflict. Faith in the Divinity "shaping our ends"
                        has displaced all doubts, and the inspiration of every one is patriotism.
                        Upon this subject, "Occasional," correspondent of Forney's <emph
                            rend="italic">Press</emph> remarks:</p>
                    <p>"Some of the triumphs of the new revelation that has fallen upon our people
                        are nearly inexplicable. The instant extinction of party feeling is novel
                        enough; the patriotism of the women, natural always, but now sublime; the
                        bravery of the men, from the priest to the publican, from sire to son, would
                        be explained by other causes if it were not so universal and all-pervading.
                        But when you see the miser unlocking his coffers and giving his hoards to
                        his country, flags flying from churches of every creed, and whole
                        populations giving up work and rushing into the army, may we not feel that
                        we are in the hands of God , and that He has become our Protector and our
                        President?</p>
                    <p>"I have been present at some extraordinary meetings during the last six
                        weeks, particularly since Sumpter [sic] fell. The spirit that moved them was
                        not patriotism merely--it was a religious phrenzy [sic]. The songs that were
                        sung were songs of liberty; and not by one, but by all. The Star Spangled
                        Banner has become quite a chant and a chorus everywhere. It is hymned in
                        churches, shouted in taverns, sounded in the streets, and made familiar to
                        the lips of beauty and the lisp of childhood. There is joy and harmony at
                        all these meetings, and a gratitude for blessings received and realized that
                        calls tears from the strongest men, and makes the orator almost a clergyman.
                            <emph rend="italic">As to party feeling, he who shows it is shunned like
                            a plague.</emph> We have forgotten all of the past save that which
                        teaches to love our country, and look only upon the future to save and fight
                        for her." </p>
                    <p>We hail with gratitude and delight all such noble and patriotic sentiments.
                        Coming from people and newspapers of, heretofore, various and opposing
                        political opinion, as well as religious and the more conservative, our cause
                        must prevail, and the designs of Providence in thus visiting us, must be
                        those of ultimate and substantial good.</p>
                    <p>"Then conquer we must, for our cause is just, <lb/> And this be our
                        motto:--In God is our trust, <lb/> And the Star-spangled Banner in triumph
                        shall wave <lb/> O'er the land of the free and the home of the brave!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses agreement with Forney's Press that God has helped to inspire
                    patriotism and enthusiasm for the Union cause among Northerners. Comments on the
                    surprising and uncommon "love of country" that has "burst so suddenly and
                    sublimely" upon Northern men and women.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"Knapsacks for Democrats"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under the above caption the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph>, of the
                        17th, copies a very invidious article, taken by the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Luzerne Union</emph> from the <emph rend="italic">N. Y. Daily
                        News</emph>, with some editorial of the <emph rend="italic">Union</emph>. We
                        are pained to see a disposition on the part of any portion of the public
                        press to create a spirit of jealousy and heartburning among our countrymen,
                        and especially among our brave volunteers. Even if every word were true as
                        stated, the bare publication of such articles in times likes this, shows
                        that in the minds of the writer and publisher exist a want of knowledge and
                        appreciation of the perils through which our country is now passing--a
                        disbelief of the truth regarding the ends and aims of the Traitor Government
                        at Montgomery--or a reckless and criminal disregard for the welfare of the
                        nation; the maintenance of our Union undivided; the vindication of the
                        supremacy of all our constitutional laws, and the preservation of our civil
                        and religious liberties. If the latter, then open traitors are, in
                        comparison, honest men. Davis, Rhett, Yancey and Wigfall, are higher in the
                        scale of morality, and no lower in that of treason, than such writers and
                        such publishers. If this is so--and who can deny it?--how much lower must
                        sink the man who, for party purposes, when our country is bleeding at every
                        pore; when barely convalescent from an attack which started the death-sweat
                        upon its brow, would knowingly and wilfully [sic] give currency to slanders
                        calculated to wound that agonized country deeper in the house of its
                        friends.</p>
                    <p>The following we quote from the article mentioned:</p>
                    <p>We have it from data which we deem perfectly reliable, that of the regiment
                        from Luzerne, commanded by Col. Emley, there are but 57 Republicans in the
                        ranks out of nearly 800 men.</p>
                    <p>This regiment being stationed here, a reliable gentleman, wishing to test the
                        statement, found one company in it that contained 60 persons who had
                        heretofore acted with the Republican party, and another contained 65. He
                        concluded it was not necessary to proceed any further in the search. We
                        think not. As for the appointments of Generals, Colonels, Majors, on down,
                        it is altogether unnecessary to name any. The whole thing is degrading and
                        insulting to the good sense and knowledge of our people.</p>
                    <p>To the honest indignation of every country-loving and country-sustaining
                        citizen, we leave these offenders. We sincerely hope a better spirit may be
                        infused into them; better motives actuate them; and for their own welfare as
                        well as for the welfare of our whole people, their future publications may
                        not be blemished by the dissemination of such incendiary and pernicious
                        articles.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains about an article in the Valley Spirit that claims 57 out of 800
                    men in a particular regiment supported the Republican party before the war. The
                    editor writes that such partisanship is only detrimental to the cause of Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.05.21.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Officers affiliated with Camp Slifer have unanimously agreed to enter the
                    service for three years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fugitive Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On last Saturday a colored woman was arrested in this place by constable M.
                        W. Houser, on charge of being a runaway slave. The case had a hearing before
                        P. Hammond, Esq., who remanded her to prison for a further hearing.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A black woman was arrested in Chambersburg last Saturday, charged with
                    being a runaway slave. She was remanded to prison for a further hearing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Arrest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brig. Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Judge Mason of Hagerstown was arrested on Saturday for being a spy. He was
                    released, however, after insufficient proof was offered that he was a
                    secessionist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Movement of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A source has reported that troops stationed at Chambersburg may be moved
                    shortly, perhaps within a day or two.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Camp Instructor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hershberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Governor Curtin will soon appoint several camp instructors to teach the
                    Pennsylvania regiments in the drill, including Major Herschberger of
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Visit of Gov. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On Saturday, Governor Curtin and his staff visited Chambersburg. The
                    governor was met by General Williams of the 7th regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Soldiers' Health</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Copied from Hall's Journal of Health, this list of recommendations advises
                    soldiers on precautions they can take to remain healthy (and, in some cases,
                    alive) while at war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yoe</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddle</ln>
                        <fn>Ariana R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Benjamin R. Yoe, merchant from Baltimore, and Miss Ariana R. Riddle of
                    Chambersburg were married on the 16th of May.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>Robert T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. K.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reverend George K. Harper, aged 48, died in Gatesville, North Carolina,
                    after a lingering illness. Nixon was a native of Chambersburg, where he learned
                    the printing business from the late George Harper before going into the ministry
                    of the Methodist Episcopal church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>General Orders, No. 10</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Establishes new orders for the Sabbath. No companies will be permitted to
                    leave the base, and all soldiers are urged to attend a religious service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.05.21.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2, 3, 4, and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
