<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.07.02">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/29/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-02">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Header indicates that it was published on Friday, July 2, but July 2 was a
            Tuesday.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>New Orleans Despotism</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints article from London Times reporting that British subjects in New
                    Orleans have been impressed into "voluntary" service for the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The French Ambulance System</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A number of medical gentlemen met lately in New York to discuss the medical
                        equipment necessary for an army. Drawings were produced of an ambulance,
                        made after the latest pattern used in the French army in Algeria and the
                        Crimea. The ambulance is an omnibus-shaped vehicle, to be drawn by two or
                        more horses, weighing some 1200 pounds, but constructed in such a manner
                        that it may be easily detached, separated in several pieces in the interior,
                        the most important portion can be easily carried by several men. The
                        interior is, when fully standing, a row of beds, carrying six or eight men,
                        with great ease, but when crowded, may be forced to transport three times
                        that number. Each bed is a "field stretcher," or portable cot, which takes
                        the wounded man from the field, and without any fatiguing change places him
                        in this portable hospital. An India rubber bath is also attached.</p>
                    <p>The ambulance system is the result of Napoleon's great surgeon volunteered
                        more freely, exposed their bodies with less thought, when they knew that
                        there was an effective medical cops to attend in case of accident or injury.
                        What if they received a ball or a bayonet thrust--pain to be sure, for which
                        they cared little--but their surgeon could extract it, and in a few weeks or
                        months they were well, and it was a distinction ever after. With an
                        effective ambulance, they would undertake any march, knowing that, if
                        over-fatigued, there they would be received, and not left on the road, to be
                        killed by any thieving camp follower.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the ambulance system being used by France in Algeria and the
                    Crimea is being considered by medical personnel in the United States. The French
                    maintain that soldiers are more willing to take risks in battle when they know
                    that there is effective medical treatment available for them if wounded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>List of government officeholders, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-3; poem,
                column 4; items of news, column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Mutterings of Trouble</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"As the physical world requires the scathing lightning, the destructive
                    tornado, and even the overwhelming volcano and devastating earthquake, to purify
                    the miasmatic atmosphere and render earth the suitable abode of man, so it has
                    come to pass in the political history of our nation."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Bane and Antidote.</p>
                    <p>Regarding a modification of the Tariff, at the approaching extra session of
                        Congress, we presented our views in a former issue. There is another and
                        mare [sic] serious danger menacing us; one, compared to which Tariff
                        modifications, and all other questions of mere political economy, sink into
                        utter insignificance. This deadly foe, like its most fitting prototype,
                        appears in the garb of an Angle of Light, and assumes the beneficent name of
                            Compromise--<emph rend="italic">Compromise with Traitors</emph>. The
                        leaders of Rebellion, amazed and confounded at the grand display of loyalty
                        ready to meet and foil them in their ignominious attempt at the subversion
                        of popular Liberty, are seeking, by means of Northern sympathisers, to bring
                        about a compromise, by which their necks may be saved the painful
                        application of the hempen cravat which begins so ominously to loom up before
                        their affrighted vision. Sorrowful indeed are we, that devastating and
                        merciless civil war should become a necessity to our future peace and
                        national freedom. But so it is. The die has been cast, and cast by the very
                        men who now would fain [sic] compromise, and for our nation now to accede to
                        any propositions of peace short of an entire yielding on the part of the
                        Rebels, and the prompt punishment of the leading spirits among them, would
                        entail upon our country and the world a curse which for its baneful effects
                        would far eclipse any war the world has ever known. The evils of war are but
                        temporary, these would be lasting. And indeed the war will doubtless be
                        followed with such results as will prove of momentous good instead of evil. </p>
                    <p>As the physical world requires the scathing lightning, the destructive
                        tornado, and even the overwhelming volcano and devastating earthquake, to
                        purify the miasmatic atmosphere and render earth the suitable abode of man,
                        so it has come to pass in the political history of our nation. The
                        atmosphere of Washington has long been surcharged with the accumulations of
                        venality and corruption. Plotters have been for years busy in secret
                        conclave, ready to seize a nation's liberties that they might fill the cup
                        of their own ambition; within a few short months treason stalked abroad
                        there and elsewhere, not caring for even the covering of night, and
                        eschewing as useless its wonted costume of Hypocrisy. Sitting in the seat of
                        Power, under the plea of Justice, it dealt the fiercest blows upon the
                        upholders of constitutional liberty: under the guise of Patriotism,
                        inflicted the severest penalties upon the upholders of true freedom: and,
                        under the pretext of law and order, reduced violence to a system, and placed
                        a premium upon crime. Thank God, their end has almost come. Palsied and
                        powerless, their last despairing cry is heard--"Let us alone." But no! a
                        free people, inspired of Heaven, demand the utter destruction of even the
                        elements of Treason. Woe to the hypocritical mocker, that shall attempt to
                        foist upon us such a barefaced imposture as a compromise with Treason and
                        Rebellion. Incensed and outraged Liberty has roused herself from the
                        temporary lethargy into which she had fallen. With one hand she bears aloft
                        the Stars and Stripes, with the other she grapples the throat of Treason.
                        Speedily will the unequal contest be decided. Her foe must die, and his
                        abettors will be crushed in his downfall. With her foot upon her prostrate
                        foe, she will gather her rejoicing children to her banquet, and the feast
                        will be Universal Freedom.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges that the North must not compromise with perpetrators of "Treason and
                    Rebellion," but must fight to the end so that justice is done and "Universal
                    Freedom" is secured.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Forneys Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Declares that rumors reporting that the South has offered the North
                    proposals for a compromise are false and that, regardless, the North should
                    never compromise with "the traitors." Instead, the Union should put down the
                    rebellion, a feat they have the power and the will to accomplish.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Startling News from Virginia</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"The following extracts from a letter, purporting to have been written
                    by Hon. John M. Botts, was published in the New York Tribune of last Friday. On
                    Saturday, however, the Tribune stated its belief that the letter was a forgery.
                    As a matter of news, we give the extracts, and await further development
                    respecting its authorship and authenticity:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extracts from the letter report that, if the Confederates do not raise one
                    hundred thousand men in the coming six weeks, they will be ruined. In addition,
                    the letter says that troops in Virginia are occupied with putting down
                    rebellions by African Americans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter from the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Correspondence of the Semi-Weekly Dispatch.</p>
                    <p>The following letter was sent us by a young townsman, of company A, 2d
                        Regiment Pennsylvania Volunteers:</p>
                    <p>Camp Spielman, June 26, 1861.</p>
                    <p>As nothing of note has occurred since we left Camp Chambers, I have not
                        thought it worth while writing. We are encamped on a farm belonging to the
                        Messrs. Speilman, fourteen miles south of Hagerstown, and directly along the
                        Sharpsburg pike. All the boys are in good spirits, and are getting along a
                        great deal better than they expected. Our regiment is not ashamed to cope
                        with any volunteer regiment in the Union in drill and appearance. Now that
                        we have received new pantaloons, of light blue, our appearance is greatly
                        improved.</p>
                    <p>Last night the picket fired nine times, one shot killing a young man
                        belonging to the neighborhood. He passed the picket, but would not halt,
                        when the guard fired on him, ending fatally to the young farmer. The boys
                        were up in a second when the picket fired, and were very anxious for a
                        brush. Few men of course feel disposed to rush recklessly into the very jaws
                        of death, but "conquer or die" is the universal motto among us. While I am
                        writing, the booming of Capt. Doubleday's cannon is faintly heard. Something
                        must be going on--"bully for that!"</p>
                    <p>Yesterday evening the regulars captured a spy dressed in female apparel,
                        while we were marching from Funkstown. I saw the same individual riding
                        through the woods, and remarked to one of the boys that the stranger might
                        be a spy in disguise. My suspicions were well founded--he rode too unwomanly
                        on a side-saddle.</p>
                    <p>We wish to spend the Fourth in Virginia, and I hope this wish will be
                        gratified. Instead of firing blank cartridge, we are eager to throw in the
                        solid lead!</p>
                    <p>Give my love to all, and write to mother for me. Write to me also, for news
                        from home is cheering, as you would yourself know were you in my situation.</p>
                    <p>Yours affectionately, <lb/> T. W. M.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>T. W. M.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from "a young townsman" of Company A, the Second Regiment of
                    Pennsylvania volunteers, reports on the situation at Camp Spielman, fourteen
                    miles south of Hagerstown. The soldier remarks that his company has received new
                    pantaloons and is ready to exchange its blank cartridges for "solid lead."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News items from Baltimore, Cincinnati, and Washington, columns 3 and 4;
                advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.02.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Comet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that a "beautiful Comet" was seen the previous evening around two
                    o'clock, almost directly north.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Infanticide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammond</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esquire</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stareliper</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that a newborn child was found dead in a bucket of water at
                    Fisher's Hotel the previous Saturday morning. Esquire Hammond immediately
                    summoned a Coroner's Jury who decided the child was born alive and died through
                    violence. A warrant has been issued for the arrest of the mother, Mary E.
                    Stareliper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Deaths of Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfkill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that two volunteers from Pittsburgh who had been staying at the
                    houses of Mrs. Wolfkill and of Mr. Henry Embich, have died. The body of another
                    soldier shot by a Union picket near Hagerstown passed through Chambersburg the
                    previous day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Alvey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Mr. Alvey, a "gentleman of secession proclivities," passed
                    through Chambersburg the past Saturday morning on his way to Washington. Mr.
                    Alvey was escorted by several guards headed by Captain Hays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Forward Movement of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammon</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Major Mourer of the Fifteenth Pennsylvania regiment divulged
                    to P. Hammon, Esq., that General Patterson's column would move on Sunday night,
                    which they did. Their destination is unknown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Announcement that the Dispatch will not publish a paper on July 5 so that the
                staff might enjoy the Fourth of July, column 1; list of members of the
                Thirty-seventh Congress, column 2; advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.07.02.04">
            <pageNote>Current prices, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
