<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.12.06">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jennifer Muter</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/6/2003</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-12-06">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.12.06.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.12.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Great Question.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By reference to the proceedings of Congress, it will be seen that the
                        question of the emancipation of the slaves of those in rebellion against the
                        Government, has already been sprung on Congress, and the temper of the
                        members upon the important question, and its ultimate disposition, may
                        readily be foretold by the decisive vote upon the question of laying upon
                        the table the resolution of Mr. Elliott, of Massachusetts, which was
                        negatived, 56 members favoring the tabling of the resolution, and 70
                        opposing it. Mr. McPherson, the representative of this District, voted with
                        the minority.</p>
                    <p>Our own views upon this question we can give in a few words. With the
                        Republican party, from motives of policy we have every been opposed to
                        interfering with Slavery in the South. We regarded it as a compromise--as
                        one of the rights guaranteed by the Constitution--as local in its bearings
                        and influences, and which could not exist anywhere else in our country but
                        by local law. Where it was we were content to tolerate it; but when at last
                        it was to be made the dominant feature of the Republic, and like a black
                        cloud to obscure the sun of Freedom, yet, having been balked in the attempt,
                        has madly rushed into revolution, and convulsed our country with civil war
                        and bloodshed, we are for striking the monster down! No one who is
                        conversant with the history of this country, for the last thirty years, will
                        question that the war had its origin in Slavery; and if the war should close
                        without witnessing the rising of the sun upon a Free Country, the same cause
                        that has brought the present trouble will be left to produce the same effect
                        in the future. The rebellion must be crushed, and the Union saved at all and
                        every hazard, and the emancipation of the slaves would be the heaviest blow
                        that could be dealt upon the head of rebellion. The loyal men of the South,
                        who would suffer by such a policy, could be indemnified by the Government.</p>
                    <p>If it be deemed impolitic to pass a law proclaiming the indiscriminate
                        manumition [sic] of all the slaves, there should be no hesitation about the
                        liberation of those of the disloyal. If it is right to confiscate one
                        species of rebel property, it is right to confiscate every other, which
                        would surely include slave property. Let the people and the Government
                        determine, before God and the world, that our Constitution and Union shall
                        be preserved intact, cost what it may, and if Slavery be in the way of their
                        preservation, let this hateful source of all our trouble be destroyed. The
                        act would be received by the nation as just, and the world would resound
                        with one universal acclaim of Amen and Amen!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article supporting emancipation of the slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.12.06.03">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.12.06.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
