<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.08.05">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/4/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 12/1/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-08-05">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Letter from an Austrian Officer</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Daily Commercial</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advice offered by Godfrey F. C. Tratzcky, officer in the Austrian service
                    to the military leaders of the United States armed forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; proceedings of Congress, columns 3 and
            4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Taxable Resources</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Possessing an area almost nine times as great as Massachusetts, water
                    power a hundred-fold greater, a soil of unsurpassed fertility, rich mineral
                    deposits, one of the best harbors on the continent, hundreds of miles of
                    navigable river, yet with all these advantages--the elements of an empire within
                    herself--the Real Estate of the Old Dominion is valued at $57,461,937 less than
                    that of the little Bay State."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that the Northern states, particularly New York, Massachusetts,
                    Pennsylvania, and Ohio have significantly greater populations, personal property
                    values, and real estate values than those of the Southern states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Violating Parole</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Gen. McClellan, while in command in Western Virginia, went to work in
                    earnest to stop the perjury and villainy of the Secession traitors, by having
                    twelve of them shot at Beverly, for violating their paroles."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General McClellan ordered twelve Confederate troops shot after
                    they carried out a guerrilla attack on a government train. The soldiers had been
                    among ninety rebel troops who had taken an oath not to bear arms against the
                    United States in order to secure their release from capture by the federal army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Major General McClellan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes General McClellan as efficient, unpretentious, "indefatigable in
                    his pursuit and attack of the enemy," and devoted to his men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various brief articles concerning the blockade of the Mississippi River, an
                account of action by the Rhode Island units at Bull Run, and circumstances at
                Washington, columns 1-4; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fine Stock</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John Trostle of the Borough of Chambersburg has a
                    nine-week-old calf that weighs 205 pounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Election of Field Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T&gt;</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the election of officers for the First Artillery Reserve Regiment
                    of Pennsylvania that took place at Harrisburg the previous Thursday. Captain
                    Richard H. Rush of Philadelphia was elected colonel; Captain Charles T. Campbell
                    of Chambersburg was elected lieutenant colonel; Captain A. E. Lewis of York was
                    elected senior major; and Captain H. T. Danforth of Pittsburgh was elected
                    junior major.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Looking Well</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on the "robust and vigorous appearance" of returning soldiers.
                    Ventures that more deaths would have occurred had the soldiers stayed home than
                    did since they entered the army. Attributes this situation to the "change and
                    active mode of existence they had adopted" which "so invigorated them that it
                    gave them a new lease upon life."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Greencastle Zouaves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shorb</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Greencastle in Franklin County is attempting to raise a
                    volunteer company of Zouaves. So far, forty-three "names of good and true men"
                    have been put upon the roll. Mr. Wm. H. Shorb has been chosen captain, and Mr.
                    G. H. Miller has been selected to serve as first lieutenant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cruelty to Animals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that a dog belonging to Hiram Senseny returned home one night the
                    previous week "with the scalp and both ears completely pared off his head."
                    Reports that Mr. Senseny shot the dog to put it out of its misery. The Dispatch
                    expresses its indignation at the act of cruelty perpetrated against the dog and
                    asserts that "the person who would be guilty of such wanton barbarism is only
                    fit for residence among savages of very low grade."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Major C. T. Campbell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the promotion of Captain C. T. Campbell of Chambersburg to major
                    in the Artillery Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bank of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Bank of Chambersburg at present possesses $295,759.40 more
                    in assets than in liabilities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Light Dragoons</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stetzel</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that two regiments of light dragoons are being raised in
                    Pennsylvania. General Josiah Harlan of Philadelphia will command the first, and
                    Mr. Geo. Stetzel of Chambersburg has obtained a Captain's commission in General
                    Harlan's Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Distressing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Speculates that Dr. S. Hagerdorn of New York, who accompanied W. S.
                    Everett, Esq., of Chambersburg, to the site of Bull Run during the battle, may
                    well have been captured or killed by the rebel army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.05.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Why Straggling Was Permitted</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Many civilians have been very much surprised that the military authorities
                        should have permitted the straglers [sic] of the demoralized regiments to go
                        around Washington and Alexandria, without any apparent effort to sift them
                        apart, and gather them up by companies and regiments. General Scott explains
                        that by letting volunteers ran loose as it were after such a disaster, they
                        much more rapidly recover their spirits and get over the fatigues of the
                        fight and the retreat--that being habituated to reading and hearing news,
                        they would become discontented and morose if they were at once returned to
                        rigid discipline and the seclusion of a camp. By letting them mix together
                        and talk it over, they soon hear all there is to be said--to realize the
                        extent of the disaster--to revive their hopes and inflame their desire for
                        revenging the death of friends, and reversing the tide of the battle. For
                        these reasons, no more notice was taken of the members of the disorganized
                        regiments than to guard against any acts of violence. After three or four
                        days of idleness, the men went almost of their own accord back to camp, and
                        resumed with apparent relish camp duty and camp fare.--<emph rend="italic"
                            >N. Y. Times.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that "stragglers"--men who have wandered away from their
                    regiment--are not forced back into camp and into rigid discipline after a battle
                    because it allows them to recover and to resume the duties of a soldier with
                    greater enthusiasm than they would have otherwise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Incidents from the battle at Manassas, column 1; prices current, column 2;
                advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
