<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.08.23">
 <header>
  <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
  <tagger>
   <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
   <tagDate>6/15/98</tagDate>
   <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 12/1/98</tagNote>
  </tagger>
  <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
  <date n="1861-08-23">
   <year>1861</year>
   <month norm="08">August</month>
   <day norm="23">23</day>
   <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
  </date>
  <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
  <extent>04</extent>
  <editionNote/>
 </header>
 <paperBody>
  <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.23.01">
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Proclamation by the Governor</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"If Pennsylvania puts forth her strength, the hordes of hungry rebels may be swept down
     to the latitudes where they belong."</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Proclamation in which the governor requests Pennsylvanians to come to the aid of the
     government by providing more troops to quash the rebellion.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>From Harrisburg</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Commends Pennsylvania for furnishing more than 3,000 men of late who are "en route for
     the seat of war."</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; news brief from the Virginia state convention at
    Wheeling, column 3; news items from West Chester in Pennsylvania, from Fort Monroe, from Boston,
    Easton, New York, Pittsburgh, and St. Louis, columns 3 and 4; news of how Bull Run was reported
    in Europe, column 5</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.23.02">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>The Fat's in the Fire</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p>The "Union" will have to "slide" now, we suppose--not the Federal Union--but the Union Party
      which was so gloriously and so patriotically inaugurated in the Court House, on the evening of
      the 15th inst. The <emph rend="italic">Repository and Transcript</emph>, in its last issue,
      has graciously condescended to intimate to the Union Party whom it will and whom it will not
      support for Judge. So far as its influence upon the action of the Union Convention is
      concerned, it might as well have extended its list, and say whom it will support for the other
      positions that are to be filled. Now we opine that the Convention of the Union Party will make
      its nominations regardless of secession sympathisers or unblushing dictation from a
      presumptuous editor--and, by way of approval, the nominees of the Union Party, who ever they
      may be, (supposing them to be unconditional Union men) will be triumphantly elected, even
      though the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> and its editor should be found in opposition.</p>
     <p>The favorite candidate of the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> for Judge, it appears,
      is Wm. McLellan, Esq., of this place, a gentleman of undoubted qualifications, and than whom a
      more sterling man is not in our community; but Mr. McLellan, we understand, is not, and does
      not desire to be, a candidate. If, however, Mr. McL. should be the nominee, and would accept
      it, no one would support him more heartily than we would. </p>
     <p>But pre-supposing that his Honor, Judge Kimmel, might be chosen as the candidate of the
      Union Party for that responsible position, the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> very
      gravely tells the party beforehand, that "WE [the editor of the <emph rend="italic"
      >Transcript</emph>,] "will not consider OURSELF bound by the action of the Union movement; but
      will oppose it and its candidates down till the evening of the second Tuesday of October, with
      all OUR might"!!! After this, will not our readers agree with us that "the fat's in the fire?"
      Or will those who know, regard the declaration of the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> as
      sublimely rediculous [sic]? For our part, we scarcely know which to admire most--the
      presumption or the egotism of that editor. </p>
     <p>So far as our humble selves are concerned, we have gone into this Union movement with a
      zest, and without any political "mental reservations or self evasions." To suppose that the
      Union Convention will put in nomination a man as a candidate for any position to be filled at
      the approaching October Election, who is not an out-spoken, unconditional Union man, and a
      firm, decided supporter of the war policy of the Administration in its efforts to suppress the
      rebellion, is to suppose that the Convention will be composed of fools--which we are free to
      confess, we do not anticipate as likely to be the case. In this view of the matter, then, let
      who may be the candidates--Judge Kimmel, or who ever else--we will support the Union Ticket
      with whatever humble ability we may possess, regardless of the political anticedents [sic] of
      the gentlemen who may compose it, and regardless, also, of any narrow-contracted, personal
      considerations or objections.</p>
     <p>As a matter of course, we would prefer to see a citizen of our own county on the Bench.
      Somerset has occupied the position in the persons of Judges Black and Kimmel for the last
      twenty years, and for twenty or more years prior to that, the late Judge Thompson, a citizen
      of Bedford, filled the position, so that Franklin county has not had a President Judge for
      nearly the last half century. So far as Fulton is concerned, we believe she presents no
      candidate; but whether she did or not, her claims would be weakened by the fact, that she
      belonged to Bedford during the Judgship [sic] of Thompson, and has since had candidate in the
      person of a Mr. Lyon.--The claims of Franklin, therefore, we apprehend, will be readily and
      willingly conceeded [sic].</p>
     <p>While we have no particular choice of candidates, yet we believe the Union party would act
      wisely in selecting Judge Nill as its Judicial candidate--and in saying this, we believe we
      express the desire and the hope of a decided majority of the people of the county. The
      character of Judge Nill, and his fitness for the position, are so well known, that an attempt
      by us to portray either, would be supererogation.</p>
     <p>If the candidate, however, should come from another county, we would be pleased to see John
      Cessna, Esq., or Alex. King, Esq., of Bedford, receive the nomination. Both are gentlemen of
      fine legal attainments.--But let the candidates be whom they may, for this or any other
      position on the Ticket, they will triumph gloriously over the combined opposition of
      quasi-secessionists, and supercilious editors.</p>
     <p>But upon the principle that it is preferable to make a man your friend rather than your
      enemy, however contemptible he may be, we would advise the Delegates to the Union Convention,
      to consult with the editor of the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> prior to making any
      nominations. It appears that he has been "very much pleased with all that has thus far
      occurred," in this Union movement, and there is no use of unnecessarily incurring his supreme
      displeasure now, or of recklessly running against the thick bosses of his buckler.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Article in which the Dispatch reproaches the Repository and Transcript for declaring
     which candidates in the Union Party it would and would not support for judge and then declaring
     that if their candidates were not elected, they would feel no compunction to support the Union
     Party. The Dispatch also offers the candidates it would recommend for judge.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look>**</look>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>The "Peace" Party</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> says, that its party (the Breckinridge faction it
      means we suppose) is "the only party that can restore peace to our distracted country and
      re-establish the Union." That may be, for it is the only party in the country that proposes
      terms of Compromise with the Rebels. The Douglas Democracy, to their honor be it said, are as
      firm in their support of the Administration in the war now waging to suppress the rebellion,
      as the most ardent Republicans. The followers of Breckenridge are for compromising with Jeff.
      Davis, which means, to give the traitors their own terms, and the North to assent to a
      peaceful, dismemberment of the Union and the consequent distruction [sic] of the Government.
      How does the <emph rend="italic">Spirit's</emph> party propose to "restore peace," if it is
      not upon the rebels' own terms--for it is certain they will submit to no other, unless they
      are forced.</p>
     <p>The Tories of the Revolution also deplored the war in which our fathers involved the
      Colonies on account of their opposition to further foreign domination. They claimed also to be
      "the only party" that could "restore peace," and if they had been chosen by Washington,
      Jefferson, and their compatriots, as the pacificators, a complete surrender of the Colonists
      to the demands of the mother country would have been the result, and a "peace" would have
      resulted there-from, such as it would have been --procured at the sacrifice of their manhood,
      their self-respect, and their independence.</p>
     <p>While Northern sympathisers with treason and clamoring for "peace," it is refreshing to read
      the protests of Southern Union statesmen and journals against concessions to and compromise
      with the desperadoes who are in arms against the government. "The only compromise I have to
      make," cries Andy Johnson, of Tennessee, "is ground your arms; obey the laws; acknowledge the
      supremacy of the Constitution." "All idea of compromise is now to be deemed base--is scouted
      as dishonorable," says the Winchester (Ky.) <emph rend="italic">National Union</emph>. The
      Danville (Ky.) <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, the Louisville <emph rend="italic"
      >Journal</emph>, and the Louisville <emph rend="italic">Democrat</emph>, are equally emphatic
      in the demand that the rebels shall be made unconditionally to surrender before peace is
      discussed or entertained. </p>
     <p>On the 4th, of March last, when the President was inaugurated, he found seven States in arms
      against the authority of the Government, the Constitution and Laws of which he had just sworn
      to administer and enforce. What was he to do?--What would the <emph rend="italic"
      >Spirit</emph> have had him to do? Sit with folded hands, disregard his oath, and permit the
      Union to crumble to pieces without an effort to stay the destruction?--or would it have had
      him to do as he did, is, and as all loyal and true friends of the Union hopes he will continue
      to do, wage war upon all who are found in arms against the Government until the rebels submit
      to its benignant and mild authority? No other course was left open--it was life or death to
      the Union--and that is the only question now, Union or No Union, and it will be no difficult
      matter for loyal men and loyal journals to choose between them.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Criticizes the Valley Spirit for promoting peace at the expense of the Union.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look>**</look>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>More Troops Ordered</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"There can no longer be any doubt that the rebels are determined to attack the
     capital."</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Argues that the Confederate army must be preparing to attack Washington, given the late
     call for troops by the President.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Resolutions of the Late Union Meeting</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p>Below we re-publish the Resolutions adopted by the late Union Meeting of Franklin County:</p>
     <p>WHEREAS, The Government of this Nation is now involved in a war for the suppression of
      Rebellion, the maintainance [sic] of the Union, the Constitution and the Laws:</p>
     <p>AND WHEREAS, It is of vital importance, in this struggle for existence on the part of the
      Government, that there should be perfect unanimity of sentiment on the part of our
      people--therefore</p>
     <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That in the selection of the candidates for the
      different offices to be filled at the coming October election, the partisan should be merged
      in the patriot, and men should be merged in the patriot, and men should be selected without
      reference to former political predilections, possessed of capacity and integrity, who are
      willing to give all their energies to the Government for the purpose set forth in the preamble
      to these resolutions. </p>
     <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That those of our fellow-citizens of the county, who
      concur with us in sentiment, be requested to meet in their respective districts at the usual
      place of holding delegate meetings, on <emph rend="italic">Saturday, the 31st day of
      August</emph>, for the purpose of selecting delegates to a County Convention, to be held at
      Chambersburg, on Monday, the 2nd day of September, for the purpose of forming a County Ticket
      and selecting Conferrees to represent us in the Judicial and Legislative Conferences. </p>
     <p>The following Resolution was submitted by J. W. Douglas, Esq., which was also adopted
      unanimously:</p>
     <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we urge a most vigorous prosecution of the War,
      solely for the purpose of the suppression of the Rebellion, the restoration of the Government
      in its unity, the maintenance of the Constitution in all its compromises, and the Enforcement
      of the Laws; and not for the purpose of the Abolition of Slavery, or for impairing in any
      degree, the Constitutional Rights of any section of the Republic.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reprint of the resolutions adopted at the Union Meeting of Franklin County.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look>**</look>
   </div>
   <div type="l">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Card</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p>For the Dispatch.</p>
     <p>At a meeting of the Board of Directors of the Farmers and Mechanics' Industrial Association,
      held at the Secretary's office on Tuesday, 13th inst., it was unanimously resolved not to hold
      the usual Annual Fair this coming fall.</p>
     <p>The motives which induced the Directors to take this step are as follows:</p>
     <p>The Fair Ground and buildings having been occupied by the State and National Troops during
      the last summer, and by them so much injured and destroyed as to render them entirely unfit
      for use; and not being able to get a definite understanding when the Government shall
      appropriate money to place the same in proper order, the Directors feeling unable to do so at
      their own expenses. Again: The Directors at a former meeting appointed a Committee to call
      upon the leading business men of Chambersburg to contribute to this enterprise (which, in its
      effects, benefits all,) and which call was responded to so illiberally, that the Directors
      feel no encouragement in undertaking the responsibility attending the holding of the usual
      Annual Fair.</p>
     <p>By order of the Board.<lb/> W. S. Everett, Sec'y.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer>W. S. Everett, Sec'y.</trailer>
    <names/>
    <summary>Notes that the Board of Directors of the Farmers and Mechanics' Industrial Association
     have decided not to hold the annual fair during the coming fall. The decision was made because
     the fair ground buildings have been damaged and some destroyed due to their occupation by state
     and national troops.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look>**</look>
   </div>
   <pageNote>News items from Washington, column 4; advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.23.03">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Drafting</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Attempts to allay reported fears that the federal government will be compelled to
     conscript men into the army to fight the rebellion. Points out that "thousands of brave men"
     have thus far volunteered, lessening the chances of a draft.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Burglary and Incendiarism--Arrest of the Villains</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports the arrest the previous morning of two "scoundrels" who are believed to have
     broken into the large warehouse of Messrs. Oaks &amp; Austin and blown open the safe. The
     Dispatch warns that patrols must be organized or such criminal activity will doubtless
     continue.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Campbell's Artillery Regiment</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Notes the enthusiasm with which the people and soldiers of Washington have met
     Campbell's Artillery Regiment, expressing delight in particular at the "grand movements of the
     men" during drill.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>The Volunteer Company</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p>As we stated in our last, an adjourned meeting was to be held in the Court House on Tuesday
      evening last, to organize a Volunteer Company. The Brass Band turned out on the occasion, and
      discoursed, in its usual excellent style, some soul-stirring music, and a much larger crowd
      was attracted to the meeting than the most sanguine had reason to expect. Everything indicated
      the formation of a company without difficulty, but to the surprise of all, but <emph
       rend="italic">thirteen</emph> persons signed their names to the paper, signifying their
      readiness to participate in the laudable undertaking. It may the part of those in attendance,
      as to the course to be pursued by the company, in the event of its organization; be that as it
      may, the result was anything else than creditable to the military spirit of the town,
      especially in view of our close proximity to the enemy. We hope other efforts will be more
      successfull [sic].</p>
     <p>A gentleman of means, since the holding of the meeting, has called upon Capt. Jeffries, the
      President of the meeting, and assured him that as he was incapable of bearing arms, he would
      contribute $50 towards uniforming a company. This is patriotic.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports that only nineteen men signed up for the new volunteer company, though the
     meeting at the court house for its organization was attended by a large crowd and indicated
     much enthusiasm.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look>**</look>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2, 3, and 5; war news items from Harper's Ferry, St. Louis,
    Independence in Missouri, and Sandy Hook in Maryland, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.23.04">
   <pageNote>News from Fortress Monroe, anecdote from Connecticut, news of measles among rebel
    troops, column 1; prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
  </page>
 </paperBody>
</hwp>
