<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.08.13">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/8/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 12/1/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-08-13">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="13">13</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>N. Y. Herald's Proposition</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that slaves should be taken from the "300,000 rebel aristocrats
                    who now own them" and sold for $25 a piece to the "750,000 poor whites" of the
                    South. This scheme would turn the poor whites into Union men, and the government
                    would receive $750 million, "or rather more than enough to pay the whole cost of
                    the war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; article describing the incarceration at
                Philadelphia of pirates from the sunken privateer Petrel, column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen. McDowell's Report</head>
                <origin>Phila. Eve. Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the official report submitted by Brigadier General McDowell
                    "makes it quite clear" that the army was not ready for the advance on Bull Run.
                    However, the action could not be delayed, because the term of service of most of
                    the Union troops was about to expire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>What It Takes for an Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that an army officer estimates the amount of food that 50,000 men
                    consume per day at 312 tons, 10 cwt., thus requiring 300 horses to carry one
                    day's provisions for an army of that size. With baggage and ammunition, an army
                    would require over 1,000 horses for a single day's necessities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Thirteen Dollars Per Month</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the passage of a bill in Congress to increase soldiers' pay by
                    two dollars per month. The bill as first proposed provided for an increase of
                    four dollars per month.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News articles from Washington, Baltimore, New Hampshire, St. Louis, and
                Fortress Monroe, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.13.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Jewish Burial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the remains of a Jewish woman by the last name of Einstine
                    were brought to Chambersburg from Hagerstown, Maryland, the previous Sabbath.
                    She was buried in the "burial ground of that people" on the eastern part of
                    Washington street.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Hope, Attention!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>JAS. McKESSON, Pres't.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Requests that the members of the Hope Fire Company attend a meeting this
                    evening at eight o'clock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Whortleberries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that on the previous Thursday a woman from the South Mountain
                    brought 250 quarts of huckleberries into town to sell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of Col. James C. Boyd</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the death of Col. J. C. Boyd, which took place at his residence
                    near Mercersburg on August 7 after a protracted illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fast Riding</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday afternoon last, Constable Gross arrested a man for fast riding
                        through our streets, which is in violation of a Borough Ordinance. He was
                        taken before L. S. Clarke, Esq., Burges, when he paid the fine imposed. It
                        would be a very fine thing if more were arrested and fined for the same
                        offence, as there is a deal of risk of life and limb incurred by children
                        particularly, owing to fast riding and driving on our thoroughfares.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the arrest and fine of a man the previous Saturday afternoon for
                    "fast riding through our streets."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Change of Name</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the name of Mr. John Fisher's hotel will be changed from the
                    "Southern Hotel" to the "Union Hotel."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Forced to Leave</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Jno. W. Shinefield, son of Mr. Shinefield, late Steward of our Alms
                        House, with his wife and four children, arrived in our midst on last Friday,
                        under very distressing circumstances. For five or more years past, Mr. S.
                        has been a resident of Ravenswood, Jackson County, Va., where he carried on
                        the merchant tailoring. The people of the town in which he resided, owing to
                        their Union sentiments, and for fear of being forced into the rebel ranks by
                        Gov. Wise, who was approaching the place with his rebel forces,
                        precipitately crossed the river into Ohio, with whatever of their property
                        they could hastily gather up. Mr. S. succeeded in taking but a small
                        quantity of his goods, leaving behind nearly all that he was worth, which of
                        course, fell into the hands of the enemy. With his family he then endeavored
                        to make his way to this County, his former residence, with what difficulty
                        any person may well imagine, as he had but a small amount of money when he
                        left Virginia. He succeeded, however, thro' much trouble, in reaching
                        Harrisburg, where he supposed he had escaped the ferocity of the rebels and
                        reached a humane and civilized community, but judge of his surprise when, on
                        application to obtain lodgings and something to eat for his family, he was
                        denied entertainment by the proprietors of eight different Public Houses! He
                        was refused this after a statement of his situation and after offering
                        everything he possessed in pledge for payment. Mr. Shinefield would have had
                        to lodge his little ones in the Market-house but for the kindness of a
                        police officer, we believe, who took them to his home. Mr. S. and family are
                        of genteel appearance, and why such cold-blooded inhumanity should be
                        exhibited towards him, we are at a loss to say. One thing is certain, the
                        names of these hotel proprietors should be made known, and their houses
                        shunned by all decent people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shinefield</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the departure of Mr. Jno. W. Shinefield and his family from
                    Ravenswood in Jackson County, Virginia, where they had lived for the past five
                    years, and their arrival in Chambersburg. The Shinefields left Virginia because
                    of their Union sentiments and because Governor Wise's forces were approaching
                    the town. The Dispatch criticizes the eight tavern owners in Harrisburg who
                    refused the Shinefields hospitality.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Court Week and Rain</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments that, "as usual," it has begun to rain since the August term of
                    court began the previous Monday morning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Returned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the wife of J. Allison Eyster has returned from an attempt to
                    visit her husband at Richmond, where he is held prisoner. When she reached his
                    headquarters, General Banks advised her to return when he feared for her safety.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Volunteer Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the organization of the first Regiment of Volunteer Artillery ever
                    formed in Pennsylvania. Captain H. Easton and Lieutenants Palsgrove and Stits,
                    all of Chambersburg, command the regiment of 800 men, who comprise eight
                    companies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConnell</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Wm. H. B. McConnell, died on August 11 in Antrim Township after a
                    protracted illness. Mr. McConnell was 40 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.08.13.04">
            <pageNote>Article describing the execution of Thomas J. Armstrong at Philadelphia,
                column 1; prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
