<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.05.28">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/26/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 5/17/99</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-28">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="28">28</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.28.01">
            <pageNote>Listing of national, state, and local officeholders, column 1; prospectus of
                the Semi-Weekly Dispatch, column 1; advertisements, columns 1 and 2; poem, column 3;
                short article from the National Intelligencer about the particulars of the blockade,
                column 3; long article about the failure of the Armstrong gun, columns 4 and 5;
                article about the French invasion of Syria, column 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor Curtin has dispatched Benjamin Haywood, Esq., of Schuylkill County
                    to visit the Fourth, Fifth, and Twenty-fifth regiments and ascertain whether
                    they need clothing. "No doubt many of the evils complained of have grown out of
                    the want of an established military system in Pennsylvania, and the unexpected
                    demands upon all men having charge of the military arrangements."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Occupation of Virginia by Federal Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that federal troops have taken over the cities of Alexandria and
                    Arlington Heights in Virginia, near the nation's capital.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Assassination of Col. Ellsworth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that assassination of Colonel Ellsworth just after he had removed
                    the "Secession flag" from the roof of the Marshall House in Alexandria. Col.
                    Ellsworth was the only person among Northern forces who was killed at the
                    seizure of Alexandria.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article excerpted from the Knoxville Whig stating that the true purpose of the
                was is to restore the government of the United States, column 2; short article on
                how the death of Col. Ellsworth was received in his hometown of Mechanicsville, New
                York, column 4; article detailing the capture of Alexandria, columns 4 and 5;
                advertisements, column 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the members of regiments stationed at Chambersburg have been
                    supplied with overcoats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We stop the press to announce the arrival this morning, of the 2d and 3d
                        Regiments Penna. Volunteers. The troops from this place belong to the 2d
                        Regiment, and many a glad heart was in our town, on meeting sons, brothers,
                        husbands and friends.--Our men all look well; some have much improved in
                        health and appearance. They cheered loudly in the Square on passing the
                        flag. Both Regiments were accompanied by excellent brass bands.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the 2d and 3d Regiments of the Pennsylvania volunteers arrived
                    in Chambersburg this morning. The 2d Regiment is made up of men from
                    Chambersburg, so "many a glad heart was in our town, on meeting sons, brothers,
                    husbands and friends." The paper remarks that the men all look well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sick in Hospital</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plaster</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etchberger</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports two or three additional cases of soldiers in the hospital since the
                    last issue. Remarks that the case of Peter Plaster of Lancaster County is
                    particularly severe. He was taken to the house of Mr. G. Etchberger when he fell
                    ill at midnight on Saturday and then was removed to the hospital in the morning.
                    Plaster has the same disease that those who died had suffered from.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lying Telegrams</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following, which has appeared in several widely circulating and
                        influential newspapers, is part of a telegram purporting to have been sent
                        from Chambersburg on the 24th inst.:</p>
                    <p>"Great apprehension prevails in Cumberland valley of an invasion from
                        Virginia. Ten thousand head of cattle and five thousand horses along the
                        Valley could be seized by a sudden irruption [sic] of an expeditionary corps
                        holding the Valley for five days, even if driven back into Virginia.</p>
                    <p>Forward movements of the Virginia troops may be expected immediately.</p>
                    <p>Campbell's Flying Artillery of six pieces has positively been ordered back
                        from York to Chambersburg. Two additional infantry regiments must be moved
                        to this point and a battalion of cavalry added, or devastation will overtake
                        the whole Valley. We want at least three batteries of six and twelve
                        pounders."</p>
                    <p>Appended to the above appeared the following:</p>
                    <p>"The officers, who recently made a reconnoisance as far as Harper's Ferry,
                        report that they learned there that a sentinel had been captured by means of
                        a lariat, about a week before from the camp here, and was carried to
                        Harper's Ferry. There he had been hung up twice to force him to impart
                        information to the rebels, with what success was not known."</p>
                    <p>Having serious doubts respecting the truth of these statements, we went with
                        them to head-quarters to ascertain the facts. Gen. Williams declared them
                        both fabrications, and said they were never sent over the telegraph wires
                        from this place. The General was highly indignant, both at the author of
                        such falsehoods, and also at the Associated Press for the employment of such
                        reckless or at least gullible agents.</p>
                    <p>The following dispatch has been sent by Gen. Williams to the Associated
                        Press:</p>
                    <p>CHAMBERSBURG, May 25th.--We desire neither of artillery, dragoons, nor
                        infantry, as mentioned in the dispatch published in this morning's papers,
                        but are prepared to repel any invasion of the soil of Pennsylvania,
                        promptly.</p>
                    <p>Gen. E. C. WILLIAMS. <lb/> per John J. Patterson, Aid-de-Camp.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a telegram reported to have been sent from Chambersburg,
                    expressing fear among the people of Chambersburg that an invasion from Virginia
                    would occur. Reports that General Williams at the military headquarters in
                    Chambersburg declared that the telegram was a "fabrication" and was "highly
                    indignant" at the author and at the press for having published it. The editor
                    goes on to state that Chambersburg is fully prepared should an attack occur and
                    that "the people feel perfectly secure from any invasion on the part of the
                    Virginia Secessionists."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Three Months Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the companies stationed at Camp McAllen, which enrolled
                    themselves for three years were disbanded and made into companies of three
                    months recruits. These companies are now busily attempting to reorganize for the
                    three years service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Commissariat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The scoundrels who would furnish such miserable articles as we have seen,
                    and received the amount allowed by Government, for the clothing of the men,
                    should be held up to public scorn and contempt, and suffer the full penalty of
                    the laws against swindlers."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites articles from other newspapers that have complained about the
                    insufficient rations and poor clothing furnished to Pennsylvania volunteers. The
                    editor applauds these other papers for exposing those who deserved to be
                    prosecuted for how they have treated Pennsylvania's troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 3; advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.05.28.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Soldiers' Rations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There has been much said about what constitutes the daily rations of the
                        soldier and the cost of the same, and yet the mass of the people know very
                        little on the subject. We therefore gather some interesting items in
                        relation to army subsistence from the official Regulations of the Army of
                        the United States, and publish them, that the men may know what they are
                        entitled to, in case grasping contractors should attempt to practice
                        impositions:</p>
                    <p>One hundred complete rations consist of-- <lb/> 32 rations fresh beef is 40
                        lbs, or 1 1/4 lbs per man. <lb/> 68 " pork, is 51 lbs, " 3/4 lb " <lb/> 100
                        " flour, is 11 lbs, " 18 oz. " <lb/> 100 " beans, is 8 qts. <lb/> Or, <lb/>
                        100 " rice, is 10 lbs. <lb/> 100 " coffee, is 6 lbs. <lb/> 100 " sugar, is
                        12 lbs. <lb/> 100 " vinegar, is 4 qts. <lb/> 100 "candles, is 1 1/2 lbs.
                        <lb/> 100 " soap, is 4 lbs. <lb/> 100 "salt, is 2 qts. </p>
                    <p>When the officers of the Medical Department find anti-scorbutics necessary
                        for the health of the troops, the commanding officer may order issues of
                        fresh vegetables, pickled onions, sour krout, or mollasses [sic], with an
                        extra quantity of rice and vinegar. (Potatoes are usually issued at the rate
                        of one pound per ration, and onions at the rate of three bushels in lieu of
                        one of beans.) Occasional issues (extra) of molasses are made--two quarts of
                        one hundred rations--and of dried apples of from one to one and a half
                        bushels to one hundred rations."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the amount and kind of rations that soldiers are allowed per day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article about a piece of shell used in the bombardment of the Citadel of
                Messina by Victor Emanuel, column 1; article promising a grand celebration at the
                next Fourth of July, column 1; article on how to cleanse gun barrels, column 1;
                advertisements, columns 2-5.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
