<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.10.18">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/21/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-18">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="18">18</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.18.01">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; news from Louisiana and Virginia, columns 3
                and 4; graph indicating the voting results for Franklin County from five companies
                stationed at Washington and Pittsburgh, columns 3 and 4; explanation of why Henry
                May went to Richmond, anecdotes, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Government</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If we would command the respect of the world, the rebellion must be
                    crushed out, though it should cost untold treasure and blood, and we must
                    exhibit to mankind everywhere, at home and abroad, the ability of the Republic
                    to maintain itself against the attacks of internal as well as foreign enemies."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>After an existence of eighty-five years as an independent nation--recognized
                        by all Government as the peer of either; with a growth of population
                        unparalleled, and a development of wealth and national resources which has
                        astounded the world; with a future, upon which the nation was just entering
                        with giant strides, that bid fair to place us, in point of influence,
                        prosperity, strength, and power, if not in the lead, at least among the
                        first nations of the earth; with a system of government the least
                        oppressive, and the best ever devised by human wisdom, in which the rights
                        of all were abundantly protected--to have such a picture, such a glowing
                        prospect, marred by a few bad, ambitious men, is sufficient to arouse not
                        only the wrath of men but the indignation of angels.</p>
                    <p>But deplorable as it is, the bright prospects of our country have been
                        clouded by the rebellious spirits of the South, who have precipitated a
                        revolution for the purpose of subverting the Government, which cannot but be
                        regarded as the most wicked, the most unreasonable and the most
                        unjustifiable that is found upon the page of the world's history.</p>
                    <p>Ours is, emphatically, the People's Government, and it is for the People to
                        say, whether it shall be maintained intact, with all its advantages and
                        blessings, not only for the present but for future generations, or whether
                        the fair fabric shall be permitted to crumble before their eyes, shorn of
                        its strength and beautiful proportions, resulting in anarchy and confusion,
                        and productive of the worst evils which afflict any people anywhere.</p>
                    <p>We are in the war for the maintainance [sic] of the Constitution and the
                        union, and having laid the hand to the plow, it will not do to look
                        back--our watchword must be onward to victory. Any other course would but
                        prove our people cravens, unworthy of their glorious inheritance. If we
                        would command the respect of the world, the rebellion must be crushed out,
                        though it should cost untold treasure and blood, and we must exhibit to
                        mankind everywhere, at home and abroad, the ability of the Republic to
                        maintain itself against the attacks of internal as well as foreign enemies.
                        The time for compromising with the thieving, perjured rebels, has long since
                        passed; and if the whole people have not already made up their minds to
                        carry the war to a successful conclusion, it is time they would. It cost too
                        much blood and treasure to secure our Republican Government, and we should
                        be willing to spend an hundred times as much to maintain it. If the teeming
                        millions of the North but put their shoulders to the wheel, the work will b
                        accomplished in good time--the Constitution will be maintained, the Union
                        will be saved, and peace will be restored--and our country will against
                        resume her march on the road to prosperity and to her destined greatness and
                        grandeur.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that the United States, in existence for eighty-five years has
                    become one of the most profitable and greatest nations in the world. Argues that
                    if the government compromises with the "thieving, perjured rebels" of the South,
                    it would allow the strength of the nation to crumble. Asserts that the Union
                    must be maintained at any cost.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Short Cut to Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our neighbor of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> has discovered a
                        panacea which is warranted to cure the ills of the country--"the remedy"
                        that will be sure to restore Peace to our borders; and he is so confident in
                        its curative properties that he asserts that our troubles "<emph
                            rend="italic">never will be settled until that is adopted.</emph>" Now,
                        reader, what do you suppose the balsam is that is possessed of such intense,
                        double-distilled, concentrated Union-saving virtue?</p>
                    <p>Do you reply, it must be larger armies, more bullets, and heavier blows on
                        the heads of the traitorous crew that are in revolt against our mild
                        government. That is a reasonable and sensible idea, and one that a real
                        Union man would suggest as not only practicable, but the only one that would
                        seem to be possessed of those medicinal qualities and virtues demanded by a
                        natural and sensible treatment of the disease. But even this is not "the
                        remedy" proposed by the Spirit, and not to detain you longer, we will reveal
                        the secret in our neighbor's own language, as follows:</p>
                    <p>"If the real Union men of the North, Democrats, old line Whigs and
                        conservative Republicans will unite and crush out the Greeley and Beecher
                        Black Republican party, the Union may yet be restored without much
                        bloodshed."</p>
                    <p>This appears to be a very silly (simple we should have said) remedy for so
                        terrible a disease; but to show the insincerity of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Spirit</emph>, and that it has no confidence in its own prescription,
                        why did it not unite with the "real Union Democrats," old line Whigs and
                        conservative Republicans," at the late election to "crush out" not only "the
                        Greeley and Beecher Black Republican party," which seems to be so very
                        heinous in its estimation, but all other parties that stood in the way, and
                        consolidate a great Union Party on their ruins? No, no; that didn't come up
                        to our neighbor's Union-saving idea. He only wants the "Black Republican
                        party" "crushed out," judging from the manner in which he rejected the union
                        proposed by the Republicans before the election.</p>
                    <p>The Republican party is the "Mordecai at the king's gate," and which so
                        offends this Union-saving Haman; and as long as Mordecai is in the way,
                        Haman will not save the Union. So grievous in the estimation of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, is the existence [sic] of the Republican
                        party, that if it could save the Union by any other means than the one it
                        suggests, the Union might go to the dogs, for all it cared, rather than use
                        the other remedy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mocks the Valley Spirit's solution to the current conflict, which is to
                    eliminate the Republican party. Argues that if the Spirit really wanted to end
                    the conflict and to eliminate all parties, they should have supported the Union
                    party in the recent election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>High Prices</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responds to reports that Southerners laugh at the idea that they could be
                    defeated by starvation. Speculates that Southerners will not be able to survive
                    very long on the food they produce themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Southern Rumors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns readers that they cannot believe the news of federal defeats that has
                    been printed in Southern papers until those reports are confirmed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports of skirmishes near Washington, report of a battle at Rolla, Missouri,
                column 3; reports from Fortress Monroe, Darnstown in Virginia, and Baltimore, column
                4; advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Stumbaugh's Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Stumbaugh's regiment is presently at Pittsburgh, practicing
                    "at the guns."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Second Crop</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reinhart</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that a plum tree on the lot of Mr. A. Reinhart has put forth a
                    second round of blossoms this season, and well-formed fruit hangs all over it. A
                    plum tree owned by Mr. Joseph Frey is now full of blossoms, and Mr. J. S. Nixon
                    is in the midst of growing a second crop of strawberries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Governor Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Governor Curtin and his staff set out for Pittsburgh on the
                    previous Wednesday, with the intention of presenting the regiments commanded by
                    Brigadier General Negley with the state regimental colors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Regiment That Will Suit Everybody</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the formation of a regiment in Lancaster, no members of which
                    will be privates. Instead, all men who join will be commissioned officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Subscriptions to the National Loan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists individuals and organizations who have made subscriptions to the
                    national loan, along with the amount of each subscription. In Chambersburg, the
                    Columbus Lodge has pledged $100, and the Bank of Chambersburg has pledged
                    $20,000. None of the individual subscribers come from Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-5; short article announcing that Colonel Geary has
                engaged in a fight with the rebels at Harper's Ferry.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.10.18.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Flight of Breckinridge--A Historic Parallel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the parallels between John Breckinridge and Aaron Burr.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The President a Tired Giant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"You could not to save your life, even in you were that man's bitterest
                    enemy, look upon that shattered giant and come away without feeling a respectful
                    pity for the suffering that is so plainly written on his honest face."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes President Lincoln as tired and careworn, having experienced a
                    drastic change in his physical appearance since his inauguration. Expresses pity
                    for him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
