<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.09.13">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/16/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-09-13">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="13">13</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The New Army Order--The Sabbath</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints Major-General McClellan's order that the army is not to work on
                    the Sabbath, unless attack by the enemy makes fighting necessary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Reconciliation</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Governor Curtin of Pennsylvania and Secretary of War Cameron
                    have resolved the struggle over who possessed authority over Pennsylvania's
                    troops, a quarrel existing since the war began. The troops will be under the
                    command of the governor until they are turned over to the federal government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Pardon of the Sentinel Who Slept on His Post</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the issuance of a pardon by Major-General McClellan of Private
                    William Scott of the Third Vermont Volunteers, a sentinel who was to be executed
                    for sleeping on his post.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Cotton for Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Dr. J. C. Reinhardt claims that two kinds of cotton--Nankin,
                    or yellow cotton, and white cotton--can be grown in Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; article concerning Prince Napoleon, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Profession vs. Practice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Only last week, the Democratic Convention assembled in this place, and passed
                        resolutions eminently patriotic, and satisfactory to every true Union man in
                        the County. It was evident to outsiders, who attended that Convention, that
                        about one-third of the delegates heartily and cordially endorsed those
                        resolutions. It was equally evident that the remaining two-thirds received
                        the resolutions like a nauseous dose, sitting sternly and silently, and
                        voting neither affirmatively nor negatively. From this fact, and from the
                        organization of the Convention it was predicted that neither its practice
                        nor that of the party would correspond with the spirit of the resolutions.
                        The Convention set out by electing a man of more than doubtful loyalty,
                        President. One of the Secretaries was a friendly and honored guest in the
                        head-quarters of Gen. Johnston of the Rebel army, if we may believe the
                        testimony of one of our citizens who was an impressed soldier in the ranks
                        of the same army, and who afterwards escaped. The Convention immediately
                        after the passage of the patriotic resolutions, nominated for important
                        offices several men, well known in this community to be bitterly hostile to
                        the war, and per consequence, to the Government, the Country, and their own
                        resolutions.</p>
                    <p>So far the prediction above referred to was fulfilled.</p>
                    <p>This week's issue of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> confirms
                        the remainder of the prediction, and the insincerity of the majority of the
                        party represented in the Convention. It is filled with attacks, both open
                        and covert, on the war and on the Administration. Extracts from disloyal
                        papers like itself, teem in its columns. It reiterates the Secession
                        argument that the present Administration has brought all the present trouble
                        upon the Country. It says:--"Under Buchanan the people <emph rend="italic"
                            >was</emph> happy, prosperous, and at peace; under Lincoln they are
                        starving and at war." The people are judges of the peaceful condition of
                        affairs handed over by Mr. Buchanan to Mr. Lincoln. So peaceful that the
                        latter was compelled to go disguised to his inauguration, to escape
                        assassination, and the former to surround himself with armed men to protect
                        the Capital during the last days of his reign. The "corruptions" also of the
                        present Administration effect [sic] unpleasantly the olfactories of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> and its followers. No doubt the
                        peculations of Mr. Floyd, to the tune of six millions of dollars, his
                        wholesale delivery of arms and munitions of war to the Rebels under the late
                        Administration, to say nothing of printing frauds and frauds of all kind,
                        revealed by Congressional investigation, are odors pleasant to the nostrils
                        of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, as those borne on the balmy
                        breezes of Araby. It would appear so, at least, from the fact that it has no
                        word of denunciation for these corruptions, and for the corruptions and
                        wrongs which the Rebels have perpetrated and are now perpetrating every day.
                        It is possible that it is for these things that "Buchanan and his
                        administration are to be remembered with gratitude, long after the name of
                        Lincoln has been forgotten." </p>
                    <p>The faithful are next reminded of the taxes imposed upon them by the Lincoln
                        administration. Of course it is a logical consequence that as our own
                        Government has brought all this trouble on us, it has also brought on the
                        taxes. It is not worth while to dispute this, nor to follow out the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit's</emph> line of argument in defence of the Union
                        cause any further. We have only to say, that it is a very singular course
                        for a paper that endorsed the Resolutions passed at the Democratic
                        Convention, one of which distinctly says, that this war and the troubles,
                        taxes, and all else consequent upon it, was forced upon the Country by the
                        disunionists of the South.--The course of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph> might be Union in Franklin County, but in some localities it
                        would be considered sympathy with Secession. We are certain of one thing,
                        that the course of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> this week, is not
                        in accordance with the spirit of the Resolutions are to be used as a mere
                        cloak for treason, and that its practice was never intended to correspond
                        with its profession. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Charges the Valley Spirit with failing to live up to the professions of
                    Union approved by the Democratic convention of Franklin County. Asserts that the
                    most recent issue of the Spirit criticizes the present administration
                    repeatedly, in essence blaming it for the war while endorsing resolutions that
                    put the responsibility for the conflict entirely on the Secessionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Which Is the Loyal Party?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Casts dispersion on the contention made by Colonel James Orr at the county
                    Democratic Convention that the Democratic party has always been the party of
                    union. Points out that the Democratic party has always been dominated by
                    Southern men, and that far more Democrats have been arrested for "aiding and
                    abetting" the rebellion than Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A "Loyal" Candidate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Argues that the candidate the Valley Spirit promotes for the office of
                    Associate Judge, Mr. Augustus Duncan, is not the kind of loyal unionist the
                    Democrats profess to prefer. Instead, Mr. Duncan, the Dispatch alleges, has
                    proclaimed that the war against the South is "most unjust" and was brought about
                    by President Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses the opinion that the Spirit's proclamations of loyalty are merely
                    "a blind to hide its secession proclivities."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Inconsistency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Points out that the Valley Spirit has accused Judge Nill of joining the
                    Union party for the express purpose of gaining a judgeship. Yet at the same
                    time, the Dispatch claims, the Spirit have no similar complaints against Nill's
                    "competitor," Mr. Reilly, who has constantly held or been in the running for a
                    number of different offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Audacity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Excepting several Democratic papers printed in New York . . . we know of
                    no other printed in the loyal States that transcends the Valley Spirit in
                    audacity, hypocracy [sic] and jesuitical shiftings."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the suppression of the Hagerstown <emph rend="italic">Mail</emph>, and
                        imprisonment of its pseudoeditor, Dan. Dechert, for its treasonable
                        teachings, and excepting several Democratic papers printed in New York, one
                        called the <emph rend="italic">Day Book</emph>, and another the <emph
                            rend="italic">News</emph>, which the Government refuses to carry in the
                        mails, we know of no other printed in the loyal States that transcends the
                            <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> in audacity, hypocracy [sic]
                        and jesuitical shiftings. Its <emph rend="italic">cuttle</emph> editor is
                        like a peculiar kind of fish that naturalists describe as possessing a small
                        bladder under the throat, which is filled with an ink-like fluid, and when
                        pursued by an enemy is able to eject this dark fluid, which so darkens the
                        surrounding water that its whereabouts is lost by the pursuer, and, in the
                        midst of the darkness it has created, makes good its escape.</p>
                    <p>This is precisely the policy pursued by the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph>. It seeks to escape the just odium that attaches to its mean,
                        underhanded attacks upon the Administration, owing to its energetic
                        prosecution of the war upon the Rebels, by asserting that the columns of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Dispatch</emph> is "weekly filled with the rankest
                        treason against the North!" It seeks to darken the waters by ejecting its
                        black falsehoods against others, thus covering its own filth and eluding the
                        just indignation of an outraged and incensed loyal people.</p>
                    <p>The sympathies of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> for the desperate
                        conspirators against out Government, have been so marked, glaring, and
                        shameless that it was with difficulty many Union Democrats of our Borough,
                        during the first weeks of the Rebellion, could restrain themselves from
                        going in a body and heaving the materials of the concern into the street.
                        The feelings, views, and principles of the Union Democracy are outraged in
                        every issue of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> by its double-dealing,
                        prevaricating editor, while papers even less debauched than the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, have been mobbed by an indignant and loyal
                        public, such, for instance, as the Easton <emph rend="italic"
                        >Sentinel</emph> and West Chester <emph rend="italic">Jeffersonian</emph>.</p>
                    <p>A paper in the South, that would advocate the cause of the Union with half
                        the boldness, zeal and earnestness which he <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph> does that of this causeless and wicked Rebellion, would be
                        dealt with very summarily, speedily, and effectually; and that it has not
                        thus been dealt with, is owing altogether to the forbearance of the
                        community--to their love of "law and order,"--and in hope that its editor
                        and proprietors may yet see the propriety as well as the necessity of
                        changing their course so as to accord more with the loyal sentiments of the
                        masses of the great Free North. There is a <emph rend="italic">limit</emph>
                        even to the Freedom of the Press, which, if persistently and wilfully [sic]
                        transcended, should be punished, and we would advise our neighbor not to
                        lean too heavily upon the forbearance and lenity of the community, for there
                        is a period when even patience ceases to be a virtue, and the <emph
                            rend="italic">cuttle</emph> of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>
                        might wake up some morning without a channel through which to promulgate his
                        slanders and treasonable effusion. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains that the "sympathies" the Valley Spirit exhibits toward the
                    Secessionists should have led to its suppression long ago.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Two Flags in the Camp</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Questions the loyalty of the Times to the Union, if it is satisfied with
                    the nomination of candidates selected by the Valley Spirit. The Times secured
                    the passage of its Unionist resolutions, but did not recommend many of the
                    candidates that emerged on the Democratic ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls into question the truthfulness of the Spirit's contention that "the
                    Democratic party in toto deny the right of Secession."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Union ticket, column 1; news from Washington, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.13.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Wood Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Requests that any Dispatch readers wishing to pay their subscription in
                    wood should do so now.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ordered on Duty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Dr. S. G. Lane of Chambersburg has been ordered to report to
                    Georgetown immediately. Dr. Lane is a surgeon for the First Regiment of
                    Pennsylvania reserves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuchs</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuchs</ln>
                        <fn>Peter P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuchs</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Fuchs, infant son of Peter P. and Mary A. Fuchs, died of diphtheria
                    at the age of 11 months on September 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-4; report of skirmishing around Washington, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.13.04">
            <pageNote>Article from the Richmond Whig, column 1; prices current, column 1;
                advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
