<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.05.31">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/26/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/23/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-31">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="31">31</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.05.31.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fun Among the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I am living luxuriously, at present, on the top of a very respectable
                    fence, and fare sumptuously on three granite buscuits [sic] a day, and a glass
                    of water, weakened with brandy."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a comical letter, supposedly written by a soldier stationed in
                    Washington. His letter emphasizes the rustic sleeping conditions and the
                    constant false alarms that the capital is in danger of being attacked.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Drill! Drill!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges soldiers who have not yet been sent into battle to remain patient and
                    to continue to drill. Points out that only troops experienced in drilling would
                    have the discipline necessary to fight effectively.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>List of national, state, and local officeholders, column 1; prospectus of the
                Semi-weekly Dispatch, column 1; advertisements, columns 1 and 2; poem, column 3;
                anecdote about Benjamin Butler, article about the destructive properties of the
                conical balls fired from Minie rifles, column 4; the chronology of secession, column
                4; article about the case of John Merriman, charged with treason in Baltimore,
                column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.05.31.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Attitude of England</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that England will most likely "remain a neutral spectator of
                    American affairs." The editor applauds this decision because, in his opinion,
                    the United States should be allowed to demonstrate its ability to keep the
                    country together without outside assistance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Virginia Affairs</head>
                <origin>The Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints an article from the Press that predicts Virginia will return to
                    the Union without blood being shed. This prediction was based on the strong vote
                    against the secessionists in many Virginia counties the previous Thursday, as
                    well as on the difficulties Virginia is experiencing due to the federal blockade
                    of its ports.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Horses and Wagons for the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that four hundred horses and about seventy baggage wagons are
                    stationed in Harrisburg. They are reportedly be moving toward Chambersburg
                    within the next few days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Short articles giving news from Washington, North Carolina, Mechanicsville in
                New York, Cincinnati, and other locations, columns 3 and 4; advertisements, column
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.05.31.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Sixth Regiment, led by Colonel Nagle; the Twenty-third
                    Regiment, led by Colonel Dare; the German Rifles, led by Colonel Ballier; the
                    Irish Regiment, led by Colonel Owens; and the Scott Legion regiment, commanded
                    by Colonel Gray arrived in Chambersburg the previous day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Shot Himself</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Mr. John Fisher, the owner of the Southern Hotel, accidentally
                    shot himself with a revolver. Though he wounded himself seriously, he now seems
                    to be doing well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Arrival of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that 12,000 to 14,000 more troops are expected within a day or two
                    to arrive in Chambersburg. Those who arrived the previous day are encamped near
                    town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Buried at Last</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that about twenty-five soldiers stationed in Chambersburg buried
                    the beef that was to be their food rations, as it "was entirely dead."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that several nights earlier, four soldiers entered a local hotel
                    and were refused liquor. They then proceeded to rob a woman sitting in the hotel
                    of a gold watch and chain she wore. The soldiers have not been apprehended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Relief Fund</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for Chambersburg citizens to be generous with their gifts to the
                    relief fund designated for the families of the Chambersburg volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Quarters of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that members of the Second and Third Regiments are quartered in the
                    various churches and public buildings of Chambersburg, while some are staying
                    with friends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On yesterday morning the body of a soldier, named Samuel Hoin, Company G, 2d
                        Regiment, Pennsylvania Volunteers, was conveyed to the railroad station to
                        be taken to his friends. The company of which the deceased was a member
                        followed the corpse to the station, another company with the regimental band
                        preceded it, the band playing a dead march. The whole was conducted in a
                        very solemn manner, and we noticed as the procession passed that some of his
                        comrades in arms were in tears. The disease, we understood, was brain
                    fever.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the story of how troops from Company G of the Second Regiment
                    conveyed a the body of a dead comrade to the railroad station to be taken back
                    to his home. The soldier had died of brain fever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Disgraceful</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday night a soldier went to the house of Mr. Christ, and represented
                        himself as an officer, sent to search the house for a man whom he named. He
                        was told that no man of that name was there, and was denied admission. He
                        threatened to break the door, when he was admitted, and after passing
                        through the house, went away without doing any damage. What his object was
                        is not known, but such conduct is not to be tolerated. If the soldiers
                        stationed here cannot be kept in order by their officers, some other means
                        must be devised. The citizens here are ever ready to do all in their power
                        for the comfort and kind treatment of our soldiers, and we are glad to
                        record that nearly all the soldiers are well behaved, and appreciate the
                        kindness of the people. We hope the few disorderly ones may see the
                        necessity of maintaining order and conduct themselves accordingly.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Recounts the story of a soldier who masqueraded as an officer to force his
                    way into the house of a local resident, where he passed through without doing
                    any damage. The editor admonishes disorderly soldiers like this one who, he
                    says, take advantage of their position to disturb the local citizens who have
                    given them nothing but kind treatment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Soldiers Letters to be Franked</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a letter from C. H. Van Wyck declaring that he will, to the best
                    of his ability, try to ensure that letters from soldiers stationed in Washington
                    are sent without their having to pay postage on them. The editor comments that
                    something must be done to allow soldiers to send letters free of charge,
                    particularly since the government has as yet paid them nothing for their
                    service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Secessionists</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports an attack on some men employed in peeling bark near Shade Gap in
                    Huntingdon County. These attackers are alleged to have been Pennsylvanians
                    harboring a disloyalty to the union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 3; advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.05.31.04">
            <pageNote>Poem, column 1; excerpt from an article written in Richmond by a correspondent
                of the New York Tribune about the state of Southern troops, column 1;
                advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
