<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1861/pa.fr.sd.1861.09.24">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/18/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1861-09-24">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="24">24</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.24.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>An Enlistment Incident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"O Judah and Jerusalem; fear not, nor be dismayed; tomorrow go out against
                    them; for the Lord will be with you."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that a minor attempting to enlist in a new regiment in Newport,
                    Rhode Island, when his mother agreed to sign his certificate of consent only if
                    the son should move his finger through the Bible and select a passage at random
                    that persuaded her to allow him to go to war. The son did so and chose a passage
                    charging the Hebrews to "go ye down against them," and the mother gave her
                    consent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Large Consumption</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some nine hundred barrels of their <emph rend="italic">per diem</emph> are
                        used up at Washington for the army. Of fresh bread alone there are one
                        hundred and fifty thousand loves consumed. Foreigners there express
                        astonishment at the abundant and varied rations served our troops. They are
                        undoubtedly the best fed as well as the best paid army in the world. We all
                        hope their performances will equal their treatment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the amount of rations distributed to government troops stationed in
                    Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Reading for the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges family members to send soldiers newspapers for them to read on the
                    Sabbath, since General McClellan has declared that no work is to be done on that
                    day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Important to the Families of Soldiers--Assignment of Pay</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that part of a soldier's pay may be distributed directly to his
                    family and explains the procedure for taking part in the program.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; miscellaneous articles, columns 4 and
            5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The "Day Book" Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>The editor of the Times "has heretofore denounced all who are for
                    compromising with the rebels as 'traitors' and 'cowardly fools,' in which we
                    agree with him, but strange to say, he is advocating the election of just such
                    men, and when he is charged with it, he endeavors to screen himself from a
                    further exposure by saying that 'this is no time for such contests.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The editor of <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph> not only knowing, but
                            <emph rend="italic">feeling</emph> the unenviable position he occupies
                        as a co-laborer with the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> in an
                        effort to seduce the loyal people of Franklin into support of a Ticket
                        composed, in part at least, of men whose known sentiments are bitterly
                        antagonistic to all his former professions and teachings with regard to the
                        preservation of the Union, wriggles and twists like an injured worm under
                        our strictures.</p>
                    <p>He dislikes the company his peculiar course has necessarilly [sic] thrown him
                        into, and he frets himself wonderfully because we have honestly endeavored
                        to expose his inconsistancy [sic]. We characterized the Convention that
                        nominated the Ticket now supported by <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph>,
                        as <emph rend="italic">Day Book</emph> Democrats, the meaning of which our
                        neighbor appears to understand. For thus designating them, he charges us
                        with censuring the entire Democratic party of the county. In speaking of
                        that party we have always distinguished between the Douglas and Breckinridge
                        wing, and weeks ago, before a Ticket was nominated we used the following
                        language:</p>
                    <p>The Douglas Democracy, to their honor be it said, are as firm in their
                        support of the Administration, in the war now waging to suppress the
                        rebellion, as the most ardent Republicans.</p>
                    <p>If we have charged the editor of <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph> as
                        being a <emph rend="italic">Day Book</emph> Democrat, we only judge him by
                        the company he is in. He is supporting a Ticket which he knows is composed,
                        in part at least, of men who are bitterly hostile to the further prosecution
                        of the war--men who would now compromise with the rebels. It was such men,
                        too, who controlled the Convention, and the Convention was presided over by
                        a man who is an out-spoken advocate of Peace.</p>
                    <p>How can the editor of <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph>, claiming to be in
                        favor of an uncompromising prosecution of the war, advocate the election of
                        men who are opposed to his views? He has heretofore denounced all who are
                        for compromising with the rebels as "traitors" and "cowardly fools," in
                        which we agree with him, but strange to say, he is advocating the election
                        of just such men, and when he is changed with it, he endeavors to screen
                        himself from a further exposure by saying that "this is no time for such
                        contests."</p>
                    <p>This is just the time, after the election it is too late. The people should
                        be made acquainted with the loyalty or disloyalty of the men for whom they
                        are asked to vote, and <emph rend="italic">The Times</emph>, we trust, will
                        no longer call upon the loyal portion of the Democratic party to support men
                        whom it has justly stigmatized as "traitors" and "cowardly fools." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Answers the displeasure the Times has apparently expressed about being
                    labeled a "Day Book" Democratic paper by the Dispatch. Points out that there are
                    many Democrats--generally those who harbor sentiments similar to those of
                    Stephen Douglas--who are as loyal to the Union as any Republican, but that the
                    Times supports candidates whose loyalty is questionable at best. Therefore, the
                    Times deserves the label of "Day Book Democrat."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Issue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is unusually important and necessary that every voter at the approaching
                        Election should understand and appreciate the true issue that is presented
                        for their decision.</p>
                    <p>The Legislature must be filled with men who will cordially co-operate with
                        the State and National Governments in their plan, or the military operations
                        of the State will be crippled, and Pennsylvania will stand before the Nation
                        a chained lion--a disgraced and humiliated State, and in our prostration the
                        rebels will have secured a triumph. The State administration must be
                        sustained, or the effectiveness of our State troops, to cope with the
                        rebellion, will be crippled and destroyed.</p>
                    <p>This the sympathizers with the Rebellion understand, and they will spare no
                        efforts to defeat the Union Legislative candidates, by fraud an falsehood,
                        in every district where it is possible to do so. If the Union is to be
                        preserved, a vigorous prosecution of the war must be maintained, and to
                        secure this end, candidates favorable to sustaining both the State and
                        National Administrations must be elected.</p>
                    <p>Let the friends of the Union, then rally at once, and see to it that Maj.
                        John Rowe and W. W. Sellers, Esq., the Union candidates of this district are
                        triumphantly elected.</p>
                    <p>All who are unconditionally for the Union will vote for the Union candidates
                        for the Legislature, and all who are for compromising with the rebels will
                        vote for the Democratic candidate. Chose ye between them. Compromise with
                        the traitors means a destruction of the Government--an energetic prosecution
                        of the War means the salvation of the Nation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the most important issue in the coming election is whether the
                    candidate is a strong supporter of the Union. Puts forward the Union candidates
                    major John Rowe and W. W. Sellers, Esq., as the best men in the running.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Panic in the Seceded States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Late information, upon which we can rely, says the Philadelphia <emph
                            rend="italic">Press</emph> of Saturday last, authorizes us to state that
                        a general panic has taken place in the seceded States since Monday last. The
                        preparations of the Federal Government to seize certain important posts on
                        the Southern coasts, and the unprotected character of that coast, are among
                        the chief reasons for this rapidly increasing feeling.</p>
                    <p>Davis and the confederate traitors having failed in their absurd
                        demonstration upon Washington, (which was, in fact, never <emph
                            rend="italic">real</emph>,) are now losing the confidence of the troops
                        gathered between Richmond and the Federal capital, and are daily attacked
                        with the utmost bitterness by the people they have seduced into their
                        conspiracy. It is a fact which events will soon establish, that thousands
                        now in the rebel army are anxious to be taken prisoners by the American
                        army, in order that they be rescued from the fearful horrors under which
                        they were suffering! Nothing prevents an outburst in favor of the Union in
                        North Carolina, save the invasion of that State by the South Carolina
                        troops; and such men as Holden and Morehead will undoubtedly speak out
                        against the traitors the moment they feel strong enough so to do.</p>
                    <p>Every dollar of gold and silver is caught up and hid away, and merchants and
                        tradesmen only part with their goods for the paper of the Confederate
                        Government, and of the different State authorities, because they are
                        compelled to yield.</p>
                    <p>Let the people of the Loyal States place the fullest confidence in the
                        Administration and the army under General M'Clellan. They can afford to
                        wait. Every hour that we delay the blow upon treason strengthens the good
                        cause, and weakens the bad one.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports, based on information in the Philadelphia Press, that plans by the
                    federal government to seize posts on the Southern coasts has caused a general
                    panic among the people in the seceded states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Union Candidates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Promotes the Union ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Important from Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Governor Curtin has determined to stop all volunteers from
                    Pennsylvania from enlisting in regiments from other states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Union ticket, column 1; news from St. Louis, Washington, Cincinnati, Kansas
                City, and Reading, columns 3 and 4; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.24.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Cannon from the Teachers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the State Teachers' Association has voted to spend their
                    surplus fund on a cannon that they will present to President Lincoln to help put
                    down the rebellion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Not Quite Full</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports five full companies in the regiment being raised by Colonel F. S.
                    Stumbaugh in Franklin and surrounding counties. Colonel Stumbaugh has made
                    arrangements at Philadelphia for equipping the regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>What Does It Mean</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the emergence of "strange and mysterious marks" on various items
                    throughout town. The marks consist of a circle with a stroke drawn across the
                    middle. The Dispatch speculates that they are the symbol for a disloyal
                    organization formed by the Breckenridge Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The End of the Romance</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the arrest of Sophia Cryder of Carlisle, who set on fire the barn
                    of Mr. George Kuhns of Plainfield. Miss Cryder had resided with Mr. Kuhns and,
                    it is supposed, set fire to his barn because he intended to turn her in for
                    disguising herself as a man and joining Captain Kuhn's company of Sumner Rifles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The National Fast Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Thursday next, the 20th, inst., is the day appointed by the President of the
                        United States, by Proclamation, "as a day of public humiliation, prayer and
                        fasting, to be observed by the people of the United States with religious
                        solemnities, and the offering of fervent supplications to Almighty God for
                        the safety and welfare of these States, His blessings on their arms, and a
                        speedy restoration of peace."</p>
                    <p>By Proclamation, dated the 19th inst., the Governor of Pennsylvania, in
                        furtherance of the President's desire, "earnestly recommends to the people
                        to suspend, on that day, their ordinary avocations and to close their places
                        of business and to humble themselves before the Almighty with earnest prayer
                        that He will favorably with mercy look upon this people."</p>
                    <p>We trust the day will be observed in a proper and becoming manner, and not,
                        as many do on such solemn occasions, in feasting, drunkenness and revelry.
                        We are rejoiced at this recognition, by the heads of our Government, of the
                        Supreme Ruler of the Universe, who can raise up a well as cast down nations.
                        And as our nation is passing under His afflicting rod, it becomes us to
                        humble ourselves in the dust and to cry mightily unto Him, to spare us from
                        His just indignation and from His rightious [sic] wrath, which our multitude
                        of National transgressions have so justly merited. May God! in the
                        plentitude of His mercy, hear the prayers of the people; may their minds be
                        enlightened and grace given to enable all to put away the sins that have
                        excited His sore displeasure; may righteousness, "which exalteth a nation,"
                        cover us as a mantle; may peace revisit the fire-sides of all sections, and
                        the Starry Banner again be seen upon every rampart, floating over every
                        State, and we, again a united people, with God as our Protector, go forth,
                        the admiration of the World, and the advocates of virtue, liberty and
                        independence, of justice, truth and righteousness.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the observance of a day of fasting and prayer for the restoration
                    of peace and the protection of the United States. The Dispatch expresses the
                    hope that the day will be observed "in a proper and becoming manner."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Day of Fasting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the Dispatch.</p>
                    <p>In order to observe in unison the Day of Fasting and Prayer recommended by
                        our Civil Rulers, the Ministers of the various Protestant denominations of
                        Chambersburg, at a meeting held for that purpose, agreed to the following
                        order in regard to the pubic religious services on that day, viz:</p>
                    <p>I. That each congregation have appropriate services in their own houses of
                        worship on the morning of that day. And</p>
                    <p>II. That a Union Service be held at half-past 2 o'clock in the afternoon in
                        the Lutheran Church.</p>
                    <p>It is sincerely hoped, that all our citizens will join in a general and
                        devout religious observance of the day, so befitting a Christian People,
                        especially at such a time a this.--We indulge the pleasing hope, and
                        herewith earnestly and respectfully request our people of all trades,
                        professions and occupations--whether Merchants, Hotelkeepers, Mechanics or
                        otherwise--to close their respective stores, houses, shops or offices on
                        that day. We cannot doubt that this will be cheerfully done by all.</p>
                    <p>In behalf of the Ministers Meeting,<lb/> B. S. Schneck, Chairman. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the order of observance in Chambersburg of the Day of Fasting and
                    Prayer established by the ministers of the city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Samuel Zeigler died on September 23 in Chambersburg. He was about 52
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 3 and 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1861.09.24.04">
            <pageNote>The medical uses for salt, anecdotes, column 1; prices current, column 1;
                advertisements, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
