
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.03.03">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-03-03">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>03</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.03.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.03.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The State Temperance Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The most intemperate of all persons are those enlisted in the cause of
                        temperance. Perhaps no moral evil appeals so loudly to the reformer as the
                        evil of intemperance. None, we are sure, has called forth so many honest,
                        earnest and unwise opponents. History, we believe, records that moral
                        reformers are for the most part a set of impracticables, and history
                        doubtless tells the truth.</p>

                    <p>It is not pleasant to say anything against the manner of prosecuting the
                        temperance movement, now so earnestly advocated, for the reason that those
                        who direct and control it seldom discriminate between him who opposes the
                        measure itself and him who objects to the means employed to advance it. Even
                        at the risk of being misinterpreted, we cannot fail to comment, a little, on
                        the proceedings of the annual temperance convention held at Harrisonburg,
                        last week.</p>

                    <p>The spirit of the evil one, if invoked to aid bad men in resisting the cause
                        of temperance, could suggest no better plan than that advocated by the
                        convention, and it is possible he was present. If temperance is a political
                        question the convention was right. If it is not, the convention was wrong.
                        We think it is not; and that so long as it is sought to involve it in
                        political agitation, so long must it fail to succeed. But a restless itching
                        drives these reformers, many of whom are fanatics, to sink the sacred cause
                        of temperance in the not over clean pool of politics. They see clearly that
                        the end of temperance is grand and good, but are utterly helpless as to any
                        means of attaining it. They would make men temperate by wholesale, as
                        Charlemagne made <orig reg="Christians">christians</orig>, by driving them
                        to the river in droves and baptizing them. But the latter were not <orig
                            reg="Christians">christians</orig>, except as the half-civilized
                        chieftain understood the term, nor would the former be temperate. He would
                        be deemed an unworthy preacher of the Gospel who applied to the Legislature
                        to do fill his church with members by act of Assembly. And yet it would be
                        about as rational as what these men ask the Legislature to do in the cause
                        of temperance. Perhaps the most reasonable resolution of the convention is
                        the following:</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italics">Resolved,</emph> That the manufacture and sale of
                        intoxicating drinks are everywhere a public injury, and should be held to be
                        a public crime.</p>

                    <p>And yet it is not true. The manufacture and sale of intoxicating drinks are
                            <emph rend="italics">not</emph> a public injury, and should not be held
                        to be a public crime. The buying and drinking intoxicating drinks are sinful
                        and injurious, and herein is the legitimate field of the reformers, to teach
                        men to abstain from drinking intoxicating drinks. These people are
                        illogical. It is not the manufacture and sale of intoxicating liquors which
                        cause intemperance. It is just the opposite. The intemperance of the people
                        causes its manufacture and sale. Remove the one and the other will fall of
                        itself. So long as it remains no power on earth can prevent its manufacture
                        and sale. This is not hard to understand, and yet the failure to understand
                        it has knocked the vitality out of more temperance movements than would, if
                        properly directed, have saved the lives of thousands of human beings, and
                        prevented untold woe and misery.</p>

                    <p>Let these reformers begin at the other end. Let men and women, yes! we say
                        women, abstain from tippling, and bring up their children to be temperate.
                        It is defective education that makes drunkards. Children are sent to school
                        for the purpose of training and developing their intellects, but the moral
                        nature is left, in a great degree, to take care of itself. Hence we often
                        see the ablest intellects, the most besotted drunkards. At home, in the
                        school-room and in the church the cause of temperance must be strengthened
                        and made powerful, if at all. Here are the agencies both to restrain
                        intemperance and to reclaim the intemperate. If these are properly used, the
                        manufacture and sale of the infernal decoction will come to an end.</p>

                    <p>The President of the convention understood this, and, before adjoining it
                        took occasion to say:</p>

                    <p>He felt that the friends of temperance were taking advance steps in the
                        glorious reform, and hoped that they would go from this place feeling that
                        the meeting was a profitable one; and hoped they would go, trusting in no
                        human strength - that the strength of man was not possible to accomplish
                        this great work - it was not possible to accomplish this great work - it was
                        not possible to accomplish it outside of the Christian Church; he hoped they
                        would remember that God worked many reforms. As the Christian Church is the
                        representative instrument through which He works, let us seek to bring up
                        action in the temperance reform, and that they would unite upon one basis
                        and one plan of action.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article attacks the actions of the recent Temperance Movement
                    Convention, not because the author believes alcohol to be anything but evil, but
                    rather because he feels that moral education rather than politics is the correct
                    venue for pursuing it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic Extravagance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises Republican journals for denouncing attempts of some
                    Republican members of the legislature to "squander the people's money." The
                    editors hold that "demagogues and corrupt men may creep into the party," and it
                    is the duty of the press to expose them. They denounce the Republican newspapers
                    that did not.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For Our Neighbor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>By a vote of three to one the Senate of the United States, on Friday,
                        accepted the report of the Conference Committee on the Constitutional
                        Amendment, guaranteeing impartial suffrage throughout the United States. It
                        has already been adopted by the House, and is now ready to be submitted to
                        the State Legislatures for their approval or refusal. The provision is
                        simple even to plainness, and puts all male citizens of the United States in
                        exactly the same relation.</p>

                    <p>The right of the citizens of the United States shall not be denied or
                        abridged by the United States or by any State, on account of race, color, or
                        previous condition of servitude.</p>

                    <p>Congress has dared to be just, to do exactly what is right, to take the last
                        step which was required to prove that the Republican party is both in word
                        and deed the party of equal rights to all. Whether this amendment be
                        accepted by the States or not, it can no more be said that it fears to
                        practice what it preaches. After rescuing the government from dismemberment,
                        and traitors themselves from the curse of slavery, it has taken the
                        declaration of principles of the fathers of the Republic and given it force
                        and vitality. It has declared no new doctrine. The contest for Independence
                        was fought and won upon this issue. But all that was involved in the contest
                        was not secured. With this amendment made a part of the Constitution it is
                        secured forever, and the condition, without which the Republican party would
                        never have existed, ceases. This amendment secured, the political agitation,
                        which has shaken and distracted the country for years, will be at an end,
                        and for the first time in its history we will have a united people. Our
                        practice will then conform to our principles; we will assure justice to
                        ourselves by doing justice to others, and the status fo the negro will be
                        settled for all time.</p>

                    <p>It is possible it can have taken us so many years, and cost such rivers of
                        human blood, and such countless treasure to learn to know and practice the
                        golden rule? So it seems. But Governments learn slowly and at bitter cost.
                        What they have learned they are not likely to forget.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article supports the Fifteenth Amendment, recently passed out of the
                    Senate after Conference Committee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>That Coffee Pot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper scoffs at charges made by Democratic Party Chairman William A.
                    Wallace that Republicans are planning fraud in the upcoming elections. The
                    editors charge that it is the Democrats who resort to fraud. "The unwarranted
                    outrages committed by Democratic Election Boards, last fall, surpassed all
                    former efforts in magnitude and success." The article finishes with a plea for
                    Republicans to mobilize for the spring elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>ANDREW JOHNSON is in every sense of the word a bad man. As President he ever
                        sought out the worst thing to be done and did it. But he was only human, and
                        his capacity for doing evil, like Sam Weller's vision, was limited. He was
                        always ready to give the loyal people "the best he had in his shop," which
                        is technical, among sports, for the worst.</p>

                    <p>He was not really as bad as the Devil, chiefly on account of the aforesaid
                        limitation: but old Diabolus, who was pretty severely handled by one John
                        Milton, in his time, was always spoken of in respectable English, even
                        though there was nothing good to be said of him. Not so, however, does John
                        W. Forney discourse of the retiring Johnson. Last Saturday's <emph
                            rend="italics">Press</emph> tells us that - </p>

                    <p>Next Thursday for the last time will Andrew Johnson, in nebulous imagination,
                        behold himself near that colossal altar, within that vast and shadowy
                        amphitheatre from which gaze the thirty millions of the American people. Can
                        we not have some last words and dying confession? Or will the Tribune of the
                        people "Veto" the inauguration oath of his successor?</p>

                    <p>We venture to guess that we can, and that he will not; though we are by no
                        means confident that our guesses are correct.</p>

                    <p>Alas! poor Johnson. It were better a thousand times hadst thou been impeached
                        and convicted. For then at least would'st thou have escaped this horrible
                        beplastering of meaningless words, rained down upon thy defenseless head
                        from the "nebulous imagination" of the <emph rend="italics">Press</emph>.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article calls Johnson as morally deficient as the Devil and generally
                    evil.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Cannot Something Be Done?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italics">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>I mean, cannot something be done <emph rend="italics">by law</emph> - either
                        by our Borough or State law - to compel those street-loungers and idlers of
                        our town, to follow some employment or other, in order to keep their
                        families from being a charge upon the people, or else from starvation? It is
                        a well known fact, that there are a number of black and white families in
                        town, the husbands and fathers of which <emph rend="italics">don't want to
                            work</emph>, and who spend, what money they do earn, in <emph
                            rend="italics">drinking whiskey</emph>, whilst their wives and children
                        have nothing to eat, nothing to wear, and nothing to keep the house warm in
                        winter.</p>

                    <p>You can see half a score of sable idlers and loungers every day at "Wallace's
                        corner," and anon you can see them taking a "penny collection" among
                        themselves (chicken and turkey money, mayhap), to buy a bottle full of
                        poison from some <emph rend="italics">respectable retailer</emph>, and then
                        they have a jolly time of it. Meanwhile their wives and children are crying
                        for bread and other necessaries of life, and the Christian sense of our
                        community will not allow them to suffer, nor should they.</p>

                    <p>The same thing if true of not a few miserable men with white skins. You can't
                        get them to do steady work, not at the highest wages. They will do just like
                        their equals of Wolfstown, work up little "chores," just sufficient to buy a
                        jug of liquid fire from some unprincipled licensed or unlicensed <orig
                            reg="rum-seller">rumseller</orig>, and wife and children are either
                        suffering at home, or else are aided by the charitable and humane of the
                        town.</p>

                    <p>Now I ask, is there no remedy for this state of things? Can nothing be done
                        to compel these wretched, miserable husband's and fathers, to support their
                        families? Our people cheerfully give of their means to aid the deserving
                        poor, the sick and the unfortunate. But to help to feed not only the
                        families of these besotted idlers, but to some extent these idlers <emph
                            rend="italics">themselves</emph>, is carrying charity and good nature a
                        little too far. And hence I ask again: Can nothing be done to reach these
                        wretched men, and <emph rend="italics">compel</emph> them to work?</p>

                    <p>To send them to jail as vagrants won't help the matter, as our jail is now
                        conducted. But could it not be so conducted as to make its inmates perform
                        work of some kind? I know that this plan is carried out elsewhere. I have
                        just now before me the following item, which is copied from a Philadelphia
                        paper:</p>

                    <p>In the Chester county prison last year about seven thousand yards each of
                        check and carpeting, and a considerable quantity of other articles, were
                        manufactured by the inmates. The goods sold by the prison authorities
                        amounted to $5,261, and the sum drawn from the county treasury was $4,700.
                        The labor of the prisoners thus paid more than half the expenses, and they
                        were protected from the evil effects of idleness and promiscuous
                        association.</p>

                    <p>Now it strikes me, that if we had a place where these vagrant, vagabonding
                        men could be placed, and compelled to work, it would be doing a great
                        blessing to them, to their families and the community. I would like to know,
                        Messrs. Editors, whether in this or some other and perhaps better way,
                        anything could be done in the direction referred to. A CITIZEN.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter to the editor calls for action against a vagrancy problem.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.03.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the Housum Zouaves are rehearsing for a dramatic
                    entertainment they are planning to give in Repository Hall. The proceeds will go
                    to pay debts incurred in equipping the company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Chambersburg Woolen Manufactory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Wollen Manufacturing Company is making efforts to increase
                    its capital stock. If more money is not raised, production will have to be
                    suspended and employees laid off. The paper urges Franklin citizens to come to
                    the rescue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Business Change</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Frank U.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. P. Keefer and Frank U. Keefer have formed a partnership.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swanger</ln>
                        <fn>D. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haulman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. Skinner, County Treasurer, announces that the following have been
                    named as collectors: Henry Balsley, Antrim; D. D. Swanger, Lurgan; Jacob
                    Haulman, Peters; William F. Horner, Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fire in St. Thomas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Peter C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter C. Hollar's steam saw mill in St. Thomas caught fire on February 1st.
                    The blaze did $200 in damage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Graduated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. W. B. Brown of Chambersburg graduated from Dr. Tralls Therapeutic
                    College in New Jersey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Seibert sold his dwelling house and lot on Second Street to
                    Chambersburg's Episcopal congregation for $7,500. They plan to erect a church
                    there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Temperance Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Nicholson of Philadelphia will deliver a free lecture on temperance
                    on March 16th at the Court House. The event is sponsored by the Falling Spring
                    Division, Sons of Temperance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Purchased</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. P. Keefer and Co. purchased the lot adjoining the residence of J. P.
                    Keefer from John B. Stuart for $800.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Poor House spent $13,477.42 for the year 1868, $1,953
                    less than the previous year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cleary</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John F. M'Cleary, compositor in the Repository Job office, and Ellen V.
                    Keefer from near Chambersburg, were married at the M. E. Parsonage in
                    Shippensburg on February 17th by the Rev. W. A. Houck. A poem of congratulations
                    is included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jonathan Jones and Miss Sarah Conner, both of Franklin, were married at the
                    St. Thomas residence of Solomon Hollar on February 23rd by the Rev. S. A.
                    Mowers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dysert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowen</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Dysert and Mary Bowen, both of Franklin, were married on February 16th
                    by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>L. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Kate F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>L. L. Gilbert and Miss Kate F. Shank, both of Leitersburg, were married in
                    the National Hotel on February 25th by the Rev. I. N. Hays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detwiler</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J. </fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Crider of Newburg and Miss Amanda C. Detwiler of Franklin County
                    were married on February 4th by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Elizabeth J. Clark of Chambersburg died on January 20th. She was 43
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>



            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.03.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
