
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.11.17">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/19/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-11-17">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>17</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.11.17.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.11.17.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Thanksgiving Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p><orig reg="Tomorrow">To-morrow</orig> will be observed generally throughout
                        this wide spread country, as a day of thanksgiving to Almighty God, for the
                        manifold mercies which he has vouchsafed to this favored land. In its
                        outward commemoration, all sects and parties, all creeds and confessions,
                        all colors and conditions, races and nationalities, will unite. It will be
                        celebrated in august domes and humble mission houses; with the pompous and
                        magnificent rites of the most venerable and exacting of the <orig
                            reg="Christian">christian</orig> churches, and with the crude and simple
                        modes of worship that characterize the unauthorized petty sects into which
                            <orig reg="Christianity">christianity</orig> is unhappily divided.</p>

                    <p>No people ever had so much to be thankful for, as the citizens of these
                        United States; no generation so much as this, and no year has been so
                        fraught with blessings as the one, for whose benefit we are called upon to
                        return our thanks tomorrow.</p>

                    <p>The soil has rendered us a surpassing abundance of fruits, of all kinds, for
                        our nourishment and enjoyment, the air has been singularly healthful, no
                        pestilence having spread its wings to darken it, and diseases of all kinds
                        having strangely spared us. Above all, peace has brooded over the land. The
                        war-clouds which so long shadowed us have left no "wrack behind," and
                        prosperity has followed in the paths of peace. The heart-burnings and
                        animosities, begot by war, are dying out, and good neighborhood and
                        brotherly affection are coming back, to be more pure and lasting than
                        before. An identity of interests are being felt, to be surely accompanied by
                        a harmony of action. The dark demon of caste is shrinking, and the spirit of
                        a common brotherhood among the sons of Adam is beginning to rule in the
                        hearts of Americans.</p>

                    <p>The material interests of the country are immensely enhanced. Its population
                        has been enormously swollen by the immigration of useful and
                        wealth-producing subjects of the despotisms of the old world. The means of
                        intercourse and commercial facilities throughout the republic have been
                        greatly enlarged; so that now the shores of the Pacific are as near, and the
                        wild recesses of the Rocky Mountains are as accessible, as the frontiers of
                        our own State were less than a half a century ago.</p>

                    <p>We have cause for thankfulness in the wisdom and fidelity of the rulers set
                        over us. This year will be memorable in all time as that which opened the
                        administration of Grant, rendered still more blessed in the closing of that
                        of the debauched recreant who sullied our fair fame.</p>

                    <p>We have cause for thankfulness for the religious privileges enjoyed, for the
                        advancement of the kingdom of Christ upon earth, for the wakened interest in
                        the higher concerns of life, that has manifested itself over great portions
                        of this country, and for the growing desire for <orig reg="Christian"
                            >christian</orig> unity, forcing itself outward in religious
                        communities, and illustrated so magnificently within the past few days in
                        one of the foremost of the ecclesiastical bodies in this country.</p>

                    <p>These are a portion of the many reasons for thankfulness to the Ruler of
                        Nations and the Merciful Benefactor of the meanest individual. Each one of
                        us has special cause for thanks. Let us search our hearts for them, and give
                        praise with joy, not forgetting that even tribulations and sorrows, may be
                        mercifully ordained.</p>

                    <p>How shall we observe this day? So far as religious exercises go, we answer,
                        of course, in the right spirit and manner. But on the whole, we question
                        whether the true idea of thankfulness obtains. It will be a day of mixed
                        good and evil, as it is a day in which civic and ecclesiastical authorities
                        unite in forming a holiday, in which the spirit of jollification and of
                        worship will share the sway. It will be a grand feast day, whereon we will
                        show our gratitude for the creature comforts bestowed upon us, by a greedy
                        appropriation of them to our own sustenance. And here it occurs to us to
                        suggest that while we are indulging in the luxuries of the table, that we
                        remember those of our fellows who are suffering from the want of the
                        necessaries of life, those whom the wild winds of winter will find <orig
                            reg="defenseless">defenceless</orig> from its storms, half-clad, and
                        broken by distress and disease. The consciousness that multitudes about us,
                        many of them even professing the same <orig reg="Christian">christian</orig>
                        faith, are starving while we are revelling, should temper our indulgences
                        and lead us of our abundance to bestow something upon the poor. Such
                        benevolence is the best of our good works, and is the genuine fruit of
                        faith. It is the most acceptable of thank offerings. As we have received, so
                        should we give. Selfish and insincere is the gratitude for good gifts
                        granted unto us, if we neglect those who have humanity's claim upon us, for
                        a portion of the superabundant comforts we have obtained.</p>

                    <p>We hope that the ministers of the gospel, who will accept from the State this
                        as a religious holiday, will save it from the emptiness of a mere formality,
                        a meaningless ostentation of devout gratitude for the favors bestowed upon
                        the nation and people, by the Head of the Church; and press upon the Rulers
                        of the Nation who make a rhetorical show of gratitude, their obligations to
                        Him and their duty to men whom the Father of all has organized into
                        communities and governments; and upon the people at large--the solemn duty
                        of not giving a mere outward and decorous show of thankfulness, but to give
                        evidence of its inward earnestness by a life of devotion, and to prove
                        themselves deserving of heavenly favors by their willingness to favor the
                        unfortunate who are "always with us."</p>

                    <p>"Let the people praise Thee, O God! let all the people praise Thee.</p>

                    <p>Then shall the earth yield her increase; and God, even our own God, shall
                        bless us."</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper's Thanksgiving message reflects on the accomplishments of the
                    year and the meaning of the occasion to the united nation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>There is such visible improvement of the tone and temper of our neighbor, the
                            <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, on the subject of the payment of the
                        Border damages, since our article two weeks ago, that we cannot refrain from
                        congratulating it on the change, and ourselves on being somewhat
                        instrumental in bringing it about.</p>

                    <p>On the 27th of October, with the disappointment and chagrin arising from the
                        Democratic defeat hanging heavily upon its spirits, it growled forth the
                        following:</p>

                    <p>"We are thoroughly convinced that unless the Republicans of the Border
                        Counties lay aside their political prejudice for a season and vote as their
                        interests demand, payment of the Border damages never will be obtained. They
                        must make their political friends in other parts of the State <emph
                            rend="italic">feel</emph> the danger they incur by denying the just
                        demands of the plundered people of the Border Counties."</p>

                    <p>In last week's issue of the same paper we find a far more just and hopeful
                        view. It says in concluding an article on the same subject:</p>

                    <p>"We have an abiding confidence in the ability of the border counties, if they
                        but work energetically together, to procure the passage of a bill to
                        reimburse them for the losses sustained by reason of the rebellion. Let us
                        give then, a long pull, a strong pull, and a pull altogether, and let us
                        hear no more about the inclination of Democrats to pay Rebel losses."</p>

                    <p>Faith in the power to accomplish that which we wish to do is a very strong
                        element and may be regarded as so much positive strength in any undertaking.
                        It is not an uncommon saying that if one believes strongly enough in
                        himself, he can do anything which he undertakes. In this unlimited way of
                        putting it, of course, it is not true. Examples are too common of men
                        undertaking mighty things who lack nothing necessary to make them successful
                        except ability. They have an "abiding confidence" in themselves, but it is
                        an unreasonable confidence. No person entertains it but themselves, and when
                        they fail no person is at a loss for the reason of their failure but
                        themselves. We say this in order to qualify the remark which we made above.
                        We also have an abiding faith in the ability of the border counties to
                        procure reinbursement from the Legislature, for their losses sustained by
                        reason of the rebellion. It is not an unreasonable faith, because it is
                        founded on the operation of causes and conditions which never fail in moving
                        men to the performance of every right act. We have confidence, first of all,
                        because the claim of our people on the Legislature for payment is just and
                        right. The property which was destroyed by rebels or consumed by Union
                        troops was theirs. They were loyal men and women, and gave their sons
                        without stint, to battle with the foes of the government, many of whom never
                        returned to gladden the hearts of their parents.</p>

                    <p>When the heaviest losses came upon them, the destruction of their property by
                        rebels, almost the entire available force of the county was in the army, at
                        the command of the government. Many who lived in comfort were reduced to
                        extreme poverty, and continue so to this day. Others were severely crippled
                        in their circumstances, and the entire county, once the most prosperous in
                        the State, is now heavily burdened with debt. By reason of the abundance
                        which this county and a few others furnished to fill the ravenous maw of the
                        Confederate army, the remainder of the State, with its immense wealth,
                        escaped unhurt. It can still be said that the unparalleled sacrifice of the
                        border counties by which the State was rescued from devastation was made for
                        an ungenerous and ungrateful people, because they have neglected, out of the
                        abundance saved to them, to make compensation to those who lost theirs in
                        saving it. But it will not long be said. The Commonwealth dare not suffer
                        such injustice to a part of her own people to continue. They have rights as
                        clearly established as that they owe duties. They were entitled to
                        protection against hostile invaders, and failing in that the Commonwealth
                        now owes compensation from which it cannot escape without disgrace and
                        dishonor. Hence we say our claim is just, which is the strngest reason why
                        we have confidence in its being granted by the Legislature.</p>

                    <p>Our confidence is strengthened, in the second place, by the fact of the large
                        number of persons who are among the losers. They compose the most
                        influential citizens of the border counties, a large number of them farmers,
                        and others merchants, mechanics, manufacturers and professional men. Their
                        united influence cannot fail to have great weight in bringing those who are
                        constituted the lawmakers of the State, to see the justice of their claims
                        and in procuring compensation. We hope to see all who have suffered losses
                        exert themselves as if they too had confidence in an earnest and united
                        effort, and our word for it, if they do, though their efforts may not be
                        crowned with success at once, the time will come when they will receive full
                        compensation.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper issues a strong defense of the rights of the people of Franklin
                    for compensation for war damages.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.11.17.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Something Worth Hearing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Charles Sumner will lecture in Repository Hall on November 25th. He will
                    speak on the "Question of Caste." The paper praises Sumner as a great statesman,
                    placing him "among the chiefest and ablest advocates of the rights of mankind,
                    and the boldest enemies of slavery."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Western Union Telegraph Company is announcing lowered rates. W. B.
                    Gilmore, Chambersburg operator, announces that even cheaper rates can be
                    purchased if the message is allowed to sit for awhile in the office. Messages
                    from Chambersburg to Hagerstown, Greencastle, Shippesnburg, and Gettysburg have
                    fallen from 40 cents to 25cents; to McConnellsburg from 40 cents to 35 cents; to
                    Newville, Carlisle, Mechanicsburg, and Harrisburg from 40 cents to 30 cents; to
                    Charlestown, Va., from 80 cents to 55 cents; to Winchester, Va., from 90 cents
                    to 55 cents; to New Hamburg, NY, from $1.20 to 75 cents; to Rochester, NY, from
                    $1.60 to 75 cents; to Buffalo, NY, from $1.40 to 75 cents; to Omaha, Nebraska,
                    from $5.35 to $2.40; and to San Francisco, CA, from $7.50 to $5.40.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodburn</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The First Lutheran Church of Chambersburg will be open for worship on
                    November 21st. A number of improvements have been made to the church building.
                    Rev. Schaff and Rev. I. N. Hays will lead services in the German Reformed Church
                    on Thanksgiving Day. Rev. W. G. Hawkins will preach a Thanksgiving sermon in the
                    Episcopal Church on Thursday. Rev. James Kennedy and Rev. Mr. Woodburn will
                    administer the Lord's Supper in Fayetteville on Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Furgeson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Allen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>David J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stark</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Curdy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>Noah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Porter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of Metal and Fannett township will meet in the public house of
                    C. Gross in Fannettsburg on November 27th to take action to promote the
                    extension of the railroad from Mercersburg to Loudon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Ministerial Association of the Pennsylvania Annual Conference of the
                    United Brethren in Christ, whose object is "the mutual improvement of its
                    members in their pulpit labors, pastoral duties and literary pursuits," holds
                    semi-annual meetings, and includes Franklin County ministers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A number of repairs to the basement of the First M. E. Church have been
                    completed. The rooms have been arranged for the accomodation of Sunday Schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>R. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Building Association chose officers at an annual election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the African American population of Pennsylvania in
                    1860 stood at 56,949, including 1,799 in Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mechanicsburg Brass Band will perform in Chambersburg on Thanksgiving.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The silver medal won by the Franklin County Horticultural Society at the
                    United States Pomological Convention is on display in Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Richard Newton of the American Sunday School Union spoke at the Court
                    House to the Sabbath School children of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. T. B. Kennedy and family left for St. Augustine, Florida, where they
                    will spend the winter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John P. Grove died near Brough's Mill in Hamilton on November 13th. He was
                    53 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.11.17.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
