
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.07.21">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/09/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-07-21">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.07.21.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.07.21.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Repository for the Campaign! Geary, Williams and Victory!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that the <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> will be
                    published at special low rates during the campaign in the interest of supporting
                    the campaign and disseminating the "political truth among the voters of the
                    County." Single copies will go for 60 cents, and deals will also be made on bulk
                    purchases. The editors hope all the clubs in the area will take a copy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Last week the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> said:</p>

                    <p>The Registry act, odious, unjust and unequal as it is, is now the law of the
                        State and must be observed as such until repealed. As soon as a Democratic
                        Legislature is elected it will undoubtedly be wiped out of existence. The
                        simple qualifications of an elector prescribed by our State constitution are
                        all that should be required. But this decision has been rendered in the
                        interest of the Radical party, and, for the time being, is the law.
                        Democrats will, therefore, do well to read the law carefully and study it
                        thoroughly, so as to qualify themselves properly for the exercise of the
                        right of suffrage. In order that they may do this we will publish it in full
                        in our issue of next week.</p>

                    <p>The Radical leaders are totally unscrupulous and do not hesitate to enact any
                        infamous legislation which will inure to their benefit. Let Democrats be up
                        and doing, meet them on their own ground, prepare for voting, and when the
                        time comes, cast an overwhelming vote for the Democratic candidates and the
                        repeal of this infamous Registry law.</p>

                    <p>For all this we thank the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>. We admit that
                        the Registry law is odious; that it is unjust and unequal we emphatically
                        deny. A law made for the benefit and protection of the good citizens is
                        always odious to him whose violations of the rights of others it restrains
                        and punishes. A law framed to encourage vice and fraud is detrimental to the
                        best interests of society, and odious to every upright, honest man. Hence as
                        long as there are both these classes every law must necessarily be odious to
                        one or other of them. This law is odious to the Democratic party only, at
                        least we have never seen or heard any objections made to it by the
                        Republican party. Why is it odious to the Democratic party? The <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph> says because it was made in the interest of
                        the Radical party. If the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> means by this
                        that it deprives or interferes with the right of suffrage of any member of
                        the Democratic party, and is, in that view of the case, made in the interest
                        of the Radicals, we deny it. If it means that it destroys the opportunities
                        for fraudulent and corrupt voting, which existed under the old law, and
                        thereby deprives the Democratic party of a main element of its strength, we
                        admit it, and say, in that view it has been made in the interest of the
                        Radical party.</p>

                    <p>Now we intend to hold the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> to the text in
                        this matter, "that the Registry Law was made in the interest of the Radical
                        or Republican party." We mean to prove by its own declaration, and what it
                        must admit, that the law is advantageous to the Republican party only,
                        because it prevents fraudulent voting in both parties, and thereby weakens
                        the Democratic party by as many votes as it was able to cast fraudulently.</p>

                    <p>Let us see if we are right. We admit that this law was framed in the interest
                        of the Radical party; the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> says so. It is
                        true. But it makes the requirements of all voters the same. A Republican
                        voter must comply with exactly the same conditions, because he can deposit
                        his ballot, that a Democratic voter must; and he has just exactly the same
                        opportunity to do so that a Democratic voter has, no more, no less. This is
                        true of both native and naturalized voters. Now it must be admitted that so
                        far as we have gone, and it covers the whole law, not a single provision
                        gives the Republican voter an advantage over the Democratic voter. It is not
                        in the law proper, then, that we must look for the advantage it gives the
                        Republican party.</p>

                    <p>The inequality exists in the parties, and not in the law. This is what the
                            <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> meant. It meant that to the party
                        which advocates and practices an honest ballot, the law gives a preference,
                        over the party which tries to carry elections by corrupt voting. We greatly
                        admire the candor of the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>, but protest
                        against treating its party friends with so little courtesy. The <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph>'s complaint against the law is that of all
                        rogues against all just laws. The thief says that the law which makes
                        stealing a felony has been framed in the interest of a party to which he is
                        opposed, and is therefore unjust. The murderer says that the law which
                        punishes murder with death discriminates against him, and is therefore made
                        in the interest of those to whom he is opposed. But if the thief and the
                        murderer were virtuous, honest citizens, the law would be their protection
                        and shield instead of their punishment. The inequality is not in the law,
                        but in the parties. Just so in the other case. If the Democratic party puts
                        its trust and hope for success solely in the superiority of its principles
                        over those of the Republican party, and in the clearness and vigor and
                        energy with which it presents them to the people, the Registry Law, which it
                        so much fears and hates, would be as much to its advantage as to that of the
                        Republican party.</p>

                    <p>Democrats of Franklin county, how do you relish the position in which your
                        organ has put you? Do you admit that you hate and oppose an honest and just
                        Registry Law, which discriminates in favor of neither party, because it
                        prevents fraudulent and corrupt voting? This is what the <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph> assumes to say for you? How do you like it?</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial rebutts an article in the <emph rend="italics"
                    >Spirit</emph>, which attacked the new registry law intended to reduce vote
                    fraud and corruption. The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> argues that
                    while the law helps Radical Republicans and hurts Democrats, it does so simply
                    because the Democrats have used voter fraud and corrupt politics so much more in
                    elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>How Are You Soldiers?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>We are authorized by Capt. Skinner to issue a call for the <orig
                            reg="reorganization">re-organization</orig> of his famous club of White
                        Boys in Blue, and he directs us to say that he is encouraged to do this by
                        the unparalleled magnanimity with which the soldiers were treated by the
                        late Democratic Convention. That Convention actually adopted a resolution
                        professing gratitude "to our soldiers and sailors who carried the flag of
                        our country to victory." Wasn't that a great deal? It is true that its
                        effect was a little marred by the fact that it came from the party which
                        always opposed the soldier's right to vote, and which argued and voted
                        against paying them bounties, and which favored deserters and bounty
                        jumpers. It is true, also, that the chairman of the committee which reported
                        this resolution was the notorious Frank W. Hughes, who aided and encouraged
                        the draft riots in Schuylkill county during the war, and of course his love
                        of the soldiers and sailors inspired it; and that the Honorable Brick
                        Pomeroy, of the New York <emph rend="italics">Democrat</emph>, who always
                        said so many sweet things about the soldiers in such a pious way, attended
                        the Convention and lent his influence to the nomination of Packer and to the
                        passage of the resolution professing gratitude. It is also true that the two
                        soldiers whose names were presented to the Convention as candidates for
                        nomination for Governor, Gen. Hancock and Gen. M'Candless, received no
                        support worth mentioning from the Convention, the one being entirely dropped
                        after the first ballot, and the second receiving but seventeen votes on the
                        second ballot, which nominated Packer; but then these are the merest trifles
                        in comparison with the weighty consideration that the Convention resolved
                        that it felt a feeling of gratitude for soldiers and sailors. So the Captain
                        thinks, and if there are any other soldiers who thinks as he does, we invite
                        them to make application for membership in his club of White Boys in Blue.
                        The number is small yet, consisting wholly of Capt. Skinner and himself.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This sardonic article mocks the Democratic convention's resolution
                    professing gratitude to Union veterans as a hollow gesture considering its
                    actions of the past several years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Antedeluvian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Virginia learns but Pennsylvania does not. When the Democracy of Pennsylvania
                        nominated Woodward as the anti-war candidate for Governor, Virginia stood on
                        the same political plane, and was fighting the battle on the rebellion. Six
                        years have passed, and Virginia has reached the high ground of Universal
                        suffrage and Universal Amnesty, while the Pennsylvania Democrats still
                        grovel in the low and unhealthy places which they held then. Their platform
                        has been dug out of the rubbish of a former defeat and smell awfully stale
                        and musty. To read it is about as interesting as to dig up a skeleton and
                        listen to the wind whistling wailing dirges through its shivering bones. We
                        read that the negroes must not have the right of suffrage, that our finances
                        are in an awful bad way, which was doubtless true when this platform was
                        originally written, many, many years ago, that to make them better the
                        Democrats must finger the money, that the reconstruction policy is all
                        wrong, and, that our taxation is a tyranny.</p>

                    <p>It was just as well that the Convention didn't rack its brains, if it had
                        any, to get up a new platform. The old one will do just as well for a defeat
                        as any, and the leaders can grease their palms with Packer's bonds and
                        railroad stocks as well as if it had been prepared for this special
                        occasion.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> points out that while Virginia's
                    Democrats have already accepted universal suffrage, Pennsylvania's Democratic
                    party retains the same platform it has had for many years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges party unity in the upcoming campaign. All grudges and
                    infighting should be put aside in the interest of supporting the entire ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Democrats of Pennsylvania at their late Convention, wisely concluded not
                        to rejoice over the Virginia election. The leaders of the Democratic
                        P-a-r-t-y dare not tell their deluded followers, that their Southern allies
                        are in favor of negro suffrage and that every negro who voted with them was
                        rewarded for this betrayal of his race, with a suitable present of land or
                        money. Such is the case, and that is why no reference was made to this
                        victory of Democratic rebels, and Democratic negroes. The man who believes
                        that by voting with the opposition he will prevent the final passage of the
                        15th Amendment to the Constitution would follow the man who would attempt to
                        take Fort Gibraltar, by shelling it with coriander seeds, and with the same
                        hopes of success. How would a Democratic white voter of this Congressional
                        District treat a Democratic negro voter of Virginia, who believed in all his
                        political dogmas and ideas? Gentlemen of the Democratic party, your Southern
                        friends have stolen your thunder, and you <emph rend="italics">dare not put
                            yourselves in opposition to them.</emph> They are your masters, they own
                        you, soul and body, and you must submit to their commands.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> mocks the Pennsylvania
                    Democrats' refusal to follow the lead of some Southern Democrats and accept
                    universal (male) suffrage as inevitable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Democratic State Convention, last week, resolved that they "do
                        emphatically deny that their is any right or power in Congress or elsewhere
                        to impose negro suffrage upon the people of this State in opposition to
                        their will." That is to say, if all the States except Pennsylvania ratified
                        the amendment establishing impartial Suffrage, and Pennsylvania should vote
                        against it, she would have a right to nullify that part of the constitution
                        within her limits. Is that what the resolution means? Mr. <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph>. If not what does it mean? To us it looks
                        very much like wearing the gray. Is it possible, gentlemen of the
                        Convention, that you didn't perceive the absurdity into which you were
                        tumbling? This is the lovely party that talks of "ameliorating the condition
                        of the laboring men," and declares that "our soldiers and sailors who
                        carried the flag of our country to victory must be gratefully remembered."
                        What a muddle; declare themselves in favor of disloyalty, and in the same
                        breath speak of gratefully remembering the soldiers and sailors who put down
                        disloyalty.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> attacks what it sees as an
                    antiquated and fractured message coming from the Democratic State Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper suggests that Packer, Democratic candidate for governor, was
                    nominated because of his vast wealth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>County Treasurer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flinder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"An Old Republican" writes to support the nomination of Jacob N. Flinder
                    for County Treasurer. He cites his service to party and as auditor of the
                    Quarter Master's department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.07.21.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. M'D</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the defeat of Capt. G. W. Skinner of Franklin in his
                    efforts to get the Franklin delegation to vote for Cass at the Democratic
                    convention. The editors imply that a number of prominent Franklin Democrats,
                    including William M'Lellan, J. M'D Sharpe, and T. B. Kennedy, defected to Packer
                    in hope of securing lucrative patronage and offices should he be elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funston</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A recent rainstorm has brought great benefit to the crops of Franklin
                    County. Some areas of Amberson's Valley reported hail, however, where it did
                    damage to the unmown meadows of William D. Funston, Simon Stewart, and William
                    Piper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Greencastle is constructing a town hall. The new
                    building will be invaluable in attracting speakers and events to the town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ahl</ln>
                        <fn>D. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shannon</ln>
                        <fn>O. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Some citiznes of Newville, Bedford, and Burnt Cabins are calling for a
                    railroad meeting at Burnt Cabins to discuss construction of a railroad from the
                    Pennsylvania Railroad at Mt. Union to the Cumberland Valley Railroad. The paper
                    urges Chambersburg residents to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The society met on July 6th at the seed store. Several members exhibited
                    fruits and vegetables and J. S. Nixon read a paper on agricultural chemistry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Picnic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gilmore Lodge No. 358, I.O.G.T., will hold a basket picnic in Fayetteville
                    on July 31st. M'Murray Lodge of Chambersburg has also been invited. The
                    Fayetteville band will play.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George E. Jones of Fannettsburg won the Latin Salutatory at Lafayette
                    College. Jones has been offered the position of English teacher at a Spanish
                    boarding school on the island of Curacoa, South America.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Fayetteville will hold an ice cream festival on July 31st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Rodgers of Mercersburg attempted to commit suicide but was
                    discovered in time to prevent injury. The attempt is ascribed to family
                    difficulties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Josiah D. Detrich of Waynesboro graduated from Franklin and Marshall
                    College on July 1st. he gave a commencement oration on "Pleasures of Art."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>D. R. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major D. R. B. Nevin, formerly of Chambersburg, has been propmoted to chief
                    of the division of receipts and expenditures in the register's office in
                    Washington D.C.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The sociable of the Falling Spring Presbyterian Church will meet on the
                    grounds of William McLellan on July 22nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. B. Shively of Fayetteville recently returned from a trip through the
                    western states and territories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. H. Noble, formerly of Chambersburg but now of Buckingham County, Va.,
                    was "triumphantly" elected to the Virginia House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. A. Crawford will preach in the Falling Spring Presbyterian Church
                    on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn>D. Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. Z. Shook of Greencastle has been appointed telegraph operator at
                    Monterey Springs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The town hall of Waynesboro has been recently repaired.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Greencastle has ordered a town clock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Democratic Platform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Democracy of Pennsylvania in convention met, do unanimously declare - </p>

                    <p>1. That the federal government is limited to the grants contained in the
                        Federal Constitution; that the exercise of doubtful constitutional powers is
                        dangerous to the stability of the government and the safety of the people,
                        and the Democratic party will never consent that the State of Pennsylvania
                        shall surrender her great right of local self-government.</p>

                    <p>2. That the attempted ratification of the proposed fifteenth amendment to the
                        Federal Constitution by the radical members of the last Legislature, and
                        their refusal to submit the same to a vote of the people, was a deliberate
                        breach of their official duty and an outrage upon every citizen of the
                        State, and the resolution making such ratification should be promptly
                        repealed and the amendment submitted to the people at the polls for
                        acceptance or rejection.</p>

                    <p>3. That the democratic party of Pennsylvania is opposed to conferring upon
                        the negro the right to vote, and we do emphatically deny that there is any
                        right or power in Congress or elsewhere to impose negro suffrage upon the
                        people of this State in opposition to their will.</p>

                    <p>4. That reform in the administration of the federal and State governments, in
                        the management of their financial affairs is imperatively demanded.</p>

                    <p>5. That the movements now being made for the amelioration of the condition of
                        the laboring man have our most cordial co-operation.</p>

                    <p>6. That the legislation of the late Republican Congress outside of the
                        Constitution, the disregard of the majority therein of the will of the
                        people and sanctity of the ballot box, in the exclusion from their seats in
                        Congress of representatives clearly elected, the establishment of military
                        governments in States in the Union and the overthrow of all civil
                        governments therein, are acts of tyranny and usurpation that tend directly
                        to the destruction of all republican government and the creation of the
                        worst forms of despotism.</p>

                    <p>7. That our soldiers and sailors, who carried the flag of our country to
                        victory, must be gratefully remembered, and the guaranties given in their
                        favor must be faithfully carried into execution.</p>

                    <p>8. Equal rights and protection for naturalized and native-born citizens of
                        home and abroad; the assertion of American nationality which shall command
                        the respect of foreign powers and furnish an example of encouragement to
                        people struggling for national integrity, constitutional liberty and
                        individual rights.</p>

                    <p>9. That the present internal revenue and taxing system of the government is
                        grossly unjust, and means ought at once to be adopted to cause a
                        modification thereof.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article lists without comment the officially published Democratic
                    platform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.07.21.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
