
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.03.31">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/02/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-03-31">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.31.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.31.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>New Railroad Enterprise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The citizens of Mercersburg are again agitating the question of a railroad,
                        to connect their exquisitely dull old town with the live world. The present
                        project has for its object, as our informant tells us, the construction of a
                        railroad from Mercersburg to Marion, about six miles South of Chambersburg,
                        where it will form a junction with the Franklin road. It is thought that
                        there are some valuable iron ore lands in the vicinity of Mercersburg, and
                        large tracts have been leased by capitalists, who propose to develop them,
                        and make the ore available by constructing this road would be twelve or
                        fifteen miles long, running through a valuable portion of the county all the
                        way, and adding greatly to its material wealth and prosperity. The citizens
                        of Mercersburg, and those along the line of the projected road, are asked to
                        subscribe one hundred and fifty thousand dollars to ward its construction,
                        and are assured by the capitalists that if this be done, they will proceed
                        at once to build it. If the statements furnished us are correct, and we
                        believe they are, this is a splendid chance to rescue Mercersburg, which is
                        a dear old town, and has warm friends scattered all over the country, in
                        spite of the lawlessness to which it has of late been subjected, from the
                        threatening danger of oblivion. Mercersburg is moss-grown and venerable
                        looking now, but a railroad and iron furnaces would put new life into its
                        body, and activity and prosperity into its trade. We earnestly urge that
                        there be no lukewarmness or indifference in this matter, if there be a
                        possibility of accomplishing anything. There is little doubt that if the
                        road were once constructed, it would not be long before it formed a part in
                        an important line of railroads.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the citizens of Mercersburg are working to have a
                    railroad constructed through their town, thereby allowing nearby speculative
                    iron ore to be mined and the city to rebound in size and importance. The <emph
                        rend="italics">Repository</emph> is in favor of the project.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> last week made the following editorial
                        comments in relation to the horrible outrages which a black man committed on
                        the persons of three white women, an account of which was published in last
                        week's paper:</p>

                    <p>It is difficult, of course to ascertain the motive which prompted him to
                        commit these deeds of violence. But we can not believe that these outrages
                        were committed for the mere gratification of his lust. There must have been
                        something more than this. The arrested man is a resident of that sink of
                        iniquity called "Wolffstown." He is one of its shrewdest and most abandoned
                        inhabitants. The Free-loveism which prevails there is notorious. There was
                        no necessity for him to go out of its immediate precincts. This was not the
                        impelling motive.</p>

                    <p>This negro, as we have said, is one of the shrewdest and sharpest of his
                        race. He has been through the streets of Chambersburg and heard Radicalism
                        decant upon <emph rend="italics">the rights</emph> of the negro. He has
                        listened to the recital of the long list of imaginary grievances which the
                        poor negro has suffered at the hands of the whites. He has been told what a
                        base thing it is to deprive any of "God's creatures of their inalienable
                        rights on account of the color of his skin." All this blessed doctrine has
                        kindled an enmity in his heart against the whites and he has wreaked his
                        vengeance upon unprotected white women.</p>

                    <p>To such outrages as these are the progressive ideas of the Radicals leading
                        us. So roll on the ball. Let this degraded, ignorant, bestial race to an
                        equality with the whites, and - "let us have peace."</p>

                    <p>The spirit that inspired these remarks so often finds expression in the
                        columns of that journal, that it rarely excites a comment, and seldom is
                        worthy an expression. But the intense horror and indignation always aroused
                        in the minds of the people on the perpetration of a fiendish act, is in this
                        instance seized and used as an instrument to excite and arouse the
                        prejudices and passions of the ignorant and narrow minded, not against the
                        criminal himself, which would be natural, but against the Republican party.
                        It is on this account that we condescend to notice it. Of course the person
                        who penned these infamous lies does not undertake seriously to reason that
                        this horrible crime is the result of an act of right and justice towards the
                        colored race, but it is not to the reasoning part of the community that this
                        miserable sophistry is addressed.</p>

                    <p>Let us see how much sense there is in it? The first distinct statement is
                        that the outrages were not committed for the mere gratification of lust. On
                        the face of them there appears to be no other reason apparent, and it
                        becomes necessary for the writer to find one; which he proceeds to do, with
                        what ingenuity and skill, as well as with what honesty of purpose, we leave
                        our readers to judge. This negro he says, is one of the sharpest and
                        shrewdest of his race. He has been told what a base thing it is to deprive
                        any of "God's creatures of their inalienable rights on account of color of
                        his skin." This kindled enmity in his heart against the whites and caused
                        him to wreak his vengeance upon unprotected women. Then comes the conclusion
                        of this most sapient <emph rend="italics">spirit</emph>ual philosopher. "To
                        such outrages as these do the progressive ideas of the Radicals lead us." It
                        might be objected to this extraordinary conclusion that common sense, as
                        well as the experience of all mankind, proves that the performance of an act
                        of justice and right never leads to the perpetration of crime, but to its
                        prevention. It is such an universal principle that our laws are founded upon
                        it, and society exists by virtue of it. But common sense was nor invoked
                        when this lying-article was penned, else, instead of finding its way into
                        the columns of the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>, it would still be
                        only a figment of the false but fertile brain of its editor.</p>

                    <p>Says the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>, this black demon was one of the
                        shrewdest of his race. It also says that he committed these crimes to wreak
                        his vengeance upon the white race; having been told that all men were
                        entitled to equal rights. How does the history of these outrages fit in with
                        the declaration of the shrewdness and sharpness of the perpetrator? An
                        elaborate statement was published in the columns of this same journal, last
                        week, so full that not even the names of the unfortunate victims were
                        suppressed. From it we learn that the negro went in broad day into a thickly
                        settled neighborhood, only a mile or two from Chambersburg, and entered a
                        house where he violated a little girl. Thence he started, going without
                        attempt at concealment and seen by various persons, until he meets another
                        girl, or young woman, near to a dwelling house, and by force and threats
                        again effects his fiendish purpose. Still by frequented ways, and in
                        daylight, he does on; until he meets a third victim, and within a short
                        distance of a dwelling house, and with persons working in the fields around,
                        he assails and overcomes and ruins her. Then at the approach of night he
                        returns to town, goes to one store at least, and to his home, where the
                        officers arrest him.</p>

                    <p>There never were more horrible crimes more stupidly, more bunglingly
                        executed. The perpetrator was clearly a beast possessed only with the demon
                        of lust. Regardless of humanity, and ignorant or indifferent is the
                        punishment that must follow, he did not even attempt concealment of his
                        crimes. It is absolutely impossible to gather from the whole sickening story
                        a single motive save only the gratification of his infernal lust. Where then
                        is the sharpness and shrewdness which the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>
                        deemed necessary in order to give it political significance? We are in favor
                        of equal rights because God made it impossible for us to be otherwise, but
                        if there are any who can be deceived by such miserable sophistry as that of
                        the Spirit, it would be enough to stagger our conviction as to the
                        universality of even this principle.</p>

                    <p>We admonish our neighbors to modify their theory. Enmity and a desire to
                        wreak vengeance upon one human being, or upon a community or a race, is not
                        inconsistent with extreme ignorance and stupidity, any more than a desire to
                        subvert the passions and prejudices of the ignorant to corrupt political
                        purposes is inconsistent with the intelligence, the shrewdness and sharpness
                        of the editors of the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> recently issued an editorial
                    blaming the recent rape of three white men by a black man on Radical
                    Republicanism's insistence on equal rights. The <emph rend="italics"
                    >Repository</emph> here rebuts this editorial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper advocates repeal of the Tenure of Office Act, that it holds is
                    getting in the way of the business of Congress. The editors hold that its
                    original purpose was to prevent abuse of power by a bad president. Now that a
                    good president has been elected, it is no longer needed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Legislature, on Thursday last, completed the ratification of the
                        Fifteenth Amendment to the Constitution by passing it in the House. A week
                        was spent, we can scarcely say usefully, in making stump speeches, after
                        which every Democrat voted against it and every Republican for it. Inasmuch
                        as the vote resulted just as it would have done if it had been taken at
                        once, we fail to see what good was accomplished by these interminable
                        speeches, unless to show that the Democracy, even in the best of schools are
                        incapable of learning. Even such a forcible teacher as the late war has
                        failed to teach them that the colored race is wrongfully excluded from the
                        right of citizenship. Whether this amendment becomes a part of the
                        constitution at this time or not, it is sure to come soon; and when it does
                        bring citizenship to the colored race, and the Democratic party seeks to
                        lure its votes, as it will do, to the support of the Democratic ticket, let
                        it remember that in Pennsylvania not a single vote of that party was
                        recorded in favor of its freedom. Perhaps the strongest conviction in the
                        minds of the colored race is that Lincoln was the apostle of their freedom.
                        It should be as clearly seen and as strongly felt that the Democracy have
                        ever been pledged to retaining them in a state servitude and ignorance and
                        degradation, and that whatever has been done towards establishing their
                        rights, has been done by the Republican party. Whenever the colored man is
                        allowed to vote this will, of course, be denied by the Democracy, who will
                        crook the hinges of the knee to a black ballot as readily as to a white one.
                        Then let the negroes remember who were their sworn enemies.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces the passage of the Fifteenth Amendment in the State
                    House of Representatives in a strictly party-line vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Clerk of the Courts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Amicus" writes to suggest Mr. Mahon as a candidate for clerk of the
                    courts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.31.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Franklin County Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Nasby's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Nasby delivered his lecture "Cursed be Canaan" in Repository Hall.
                    Attendane was low, much to the chagrin of the organizers. The reasons posited
                    included the high price of admission, and false rumors that the lecture was
                    "coarse" in nature. The editors praise the humorous and instructive
                    presentation. The lecture gave "an array of facts and logic in favor of the
                    equal rights of the colored race as we have never before seen brought together.
                    The prejudices in which we all intrench ourselves were fairly attacked and
                    fairly battered down, and when sarcasm and humor were employed they were
                    legitimately used to show how unfounded and ridiculous these prejudices are."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting in Mercersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The citizens of Mercersburg met to advocate construction of a railroad to
                    their town. A representative of the Caledonia Land, Iron, and Railroad Company
                    told the crowd that they would commit to construction if the people of
                    Mercersburg raise $150,000. $75,000 in stock was immediately raised. The
                    boosters plan to seek aid from Greencastle as well. The paper urges Franklin's
                    citizens to back the project.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Outrageous</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the interior of the Fayetteville Union Church was
                    vandalized on Saturday night. The paper calls it "a crime of the most malignant
                    type."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sabbath School Anniversary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensberger</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Sabbath School of the Falling Spring Presbyterian Church held an
                    anniversary celebration that featured reports and addresses. The school is
                    flourishing and enrollment growing. The school mourned the loss two members who
                    passed away in the past year, Secretary James H. Reed and "little" George Nixon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensberger</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. E. B. Raffensberger, the new financial agent of the Wilson Female
                    Seminary, has arrived in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Graduated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Christ. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merklem</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christ. E. Eyster, Charles H. Merklem, and John J. Reynolds, all of
                    Chambersburg, graduated from the Phildelphia College of Pharmacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Lantz has recently taken control of the Washington House,
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Titus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Titus Adams, a resident of Wolfstown who the paper remembers for his
                    "fondness for his neighbor's chickens," died last week. Adams had been a soldier
                    and was burried with the honors of war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Talmage's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rev. T. DeWitt Talmage will lecture in Repository Hall on "The Bright Side
                    of Things" on April 6th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valentine</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. M. Valentine, President of Gettysburg College, will preach in the
                    Lutheran Church next Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. David Townsend will preach an introductory sermon at the Church of
                    God on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Albert Hoover and Isabella Brown, both of Funkstown, were married on March
                    22nd by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kahn</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>Rev. Dr.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin F. Kahn of Chambersburg and Lizzie M. Moore of Fannettsburg were
                    married on March 23rd by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coldsmith</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Coldsmith and Miss Lydia V. Shively, both of Scotland, were
                    married at the United Brethren Parsonage on March 28th by the Rev. J. G. Shaff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lutz</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John G. Lutz and Miss Ellen Miller were married in Chambersburg on March
                    25th by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dysert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Dysert and Miss Mary Brown, both of Franklin, were married on February
                    16th by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.31.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
