
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.02.24">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-02-24">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.02.24.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.02.24.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Self Preservation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Last week's REPOSITORY contained a communication detailing the action of the
                        Democratic Board of School Directors of St. Thomas township towards a little
                        colored girl, who was attending one of the free schools. Strange as it may
                        seem, the writer actually thought, and didn't hesitate to say, that their
                        action in the premises was unjust, arbitrary and without warrant of law.
                        Evidently honest in his convictions, we cannot help expressing unmeasured
                        surprise at his mistake. The gentleman is without doubt the victim of
                        uncontrollable prejudice in favor of the "nigger," else how could he write
                        as he did?</p>

                    <p>This little girl, a negro girl, the offspring of a "degraded race," perhaps
                        nearly white, but still belonging to "Canaan's accursed race," had the
                        audacity, the boldness, the insolence to stand at the head of all her
                        classes, to trap down all her white school mates, and kept them down. What
                        right had she to be smarter than white children, she with her tawny skin and
                        adultered blood? Did she have no respect for the superiority of the proud
                        Anglo-Saxon race, that she must spell better, and read better, than her
                        white class-mates? Had she lost all sense of inferiority? Did she no longer
                        feel instinctively low in the presence of her betters? It seems not. She
                        actually dared to have brains, and use them, to compete with white children
                        in the struggle for learning, and to surpass them. Think of it, O ye
                        Democratic fathers, that in your very strong hold, in St. Thomas township,
                        with a full Democratic board of Directors, such a thing could be ? that
                        here, of all places, your favorite theory of negro inferiority should be
                        challenged. Why, in the name of their degraded inferiority, you had enslaved
                        them, and bought them, and starved them, and were you going to allow a
                        little "nigger" to prove that it had all been false? Never, if it took a
                        whole Democratic School board to keep her down. Your own children might be
                        stupid intellectual blanks, through whose impenetrable skulls an idea never
                        could reach unless they were trepanned, but it should not be said that a
                        "nigger" was smarter than they.</p>

                    <p>Hence; we say that the Democratic School Board of St. Thomas township was
                        right, when, in solemn council, it resolved that Joe Winter's little girl
                        should be kept at the foot of her classes. It was not only right, it was
                        heroic. Like brave men they threw themselves into the breach and fought back
                        the assaults of the negro upon the Democratic citadel. Oh it was a
                        chivalrous deed, and deserves to be cherished in grateful recollection by
                        the Democratic party. Six men, clothed with the authority of School
                        Directors, waged an unequal warfare with a little colored girl and came off
                        victorious. Six men rose in their official might and rescued their children
                        from the shame and infamy that the "despised race" was inflicting upon them;
                        and bravely did they do their work. It reminds us of the old story - </p>

                    <p>"Father and Mother and me and twelve good soldiers more,</p>

                    <p>Beat an old woman stone blind who had never seen before."</p>

                    <p>Doubtless those brave fathers went back to their homes and looked fondly,
                        proudly, on their children. Hadn't they crushed the ambitions to excel out
                        of the little colored girl? Hadn't they taught her that she belonged to the
                        "despised race?" that the sublime declaration "that all men are born equal"
                        only meant white men? They certainly had, and they deserve, and doubtless
                        will receive, and hearty approval of the liberal minded Democracy.</p>

                    <p>Now, how does this conduct address itself to those who believe that "of one
                        blood created, He all the nations of the earth?" We have no doubt that the
                        thing in itself is a matter of trifling moment, and so far as it affected
                        the little girl, might be permitted to pass without comment. But as an
                        evidence of the spirit of narrow minded bigotry, ignorance and prejudice,
                        which inspired the men who have charge of the educational interests of St.
                        Thomas township, it deserves to be held up to the scorn and contempt of all
                        liberal minded human beings, be they white or black. These fellows should
                        know that this community despises them for what they have done. If there
                        ever was a time, among us, when such unjust discrimination could be made
                        against colored children, and we do not believe there ever was, it cannot be
                        done now. Democrats as well as Republicans, we hope, desire to be fair and
                        just to the colored race, and mean to give it encouragement and help,
                        instead of injustice and insult.</p>

                    <p>But these School Directors do not represent their township. They have brought
                        shame and odium upon it, which should only attach to themselves. It would be
                        but just to themselves if the citizens openly disavowed their action, and
                        declared themselves in favor of the golden rule, even in the case of a
                        person so insignificant as this little colored girl.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial vehemently attacks the actions of the School Directors of
                    St. Thomas, who took action against a black girl who excelled above her white
                    classmates in a free school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Exit Moses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>President Johnson has still one week of his Presidential term to live, after
                        which he will retire to private life, the poetical refuge of all great men
                        weighed down by the cares and responsibilities of office. This longing of
                        public men for the quiet and contentment of private life is one of the
                        fictions which has been indulged in so long that many have come to believe
                        it. But there is rarely anything in it. Few persons step down from positions
                        of high and commanding influence with half the alacrity that they exercised
                        in reaching them, and Johnson would love nothing in this world so much as a
                        new lease of the power which he has so outrageously abused. In four short
                        years he has swung around the entire circle of his political friends and
                        enemies. Those who elevated him to the Vice Presidency, believing him to be
                        an incorruptible patriot, his treason, his ingratitude and his debaucheries
                        have converted into his most resolute political enemies; while those whose
                        hostility to the Government and sympathy with traitors made them resist his
                        election, are now his most cherished friends. Traitors, murderers,
                        counterfeiters, forgers and thieves will regret that his term of office has
                        reached its constitutional limit. They have reason for so doing. He always
                        interposed his ill used power between them and justice, and such as he could
                        not wholly screen from the officers of the law he pardoned. The last few
                        months of his term has been wholly devoted to his friends, who have rejoiced
                        in a general jail delivery. It might be inferred from this that he possessed
                        the virtue of forgiveness, but he does not. He is cruel and vindictive in a
                        surprising degree, and hates both Houses of Congress, who have interfered
                        with his nefarious plans, with a perfect hatred. Well, let him go. The
                        country has lived through the dangers he would have brought upon it. He is
                        powerless to harm it now. A wiser and a better takes his place, and he will
                        sink into forgetfulness and oblivion, a fitting punishment to one whose
                        fiercest ambition is power and notoriety. Exit Moses.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>One week before President Johnson leaves office, the editor unleashes one
                    more attack against him and his time in office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper dismisses the "lively" talk and excitment over the Democrat's
                    nomination of a candidate for governor. The editors suggest that the party is
                    irrelevant at the state level. Even if Franklin County Democrats can succeed in
                    nominating their favorite, Judge Packer, he would only go down to defeat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper opposes the suggestion of "An Old Citizen" that the position of
                    postmaster of Chambersburg be elected rather than appointed. The editors suggest
                    that the number of persons seeking the office is too large to make for an
                    effective election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.02.24.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meeting of Damage Claimants</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabby</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hade</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>Pharez</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shartle</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickey</ln>
                        <fn>Seth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mish</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Clark</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rife</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The people of Chambersburg celebrated the 22nd with a parade by the
                    Friendship Fire Company and the Silver Cornet Band. The Housum Zouaves, under
                    the direction of Capt. Skinner, Lt. Miles, and Lt. Aughinbaugh gave a military
                    demosntration on the Diamond. The Citizen's Band also played.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>T. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. A. Creigh, son of Rev. Dr. Creigh of Mercersburg, returned to
                    Chambersburg after a three-year stay in the Montana Territory. "He speaks
                    encouragingly of the increasing wealth and prosperity of the territory, and
                    contemplates returning tither in a few months."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper encourages readers to buy tickets for John B. Gough's lecture,
                    which are selling quickly. The proceeds will benefit the Ladies' Mite Society of
                    Chambersburg's Central Presbyterian Church. The tickets can be purchased at
                    Curriden's store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Episcopal Services</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. Robert J. Keeling, rector of St. Stevens Church, Lancaster, will
                    preach in the Episcopal Church on February 28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Township Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans of Guilford will meet in Lesher's School House on March 6th
                    to nominate candidates for town office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rook</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyler</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Rook and Miss Susan Emma Oyler, both of Funkstown, were married at
                    the parsonage on February 18th by the Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Strock of Illinois and Mrs. Susan Coble of Chambersburg were married
                    on February 23rd at the residence of the bride by Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac R. Crouse and Miss Lizzie Boggs, daughter of James Boggs, all from
                    near Spring Run, were married on January 11th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Wingert and Maggie A. Etter, both of Franklin, were married on
                    February 18th by the Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plummer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mary Plummer died in Chambersburg on February 22nd after suffering a
                    lingering illness. She was 54 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewes</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Lewes died in Amberson's Valley on February 9th. She was 68 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Franklin Etter, son of A. H. and Mary C. Etter, died near Scotland
                    on February 18th. He was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carper</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie Myrtle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minnie Myrtle Carper died on February 14th. She was 3 months old. A poem of
                    mourning accompanies the notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.02.24.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
