
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.02.10">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/31/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-02-10">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.02.10.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.02.10.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meeting of Damage Claimants</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The announcement, two weeks ago, of a meeting of the citizens of Franklin
                        county, to be held on Thursday the 19th day of February, to consult on the
                        question of Border Damages, should have been Thursday, the 18th.</p>

                    <p>We hope that the meeting will be largely attended, and a full and free
                        interchange of the views of those who are interested will be had. If we ever
                        hope to receive compensation for our losses, in the war, we must not forget
                        that every day we remain inactive makes our chances more doubtful. It would
                        have been easier to secure a proper recognition of our right to compensation
                        from the Legislature, immediately after the close of the war, other things
                        being equal, than to-day. It is easier now than it will be a year hence, and
                        five years hence it would be well nigh impossible to secure anything. But
                        individual effort is of no avail in this matter. There must be a
                        concentration, of all the forces that exist, upon one point, and a harmony
                        of action to secure it. If it be deemed advisable to ask the Legislature, at
                        its present Session, to make compensation for our losses, let it be done
                        with a hearty concurrence of all our citizens, both in town and country. Our
                        only hope is with the State. The sooner we understand that we can expect
                        nothing from the General Government the sooner, and with the better reason
                        for success, will we seek to effect our purpose with the Legislature.</p>

                    <p>If the State make an appropriation, there can be but little doubt that the
                        amount thus given will be refunded by the General Government; but not so if
                        a community of individuals go to Congress to ask for aid.</p>

                    <p>The reason is obvious. The latter have no representation there, and can bring
                        but little influence to bear on the question. But if the Commonwealth once
                        assumes this obligation, the whole State is interested in recovering it from
                        Congress. Every member of Congress in the State, together with our Senators,
                        and the whole population, will work together to secure compensation. This,
                        it seems to us, is the strong and vital point of our case. The State will
                        loose nothing by being just, and making compensation, for the General
                        Government will assuredly refund the amount paid.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article announces a meeting regarding reparations for damages incurred
                    along the borders of the state during the War. The paper strongly endorses such
                    repayments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper chastises Congress for not providing financial assistance to Mary
                    Todd Lincoln. "The petition is plainly based on the fact that she is his widow,
                    that she is in want, that his services to the people of the United States can
                    never be repaid, and that a decent regard for him who gave his noble life to his
                    country will show itself in making ample provision for his widow, who has been
                    deprived of his maintenance and support by the blow of an assassin."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Packer</ln>
                        <fn>Asa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints statements of opposition in the Democratic press to the
                    nomination of Asa Packer as Democratic candidate for governor. M'Lellan, Sharpe,
                    and Brewer from Franklin County have been advocating it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.02.10.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society held its regular meeting at the
                    store of the Ryder Association. The group discussed the "squash bug" and
                    remedies for infestation. They also discussed making incisions in fruit trees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fashionable Religion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Fanny Fern" observes that many Catholics visit church on weekdays, and
                    encourages Protestants to make more of an effort to do the same. She advocates
                    opening church buildings for free prayer during the week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Raid</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Keehan</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of Chambersburg's M. E. Church paid a visit to their pastor,
                    the Rev. S. Barnes, and presented him with food and gifts for the parsonage.
                    Barnes and several other ministers addressed the congregation, and all spent the
                    afternoon socializing and hearing musical performances.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Third Week of Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The following cases were disposed of during the third week of Court, his
                        Honor Judge Rowe presiding:</p>

                    <p>Nicholas Bonebrake, Guardian of Lewis Hollinger, minor son of John Hollinger,
                        dec'd, vs. John S Oller, adm'r of John Hollinger, dec'd. Feigned issue. Jury
                        find for plff. Sharpe, Jo and J. W. Douglas for plff.; Kimmell, Adams and
                        Bonebrake for def't.</p>

                    <p>John A. Grove vs. The Bank of Chambersburg, owner, and John R. Turner,
                        contractor. Jury find for plff. $385. Kennedy and Sharpe for plff; M'Lellun
                        &amp; Kimmell and Stewart for deft.</p>

                    <p>P. A. Ahl &amp; Bro. vs. Jeremiah Monn. - Summons in assumpsit. Jury find
                        for the plff. $250, Stenger and Stewart for plffs.; Sharpe and Kimmell for
                        deft.</p>

                    <p>John M. Barr and Christiana M. Barr, his wife, in right of said Christiana,
                        vs. David Greenawalt. Summons in debt. Jury find for deft. Kimmell for plff;
                        M'Gowan for deft.</p>

                    <p>John Daley vs. James Shanabrook, Executor of Abraham Eshelman, dec'd, Jacob
                        F. Shaffer and Samuel G. Hollinger. Summons in debt. Jury find for deft.
                        Eshelman, Executor, and against Jacob F. Shaffer for $48, with interest from
                        28th February, 1866. Cook for plff.; Adams for deft.</p>

                    <p>Emma C. Embick, by her next friend, John Embick, vs. Henry Myers. Capias in
                        case. Jury find for plff. $131. Sharpe and Kimmell for plff.; Cook and
                        M'Gowan for deft.</p>

                    <p>The Court adjourned on Saturday evening.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollinger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oller</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ahl</ln>
                        <fn>P. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>Christiana M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Daley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shanabrook</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eshelman</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embick</ln>
                        <fn>Emma C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embick</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The weekly court proceedings summary includes the verdicts and names
                    involved in each case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chicken Thieves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cain</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Jim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sam Norris, Frank Cain, and Jim Jackson, all inhabitants of Wolfstown, were
                    arrested for stealing chickens and placed in Fort Fletcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Literary Entertainment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Corwin V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Corwin V. Wilson will recite a number of literary works on Thursday
                    at the M. E. Church. Selections will include "The Bells," by Edgar A. Poe;
                    "Sheridan's Ride," by T. Buchanan Reed; "Man and His Masters," by John B. Gough;
                    and "Crabbed People," by T. DeWitt Talmage. Admission is 25 cents, and proceeds
                    will go toward re-modeling the church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dalrymple</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew Dalrymple, the postmaster who absconded from Brown's Mill, was
                    arrested in Chicago.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that tickets for John B. Gough's lecture on March 18th
                    are selling rapidly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A shanty on Second Street occupied by an African American family caught
                    fire. Town firemen quickly put out the blaze.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The American Life Insurance Company of Philadelphia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper praises the company and the benefits of life insurance. Citizens
                    are directed to William G. Reed, local agent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                        <fn>William N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William N. Witherspoon of Franklin County and Miss Rebecca M. Culbertson of
                    Adams County were married on January 26th by the Rev. Patterson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reifsnider</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Baker and Louisa Reifsnider, both of Franklin County, were married at
                    the Montgomery House on February 9th by the Rev. James M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piles</ln>
                        <fn>Philip James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip James Piles and Miss Sarah Jane Burk, both of Dry Run, were married
                    on February 3rd by Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Bradley of Chambersburg died in Harrisburg on February 5th. He was
                    51 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clintock</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M'Clintock, who had been a resident of Chambersburg for 70 years, died
                    in Bedford on January 22nd. He was 87 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zuck</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zuck</ln>
                        <fn>Abram B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary J. Zuck, wife of Abram B. Zuck, died in Chambersburg on January
                    28th. She was 45 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Clara Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>L. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Prudence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Clara Emma Wingert, daughter of L. W. and Prudence Wingert, died in
                    Chambersburg on January 17th. She was 6 months old. A poem of mourning
                    accompanies the notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.02.10.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
