
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.11.24">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/19/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-11-24">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.11.24.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.11.24.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Legislature and the Press</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>It was once a fact that Legislative bodies sought to learn the wishes of
                        their constituents, and to act in accordance with them. Such a theory exists
                        yet, but practically it is only a pleasing fiction. Legislatures have long
                        since both abolished and demolished the old-time notion that their members
                        assemble to consult and act for the public good. In fact, nearly <orig
                            reg="everything">every thing</orig> legitimately pertaining to these
                        bodies have been abolished, except the Legislatures themselves; and they
                        stick with a pertinacity which affords little warrant to believe that,
                        though well nigh <orig reg="everything">every thing</orig> which called them
                        into existence has sloughed off in the forgotten past, their days of
                        dissipation and dishonesty are numbered.</p>

                    <p>The sentiment of the people upon any question of public interest is best
                        ascertained from the expression it finds through the public press. Indeed it
                        is the only way, except in the choice of public servants at the ballot-box.
                        Last year the Republican press of the State demanded, almost with unanimity,
                        that the profligate legislation and extravagant expenditures which disgraced
                        the few preceding years, should then cease. The odium brought upon the
                        party, the arms put into the hands of the Democracy, the disgust aroused
                        among honest Republicans, the utter impossibility of retaining the supremacy
                        of the party in the State, were all urged as reasons for this demand, if the
                        common honesty of the Legislature itself was not sufficient to warrant it.
                        Regarded merely as a question of policy, as a necessary precaution, if there
                        were no higher motive, the experience of the last political campaign proved
                        that their timely admonitions should have been heeded. If there was not more
                        iniquitous legislation than the year before, there was as much. If there
                        were not more supernumeraries sucking the blood of the people than before,
                        there were as many. If there were no new fat jobs created to conciliate
                        Bergner and rob the people, the old ones were reduced neither in number nor
                        in size. Hence, when the campaign began, the great and only danger which
                        imperilled the success of the party was the indefensible record of the
                        Republican Legislature. Many Republican voters were indifferent or
                        positively opposed to the <orig reg="reelection">re-election</orig> of
                        representatives of their own party, and in some instances, where old members
                        had secured their own renomination, they actually compelled their withdrawal
                        from the ticket. They should be universally commended for it. The Democratic
                        journals were not slow to take advantage of the wrongs done by the
                        Legislature and press them upon the attention of the voters of the State.
                        Though their own members had been conspicuously active in many of them, they
                        were in the minority in both branches, and the people did not hold them
                        responsible. It was no <orig reg="defense">defence</orig> of Republican
                        members that they, too, had been guilty. They alone were powerless to do
                        either good or harm, however willing they may have been.</p>

                    <p>Though the Republican party was again successful an examination of the vote
                        throughout the State clearly shows that its success was due to the positive
                        weakness of the Democratic State ticket, and the unwillingness of the loyal
                        masses to put the power of the State in the hands of a party which had
                        proved itself disloyal during the late war. These things saved us the State,
                        and only saved it, in spite of the damage done by the last Legislature. It
                        would not be safe to try again.</p>

                    <p>Again the Republican press demands that the Legislature shall start right:
                        first, in its organization, by turning adrift the corrupt men who have made
                        it a reproach, and by selecting a speaker, and clerks, and heads of
                        committees who will not need the doubtful commendation of journals which are
                        forever tongue-tied when a voice of warning or of condemnation is needed,
                        and always blatant to qualify and smooth over when an outrage is done:
                        second, by lopping off all the running sores and excrescences which drained
                        the Treasury of so many thousands last winter. The subject was pretty well
                        ventilated before, and the people are not ignorant as to what expenses are
                        necessary and what superfluous, and diverted from their proper channels, to
                        feed an army of retainers, whose use the members best know. Let it be
                        understood that there shall be nothing concealed or withheld, and that the
                        responsibility for every wrong act shall be saddled on the proper party. Let
                        those who stand up in their places and denounce journals which they cannot
                        muzzle, but whose influence they are always ready to seek when candidates
                        for <orig reg="reelection">re-election</orig>, know that their evil deeds
                        shall be heralded from one end of the State to the other; then, if they make
                        the Legislature a burden too heavy for the party to bear, let the party
                        repudiate them, as some of them were repudiated at the last election.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors blast the Republican legislature for not heeding the warnings
                    of the press to reign in corruption and waste. The paper believes that the party
                    only escaped electoral disaster because the Democrats were too weak to take
                    advantage of the recent poor performance of the Republican legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Too Low</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that teacher's salaries are too low. An article in a
                    Philadelphia paper gave a rundown on the folowing professions: cook, receives $3
                    to $4 per week, and is found equal to $6 to $7; coachman, receives $5 to $6 per
                    week, and is found equal to $10 to $11; laborer, receives $10 to $12 per week;
                    policeman receives $17.50 per week; school teacher of the lowest grade receives
                    $6.92 per week. The paper asserts that the situation is similar in Franklin, and
                    that there is no hope of raising the quality of education in the area until
                    teacher salaries are raised higher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Fifteenth Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The House of Representatives of Tennessee, on the 16th inst., rejected the
                        Fifteenth amendment, as it was expected that it would do. Indeed there has
                        been no doubt in the minds of the friends of the Amendment that Tennessee
                        would go against it since the election of Governor Senter. About the same
                        time intelligence comes from Alabama that her Legislature has ratified it by
                        a very decisive majority. The Amendment, therefore, is no worse off than
                        before, but if any thing better. Tennessee was sure to reject it, and
                        Alabama was not so sure to adopt it. The result is favorable. Now let the
                        remaining Republican States ratify it without delay, and finish the work.
                        There is no longer any human probability that it will fail to become part of
                        the supreme law of the United States, and the sooner this result is reached
                        the better.</p>

                    <p>The action of Tennessee in this matter, as well as her election, is another
                        proof how unfortunate for the Border States it was that they were not
                        allowed to carry out their disloyal inclinations and go off into the
                        Confederacy. The rebels in these States were restrained in nothing during
                        the war, unless, perhaps, in the wagging of their treasonable tongues; they
                        were not punished, nor was their property sacrificed, like that of the
                        States which seceded. They have not suffered. Hence they are as arrogant and
                        as disloyal to the Government which saved them from perdition as ever they
                        were. Tennessee, Kentucky and Maryland have no love for the Union, while
                        Alabama, on the other hand, cordially adopts the Fifteenth Amendment.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Tennessee rejected the 15th Amendment while Alabama
                    ratified it. The editors believe that, paradoxically, strong Union rule in
                    Tennessee during the war made post-war resistance of the government more likely.
                    Alabama, they claim, felt the effects of war and the errors of her ways while
                    Tennessee did not.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.11.24.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>New Roads</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The following petitions for road views were made at the last term of Court:</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italic">Montgomery Township</emph>.--A road from Mercersburg and
                        Clearspring road, near Camp Hill, to the Williamsport road near Locust Level
                        School House, was confirmed <emph rend="italic">nisi</emph>, and ordered to
                        be opened 24 feet wide. $150 damages were awarded to Isaac Gehr; $150 to
                        John S. Brewer; $20 to J. Wolfe.</p>

                    <p>A road beginning at a public road leading through said township, known as the
                        Davis Gap road, at or near the line between the farms of Glee and James
                        Rankin, thence by the nearest and best route until it intersects a public
                        road leading from Mercersburg to Clear Spring, Md., known as Blair's Valley
                        road, on lands of Peter &amp; Lawson Keller in said township. Court
                        appointed S. M. Armstrong, William Boyd, and John K. Keyser, viewers.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italic">Guilford Township</emph>.--View. A road to lead from a
                        point at or near where the Upton road intersects the road leading from the
                        Greencastle road, opposite Samuel Leedy's house, to Cashtown, to the first
                        hollow east of Whitmyer's corner, on the public road leading from
                        Frederick's Mill to Marion. Court appointed Samuel M. Armstrong, A. D.
                        Cauffman and B. F. Nead, viewers.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italic">Antrim Township</emph>--A road to lead from a point on a
                        public road known as the long lane, intersecting the Greencastle &amp;
                        Waynesboro turnpike, to the public road leading from Shady Grove to
                        Fayetteville, at or near the land of Samuel Fisher. Court appointed Saml. B.
                        Snively, James Brown and Abraham Hassler, viewers.</p>

                    <p>A road to lead from Middleburg &amp; Greencastle road at Samuel Parell's
                        House, to the Shady Grove road at A. H. M. Dehaven's Court appointed S. M.
                        Armstrong, Geo. W. Zeigler, Addison Imbrie, viewers.</p>

                    <p>A road to lead from a point, corner of the land of Thomas Pauling, Lazarus
                        Wingert, and Annie B. Wilson, on the south side of the lands of said
                        parties, through the California School House lot, to the public road running
                        by said lot. Court appointed Samuel B. Snively, John Rowe and B. F. Winger,
                        viewers.</p>

                    <p>View, supply and vacate. To vacate that part of the road commencing at the
                        Turnpike leading from Waynesboro, Greencastle and Mercersburg, on the lands
                        of John Rowe, and ending at the western end of the barn of the said John
                        Rowe, the same being 100 yds. in length, and to supply as follows:
                        commencing at the western end of the barn of the said John Rowe, and running
                        thence in a direct course to the said turnpike, at a point about one hundred
                        and twenty feet west of the northern end of the present road. Court
                        appointed Samuel B. Snively, B. F. Winger and J. B. Burk, viewers.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italic">Lurgan Township</emph>.--A road beginning at a point on
                        the Roxbury and McClay mill road near the farm of Joseph Foltz, thence by
                        the nearest and best route until it intersects the road leading from Roxbury
                        to Newburg (known as the State road) at a point near the brick church in
                        said township. Court appointed John Cauffman, John Kyner and David Spencer,
                        viewers.</p>

                    <p>To vacate and supply. To vacate as follows: beginning at the foot of a steep
                        hill near the house of David Ocker, and ending on the McClay mill road, one
                        mile in length, and supplied as follows between foot of said hill near
                        Ocker's and some convenient and suitable point on the McClay mill and
                        Roxbury road. Court appointed John B. Cauffman, David Spencer and John
                        Kyner, viewers.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Lawson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leedy</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dehaven</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imbrie</ln>
                        <fn>Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pauling</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Lazarus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Annie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ocker</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on appointments of road viewers in Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the people of Chambersburg celebrated Thanksgiving
                    with many good chicken and turkey dinners. The ministers of the town held joint
                    religious services in the German Reformed Church. The Mechanicsburg Band and
                    Chambersburg's Silver Cornet Band both performed in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>We hope that at the Annual Meeting of the Franklin County Institute, next
                        month, its members will show where they stand on the Bible question. Roman
                        Catholics and Infidels are working earnestly to expel the Bible and its
                        influences from our Common Schools. All the various Protestant sects of this
                        country are in favor of its retention and use. The one party is aiming a
                        deadly blow at our Common School System and flourished best where ignorance
                        prevails; the other believes in the education of the masses, owes its
                        existence to intelligence, and has faith in the great good accomplished by
                        our Common Schools. Gentlemen and Ladies of the Institute, there is but one
                        course for you to pursue, and that is to stand by the Bible and its truths.
                        See that you do it.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls on the Franklin County Institute to take a stand on the
                    question of Bibles in the public schools, and save them from the efforts of
                    "Catholics and Infidels" to ban them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Chambers, "one of the oldest and best citizens of Franklin county,"
                    died on Friday at the age of 87. He was a veteran of the war of 1812 and fought
                    under Jackson at New Orleans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendall</ln>
                        <fn>Mason</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>L. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The pupils of Mr. Mason Kendall will give a concert in Greenvillage. The
                    Rev. L. W. Williams will speak on the "Science of Music."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Debating Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Fayetteville Debating Society was recently reorganized. J. R. White was
                    elected president and A. B. Shively, secretary. The society has been in
                    existence for awhile, and many of the town's young men participate in it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reminds readers that Charles Sumner will lecture in Repository
                    Hall on Thursday on "The Question of Caste."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Teachers' Institute will meet in the Court House on
                    December 6th. Prominent teachers from around the country will be present. There
                    will be discussion subjects that should interest both teachers and directors.
                    Hotels in town are offering special rates for attendence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Church Dedication</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>F. Dyson, pastor, announces that the Second M. E. Church of Chambersburg
                    will be dedicated on December 5th. Dr. John Dashiell of Dickinson College and
                    Rev. J. Curns of the Carlisle district will preside.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Promotion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earley</ln>
                        <fn>Barnet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. George Eyster, Assistant U.S. Treasurer at Philadelphia, announces
                    that Barnet Earley has been appointed Chief Clerk and Cashier in the U.S.
                    Treasurer's office at $2,700 per year. "Mr. Earley's friends in Chambersburg
                    will be glad to hear of his promotion. He is a thorough Republican and will fill
                    the position with acceptance to the Department."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Central Presbyterian Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The outside work on the Central Presbyterian Church will soon be completed.
                    The paper believes it will be a welcome addition to the Diamond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The town council is grading North Front street beyond the point. This
                    should boost property values.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Continentals sang in Repository Hall on Saturday. The attendance was
                    not very good, but the audience was appreciative.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. James F. Kennedy will preach in the Stone Church in Scotland on
                    Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>Cordie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. B. Kirby and Miss Cordie Forbes, both of Chambersburg, were married in
                    the M. E. Church on November 18th by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>Kate M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. S. Gilbert and Miss Kate M. Kirby, both of Chambersburg, were married in
                    the M. E. Church on November 18th by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heysinger</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>Laura A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heysinger</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Heysinger of Philadelphia and Miss Laura A. Downey, daughter of John
                    Downey of Fayetteville, were married on October 28th by the Rev. J. L. Heysinger
                    of the Protestant Episcopal Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swinney</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Susan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. R. Swinney of Alfred, NY, and Miss Susan M. Black, daughter of
                    Robert Black of Black's Gap, Franklin County, were married on November 17th by
                    the Rev. J. F. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Starlaper</ln>
                        <fn>David L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vance</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David L. Starlaper and Miss Mary A. Vance, both of Maryland, were married
                    in Mercersburg on November 6th by the Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irwin</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irwin</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Joseph W. Winger and Miss Maggie Irwin, daughter of Matthew Irwin,
                    both of Montgomery township, were married on November 16th by the Rev. Thomas
                    Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bechtol</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob L. Neff and Miss Sallie M. Bechtol, both from near Hagerstown, were
                    married in the Washington House on November 18th by the Rev. J. G. Schaff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kane</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carper</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William M'Kane and Miss Anna Carper, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    November 14th by the Rev. David Townsend of the Church of God.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilgrim</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witmer</ln>
                        <fn>Kate E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John R. Pilgrim and Miss Kate E. Witmer, both of Cumberland County, were
                    married at Keefer's Hotel on November 18th by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Ellie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>John </fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. D. Bard of Augusta, Georgia, and Miss Ellie C. Lambert, daughter of Dr.
                    John Lambert of Chambersburg, were married on November 23rd by the Rev. P. S.
                    Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Percy M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Percy M. Orr, son of the Rev. Thomas Orr, died in Philadelphia on November
                    15th of croup. He was 6 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Grove died in Guilford on November 10th after a long illness. He was
                    57 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>Elmira </fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elmira Foltz, wife of C. C. Foltz, died in Chambersburg on November 16th of
                    consumption. She was 28 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.11.24.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
