
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.06.02">

     <header>
          <title>Franklin Repository</title>

          <tagger>
               <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
               <tagDate>06/06/06</tagDate>
               <tagNote/>
          </tagger>

          <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

          <date n="1869-06-02">
               <year>1869</year>
               <month norm="06">June</month>
               <day>02</day>
               <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
          </date>
     </header>

     <paperBody>

          <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.06.02.01" exists="no">


               <pageNote/>
          </page>

          <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.06.02.02" exists="no">

               <div type="e">
                    <column>01</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>

                         <p>The Lancaster <emph rend="italics">Intelligencer</emph> doubts the truth
                              of the story told about Barbara <orig reg="Frietchie"
                              >Freitchie</orig>, who is said to have waved a Union flag in front of
                              her cottage door, in Frederick, Md., when the rebel General Jackson's
                              corps was marching past, and <del/></p>

                         <p>But allowing that the flag was flaunted defiantly in the very face of
                              Stonewall Jackson and his men, what a contrast did the conduct of the
                              rebel soldiers present to that of Federal Generals and officials. The
                              infamous order of Butler at New Orleans, and the repeated arrest and
                              imprisonment of ladies in Baltimore and elsewhere for refusing to walk
                              under our flag is a stain upon our character which cannot be wiped
                              out. According to the admission of the Radicals themselves the rebels
                              respected womanhood too much even to insult one who defiantly flaunted
                              the banner of their foes in their very faces. When and where did our
                              armies give such an exhibition of chivalrous courtesy. The less that
                              is said about this Barbara Frietchie story the better. If true it only
                              blazons forth our shame the more conspicuously. If our Radical
                              contemporaries in Lancaster and elsewhere would reflect for a moment
                              they would hesitate before publishing items calculated to provoke such
                              odious comparisons.</p>

                         <p>The story, whether true or not does not affect the character of the
                              comments of the <emph rend="italics">Intelligencer</emph>, runs that
                              Barbara Freitchie, a decrepit old woman, but full of loyalty to her
                              country, waved a small flag when the troops were passing, and that the
                              rebel soldiers leveled their muskets to shoot down the <orig
                                   reg="defenseless">defenceless</orig> old patriot, but were
                              sternly ordered by Jackson not to fire.</p>

                         <p>Unless one saw it done, as here, he would scarcely believe that this
                              could be made the occasion for glorifying rebels who were at that very
                              moment killing loyal citizens and destroying their property, and for
                              denouncing Union soldiers and officers who were heroically giving
                              their lives to protect the persons and property of just such rebel
                              sympathizers as the author of the lines quoted. Wonderful magnanimity,
                              indeed, on the part of rebels, that they did not kill a <orig
                                   reg="defenseless">defenceless</orig> old woman, though
                              peremptorily ordered not to fire. Truly this was a marvelous
                              exhibition of chivalrous courtesy, and wholly unparalleled in generous
                              magnanimity by anything in the ranks of the brave "Boys in Blue." And
                              then the outrage the loyal hearted old woman committed on the tender
                              feelings of the chivalrous rebels was so grievous, too. Why, she
                              actually waved the "Stars and Stripes" in the face of the enemies of
                              her country; the flag which she loved and adored, and which they have
                              betrayed and trailed in the dust. Well may the <emph rend="italics"
                                   >Intelligencer</emph> ask "when and where did our armies give
                              such an exhibition of chivalrous courtesy?"</p>

                         <p>But why say <emph rend="italics">our</emph> armies? What interest does
                              he of the <emph rend="italics">Intelligencer</emph> have in our
                              armies? What right has he, on his own showing, to say <emph
                                   rend="italics">our</emph> armies? His sympathies were with those
                              who destroyed the flower of our armies, in their unholy attempt to
                              overthrow the Government. He rejoiced at rebel successes, and felt sad
                              at Union victories.</p>

                         <p>Is it true that Union soldiers were so utterly devoid of the common
                              courtesies of life that no parallel can be found to this case of but
                              ordinary decency on the part of rebels? Why there was not a town in
                              rebeldom, visited or held, by our soldiers, where rebel flags were not
                              flaunted in their faces by furious and enraged female rebels. Was any
                              one ever killed for it? Certainly not. On the contrary guards were
                              placed over their property to protect it. And it was protected. When
                              rebel armies invaded the North was private property protected? Let the
                              Cumberland Valley and Chambersburg answer! We want to see Union
                              soldiers, every one of whose experience proves the assertion of the
                                   <emph rend="italics">Intelligencer</emph> to be lies, to read
                              them. If their faces don't mantle with indignation at the insults
                              heaped upon them by this sympathizer we are much mistaken. We would
                              not open the chapter of rebel horrors and barbarities and murder
                              committed on Union prisoners in rebel prison pens, which appalled the
                              civilized world, but when we hear demagogues talk, of their
                              "chivalrous courtesy" just when the whole North is reverently
                              decorating the silent graves of its patriot dead, many of whom were
                              deliberately stoned to death by the chivalry, we cannot wholly forget
                              it. In turn we would suggest to the <emph rend="italics"
                              >Intelligencer</emph> that decency would admonish it to "hesitate
                              before publishing items calculated to provoke such odious
                              comparisons."</p>

                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>During the war, an old woman named Barbara Freitchie reportedly waved a
                         Union flag in Confederate Gen. Jackson's face as he marched past.
                         Confederate sympathizers argue that the Confederate troops' decision not to
                         harm the woman demonstrates their great chivalry and benevolence; the <emph
                              rend="italics">Repository</emph> argues that Union troops behaved far
                         more humanely than their counterparts.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="e">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>

                         <p>Prejudice against the negro has been driven steadily back from each of
                              its fortified positions, until now it may safely be said to have
                              entrenched itself in the "last ditch." Noah's drunken spree has been
                              made to father more of man's inhumanity to man than even Adam's fall,
                              but with the tumble of the rebellion fell also the logic out of the
                              hitherto irresistible argument from Noah. Slavery died with the death
                              of the rebellion, and prejudice against the colored race fell back on
                              its second line of fortifications. The negro had no right to vote.
                              Driven from that, and the right to vote in the lately rebellious
                              States conceded, he was not allowed to hold office, to testify in
                              courts, to sit on juries or to enforce contracts, nor, by reason of
                              these restrictions, to work for himself. One after another the
                              despised sons of Ham have driven the enemy from all these
                              fortifications, and now they have taken their position in the "last
                              ditch." The negro may vote, hold office, practice law, preach the
                              gospel, hold government clerkships and foreign missions, nay, even be
                              intelligent and a gentleman, but he dare not be a government printer.
                              This is the "last ditch." He might even be a government printer, but
                              to be this it is necessary to belong to the Printers' Union. He is
                              perfectly willing to belong to the Printers' Union, but the Printers'
                              Union is unwilling to belong to him. Having recovered so many of his
                              stolen rights, he is not likely to fail in his attempt to recover this
                              also. Mr. Clapp, the Congressional Printer, has employed a son of
                              Fred. <orig reg="Douglass">Douglas</orig>, colored. The Printers'
                              Union refuse to admit him into the Union, and are bound by the
                              organization to allow no one, not a member, to work with them. Either
                              Mr. Clapp must remove the negro, or the Printers' Union must admit
                              him, or the members of the Union must withdraw. As yet the
                              Congressional Printer and the Printers' Union have each refused to
                              yield. We shall see who wins. The negro holds a strong hand and has a
                              good backer. We advise him to "fight it out on that line, if it takes
                              all summer."</p>

                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>The Printers' Union, which has a closed shop arrangement with the
                         Congressional Printer, refuses to allow black workers into the Union, and
                         thus into the profession. The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph>
                         attacks this as the last bastion of an institution designed to hold back
                         equal rights for blacks.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="e">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>

                         <p>A Democratic exchange says:</p>

                         <p>"Ex-Secretary Stanton has not been heard of for a long time. It is,
                              however, not announced that he has joined the church. He is said to be
                              troubled with constant fears and a terrible dread of the hereafter.
                              The consciousness of his many crimes is crushing the life out of him,
                              and it is not expected that he will live long."</p>

                         <p>If such be the fears and feelings of a patriot so upright and pure as
                              ex-Secretary Stanton, what must we conceive to be the state of mind of
                              those Northern Copperheads whose hostility to the Union, whose
                              intrigues with the leaders of the rebellion, whose sympathy and
                              encouragement fully proffered to traitors brought down to death and
                              the grave thousands of the bravest and best men of the land? Stanton
                              gave years of intense labor to his country, and sacrificed health and
                              fortune in so doing. They sacrificed human life recklessly, but not
                              their own, and gave everything save their fortunes and their own
                              comfort and safety to secure the success of the rebellion. Other
                              things being equal, whose conscience is likely to be most troubled?</p>

                         <p>In confirmation of what we have said as to the attitude of Northern
                              Democrats, during the war, we give the testimony of the editor of the
                              Petersburg <emph rend="italics">Index</emph>. This individual belonged
                              to the fighting rebels and really seems to have a very correct
                              perception of the meanness of the sneaking rebels, though he don't
                              call them by that name.</p>

                         <p>"The glorious Democracy of the North! The forgers and riveters of our
                              chains. The hounders on of a brave people to destruction. The heroic
                              proxy-martyrs who bear with such noble equanimity and patient
                              endurance and the suffering of their Southern brethren. The men who,
                              safe in the rear, beseech the poor devils in Virginia, Texas and
                              Mississippi to keep up the fire until a reaction gives them the
                              spoils. And we are to be as Senator Casserly would do were his State
                                   <orig reg="beset">be set</orig> as Virginia is. What did the
                              Senator do when Virginia cast herself into the breach to confront the
                              tide of encroachment upon American liberality? What did he do? What
                              did they all do? Oh, they are a chivalric, a glorious set! Their
                              advice has been high-sounding and has always led to fair results. By
                              all means, let their counsels guide us for the future."</p>

                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>This article uses quotes from Democrats to show "the meanness of the
                         sneaking rebels."</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="e">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head>Mistaken Charity</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>

                         <p>Charity covers a multitude of sins, but charity may be perverted. It
                              would be if the recommendation of several Posts of the G. A. R. in
                              Washington city to decorate the graves of rebel soldiers last Saturday
                              had been adopted. We do not suppose that it was. The mere act of
                              decorating soldiers' graves may mean very little, but as the
                              expression of a sentiment or principle it means everything. Put into
                              language it says, that the loyal people of the Union hold in lively
                              and lasting gratitude the memory of those who sacrificed their noble
                              lives in its preservation and defense. If that be correct it would be
                              outrageous insult to them, and to the cause in which they fell and
                              died, to pay similar honors to the remains of those who fought to
                              destroy their country, and shed the blood of their brethren. Without
                              hatred towards the dead who died in an unholy cause, we hope the time
                              may never come when the sublime distinction between patriotism and
                              loyalty, and treason, which is sought to be fostered by this custom,
                              will be obliterated. If it does, the inspiration which filled our
                              armies, and carried us triumphantly through the war will be dead, and
                              patriotism will be dead likewise. If we fail to honor those who died
                              for the Union, in the future there will be none willing to make the
                              great sacrifice if needed. We do not merely honor their courage, we
                              honor their courage in defense of right.</p>

                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> strongly attacks the
                         G.A.R.'s recent recommendation to decorate Confederate soldiers' graves as
                         blaspheming the memories of Union soldiers.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <pageNote/>
          </page>

          <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.06.02.03" exists="no">

               <div type="a">
                    <column>01</column>
                    <head>Decoration Day</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>

                         <p>Saturday, 29th ult., was observed in Chambersburg as Decoration Day. The
                              ceremonies of this occasion were a grand success. Our ladies, soldiers
                              and citizens left nothing undone that would add to the solemnities of
                              the day. There were many persons present from the country, to witness
                              the display. During the week the following circular had been sent to
                              the ladies, who generously responded to the call.</p>

                         <p>TO THE LADIES OF CHAMBERSBURG AND VICINITY.</p>

                         <p><emph rend="italics">Saturday, the 29th of May</emph><lb/> Has been set
                              apart as a day to decorate, with flowers, the graves of the Soldiers
                              of the late war who fell in <orig reg="defense">defence</orig> of our
                              country's cause: In this tribute of respect to the glorious deeds of
                              our departed comrades, and in keeping green their resting places by
                              annual commemoration, it is earnestly desired that we have the
                              cooperation of the Ladies. One year ago they poured forth abundantly
                              their choicest floral offerings to strew the graves of the Martyr
                              dead, and on this second observance of the occasion, they are again
                              asked to aid us in keeping in remembrance the sacrifices of those who
                              gave their lives for their Country's sake, by renewing their
                              contributions of flowers. Repository Hall has been offered as a
                              depository for flowers, and all contributions should be sent in by 11
                              o'clock on that day."</p>

                         <p>JOHN A. SEIDERS,<lb/> HARRY STRICKLER,<lb/> Committee to Solicit
                              Flowers.</p>

                         <p>The stage of Repository Hall was literally covered with beautiful
                              bouquets, crosses, and wreaths. There were none who seemed to take a
                              greater interest in the occasion than the children, who were busy
                              during Saturday forenoon carrying flowers to the place where they were
                              to deposit them. There is one thing certain, that this day is
                              established in the hearts of the people, and that the observance of it
                              hereafter will require no appeals to patriotism nor to the love that
                              is borne our gallant dead. The sufferings, privations and heroic
                              deaths of those to whom we owe the very existence of our Government,
                              will never be forgotten. As these graves are annually strewn with
                              flowers, the remembrances of the fallen will return and the influence
                              of their noble lives will ever be felt.</p>

                         <p>At 3:30 P.M. the procession was formed in front of the Court House, by
                              Col. Jas. G. Elder, Marshal, who had as aids Col. Theo. McGowan, Maj.
                              John Doebler and Capt. Geo. L. Miles. The returned soldiers were on
                              the right, led by the Chambersburg Silver Coronet Band, and in their
                              rear Columbus and Chambersburg Lodges of I. O. O. F., Friendship Fire
                              Company and the Housum Zouaves in their brilliant uniforms. The column
                              marched into Repository Hall, where those who composed it were
                              supplied with bouquets. It then returned to the Court House pavement,
                              where it was favored with some excellent music by a quartette of the
                              AEolian Circle, composed of Dr. J. H. Shumaker and Messrs. Pillsbury
                              Henninger and Wright.</p>

                         <p>The procession, then marched down Front street to the Presbyterian
                              Cemetery; thence to the Catholic Cemetery; up Second street to
                              Washington; out Washington to the German Lutheran Cemetery;
                              countermarched out Second to the United Brethren Cemetery; thence to
                              Catharine street and up to the German Reformed Cemetery down Front up
                              Market to Franklin; thence to the Cedar Grove Cemetery. Revs.
                              Crawford, Davis, Barnes and Hays officiated at the various Cemeteries.</p>

                         <p>At Cedar Grove Cemetery, the Quartette sand a piece entitled "Lay Him
                              Low," and Rev. S. Barnes, of the Methodist Church, spoke as follows:</p>

                         <p><emph rend="italics">Fellow Countrymen and Ladies.</emph> - Lovers of
                              our country's flag, and, by the way,</p>

                         <p>"Long may it wave O'er" - what is now more emphatically than ever - </p>

                         <p>"The land of the <emph rend="italics">free</emph> and the home of the
                                   <emph rend="italics">brave.</emph>"</p>

                         <p>The object which brought us together has been accomplished. Our work of
                              today is done. In common with tens of thousands of our patriotic
                              fellow citizens, who elsewhere throughout our broad land, have been
                              employed in other Cemeteries, as we have been here <orig reg="today"
                                   >to-day</orig>, we have strewn with flowers the graves of our
                              country's recently fallen heroes.</p>

                         <p>As we have been thus employed, however, in this service of affection our
                              hearts have been saddened with the thought that, in so far as the dead
                              are concerned, our work has been all in vain. These fair flowers,
                              culled by fairer hands and by the hands of their comrades strewn on
                              the graves of the dead, have, alas, no magic power to call back the
                              souls of the departed, and resuscitate their now decaying bodies.
                              Would that it were otherwise. If it were, there would stand up <orig
                                   reg="today">to-day</orig> throughout our broad land, as in the
                              Prophet Ezekiel's vision, "an exceedingly great army." For, of
                              officers and men whose lives were sacrificed during the war to save
                              our country, there were no fewer, by official figures, than 280,739.</p>

                         <p>Such is the number of our war destroyed and fallen braves. We may render
                              them our tribute of affection, but we cannot bring them back. As it
                              was sung of the great Napoleon, so it may be sung of them.</p>

                         <p>"They sleep their last sleep, they have fought their last battle.</p>

                         <p>No sound can awake them to glory again."</p>

                         <p>But those acts, though useless to them, are nevertheless significant,
                              and we hope, useful to us."</p>

                         <p>It is customary when depositing in the grave the bodies of the dead, to
                              say, "earth to earth, ashes to ashes, dust to dust." Might it not in
                              some sense have been said today, <emph rend="italics">flowers to
                                   flowers?</emph> For was not, our brave army made up of the flower
                              of our country? This was the case in respect - </p>

                         <p>1. Of their youth. They were in this regard like the flowers of the
                              spring and early summer time. They were our youth of promise and our
                              manhood of earlier maturity who constituted our noble army, and many
                              of whom now sleep around us. Again,</p>

                         <p>2. Flowers are the gayest, and in appearance the most beautiful and
                              attractive of all inanimate things. And is not the same true of a well
                              appointed, uniformed and properly equipped army, with banners flying
                              and martial music filling all the air around? How sad that these
                              should fall, broken, bleeding, dying. But</p>

                         <p>3. The flowers brought and strewn on the graves today were <emph
                                   rend="italics">select</emph> and <emph rend="italics"
                              >choice</emph> in quality. So, in point at least of <emph
                                   rend="italics">patriotism</emph> and <emph rend="italics"
                                   >philanthropy</emph>, must have been the men who would volunteer
                              to expose, and even <emph rend="italics">lose</emph> life itself, for
                              their country's and humanity's good. That form of government must
                              indeed be dear to him, who, for its maintenance, would voluntarily lay
                              down his life. And since he who lays down his life to serve his
                              country's good, does it, not for himself, but for the comfort and
                              welfare of others who survive him, his is surely a <emph
                                   rend="italics">philanthropy</emph> of the very highest possible
                              type. The Great Teacher himself hath said: "Greater love hath no man
                              than this, that a man lay down his life for his friend." And yet this
                              is just exactly what our fallen braves have done, for us and for those
                              who shall come after us. Again,</p>

                         <p>4. But for flowers, or blossoms, we should have no fruits. So without
                              our revolutionary armies we should have had no country, in the sense
                              of civil and religious liberty. And but for our <emph rend="italics"
                                   >recent</emph> armies, we should have been without our broad and
                              common country now. We should have been riven and weakened and almost,
                              if not altogether destroyed, in all that now constitutes us great and
                              happy, and we should have become a byword and a hissing amongst the
                              nations. Thus as flowers are productive of fruit and good to man, so
                              have our armies been to us, in giving and preserving to us, all that
                              we hold dear in matters of human government, and who shall
                              sufficiently estimate their worth.</p>

                         <p>5. Flowers are considered emblems of purity. And, soldiering as a
                              profession, is morally and scripturally right. Though the regularly
                              enlisted soldier take the life of his fellow in regular warfare, yet
                              is he innocent of wrong. St. Paul says of the civil ruler that "he is
                              the minister," <emph rend="italics">or servant</emph>, "of God, an
                              avenger, to execute wrath upon him that doeth evil, and beareth not
                              the sword in vain." The soldier is the assistant, or commissioned
                              deputy of the civil ruler, to enforce the law, and, like the ruler in
                              so doing is the Minister or servant of his thing." As therefore "the
                              powers that be' are a God given trust, he who protects them, even with
                              the sword, executes but a Divine beast, and is innocent of moral
                              wrong.</p>

                         <p>6. Flowers are fragrant. So is the memory of our heroes, living or dead.
                              Their memory, like that of the just, is blessed. Not to cherish and
                              honor them, is to be unworthy of the blessings their blood has
                              purchased for us. For myself, I look not on the form of a living "boy
                              in blue" nor upon the grave of a fallen one, without the feeling of an
                              instinctive disposition to doff my hat in honor of his deeds.</p>

                         <p>Let love for them, then be embalmed in our hearts, as are flowers in
                              choicest caskets. Let the 30th of May be ever hereafter to us a second
                              4th of July. Let monuments be erected to their memory. I am glad one
                              is in contemplation here. May the project soon be a grand success. Let
                              the headboards or stones which mark their graves be kept in proper
                              adjustment, and, when needed, suitably renewed. Let the mounds upon
                              their graves be kept full and round, and let flowers be kept growing
                              on them to the end of time. Let our children and our childrens'
                              children be taught the same reverence for our fallen braves that is
                              now cherished for them by ourselves. And, as for our soldiers still
                              amongst us, let them share in the affections we cherish for the dead.
                              Moreover, under God, are they our country's saviors, other things
                              being equal, let them ever be first in our country's patronage, its
                              emoluments and honors.</p>

                         <p>As the interest, however, of this occasion, consists not so much in the
                              words spoken, as the deeds performed and in the affections cherished,
                              I will now close, by thanking you for your very kind and attentive
                              hearing.</p>

                         <p>After the procession had accomplished the object for which it had been
                              assembled, it returned to the Court House and was dismissed. Every
                              thing passed off in the most satisfactory manner. Most of our business
                              houses were closed from 3 to 6 P.M.</p>

                         <p>The following soldiers are buried in</p>

                         <p>CEDAR GROVE, CEMETERY<lb/> Col. Peter B. Housum, 77th Reg Penna
                              Vols.<lb/> Capt William Stouffer, Co C, 92d Reg Ill Vols.<lb/> Rev Wm
                              H Maxwell, Chaplain.<lb/> Jacob Lortz, Co A, 77th Penna Vols.<lb/>
                              Thomas J Reichter, 100th Penna Vols.<lb/> D Augustus Houser, Co A,
                              126th Penna Vols.<lb/> Robert S. Martin, 111th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/>
                              Jacob Householder, 210th Penna Vols.<lb/> James W Palmer, Co L, 21st
                              Penna Cav.<lb/> Jacob B Shaffer, Co A, 126th Penna Vols.<lb/> William
                              H Seiders, Co D, 11th Penna Cav.<lb/> T J C M'Grath, Co A, 126th Penna
                              Vols.<lb/> William B Leisher, Co D, 210th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> Andrew
                              M'Kean, Co D, 21st Penna Cav.<lb/> William M'Kean, 2d Penna Art.<lb/>
                              Benjamin F Suter, Co D, 210th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> James M'Geehan, Co
                              K, 107th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> John Liggett, Co K, 107th Penna
                              Vols.<lb/> Charles W Kline, Co K, 107th Penna Vols.<lb/> Dewitt C
                              Piper, 18th Reg U.S. Infantry.<lb/> John Caseman, Co K, 107th Reg
                              Penna Vols.<lb/> David W Hummelsme, Co D, 11th Penna Cav.<lb/> Jacob H
                              Butler, Co D, 11th Penna Cav.<lb/> John K Simmers, Co D, 210th Reg
                              Penna Vols.<lb/> George Nolan, 2d Penna Art.<lb/> Thomas M Dunkinson,
                              Co K, 107th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> Capt. Samuel R. M'Kesson, Co A, 77th
                              Penna Vols.<lb/> George S Shinefield, Co D, 126th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/>
                              James S Shuman, Co D, 11th Penna Cav.<lb/> William E Shuman, Co K,
                              107th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> John N Heckerman, 13th Penna Cav.<lb/>
                              Lieut Thomas L Fletcher, Co K, 126th Penna Reserves.<lb/> John S Oaks,
                              Co A, 26th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> Emanuel Dietrich, Co H, 213th Reg
                              Penna Vols.<lb/> Marfin Huher, Co C, 149th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> Dr
                              John R Olippinger, Co D, 126th Penna Vols.<lb/> Hugh Bretherton, Co D,
                              11th Penna Cav.<lb/> Casper Rug, Co E, 21st Penna Cav.<lb/> Robert
                              Cunningham, Penna Reserves.<lb/> C Allen, 1st Michigan Cav.<lb/>
                              Calvin Johnston.<lb/> S H Ellis, Co H, 137th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/>
                              Henry M'Cloud, New York Vols.<lb/> John Pensinger, Co A, 77th Penna
                              Vols.<lb/> James M'Kesson, Co A, 126th Penna Vols.<lb/> Capt John C
                              Sample, Co D, 11th Penna Vols.<lb/> Samuel Dine, Independent Penna
                              Battery.<lb/> Frederick Williams, Regular Army.<lb/> Samuel Armbuster,
                              Penna Infantry.<lb/> Zephemiah Burfort, 14th Penna Cav.<lb/> ------
                              Carr, 30th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> George W Creddinger, Penna Vols.<lb/>
                              Jeremiah Dakens, 10th Reg Penna Vols.<lb/> Charles A Frank.<lb/>
                              George W Gale.<lb/> Andrew Hoffman, 20th Penna Cav.<lb/> Christian
                              Hoeflich, 5th U.S. Artillery.<lb/> William W James.<lb/> Jonas
                              Nixon.<lb/> Peter Obhoff, 2st New York Cav.<lb/> George D
                              Robertson.<lb/> Adam Wier.<lb/> C.H. Wellington.</p>

                         <p>PRESBYTERIAN.<lb/> Dr Stewart Kennedy, Surgeon U S Navy.<lb/> George W
                              Wallace, Anderson Body Guard.<lb/> Samuel D C Reed, Co A, 126th Reg
                              Penna Vols.</p>

                         <p>CATHOLIC.<lb/> Patrick Curran, Co H, 69th New York Vols.<lb/> Joseph
                              Yeager, Indepedent Penna Battery.<lb/> Thos. Curran, Co H, 69th New
                              York Vols.<lb/> Frank Donovan, Co A, 77th Penna Vols.</p>

                         <p>SECOND LUTHERAN.<lb/> Henry M Fennel, Co M, 21st Penna Cav.</p>

                         <p>UNITED BRETHREN.<lb/> Charles E Rapp, Co C, 2d Penna Artillery.<lb/>
                              Jacob M'Gowan, Co A, 126th Penna Vols.<lb/> Lieut J Wesley Jones, 58th
                              Penna Infantry.</p>

                         <p>GERMAN REFORMED.<lb/> Lieut Robert Earley, Quarter Master Indiana
                              Vols.<lb/> Lieut Matthew Gillan, 2d Penna Infantry.<lb/> R Bard
                              Fisher, Co A, 126th Penna Vols.</p>

                         <p>JEWISH.<lb/> Isaac Burgauer.</p>


                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Seiders</ln>
                              <fn>John A.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Strickler</ln>
                              <fn>Harry </fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Elder</ln>
                              <fn>James G.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Col.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>McGowan</ln>
                              <fn>Theodore</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Col.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Doebler</ln>
                              <fn>John</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Miles</ln>
                              <fn>George L.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Capt.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                              <fn>J. H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Dr.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Pillsbury</ln>
                              <fn/>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Henninger</ln>
                              <fn/>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Wright</ln>
                              <fn/>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Barnes</ln>
                              <fn>S.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>The paper reports here on the recent "Decoration Day" in Chambersburg.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head>The Mercersburg Railroad</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>The people of Mercersburg have $120,000 to support construction of a
                         railroad. They need to raise $30,000 more. The paper urges other townships
                         to get involved. They have "a fine opportunity to increase the value of
                         their property, develop the minerals hid in their lands, and secure for
                         themselves an easy access to market for the produce of their farms."</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head>"Memorial Day" in Greenvillage</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <transcript>

                         <p>A correspondent writes us that "on Saturday last, the citizens of
                              Greenvillage gave us their daily pursuits, to spend the day in the
                              holy work of affection and love to the noble dead who are sleeping in
                              their midst. Just as the sun was sinking to rest, grateful and
                              friendly hands were decorating the graves of those who died in defense
                              of the old flag. Rev. L. Williams delivered an earnest and patriotic
                              address, well suited to the occasion." The following is a list of the
                              soldiers interred there:<lb/> Lieut Geo Glass, Co A, 165th Penna
                              Vols.<lb/> Sergt John Wallace, Co A, 77th Penna Vols.<lb/> Sergt
                              Mathias Glass, Co C, 2d Penna Arty.<lb/> James Glass, Co A, 126th
                              Penna Vols.<lb/> Geo Shoemaker, Co G, 126th Penna Vols.</p>

                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>A correspondent reports on the internment of several soldiers in
                         Greenvillage on the recent Memorial Day.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>An effort is being made to raise $10,000 to enlarge the Chambersburg
                         Academy. The school has been flourishing under Dr. Shumaker, and there is
                         no longer room for all those who wish to attend.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>McDowell</ln>
                              <fn>Craig</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Pauli</ln>
                              <fn>John</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Craig McDowell and John Pauli, two academy students, rescued a
                         classmate who fell into the Conococheague after their boat capsized.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>The soldiers of Franklin voted on May 29th to thank the ladies of
                         Chambersburg, Rev. S. Barnes, the clergy, the Silver Cornet Band, the
                         military, the Odd Fellows, the firemen, the musical quartette, and citizens
                         generally for assistance and support on Decoration Day.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>02</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>A lodge of the Knight of Pythias will be opened in Chambersburg.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                              <fn>J. H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Prof.</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Prof. J. H. Shumaker of the Chambersburg Academy will direct a student
                         performace in Repository Hall on June 25th.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Campbell</ln>
                              <fn>Hugh J.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Col.</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Col. Hugh J. Campbell, former principal of the Chambersburg Academy,
                         presided at the Louisiana Republican State Convention.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head>Lutheran Church</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                              <fn>S. A.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>The Rev. S. A. Gotwald, pastor-elect of the Lutheran Church, will
                         preach on Sunday.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="a">
                    <column>03</column>
                    <head/>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                              <fn>Martin</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Secrist</ln>
                              <fn>Samuel</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Martin Shoemaker has been appointed postmaster at Graeffenburg in place
                         of Samuel Secrist.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="s">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Married</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Appleby</ln>
                              <fn>D. C. M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Montague</ln>
                              <fn>M. Alice</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Montague</ln>
                              <fn>Thomas</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>West</ln>
                              <fn>William A.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Baird</ln>
                              <fn>James H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>D. C. M. Appleby and Miss M. Alice Montague, daughter of Thomas
                         Montague, all of Shade Gap, were married on May 24th by the Rev. William A.
                         West, assisted by Rev. James H. Baird.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="s">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Married</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                              <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Wrist</ln>
                              <fn>Catharine</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Lego</ln>
                              <fn>Charles</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Emanuel Stevenson and Miss Catharine Wrist, both of Green, were married
                         in Fayetteville on May 14th by Charles Lego.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="s">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Married</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Colbert</ln>
                              <fn>Isaac</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Roof</ln>
                              <fn>Matilda</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Lego</ln>
                              <fn>Charles</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Isaac Colbert of Cumberland County and Miss Matilda Roof of Green,
                         Franklin County, were married in Fayetteville on May 19th by Charles Lego.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <div type="o">
                    <column>04</column>
                    <head>Died</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                              <fn>Emma</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                              <fn>John</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                              <fn>Margaret</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Emma Gelwicks, daughter of John and Margaret Gelwicks, died on April
                         17th. She was 15 years old.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>

               <pageNote/>
          </page>

          <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.06.02.04" exists="no">


               <pageNote/>
          </page>

     </paperBody>
</hwp>
