
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.09.29">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/15/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-09-29">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.09.29.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.09.29.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To the Republicans of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The days of preparation for the great conflict are fading rapidly away, and
                        the question will soon be settled whether the government of this great and
                        influential Commonwealth shall remain in the hands of those who have been
                        loyal to the country and humanity, or pass over to those who are hostile to
                        both.</p>

                    <p>It were a calamity, State and National, that we shudder to contemplate,
                        should the old Keystone be recreant to her record and to herself, and suffer
                        the false Democracy to seize the reins of power. This can only happen if
                        Republicans falter in the discharge of duty. We have a safe majority and our
                        people are earnest enough in their convictions of right. But we are prone to
                        relax our efforts, and we trust too much to well ascertained strength. Such
                        confidence will not do now. We are pressed by desperate, hungry antagonists,
                        who are working with incredible zeal, and are backed by a candidate whose
                        fabulous wealth is lavished for the corruption of the ballot-box. His
                        political history is but the history of his party--no better, it could not
                        be worse. He carries their standard, not because he has endeared himself to
                        the people of Pennsylvania by any public service he rendered them--not
                        because he has any qualifications of statesmanship. Other distinguished
                        gentlemen were pressed in their nominating convention, who served gallantly
                        during the war, or had given evidence of fitness for the administration of
                        public affairs.</p>

                    <p>They were pushed aside; and why? Because Asa Packer counts his money by
                        millions, and is willing to buy his way to power. And upon this sole
                        qualification, it is expected that he is to win the place of a patriot who
                        has filled with honor many places of public trust; who has added to the
                        glory of our arms in two bloody wars, and has <emph rend="italic">paid his
                            taxes</emph>, discharged all his obligations, and is inferior to the
                        Democratic candidate only in being poor. There may be corrupt and beggarly
                        creatures in our ranks in the cities, who can be had for the price the
                        ambitious millionaire may be willing to pay for gubernatorial honors; but we
                        feel such purchasable material is scarce in the pure moral atmosphere of the
                        country. We will not lose here from this source. If we lose at all, it will
                        be from lukewarmness; from a want of realization of the importance of the
                        occasion; from indifference and paltry dissatisfaction.</p>

                    <p>What new good has the Democratic party developed, that atones for its
                        atrocious treason that drenched our whole territory in fraternal blood, and
                        left us a crushing burden of debt, to bear down our prosperity, and make
                        foreign governments insolent towards us? Has it spoken one kind word of the
                        heroes who bled and died in the country's cause? Has it honored with its
                        applause one great soldier, who has won glory in the struggle, unless he has
                        repented of his service, like Blair and Hancock, and bowed his suppliant
                        knees, in their interests? Are not their papers, and speeches and hearts
                        full of admiration of Lee, and Jackson, and the red handed villains who
                        slaughtered our patriotic countrymen, who held up the flag now glorious the
                        wide world over? Are they not as openly favoring the depreciation of our
                        currency, and moving towards repudiation, as ever? Have they grown any more
                        fond of freedom? Do they not still mourn for the halycon days of slavery,
                        when it secured Democratic majorities, which gave the government and its
                        chief offices to the lords of the lash, and dispensed the pap in free States
                        to their sordid followers, thankful for small favors for which no service
                        was too mean for them to render in return? True! they profess to acquiesce
                        in the abolition of slavery, but they insist that the negro is a brute,
                        incapable of civilization, and fit only for bandage.</p>

                    <p>The war has taught them nothing. The repeated indignant repudiation of them
                        by the people, has profited them nothing. As they were aforetimes, so are
                        they now. They are, perhaps, more artful and discreet. The danger of their
                        success may be less apparent; it is but little less real. Their triumph
                        would bring back into power, the unsoftened rebels, with hearts embittered
                        by disappointment and defeat. These miscreants wait, with unsuppressed
                        impudence, their hoped-for day of restoration, when the loyal public will be
                        at their feet.</p>

                    <p>Voters of Franklin county, will you play into their hands? Will you forget
                        your fidelity, in the bloody and dark days that have passed? You have
                        allowed them to steal into power partially. They are entrenched in your alms
                        house. Do not pass the county offices into their possession. They will use
                        them for party purposes. Men who made it necessary for your sires and sons
                        to leave your peaceful, happy homes to go to the front of the battle, while
                        they speculated in the calamities of war, will fatten coils of copperheads
                        upon your taxes.</p>

                    <p>It is enough if you forget the great hurt they inflict upon you; it is full
                        enough if you forgive them their almost unpardonable crimes; it were too
                        much, if you rewarded them for their iniquity. You will not do so. Honest
                        and capable men, who are in full accord with you now, who stood shoulder to
                        shoulder with you, when you sacrificed <orig reg="everything">every
                        thing</orig>, to save the nation from disgrace and dissolution, are offered
                        for your suffrages.</p>

                    <p>Give them a day of service! If you hesitate to go to the polls, remember how
                        unfairly you act, how unkind to your own associates in sorrow, in danger,
                        and at length in such great glory. Remember you are untrue to your
                        convictions, that you fail in your duty.</p>

                    <p>Next to a deserter to the enemy in obloquy is the man who is absent from his
                        place in the hour of battle.</p>

                    <p>Republicans of Franklin county, save yourselves from self-reproach, and be
                        early at the polls!</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Republicans to work hard for victory in the coming
                    election, and reminds voters that the Democrats represent the party of slavery,
                    treason, and rebellion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Future of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The great struggle for the perpetuity of the Union has now been over for more
                        than four years, and high hopes have been, and still are entertained by the
                        best friends of the nation that a firm and stable peace will soon again be
                        vouchsafed to a <emph rend="italic">united</emph> country.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italic">Reconstruction</emph>, though much delayed by the
                        treachery of him who so recently occupied the highest place in the
                        government, is still believed to be quietly and surely being accomplished,
                        according to the declared will of the <emph rend="italic">people</emph>,
                        notwithstanding those who are wedded to the ancient condition of things.</p>

                    <p>This result, we of the North, hope will be brought about mainly through the
                        influences <emph rend="italic">first</emph>, of the abolition of human
                        slavery; <emph rend="italic">secondly</emph>, of the introduction of a free
                        population from abroad, and <emph rend="italic">thirdly</emph>, by the
                        removal and establishment of Northern people and Northern capital in the
                        Southern States.</p>

                    <p>But whilst we depend so largely upon the influences of these agents in
                        changing the condition of affairs in the South--altering the feelings and
                        removing the prejudices of the people, and securing the grand results so
                        aredently desired--it is well at the same time to become acquainted, if we
                        can, with the views entertained of them by those whom we expect to be
                        subjected to their influences. We can thus judge much better, and more
                        surely, whether the results we hope for are likely to be obtained either
                        speedily or remotely.</p>

                    <p>We have been led to these reflections by the perusal of an article entitled
                            "<emph rend="italic">Chivalrous Southrons</emph>," published in the
                            <emph rend="italic">New Eclectic Magazine</emph> for the month of
                        October, 1869, in answer to an article in <emph rend="italic">Harper's
                            Magazine</emph> of January and February last. The <emph rend="italic"
                            >New Eclectic</emph> is published at Baltimore, and is devoted to the
                        "Lost Cause," and in the article referred to the author goes lengthily into
                        the <emph rend="italic">causes</emph> of the recent rebellion, and gives
                        freely and fully the <emph rend="italic">Southern view</emph> of the
                        subjects from which we of the North hope so much.</p>

                    <p>These views we infer may be taken as a true exponent of the educated <emph
                            rend="italic">Southron opinion</emph> upon these great questions, and
                        therefore we think the people of the North should be made more fully
                        acquainted with them than they will likely ever be through the circulation
                        of the <emph rend="italic">New Eclectic</emph> alone. This must therefore be
                        our excuse for the following extracts:</p>

                    <p>"Many a cause has been assigned for the late war. The Northerners say that
                        the cause was <emph rend="italic">Slavery</emph>; and that <emph
                            rend="italic">they</emph>, therefore, are the grand vindicators of
                        liberty. Mr. Alex Stephens also endeavors to show that this was the real
                        cause of the war. He is right as far as he goes, but he has made the contest
                        too much a mere difference about the <emph rend="italic">words</emph> of the
                        constitution. If every word of the constitution had been against us, we
                        ought to have seceded from the Union of the United States, <emph
                            rend="italic">because it had become a vile despotism</emph>. If he had
                        dug deeper in his search for causes, Mr. Stephens might have turned up
                        another cause--the cause which set aside the constitution itself--<emph
                            rend="italic">the faithfulness of the Northern people</emph>. No words
                        however clear could bind this people. If the right of secession had been
                        expressly reserved to the States in the Constitution, it would have made no
                        difference whatever in the result. They would have made war upon us, just as
                        their interests or passions dictated, without the least regard to their
                        covenants. The same faithlessness accompanied all the compromises their
                        usurpations produced. They violated every one of them. The violation of the
                        last--the California compromise--and the formation of a sectional party
                        consisting of the Whigs and Abolitionists combined, with the mean subterfuge
                        of squatter sovereignty, by the only party which professed to respect the
                        constitution, satisfied the Southern people that there was no hope for the
                        constitution, and none for their institutions, or the principles of free
                        government, in the good faith of the North. They therefore seceded from the
                        Union they had voluntarily made with them."</p>

                    <p>"To break down and abolish the characteristics of the Southern people, and
                        reduce them to an assimilation with the Northern people, these
                        instrumentalities are relied upon. First. The influence of the negroes no
                        longer slaves, and now free. Second. Foreign immigration. Third Northern
                        immigration.</p>

                    <p>"1st. The emancipation of the slaves of the South, according to Northern
                        logic, is to work a complete overthrow of the characterisitics and
                        civilization of the South."</p>

                    <p>"There would be some force in this expectation, if the negro could change his
                        nature and lift himself beyond an inferiority to the white race. But if he
                        is still to continue an inferior, how does his exemption from slavery
                        abolish the sense of superiority in the white race? Under the teachings and
                        excitations of Northern emisaries, and the government of the United States,
                        all sympathy between the white and the black race is rapidly disappearing.
                        The negro is deteriorating from the civilization he possessed as a slave,
                        and relapsing into his natural barbarism. While a slave there were two
                        powerful supports to the civilization of the negro. He was the best fed and
                        clothed laborer in the world, and the <emph rend="italic">marital</emph>
                        relations were <emph rend="italic">enforced</emph> upon him. He must now
                        labor or starve. He will starve."</p>

                    <p>2d. "But immigration from foreign nations will mould and abolish the
                        characteristics of the South."</p>

                    <p>"It appears to be a law of all immigration, that the immigrant sinks <orig
                            reg="into">in o</orig> the habits and mode of thought of the people with
                        whom he seeks a home. He comes as a friend, and he wants friends. His
                        children grow up with the children of the country, and it becomes their
                        country. Let the immigrant from Europe come. Let him come, as he always has
                        come to the South, not as a revolutionist, and enemy to the country; a busy
                        fermenter of hate between races, but a lover of order and peace, a friend of
                        education and industry, a hater of oppression and barbarism, and the whole
                        South will open its arms and say to him--come!"</p>

                    <p>3d. "The least instrumentality for revolutionizing and <emph rend="italic"
                            >improving</emph> the character and civilization of the South, is
                        Northern immigration."</p>

                    <p>"The last people on earth to influence and change the Southern people by
                        their emigrant population, is the people of the North. There has never been
                        much love or respect for them among the Southern people; but now they come
                        into the country the living symbols of hate and tyranny. It is vain to say
                        that the peaceful emigrant who comes to cultivate the land, is not the
                        soldier who desolated the country. He is of that race--that race which for
                        seventy years has been false to their constitutional compacts, and which by
                        war and blood has made the Southern people political slaves--the slaves of
                        slaves--slaves to the most ignominious despotism. By the blessings of our
                        past, lost liberties, we cannot follow or imitate our destroyers. But the
                        Northern emigrant comes to us with a still fouler pollution. He is the ally,
                        the patron, the leader, the instigator of the negro race to rule and plunder
                        the white race. Identified with negroes in all their moral squalor and weak
                        barbarity, how can he have the least influence upon the white race to change
                        their characteristics? Yet, although he cannot influence the characterisitcs
                        of the South, the Northern emigrant may better his condition by emigrating
                        to the South. Politically he is not worse; for in the North the despotism of
                        the United States alike prevails. He is safe from molestation, if he will
                        leave others unmolested. His industry will have its reward, and in two
                        generations his children will be as good Southern men as walk the land. He
                        will soon understand the negro, and know his capacity to rule him, or to
                        rule himself. He will understand also the government of the United States,
                        in its sectional despotism, when he also is its victim. Let him come
                        therefore, and we will freely welcome him, if neither a <orig
                            reg="carpetbagger">carpet bagger</orig>, nor a miscegenist nor a
                        white-man hater. It matters not, however, what he is, so far as the
                        characteristics of the <orig reg="South">south</orig> are concerned. <emph
                            rend="italic">We may adopt them</emph>--he cannot change them."</p>

                    <p>"The late war against the <orig reg="South">south</orig> has laid the
                        Constitution of the United States in the coffin of consolidation. Its lid is
                        held down by two screws, one <emph rend="italic">black</emph> and the other
                            <emph rend="italic">yellow</emph>. We have got negro emancipation, and
                        negro equality already--and the Pacific Railroad being now completed, the
                        United States will receive into its boson, by the operation of the last
                        constitutional amendment, all the yellow races of Asia to an equal
                        participation of power with the white race in the government of the United
                        States. The civil war in Rome, in which the slaves were emancipated and made
                        citizens, destroyed the liberties of Rome. The same means must produce the
                        same results in the United States. Despotism--not the mere Despotism of
                            <emph rend="italic">factions</emph>, but the Despotism of a sectional
                        majority, fixed, heartless and insatiable rules the United States, and must
                        ever continue to rule them under the present condition of things."</p>

                    <p>That there are many errors, misstatements and falsehoods in these quotations
                        will be perceived by every unprejudiced reader, and we give them, not to
                        attempt their refutation, for we have not the time for that, but to show the
                            <emph rend="italic">animus</emph> controlling the intelligent minds of
                        the South towards both the government of the nation and the measures adopted
                        for the pacification of the lately rebellious States. If such be the
                        sentiments of the <emph rend="italic">masses</emph> of the Southern people,
                        a complete and cordial Reconstruction must assuredly be more distant and
                        difficult than the friends of the Union had hoped. Upon the good sense of
                        the people there must depend the result.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints excerpts from an article defending the white South, and
                    blasts it for making peaceful Reconstruction less likely.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper charges that Democratic gubernatorial candidate Asa Packer is
                    hostile to Catholics and working men. The editors assert that he once refused to
                    support a Catholic nominee, and opposed an 8-hour-day law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Lew W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper calls on the "soldiers of Franklin county" to vote for "comrades"
                    Lew W. Detrich, Capt. James C. Patton, and Capt. John Doebler. "They were all
                    faithful to their country in her hour of peril, and with you confronted the
                    armies of the rebellion at the cannon's mouth."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper condemns Asa Packer for supporting the southern wing of the
                    Democratic Party during the 1850s. The editors charge that he supported
                    Breckinridge over Douglas, and, "when even a word from a man of his influence
                    would have helped the Union cause, he was silent."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Knight</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper urges Franklin citizens to work for the election of Capt. William
                    C. M'Knight to the legislature. The editors assert that he was first to champion
                    reimbursement for war-damages, and has the experience needed to push it through
                    the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes the Democrats of Pennsylvania for resorting to
                    "prejudice and passion" to prevent adoption of the 15th Amendment. The editors
                    compare that to the stance of many southern journals that have allegedly dropped
                    the fight against African American citizenship and voting rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Cain</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper denounces as a lie Democratic charges that Gov. Geary has
                    pardoned Cain Norris, the black man who was sentenced to 35 years in prison for
                    "fearful crimes" allegedly committed in Franklin County last spring.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges local Republicans to awake and organize for the upcoming
                    campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Asa Packer for inviting Clement Vallandigham to his
                    home, and entertaining him during "the darkest days of the war." "What think the
                    gallant soldiers of Pennsylvania of such a record? Can they who wore the blue
                    vote for such a man?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses John Frey for administrator of the county Poor House.
                    "Mr. Frey is a hard working farmer of Guilford township, and is 'honest as
                    steel.' He would carefully guard your interests."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges citizens to vote for Hyssong, Greenawalt, and Detrich--all
                    "responsible men" who will handle the business of the Court House with "care and
                    promptness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.09.29.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lippy</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Culloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>H. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>S. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sloan</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. Agnew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Nulty</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heagy</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allison</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLenegan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Banker</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society submits a report testifying to
                    the great success of their recent exhibition of fruits and vegetables held in
                    Repository Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Emancipation Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The colored citizens of Chambersburg, had a grand celebration of the
                        Emancipation Proclamation, on the 22nd inst. The colored men from this
                        vicinity had been working for several weeks past, to have the occasion they
                        celebrated well observed on the part of their race, and their efforts were
                        very successful. Delegations were present from various points in the valley.
                        At 11 A.M. the procession was formed and moved through our principal
                        streets. The men in the ranks kept good time and marched well.</p>

                    <p>The following were the officers of the day:--Chief Marshal, Edward Lowery;
                        Assistant Marshal, David Patterson; Aids, Alexander Lewis and Ashford
                        Collins. Col. Henson Turner was in command of the military, which consisted
                        of the Independent Blues of Chambersburg, Capt. Alfred Bradford; Grant's
                        Rough and Ready Boys, Capt. Elijah Hommet; Lincoln Guards, of Mercersburg,
                        Capt. H. H. Watson; Cavalry Company from Mt. Alto, Capt. Shadrick Campbell</p>

                    <p>An entertainment was held in Reside's woods, near town, in the afternoon,
                        where not only large numbers of colored men and women assembled, but also a
                        goodly proportion of white men, to hear the orator, Prof. D. D. Brown, of
                        New Jersey. The meeting was organized by electing Rev. Isaac Gassaway
                        President, Rev. J. D. Brooks and Levi Lee Vice Presidents. The speaker was
                        introduced by Rev. Hopkins.</p>

                    <p>Prof. Brown is a pure black man, without the least tint of amalgamation about
                        him. His remarks were spoken in an earnest and forcible manner. He said,
                        among other things, that he was not in favor of any party which did not fear
                        God and regard race, color or condition as a necessary element of
                        citizenship; that there was no natural inferiority in any race, and that God
                        had endowed all men with the right of life, liberty and independence; that
                        all the colored men needed was an opportunity to show those who had been
                        oppressing them for years that they had intellects and could cultivate them.
                        He further said that as a representative of a race that had been loyal to
                        the "Stars and Stripes" when traitors attacked it; that as the
                        representative of a race that had shown its manhood and courage under the
                        lamented Col. Shaw at Fort Wagner, under Gen. Banks at Port Hudson, under
                        Gen. Grant at Petersburg, and in many other engagements, that had its
                        patriotic dead and wounded, who suffered and died, he demanded protection
                        from the rebels and assassins of the South, and Justice from the North; that
                        if the colored men could be trusted with the bullet in order to save the
                        sons and brothers and fathers of the North from the deadly fire of Jeff
                        Davis' army, that it was but right that they should have the ballot to
                        protect themselves. He spoke for about an hour. His manner was easy and
                        natural and many parts of his speech were full of outbursts of true
                        eloquence. His audience listened attentively. His colored hearers seemed
                        proud of this, their representative.</p>

                    <p>In the evening a festival was held in Repository Hall, which was well
                        attended. The order during the day and evening was excellent. There was no
                        disturbance of any kind. Everything passed off exceedingly creditable to
                        those who has this movement in charge.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowery</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Ashford</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Henson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradford</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hommet</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Shadrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>D. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gassaway</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lee</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper publishes an ccount of an emancipation celebration held by
                    Chambersburg's African American community. The article includes a summary of
                    remarks made by the primary speaker, Prof. D. D. Brown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shade</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleming</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Osbraugh</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bort</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonner</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreps</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weir</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>William U.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper summarizes the news from Greencastle. Philip Shade was found dead
                    in his garden on September 20th. He was 83 years old and died from natural
                    causes. Archibald Fleming died at his residence on the 20th. He was 87 years old
                    and had once been county sheriff. He also had held office in Antrim. "He was a
                    good citizen, a successful farmer, a social neighbor and a Christian gentleman,
                    being a life-long member of the Presbyterian Church. He was laid to rest in Moss
                    Spring Cemetery and survived by a number of family and friends. The Republicans
                    of Greencastle nominated the following borough ticket: Col. Joseph A. Davison
                    for burgess; Joseph B. Strickler, William Osbraugh, John Bort, C. F. Bonner, and
                    Theodore Koontz for town council; D. Watson Rowe and William Kreps for school
                    directors; A. K. Weir for justice of the peace; William U. Brewer for town
                    clerk; Jacob L. Detrich for auditor; Daniel Hawbecker for constable; Benjamin
                    Snively for judge; and John Wilhelm for inspector.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The third quarterly meeting for the Chambersburg Station, United Brethren
                    in Christ, will begin on Saturday with the Rev. Z. A. Colestock presiding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fritz</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightcap</ln>
                        <fn>Stephen D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stephen D. Lightcap, dispatcher of trains at Bridgeport on the Cumberland
                    Valley Railroad, will replace Lt. Robert A. Sharp as conductor of the afternoon
                    passenger train. Alex Fritz, long-time baggage handler on the road, turned down
                    the position. Harry Elliott will take Lightcap's place. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Andrews passes, on behalf of the Conductor's Brotherhood No. 11, a
                    tribute of sympathy and respect upon the death of Robert A. Sharp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>On Friday evening last, the Republicans of the North and South Wards met at
                        their accustomed places of meeting, for the purpose of nominating borough
                        and ward officers. As the various officers are selected alternately from
                        either ward, the following list was soon agreed upon:</p>

                    <p>Borough</p>

                    <p>Chief Burgess--E. J. Bonebrake, S.W.<lb/> Town Council--F. S. Gillespie,
                        N.W.; L. B. Kurtz, N.W.; Samuel F. Greenawalt, N.W.; Dr. J. L. Sueserott,
                        S.W.; Peter Creighbaum, S.W.<lb/> School Directors--J. N. Snider, S.W.;
                        Calvin Gilbert, S.W.<lb/> Auditor--R. P. Hazelet, S. W.</p>

                    <p>North Ward</p>

                    <p>Judge of Election--Samuel Etter<lb/> Inspector--David M. Leisher<lb/>
                        Constable--Philip Hamman</p>

                    <p>South Ward</p>

                    <p>Justice of the Peace--Hugh B. Davison<lb/> Judge of Election--Joseph
                        Frey<lb/> Inspector--Wilbur F. Eyster<lb/> Constable--David Davis</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creighbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>David M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Wilbur F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the Republican nominees for Chambersburg city offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Dedication</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letterkenny Lodge No. 663, I. O. O. F., will hold dedicatory ceremonies on
                    October 2nd. The Lodge was first organized last June at Strasburg and boasts 50
                    members. I. H. McCauley will deliver the address, and the Silver Cornet Band
                    will perform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horst</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirk</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frederick</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans of Guilford met and nominated the following ticket: Samuel
                    Myers for judge; A. S. Lehman for inspector; Solomon Sollenberger and Solomon
                    Miller for school directors; Michael Ebersole, Samuel Caufman, and Abraham Horst
                    for supervisors; Jacob Shirk for auditor; Samuel Frederick for treasurer; George
                    W. Foltz for town clerk; George Bowers, Sr., for constable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shannahan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Dr. Shannahan, bishop of Harrisburg, will administer the sacrement
                    of confirmation at the Catholic Church in Chambersburg on October 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A new bell weighing 1,583 pounds has been installed in the First Lutheran
                    Church of Chamberbsurg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boner</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Maudie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Boner and Miss Maudie Knepper, both of Franklin, were married near
                    Quincy on September 19th by the Rev. John Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Feidt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grabill</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Feidt and Miss Kate Zimmerman, both of Warren, were married on
                    September 19th by the Rev. J. M. Grabill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minnie Ross, daughter of Daniel and Susan Reisher, died in Chambersburg on
                    September 24th. She was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jesse Craig died in Montgomery on September 24th. He was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.09.29.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
