<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.05.15">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/31</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-05-15">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="00">15</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>4</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.05.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Slaughter of the Unborn</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are social errors and crimes difficult to expose and correct without
                        shocking the sensibilities of the virtuous and suggesting evil to the
                        innocent; and extend themselves without resistance until society is
                        threatened with utter corruption and decay. Such is the fact now with the
                        crime of infanticide before birth, or more accurately, foeticide. So general
                        and destructive has this crime become as to cause reasonable alarm, and at
                        length the silence is broken, and the doctors of medicine and divinity unite
                        in solemn remonstrance and appeal against its guilt and danger.-Dr. Morse
                        Stewart, an influential physician of Detroit, Michigan, has contributed to
                        the Western Medical Review, a paper discussing the physiological effects of
                        abortion, as well as the moral guilt of the practice, and making startling
                        disclosures as to its prevalence and the immense amount of disease and death
                        resulting from it. Dr. Stewart declares that his statistics, confirmed by
                        the observations of physicians, prove that there is no crime more surely
                        punished in the persons of those committing it, than that of abortion, and
                        that more lives are lost by it than by childbirth. Of those who survive the
                        operation, the majority are made invalid for life, by a complication of
                        incurable disorders that break down the constitution and often produce
                        insanity.-When the attempt fails, the child that escapes the fate plotted
                        for it, and often the succeeding children, will be deformed, idiotic or
                        diseased in various ways. The crime is never safe, and when the evil
                        consequences of the unnatural act are apparently evaded at the time, they
                        are certain to be developed later, and to bring terrible retributions upon
                        the mother.</p>
                    <p>There is general concurrence in the opinion that the practice of abortion has
                        rapidly increased within a few years until it may be said to be common, Dr.
                        Stewart declares that if every mother guilty of it should be hung for
                        murder, the married women would be almost decimated, for the criminals are
                        chiefly married women. For the single woman, deceived and betrayed, there
                        would seem to be some excuse in resorting to this means to conceal her
                        shame. The wife, who desires to escape the pain of child-birth and the
                        trouble of rearing offspring, and so ruthlessly outrages her maternal
                        instincts and destroyes her unborn children can not satisfy her conscience
                        with the selfish and cowardly reasons which move her to ten unnatural crime.
                        A New York physician states that there are in that city over four hundred
                        professional abortionists, most of whom do an extensive business and some of
                        whom advertise in the leading papers. There are establishments for the
                        purpose adapted to the different classes, some fitted up luxuriously for the
                        rich, who pay as high as $500 for the service. Besides the professional
                        abortionists, there are some regular physicians who secretly assist there
                        patients to the commission of the crime at their own homes, and hundreds of
                        ignorant quacks, men and women, to fall into whose hands is almost certain
                        death, and whose sole recommendation is that they do their work quickly and
                        cheaply. The specifics advertised in the Metropolitan papers for causing
                        abortion are generally but baits and advertisements of practicing
                        abortionists, for they almost invariably fail of their purpose, while the
                        directions accompanying them, point to the establishments where the work may
                        be surely accomplished. In addition to these systematic methods of procuring
                        abortion, the physician says they are called to prescribe for many women who
                        have attempted the crime upon themselves, with such crude means as were in
                        their power, and these are some of the worst cases in their results of
                        sickness and pain.</p>
                    <p>Abortion would seldom be practiced if it were felt to be a crime. There is a
                        prevailing notion that the life of the human germ is not sacred, that it may
                        be destroyed without guilt at any moment before it exhibits life, or indeed,
                        at any moment previous to birth. Dr. Todd tells us that Catholic Christians
                        are better instructed on this subject than Protestants. The confessional
                        guards human life from its first stage, and fearful penalties are threatened
                        against those who interfere with its natural growth. The Catholic Bishop of
                        Boston says on this subject:</p>
                    <p>The very instant conception has taken place, there lies the vital germ of
                        man.-True, it is hidden in the darkness of the womb, and it is helpless; but
                        has sacred rights, founded on God's law, and so much the more to be
                        respected because it is helpless. It may be already a living man, for
                        neither mothers nor physicians can tell when life is infused; they can only
                        tell when its presence is manifested, and there is a wide difference between
                        the two things. At any rate it is from the first moment potentially a man,
                        with a body and soul destined most surely by the will of the Creator and by
                        his law, to be developed into the fullness of human existence. No one can
                        prevent that development without resisting and annulling one of the most
                        sacred and important laws established by the Divine Author of the Universe,
                        and he is a criminal, a murderer, who deals an exterminating blow to the
                        incipient man, and drives back into nothingness a being to whom God designed
                        to give a living body and an immortal soul."</p>
                    <p>Dr. Todd asserts that the practice is far more common among Protestants than
                        among Catholics. In this fact, doubtless lies the explanation, in whole or
                        in part, of the decline of our Protestant population as compared with the
                        Catholic. It is not common to find more than two or three children in our
                        Protestant families and those who have abundant means for the care and
                        education of children are more likely to limit their families by unnatural
                        methods than their poorer neighbors. Women in the very highest circles of
                        society evade the duty of maternity on the pretense that they are too
                        delicate for it, and by that evasion often become helpless invalids for
                        life, while all observation confirms the fact asserted by Dr. Todd, that
                        "the fairest, healthiest, happiest, most respected and most useful women
                        that ever lived, have been the mothers of large families." It might also be
                        shown that many cases of domestic infelicity and alienation of husband and
                        wife, of late so common, originate in premature sterility caused by the
                        attempt to circumvent the divine law. Our women need to be taught that the
                        laws of nature cannot be evaded, nor its processes obstructed in any way,
                        without incurring the penalty. And the penalty will be fearful in proportion
                        to the crime and perversion.-Health and enjoyment, of body, mind and heart,
                        come only through obedience to law.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Noting that the number of abortions has increased in recent years to the
                    point that "it may be said to be common," the editors label the women who
                    undergo the operation as "selfless and cowardly" and castigates the doctors who
                    perform the procedure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.05.15.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>State Rights</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Though the State Rights' doctrine was "held in high esteem by our
                    ancestors" and "was made the very cornerstone of the government," presently, the
                    editors assert, it is "scoffed at and derided" by the Radicals who imposed
                    "centralized despotism" in its place. This form of governance, the editors
                    allege, enabled minority factions in Maryland, Missouri and Tennessee to obtain
                    abosolute political power, which they used to contravene the wishes of the
                    constituents in those states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Incendiarism and Negro Riots</head>
                <origin>Richmond</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radical policy of reconstruction is rapidly bearing fruit at the South.
                        Richmond being the first point of attack in the new war inaugurated by the
                        Radical party against the people of the South, we naturally look there for
                        the first fruits of the campaign, and we need not in vain. Thousands of
                        worthless negroes have been congregated there through the agency of Hunicutt
                        and his Yankee co-laborers, with the view of organising a grand black
                        Radical party, with the Richmond niggers as a central nucleus. A black
                        "loyal league" has been established there, through which it is hoped the
                        darkies in other portions of the state can be reached in due time, and
                        manipulated so as suit the purposes of the Radicals in Congress. It was in
                        Richmond that Senator Wilson made his great debut before the colored
                        citizens of Virginia; it was there that the thousands of Africans assembled,
                        according to Forney, were so overcome with profound reverence for the
                        big-bellied Senator from Massachusetts, that they were unable to greet him
                        with a single cheer, but stood in silent awe before him with heads
                        uncovered! Richmond, as we said before, was the initial point of the Radical
                        campaign against the South. Now for the result.</p>
                    <p>In the early part of last week, a number of fire companies met in the lower
                        part of the city of Richmond for a trial of their engines. As usual on such
                        occasions, thousands of idle negroes assembled on the ground. One of their
                        number was arrested by the police for disorderly conduct. The other then
                        made a riotous assault upon the officers of the law, and rescued the
                        prisoner. A general negro riot ensued, which was only quelled by Gen
                        Schofield ordering the U. S. troops, who had been sent to the scene, to
                        drive them from the ground at the point of the bayonet, which was
                        accordingly done. A few days later another riot occurred in the same part of
                        the city, and growing out of a similar cause-the arrest of one of their
                        number by the police. The Telegraph gives the following account of it:</p>
                    <p>RICHMOND, May 12.</p>
                    <p>Another negro riot occurred in the lower part of the city last night. The
                        negroes attempted to rescue a drunken negro from the police. Bricks, clubs
                        and pistols were used, and four policemen badly beaten.-One of them is
                        severely injured. A company of soldiers guarding the Libby Prison were
                        called on, and captured eighteen of the rioters.</p>
                    <p>While this was going on, another negro difficulty occurred on First street.
                        This last mob dispersed upon the persuasion of a colored juryman. To-day
                        mounted soldiers patrolled the streets to keep order, and squads of police
                        were placed at all the churches, in view of threats of the negroes to force
                        their way in amongst the white people. A large procession of negro societies
                        attended a funeral to-day, accompanied by an unarmed company of colored
                        militia, the officers of which carried swords.</p>
                    <p>These are some of the first fruits of the Radical policy of reconstruction,
                        and of the attempt to organize a "black man's party" in the South, in
                        opposition to the whites. Wilson has gone to other cities and towns further
                        South, haranguing the negroes and organizing them into a Radical party. The
                        same results will doubtless follow his efforts elsewhere which so speedily
                        developed themselves in Richmond. How do our Republican friends like the
                        prospect? How do they relish increased taxation to keep up a large military
                        force in the South to quell negro riots, incited by Radical emissaries for
                        political purposes? If we find these things in the green tree, what may we
                        not expect in the dry?</p>
                    <p>We are also informed by telegraph that some citizens of Richmond have laid
                        before General Schofield a complaint about the language used at a colored
                        meeting on Friday night last. The General promised to investigate the
                        matter. Subsequently one of the speakers, a Yankee, named Frederick K.
                        Hayward, of Massachusetts, was arrested on a warrant from the Mayor for
                        uttering the following incendiary language to the negroes:</p>
                    <p>After Judge Underwood leaves, you can hold high carnival, or what you please.
                        I need not advise you what to do, for great bodies do as they have a mind
                        to.</p>
                    <p>Such are a few of the beauties of Radicalism-these are the evidences of its
                        practical workings. Who would not belong to the party of "great moral
                        ideas?"</p>
                    <p>We are glad to see it stated that General Schofield told Judge Underwood that
                        if there was any more rioting on the part of the negroes, "he would plant
                        cannon in every street and sweep the rioters down with grape." This evinces
                        the right determination, but if he would go to the root of the matter, he
                        should send for Wilson, Kelly, Hunnicutt &amp; Co., and "sweep <emph
                            rend="italic">them </emph> down" along with the negroes. <emph
                            rend="italic">They </emph> are the real criminals </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article discusses an incident of racial unrest in Richmond, where
                    thousands of blacks have congregated with "the view of organizing a grand black
                    Radical party." The violence began after a black man was arrested for disorderly
                    conduct. Believing him to be innocent, blacks in the crowd "made a riotous
                    assault" on the police and rescued the man from the authorities' custody. In the
                    wake of this event, "a general negro riot ensued," which was only quelled by
                    arrival of U. S. troops led by Gen. Scholfield.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Haytian Affairs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relating that Radicals are "striving to put the balance of political power
                    in the country in the hands" of blacks, the editors suggest that Haiti provides
                    a "fitting illustration" of blacks' incapacity for self-government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.05.15.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--A Good Officer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. John Forbes has been appointed Street Commissioner by the Town
                    Council.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Painful Accident</head>
                <origin>Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushey</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Marshall, the engineer at Cromwell and Davidson's machine shop in
                    Greencastle, came close to cutting off his leg when he slipped on a piece of
                    bark and fell on a circular saw on May 9th. The saw severed his "skin, muscle,
                    and integuments down to the bone." Marshall was treated by Dr. Frank A. Bushey
                    and "by all accounts he was doing well."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--The Theatre</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a laudatory account of the theatrical production performed by
                    McKean Buchanan and his troupe on May 12th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Temperance Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chenworth</ln>
                        <fn>George D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Pastors of various churches in Chambersburg and the Rev. George D.
                    Chenworth, Corresponding Secretary of the State Temperance Union, agreed to hold
                    a convention in Chambersburg on May 28th. The convention is expected to draw
                    delegates from the counties of Franklin, Fulton, and Adams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--"Grand Army of the Republic"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article disparages the Grand Army of the Republic and contends the
                    organization was created "for the purpose of securing the votes of Soldiers,
                    through false pretense."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Borough Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that H. M. Sibbett won the post of Chief Burgess in the election
                    held in Waynesboro on May 6th. In addition, George Fourthman, George Harbaugh,
                    Henry Gilbert Jr., Peter Dock, and Hiram Snider were selected as Councilmen
                    while Jacob Breneman was named the High Constable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Music and Musical Entertainments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>F</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Professor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contains a letter praising the efforts of the Chambersburg Musical Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 29th, George Miller and Anna Craig were married by Rev. P. S.
                    Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stepler</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 5th, Lewis Stepler and Amanda M. Burns were married by Rev. P. S.
                    Burns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murphy</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 9th, Samuel J. Murphy and Sarah Stenger were married by Rev. J.
                    Gordon Smith at the residence of J. D. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisner</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisner</ln>
                        <fn>Allice A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisner</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 1st, Anna Mary, daughter of John S. and Alice A. Weisner, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>David Rowen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 23rd, David Rowen Duffield, eldest son of Elizabeth Duffield, died
                    near Henry Marshall Co., Ill..</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.05.15.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
