<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.11.27">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>06/14/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-11-27">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="11"/>
			<day norm="00">27</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.27.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.27.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Pardoning Power Abused</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The abuse of the pardoning power by Governor Curtin was so extensive and
						unprincipled as to excite great indignation in the popular mind all over the
						Commonwealth. At no period in the prior history of Pennsylvania, did crime
						prevail to such an alarming extent as did the periods of his administration.
						We were engaged in a gigantic war. The basest passions of men were
						unchained. Almost every community felt the baneful influence o this
						disordered condition of society. Violence was the order of the day. Theft
						and robbery were common, and murders not unfrequent. In our own county, the
						criminal calendar was unprecedentedly large. And yet, a trial of the
						perpetrators of these crimes seemed but a mockery. If conviction was the
						result, hardly had the sentence been pronounced before Executive clemency
						interposed and the prison doors were thrown open. Men sensed to entertain
						that awful dread of punishment which is frequently the chief terror of the
						evil-doer. They argued that, even if justice did overtake them and pass
						judgement upon them within her courts, there was yet a refuge to which they
						might fly. Influential friends would come to the rescue and a pardon would
						be procured. We venture the assertion that during the administration of
						Governor Curtin, three out of every five who were sentenced to the
						penitentiary from his county, were pardoned before the expiration of their
						terms of imprisonment. Indeed, so flagrant had the abuse of the pardoning
						become in his hands, that when our present Governor was inducted into
						office, he felt called upon to satisfy the public mind upon this subject,
						and to declare that this system of granting wholesale pardons would be
						abandoned. He adopted the most stringent regulations upon the subject. He
						established certain conditions which he alleged, applicants for pardon must
						comply with strictly before their prayers would be heard. He caused these
						rules to be sent to every prosecuting officer in the Commonwealth. He gave
						them the widest publicity by causing them to be inserted in the daily
						newspapers. We print them now for the purpose of showing the people, and
						also of reminding the Governor himself of the good intentions which he
						entertained in this respect at the beginning of his official term.--They are
						word for word, as they were issued, signed by His Excellency and transmitted
						by his Attorney General, on the 31st day of January, A. D. 1867:</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">First</emph>.--No Pardon will be granted until notice of
						the application therefor shall have been given by publication once a week
						for two consecutive weeks, in a newspaper printed in the county in which the
						conviction was had. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Second</emph>.--No pardon will be granted unless notice
						of the application shall have been given to the Judge who tried the cause,
						to the District Attorney or to the Attorney who prosecuted. Proof of which
						notice shall be furnished this Department </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Third</emph>.--All applications for pardon must have with
						them the following papers written in a clear and distinct hand: </p>
					<p>1. A certified copy of the whole record including docket entries, minutes of
						the Court, copy of indictment, pleas, and all other papers on file in the
						Court relating to the case.</p>
					<p>2. A full statement of the reasons upon which the application is based,
						setting forth all the facts; the notes of evidence taken on the trial;
						letters from responsible persons in the community where the crime was
						committed; a recommendation from the Jurors who sat on the trial, and if any
						of them refuse to recommend a pardon, reasons given for such refusal;
						letters from the District Attorney or Counsel who tried the case; and a
						letter from the Judge setting forth his views upon the subject of the
						application.</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Fourth</emph>.--Recommendations for Pardons for unexpired
						terms of sentence must have a copy of the whole record, as before required.
						Also copy of commitment; petition from prisoner setting forth reasons; and
						statement from Warden and inspectors of Prison. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Fifth</emph>.--No personal applications will be
						permitted. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Sixth</emph>.--All of the above papers, when submitted
						must be accompanied by a printed copy of same in pamphlet form, twelve
						copies of which, at least, must be sent to this Department. If the parties
						are too poor the Paper Book need not be printed. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Seventh</emph>.--As these rules are intended to subserve
						the administration of justice they will be strictly enforced, and relaxed
						only when good reasons shall be furnished for doing so. </p>
					<p>The publications of these regulation gave promise of a healthy change in the
						mode of granting pardons. The law-abiding citizens of the Commonwealth were
						rejoiced. They felt that henceforth there would be something to deter men
						from the commission of flagrant violations of the laws. The surest
						preventive of crime is the <emph rend="italic">certainty </emph> of
						punishment, not the <emph rend="italic">severity </emph> of it. A rigid
						compliance with these published regulations would have subserved the ends of
						justice admirably, by teaching criminals that the pardoning power of the
						Executive could not be considered a loop-hole through which they might
						escape. But this publication was a mere blind. It was a mere bid for popular
						favor. Or, if ever the Governor entertained the idea of requiring conformity
						to these rules, he abandoned it very soon. Scarcely had they been issued
						before several convictions of the Governor's party friends took place for
						riot, and hardly had the sentence been pronounced, before the power of the
						Governor was interposed and the guilty parties were shielded from
						punishment.--Numerous pardons have been issued since, to parties in
						different parts of the State, without any notice whatever having been taken
						of these prescribed rules. And only ten or twelve days ago, in the Court of
						Quarter Sessions of the City of Philadelphia, a trial took place, in which
						one William Carson was the defendant, charged for keeping a gambling house.
						For many years there had not been a single conviction in that city for this
						offence. It seemed impossible to bring such guilty parties to punishment.
						The evidence in this case was clear. The District Attorney appealed
						eloquently to the jury to make an example of this man, so as to put the seal
						of judicial condemnation upon the nefarious business in which he was
						engaged. A verdict of guilty was the result, and the sentence of the court
						was promptly pronounced. Hardly an hour elapsed after the sentence, until
						Carson was a free man, the <emph rend="italic">pardon of Governor Geary,
							procured in advance of the conviction</emph>, having set at nought the
						whole proceedings of the court. Certainly this was a case in which the
						regulations given above, so solemnly prescribed by the Governor, should have
						been rigidly enforced. Will the public excuse such a relaxation of his fixed
						rules? With a reputation already established for complicity in the Fort
						Delaware ballot box stuffing affair, the Governor can not afford to repeat
						these violations of his own regulations, outrage the popular sense of
						justice and nullify the solemn judgements of the courts, and that for the
						purpose of letting loose upon society the most notorious criminals. Let the
						laws have free course--let justice, as administered by the courts, have full
						sway--and let Executive clemency interpose only where clear injustice has
						been done, or where there are peculiar circumstances that would make
						clemency more an act of justice than the execution of the sentence, and for
						the sake of common decency as well as justice, let us have no further
						issuing of pardons in advance, and in anticipation of the judgement of the
						courts, or let us abolish courts of justice for the trial of criminal
						offences altogether.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>One of the numerous corrupt practices that went unchecked during
					ex-Governor Curtin's administration was the "flagrant" abuse of the pardoning
					process, assert the editors. When Gov. Geary came to power he promised to put an
					end to his predecessor's "system of granting wholesale pardons." Yet, despite
					his early efforts to change the laws regulating the procedure, he "abandoned"
					his plans soon after taking office.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Radical Inconsistency</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>According to the editors, the Democrats' refusal to admit Tennessee's
					congressional delegation is based upon the same principles used by the
					Republicans to reject the representatives from Kentucky, who happened to be
					Democrats, last January. For this reason, then, the editors declare the
					Republicans to be hypocrites bent upon maintaining their power.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.27.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Purchased A Farm</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Dorsey</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Clugston</ln>
						<fn>Joseph C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Joseph C. Clugston, of Greenvillage, purchased Dr. Dorsey's 145 acres
					limestone farm last week.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Robbery</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Loudenachlager</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Notes that an "old citizen" named Loudenachlager was knocked down and
					robbed in Wolffstown by two black men, an occurrence the editors say has become
					"all too common."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Serious Accident</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Eby</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McDonald</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Feimlee</ln>
						<fn>J. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>It is reported that David Eby suffered a serious accident last week in
					Fulton county while driving his four-horse team in the neighborhood of Licking
					Creek. Eby was a few miles from McConnellsburg when slipped from his wagon while
					attempting to slow the vehicle. Eby sustained severe bruising of his leg but
					broke no bones. He was attended to by J. G. Feimlee and brought to Mr.
					McDonald's hotel to recover.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Chambersburg Building Association</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>On Wednesday evening the 20th inst. a meeting of the citizens of this borough
						was held in the Court House for the purpose of organizing an association to
						be called "The Chambersburg Building Association."--The attendance was
						tolerably large, but not as large as it should have been. The association
						was permanently organized. The following officers were elected for the year
						beginning the third Monday of this month: President, Geo. Eyster esq.; Vice
						President, Wm. D. Guthrie; Treasurer, B. F. Nead; Secretary, Calvin Gilbert;
						Directors, B. I. Maurer, Jacob Henniger, Wm. D. Guthrie, B. F. Nead and Dr.
						W. H. Boyle. The association has thus been fairly launched upon its career,
						which we hope and believe will be one of great usefulness. Its object is, as
						stated in its Constitution, "the accumulation of a fund by the savings of
						the members thereof, sufficient to enable every stockholder to invest his
						savings safely and speedily, and to purchase Real Estate, or to invest the
						same as it may be deemed by him most profitable." Any citizen of the State
						aged 21 years, who buys one or more shares of stock, and signs the
						Constitution and by-laws, may become a member. The number of shares of
						capital stock shall bot exceed 1600. The association has limited the number
						at present to 500. No person can take more than ten shares. Every member
						pays for each share 25 cents entry money, and a weakly contribution of 50
						cents for each share. As soon as $250, or more shall be found in the
						Treasury, it shall be offered in open meeting of the members and shall be
						paid to such member who pays the highest premium for the same, and all
						premiums paid shall be for the benefit of the association. Security is
						required in lands or buildings and in the latter case, the insurance policy
						must be assigned to the association.</p>
					<p>Every possible precaution is taken to insure safety to the members for the
						monies which they invest. The chief thing necessary to make this association
						a paying institution is the exercise of great caution as to the security,
						taken for the money given out. It will be a great convenience to men who
						purpose building. They here have the opportunity of borrowing money and
						paying for it in small weekly installments until the whole amount is
						liquidated, instead of being pressed by some creditor who needs his money
						and enforces payment by regular process of law. On Monday night, the first
						payment on the shares was made we are informed that there is every reason to
						believe that all the shares will soon be taken.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Eyster</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Guthrie</ln>
						<fn>William D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nead</ln>
						<fn>B. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gilbert</ln>
						<fn>Calvin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Maurer</ln>
						<fn>H. L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Henninger</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Boyle</ln>
						<fn>W. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Relates that the Chambersburg Building Association was organized and its
					officers elected at the Nov. 20th meeting.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Anniversary</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Notes that the second anniversary of the McMurray Lodge No. 119, of the I.
					O. G. T., will be held on Wednesday evening.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Still Another</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Informs readers that Seth Wilber Payne, who is on "a grand trip" from New
					York to San Francisco, left Shippensburg on Nov. 25th for Loudon. Apparently,
					Payne intends on documenting his trek in a book to be published in the near
					future.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Centenary Meeting In Upper Path Valley</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>West</ln>
						<fn>W. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gordon</ln>
						<fn>J. Smith</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hays</ln>
						<fn>Isaac</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kuhn</ln>
						<fn>W. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that the centenary celebration of the Presbyterian Congregation of
					Upper Path Valley, held on Nov. 19 and 20, was well attended.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--The Peak Family</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Announces that the Peak Family, a "widely known Company of Swiss Bell
					Ringers," will perform in Repository Hall on Dec. 6 and 7.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Wolf Caught</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Rosenberry</ln>
						<fn>Abraham</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Weaver</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fricker</ln>
						<fn>Andrew</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Horn</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Horn</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>After catching a young female wolf in his trap, Abraham Rosenberry was in
					the "act of dispatching her with an axe" when he was attacked by a pack of
					fifteen wolves, and was forced to make a hasty retreat. According to reports,
					there are eighteen wolves roaming the woods nearby.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Real Estate Sales</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Gelwicks</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Cormany</ln>
						<fn>B. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stouffer</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Karper</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Lewis</ln>
						<fn>Diana</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brandt</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Detrich</ln>
						<fn>Jacob L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fetterhoff</ln>
						<fn>H. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Deardorff</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Coulter</ln>
						<fn>Matthew</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Campbell</ln>
						<fn>Robert</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lists recent real estate sales. Last Tuesday, William Gelwicks sold his
					house and lot on Second St. to B. A. Cormany for $1,600; on Nov. 21st, William
					Gillan's executors sold two of his farms at public auction; John Karper
					purchased the 177 acres plot for $58 an acres and Henry Stouffer bought the
					adjoining 183 acres plot for $37.75 an acres; Diana Lewis sold her property on
					North Main St. for $252; David Brandt sold the Antrim Hotel to Jacob L. Detrich;
					Jacob Deardorff purchased Dr. H. R. Fetterhoff's property on West Baltimore St.
					in Greencastle for $2,700; Robert Campbell acquired at public auction a 73 acres
					slate farm from Matthew Coulter's estate for $45 and acres.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Sad Casuality</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Youst</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Youst</ln>
						<fn>Augustus</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The author of the article laments the passing of Augustus Youst, the
					twenty-year old son of William Youst, who died from injuries he suffered while
					unharnessing a horse on Nov. 15th. Youst served during the Civil War, enlisting
					first with Pa. Cavalry in Company D, 21st, Reg't, for six months and later in
					Company E of the same regiment for two years befoe being honorably discharged at
					the end of the rebellion.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Mish</ln>
						<fn>Frederick</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nave</ln>
						<fn>Priscilla</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sheffer</ln>
						<fn>D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 30th, Frederick Mish and Priscilla Nave were married by Rev. D.
					Sheffer.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shaffer</ln>
						<fn>Joseph J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Prim</ln>
						<fn>Mary J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>S. H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 18th, Joseph J. Shaffer, of Frederick Co., Maryland, and Mary J.
					Prim were married by Rev. S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Nimmon</ln>
						<fn>John S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Flickinger</ln>
						<fn>Sarah A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>West</ln>
						<fn>William A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 20th, John S. Nimmon and Sarah A. Flickinger were married by Rev.
					William A. West, who was assisted by Rev. I. N. Hays.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Zimmerman</ln>
						<fn>Jonas B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hege</ln>
						<fn>Anna</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Schneck</ln>
						<fn>B. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 21st, Jonas B. Zimmerman, of Cumberland Co., and Anna Hege were
					married by Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Holliday</ln>
						<fn>James W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 9th, James W. Holliday, 70, died at Dry Run.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Coble</ln>
						<fn>Susannah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Coble</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Capt.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 22nd, Susannah, consort of Capt. John Coble, died in St. Thomas.
					Susannah was 70 years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.27.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
