<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.12.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/15</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-12-04">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="00">04</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.12.04.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.12.04.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Presidency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although they have received numerous letters soliciting their endorsement
                    for candidates in next year's presidential election, the editors have opted to
                    withold their preference because it is too early to make a decision. They do,
                    however, offer a vague sense of what characteristics a candidate would have to
                    possess to earn their backing: he will have to be "a high toned gentleman and a
                    sound Democratic" as well as a "highly intellectual statesman."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>At Last</head>
                <origin>Repository</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, in its last issue, flings to the
                        breeze its banner on which is inscribed, "Manhood Suffrage." Its senior
                        editor has written this inscription upon it, and henceforth, our assertion
                        that the leaders of the Radical party in this country are in favor of that
                        doctrine, will certainly not be denied, as it was all through the late
                        campaign.--Such unblushing effrontery--such open, reckless defiance of the
                        popular will has scarcely ever been exhibited before. From that far-off
                        Territory, which but recently, in spite of Col. M'Clure's most strenuous
                        efforts, thundered its denunciation of this doctrine, he writes to a county
                        in which Radicalism, after a series of unbroken successes covering a period
                        of ten years, has been repulsed, for the simple reason that the people
                        believed that it was secretly carrying them in that direction. Rebuked here
                        and there, he refuses to be bound by the popular verdict, and plants his
                        standard far in advance of the foremost position which his party has had the
                        hardihood to assume here. The stone which the builders rejected has become
                        the corner. In the future, therefore, citizens of Franklin county, the issue
                        will be a plain one. <emph rend="italic">For manhood suffrage, or against
                            it, is the question</emph>.--Hereafter, the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository</emph> as an organ of the Radical party, will advocate the
                        right of the negro to vote. The VALLEY SPIRIT as the organ of the Democratic
                        party, will continue to oppose this monstrous doctrine. There is no middle
                        way--choose ye between us. </p>
                    <p>Col. M'Clure enumerates different causes which contributed to the defeat of
                        his party in Pennsylvania and the other Northern States. But, strange to
                        say, his judgement is so completely blinded that he fails to perceive the
                        real issue. Nay, so infatuated is he, that he insists that the source of
                        their weakness in the late elections is to be the pillar of strength in the
                        future. The truth is, that the overwhelming reverses which the radical party
                        has suffered are mainly if not altogether attributable to the fact that they
                        had linked themselves to the negro and were engaged in a fruitless attempt
                        to draw him up to an equality with the white man. It was because of this
                        belief that such a ruinous apathy took possession of large numbers of
                        Republicans. It was on this account that many who had never faltered before
                        in their fealty to that organization, broke loose from it altogether and
                        cast their lot with our own party. And yet, he insists that his party must
                        cling to this fanatical idea, and predicts that the negro "will vote again
                        in every State within the next decade." He says:</p>
                    <p>The issue may be defeated for a time, and each defeat will but strengthen it.
                        Men may fall who have the manhood to advocate it; but all who have abiding
                        faith in the fidelity with which the people will perfect the mighty
                        revolution now in progress in this nation, will look hopefully, confidently
                        for this great consummation. It is founded on the principles of eternal
                        justice that those who are governed, and taxed and required to defend the
                        country's honor and flag with their lives, shall have a vote in their
                        government, and it cannot fail without shattering our boasted structure of
                        Universal Freedom.</p>
                    <p>To what "mighty revolution" does he refer? Does he mean that the Democratic
                        tornado which has lately swept over the whole country? Surely, that is the
                        only "mighty revolution now in progress in this nation." We cherish and
                        "abiding faith in the fidelity with which the people will perfect" it, but
                        we <emph rend="italic">do not</emph> "look hopefully, confidently, for this
                        great consummation" of negro suffrage. On the contrary, we believe that this
                        Radical party which has inscribed negro suffrage upon its banner, will be
                        swept clean out of existence by the mighty masses of the people rising in
                        their majesty, and proclaiming their fixed determination to maintain the
                        freedom of the Republic, by forever preventing the negro from participating
                        in the work of its government. Our free institutions are jewels to precious
                        to be entrusted to the hands of men who have never shown any capacity for
                        self-government. </p>
                    <p>But he tells us that "100,000 sable heroes died to defend our free
                        institutions." Prey, when and where? Perhaps he counts all the negroes who
                        were in the army as so many "dead ducks," in view of the late elections.
                        Surely, the compositor must have added a cypher to the manuscript. The
                        Colonel can not be serious. If so, we must insist upon seeing "the papers."
                        The senior editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> has been so
                        accustomed to victory that he does not know how to take defeat. He will not
                        be admonished. Much whipping hath made him mad. He exhibits the courage and
                        the rashness of desperation. If the people will not be led, they must be
                        driven. If they will not be coaxed, they must be coerced. If they will not
                        allow themselves to be deceived, they must be compelled openly to quaff the
                        bitter cup of negro equality to its dregs. What say you? Get ready for the
                        plain issue. It is before you. You must meet it. Meet it like men.--Meet it
                        like <emph rend="italic">white</emph> men. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In the last issue of the Repository, the article informs readers, Col.
                    McClure, the editor of the Republican organ, made clear his, and his party's,
                    position relative to granting blacks the vote when he inscribed "Manhood
                    Suffrage" as the newspaper's banner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gen. Grant's Prospects For The Radical Nomination Ruined</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Grant, say the editors, was the likely choice to become the
                    Republicans' candidate in the upcoming Presidential election. The chances of
                    this occcuring were dashed, however, when he appeared before the Judiciary
                    Committee on July 18th and offered several opinions that the "ultras" within the
                    party found objectionable. In particular, the editors contend, his neutral stand
                    on black suffrage ruled out any possiblity of compromise on his candidacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Impeachment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that the Judiciary Committee has come out in favor of
                    the impeachment of President Johnson, but it contends that the move is not
                    supported by the massses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.12.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Associate Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 2nd, John Armstrong was sworn in as Associate Judge, taking over W.
                    W. Paxton's position, which expired that day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Removed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. S. Stenger has moved his law office to the George Eyster's former office
                    beside the Valley Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Disturbance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that several black residents of Chambersburg stoned Michael
                    Miller's house on Saturday night. The cause is of the unrest is unknown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Good Templars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The second anniversary of the McMurry Lodge was celebrated on Wednesday.
                    Speeches a the event were given by Rev. S. H. C. Smith, Rev. J. A. Crawford, Dr.
                    N. Schlosser, and W. W. Paxton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Chambersburg Building Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At the regular meeting of the Chambersburg Building Association held last
                    Monday, it was decided that no more than 500 shares would be sold before January
                    1869, after which another 500 will be offered. So far 300 shares have been
                    purchased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Supposed Horse-Thief Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cromer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>House</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>High Constable</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Joseph Cromer was arrested for stealing a "valuable horse
                    from the stable of Dr. Howard" and "a buggy from Henry White," both of which
                    were taken from the Shippensburg area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Pilfering</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that a girl was detected stealing a small sum of money from a
                    drawer in Augustus Fahnestock's store. After being detected the girl returned
                    the money and was "allowed to run free," which, according to the article, was
                    "an excellent way of preventing a repetition of the offense."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Almost A Swindle</head>
                <origin>Somerset Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There is a swindler praying upon farmers in the area, informs the article.
                    The con man called upon Jacob Hostetter several months ago and promised to build
                    a Sorghum Mill on his land free of charge. The only thing he requested was a
                    signature attesting that they had an agreement. That was the last the farmer
                    heard of the swindler until Jeremiah Rodarmer presented him with a $150 note
                    that the swindler had evidently forged. It is believed the same con-man
                    attempted a similar trick in Somerset county recently.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 20th, William H. Wilson, of Delawre Co., Ohio, and Mary E.,
                    daughter of Col. James B. Orr, were married by Rev. I. N. Hays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>David B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 21st, David B. Shoemaker and Sarah Miller were married by Rev. John
                    Shank.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spital</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 23rd, Christian Spital, 40, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Frances</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 27th, Frances Culbertson, relict of the late Joseph Culbertson, of
                    Chambersburg, died in New York City. Frances was 82 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.12.04.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
