<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.09.11">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>06/01</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-09-11">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="09">September</month>
			<day norm="00">11</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.09.11.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Our Public Schools</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>P. M. Shoemaker, esq., Superintendent of Common Schools for Franklin county,
						has kindly furnished us with a copy of his official report, which we print
						below:</p>
					<p><lb/>SCHOOL HOUSES AND GROUONDS. </p>
					<p>There are two hundred school houses in the county that belong to the
						district.-There are a few others that are used as school houses, but as they
						do not belong to the district, I have omitted them. Seven new houses were
						built during the first year-two in Antrim, one in Green, one in Hamilton,
						two in Letterkenny and one in Montgomery. They are all brick except the one
						in Montgomery, which is frame. One of the houses built in Letterkenny is
						large, well arranged vestibule and clothes rooms; is well ventilated, well
						supplied with furniture, and is one of the best school houses in the county.
						It certainly is a credit to the directors of the district. The other new
						houses are all good, substantial buildings; all tolerably well arranged, and
						tolerably well ventilated, and all well supplied with furniture, except the
						one in Green. The directors of Metal commenced building a large house in the
						town of Fannetsburg, one year ago, but owing to a difficulty in getting a
						good title for the ground, it was delayed, but will be completed during this
						summer. One house in Metal was enlarged and remodeled; also one in Antrim.
						These houses are now as good as new. All of them show much improvement over
						those built or remodeled a few years ago. During the coming year there will
						be a number of good houses built in this county. Forty-four houses are
						classed in the statistical table as unfit for use. These are all cold,
						rickety old houses, and are certainly unfit for the training places of
						youth. I am told that in some of them, some of the children froze their feet
						last winter within ten feet of a stove red-hot.</p>
					<p>In the tabular statement I have reported but few houses have sufficient play
						ground. There are, however, a good many that have tolerably good play
						ground, but in my opinion, not a sufficiency.</p>
					<p><lb/>FURNITURE AND APPARATUS. </p>
					<p>Of the two hundred school houses, seventy-nine are well supplied with
						furniture.-A majority of those in the second class could be well supplied at
						very little expense. Those in the third class are badly supplied with seats,
						desks, &amp;c. One hundred and ninety-one schools are supplied with
						outline maps, and about the same number with elementary charts. A few have
						globes, but they are the property of the teachers, and are used by them in
						their schools. About fifty were supplied with astronomical charts during the
						past year.- SCHOOLS.</p>
					<p>The whole number of schools is two hundred and twenty-eight. Of that number,
						forty-four are said to be graded, but in most of them the grading is very
						imperfect. The graded schools are nearly all in the largest towns and
						boroughs, and in some of them they cannot be graded as they should be, on
						account of the houses being badly arranged. The one hundred and fifty-one
						reported as well classified include the forty-four reported as graded;
						leaving seventy-seven that are not well classified. In some of these there
						is no uniformity of books, which makes it almost impossible to properly
						classify a school. The winter was unusually severe; the roads almost
						impassable for several months, on account of snow drifts, causing the
						attendance of pupils to be very irregular, and this, especially in
						out-of-the-way places, operated very much against classification.</p>
					<p><lb/>EXAMINATIONS. </p>
					<p>I hold nineteen public examinations; one in each district. At these I
						examined one hundred and seventy-nine applicants. I then appointed five
						Saturdays, for applicants to meet me in this place, and gave notice to
						directors and teachers that on these days I would examine all applicants for
						schools, and at no other time. On these five days I examined twenty-five
						applicants.-There was still a want of teachers, and I was compelled to
						examine a few privately, and to renew the certificates of a few others, in
						order to get the schools filled. I examined no applicants after the nineteen
						public examinations were over, unless they had a written request from a
						board of directors stating that they wished to employ them. I renewed no
						certifications unless at the request of directors. Seventy-three directors
						and over two hundred citizens attended the public examinations, and a few
						the special ones. I consider the examination of teachers the most delicate
						duty a superintendent has to perform. I generally combine the oral and
						written methods. I believe, in some branches, more interest can be excited
						and sustained, and the qualifications of applicants more definitely
						determined by the oral method than by the written, while in other branches I
						prefer the latter. A majority of our teachers are only employed in teaching
						during the winter, and are engaged at something else during the summer. They
						generally complain of being rusty, so that I find it necessary to be
						lenient. The salaries of teachers depend, to a great extent on the grade of
						certificate. Many teachers think the standard is too high, and say that it
						operates against them in getting better salaries. I, however, try to impress
						on the mind of directors and teachers, that the higher the standard the
						better it is for the well qualified teacher and the cause of common school
						education. My opinion is that the standard is too low, instead of too high,
						but there is a scarcity of teachers now, and should we raise the standard,
						we would be unable to fill near all our schools. Last session we did not get
						teachers for some of the schools, in several districts, until half the term
						was taught in other schools in the same districts. This, directors have in
						their power to remedy, to a considerable extent. If they would lengthen the
						term and raise the salaries of good teachers to what they should be, young
						men and women would turn their attention to teaching, and would qualify
						themselves for the profession. As it is, especially the male portion, teach
						for a year or two until they can find something more lucrative,--perhaps I
						should say at which they can earn a livelihood,--and then they quit
						teaching. I have urged directors to pay good teachers better salaries, and
						they nearly all agree that they are too low, but are slow in applying the
						remedy. The reason they assign for not doing so, is that taxpayers would
						complain. I think, however, if they would try it they would soon find that
						they would get better teachers; that these teachers would render much better
						satisfaction; that there would be more interest taken in the schools by
						parents and scholars, and in the end much less complaining done, and much
						more benefit derived from the schools.</p>
					<p><lb/>TEACHERS. </p>
					<p>Whole number of teachers employed during the last term was two hundred and
						twenty-eight; one hundred and sixty-one males and sixty-seven females.
						Forty-one hold professional certificates and one hundred and eighty-seven
						provisional. Thirty-six had no experience; thirty one taught less than one
						year; seventy between one and five years; and ninety-one over five years.
						Some of our teachers have attended a normal school, but I am unable to say
						how many. One hundred and sixty-seven have read works on the theory of
						teaching, and sixty-one have not. Something over one-half of our teachers
						are well qualified; understand the theory of teaching well; "teach children
						to think, not to memorize; teach them principles and not rules." About
						one-fourth of them are tolerably well qualified, and succeed tolerably well.
						About forty are poorly qualified, and were not successful; and fifteen were
						total failures.</p>
					<p><lb/>VISITATIONS. </p>
					<p>Visited all the schools except sixteen. I was at ten of these but they were
						not open at the time; six I failed to reach owing to bad roads and inclement
						weather. Visited twenty-four twice and a few three times. Made eighty visits
						in company with one or more directors. As I wanted to see the schools in
						their every-day condition, I did not let teachers and citizens know when I
						would visit their schools, unless I could do so when on the way to the
						school. Sometimes I heard a few of the classes myself, but generally the
						teacher proceeded in his usual way. Before leaving the school I generally
						made a short address to the scholars. To the teacher I speak privately,
						calling his attention to any errors I may have noticed in classifying,
						governing, or teaching, and suggesting such plans and changes as I deem
						necessary to the successful management of the school. The visitation of
						schools is sadly neglected by directors and parents. Their indifference and
						the want of proper supervision by some district agency, are great
						impediments to the advancement of our common schools.</p>
					<p><lb/>INSTITUTES. </p>
					<p>Regular meetings of the district institute were held in Chambersburg, Lurgan,
						Metal and St. Thomas, and a few meetings in Guilford. These are praiseworthy
						examples and should be imitated by directors and teachers in every district.</p>
					<p>The county institute met in Greencastle, in November, and continued in
						session four days. The attendance of teachers was small, but the exercises
						lively and instructive.-Very able addresses were delivered before the
						Institute by Hon. J. P. Wickersham, Sates Superintendent, and D. Watson
						Rowe, Esq.</p>
					<p>There are some columns in the statistical blank that I am not able to fill,
						having neglected to get the necessary information, on these points, when in
						the districts.</p>
					<p><lb/>CHANGES IN THE SCHOOL LAW. </p>
					<p>In my opinion the minimum school term should be increased to six months, and
						the state appropriation increased in proportion; directors should be allowed
						a reasonable compensation for their services; the Legislature should pass an
						act regulating the salaries of County Superintendents on some fair basis;
						directors should have the power to appoint one of their best teachers, or
						someone else, who is well qualified as district superintendent, and to pay
						him out of the funds of the district. Where districts are small two or more
						might unite.</p>
					<p><lb/>SUMMARY. </p>
					<p>Held one county institute; nineteen public, five special and twenty-three
						private examinations; granted two hundred and twenty provisional
						certificates; made two hundred and thirty-seven visits to the schools,
						average length about one and two thirds hours; wrote one hundred and
						forty-three letters on official business; spent two hundred and three days
						in the discharge of official duty; and traveled one thousand seven hundred
						and sixty miles.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shoemaker</ln>
						<fn>P. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Contains a copy of a report on the schools in the district, furnished by P.
					M. Shoemaker, Superintendent of Common Schools for Franklin county.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.09.11.02">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Democratic Ticket</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>It must, we think, be conceded by every candid Republican in Franklin County,
						that the ticket put in nomination by the Democratic Convention is a good
						one. The standing, character and qualifications of our candidates will bear
						the closest scrutiny.</p>
					<p>Co. B. F. WINGER, who was nominated for the Legislature by a very flattering
						vote-receiving 68 out of 78 votes on first ballot-is one of our most
						intelligent, active and enterprising citizens. Entering a country store
						fresh from the farm at the early age of fourteen, he successfully pursued
						the mercantile business up to the breaking out of the rebellion. In August,
						1862, he entered the military service as First Lieutenant in the second
						Regiment of Pennsylvania Artillery. For his intelligence, courage and
						enterprise in the performance of his duties, he was rewarded with a Major's
						commission at the close of the campaign of 1864, and in the spring of 1865
						he was promoted to the office of Lieutenant Colonel. His regiment was on
						duty in the defences of Washington till the opening of Grant's campaign
						against Richmond in the spring of 1864, when it was ordered to the front. It
						participated in nearly all the battles and established a reputation for
						bravery second to that of no other body of men in the whole army. Its
						gallant officers frequently led it into the very forefront of the battle,
						and neither they nor their heroic followers ever flinched before the hottest
						fire. After Lee's surrender, Col. Winger was commandant of the city of
						Petersburg and of several military sub-districts, an evidence of the
						consideration in which he was held by his superiors. He remained with his
						regiment until it was mustered out of service in February, 1866, when he
						returned to this county and engaged in agricultural pursuits. Col. Winger
						has, until a recent period, been in opposition to the Democratic party; but
						finding the Radicals bent upon subverting the Constitution and destroying
						the Union which he had periled his life to preserve, he came out manfully
						against them a year or more ago. The time when and the circumstances under
						which he made the change in his political connections, leave no room for
						doubt about the purity or patriotism of his motives. There are no assailable
						points either in his private character or his military career. He is an
						excellent candidate and will make an excellent representative.</p>
					<p>JOHN ARMSTRONG, Esq., who received the high compliment of a nomination by
						acclamation for associate Judge, is known personally to almost every voter
						in the county. We can tell the public nothing of him that they do not know
						already. His extensive knowledge, his unbending integrity and his firmness
						of purpose, are known to all, and it must be universally conceded that if he
						should be elected he will be "the right man in the right place." No man
						could be chosen who would bring the discharge of his duties a more
						conscientious desire to <emph rend="italic">do right</emph> or a stronger
						will to carry it out. </p>
					<p>CAPT. GEORGE W. SKINNER, who was first nominated for County Treasurer after a
						spirited contest-which, however, was conducted in the most honorable manner
						by all the parties to it-is a member of the well known and highly
						respectable family of his name residing in Path Valley. We have heard but
						one single objection to him by his opponents and that is <emph rend="italic"
							>his youth</emph>.-We admit that he is young, but we believe Wm. Pitt
						was Prime Minister of England at an earlier age. Nor would it be extravagant
						to claim for Capt. Skinner a shade of the spirit and energy that made Pitt
						famous in his early manhood. A youth of eighteen when the war broke out, he
						left College and entered the army as a private in 1862, in Company A, of the
						Seventy-seventh Regiment of Pennsylvania Volunteers. He passed successively
						through the grades of Sergeant and First Lieutenant up to Captain, and
						remained in service till the command was mustered out in January, 1866. The
						reputation of the gallant "Seventy-seventh" is too well known to require any
						eulogium upon it or its officers. The man who was worthy to command a
						company in it is worthy to be County Treasurer. </p>
					<p>WILLIAM SHENAFIELD, nominated for County Commissioner; JOHN GILLIAN Jr.,
						nominated for Director of the Poor; WILLIAM BOYD, nominated for Jury
						Commissioner; and JOSEPH MOWER, nominated for Auditor-all are well qualified
						for the official positions to which it is proposed to elect them
						respectively. They rank among the most intelligent, most substantial and
						most steady going citizens of Franklin county, and are, like the rest of our
						candidates, eminently worthy of a warm support.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Winger</ln>
						<fn>B. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Armstrong</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Skinner</ln>
						<fn>George W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shenafield</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>In the article, the editors introduce the Democratic candidates for office
					in the county elections -- Col. B. F. Winger, John Armstrong, George W. Skinner,
					and William Shenafield -- and provide brief biographical sketches of each.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Reaction</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>During the last seven years the Republican party has carried almost every
						important election in every Northern State. Since the election of Mr.
						Lincoln in 1860, its power has steadily increased. Wielding the immense
						patronage of the Federal Government, together with that of the respective
						State Governments of the North, it won triumph after triumph, so that, of
						late, it fondly dreamed that it tenure of office was to be perpetual. Its
						leaders thought that nothing could impede its onward march.</p>
					<p>The war naturally gave strength to the Republican organization. The Southern
						States had acted almost as a unit with the Democratic party of the North.
						When they attempted to break the tie which bound them to the Union and ran
						madly into secession, the power of our party was broken. The effect of this
						step was not simply to take from our organization the strength which lay
						strictly in the South. It was weakened alone by the loss of the Democratic
						electors who resided there. No! The influence of secession extended beyond
						the limits of the seceding States. Its criminality hung mill-stones around
						the necks of Democrats North. The Republican party made hot haste to
						appreciate and make itself master of the situation. It charged us with
						sympathy with secession. It denounced us as aiders and abettors of treason.
						It made use of all the opprobrious epithets which our language could
						furnish. It appealed to the basest passions of the human heart. By the
						meanest misrepresentations and foulest calumnies, it sought to cast upon us
						the odium of an alliance with those who were seeking to break up the
						government. To a great extent, it succeeded. It drew away thousands he
						support of the flag. More than a million of men sprang to arms. Then-when
						the Federal Government was in almost death-throes-the Republican party
						addressed its specious partisan appeals to their patriotism. It sought to
						make them believe that the salvation of the country lay in voting with that
						organization-that if Democrats would get into power, they would turn the
						whole government over to the rebels. With extraordinary skill, it
						manipulated the soldier vote. With unequaled adroitness it persuaded the
						people that the administration was the government, and the only way to
						support the government was to support the administration. The strong arm of
						military power was used to stifle inquiry and to suppress opposition. The
						mouths of Democratic speakers were gagged. The Democratic press was muzzled.
						Democratic orators and editors were immured in forts, or driven into exile.
						The little bell tinkled, and the Democratic citizen was robbed of his
						liberty. We were derided as Constitution savers and Union shriekers. The
						populace applauded. The mob, frenzied and thirsting for blood, committed
						innumerable outrages. The Republican party was everywhere triumphant. Such
						was it in the hey-day of its power.</p>
					<p>The war closed. Rebellion was suppressed. The South was vanquished. The
						Federal Government was victorious. "The Union is saved," thought the honest
						masses. "The negro is emancipated. The Republican party will certainly be
						satisfied." But not so. The seceding States are States no longer. They must
						be held and treated as conquered territory. Representation must be denied
						them. A standing army must be maintained. Military power must hold them in
						subjection. They always voted the Democratic ticket. they must not be
						allowed to come into the union until they vote the Republican ticket. The
						white population will vote with the Democrats. They must be disfranchised.
						The negro is "loyal." He must be enfranchised. Freedmen's Bureau must be
						established. The negro must be fed and clothed at the expense of the white
						man. There must be no distinction as to political rights on account of
						color-if any, the discrimination must be made in favor of the black man. The
						lands of the rebels must be confiscated. They must be parceled out among the
						freedmen. More-the negro must vote in the District of Columbia. The war has
						wiped out State rights. The word <emph rend="italic">white </emph> must be
						stricken out of every State Constitution. The negro must vote everywhere in
						the Union. Congress is now the government. All power belongs to it. It may
						exclude representatives from any State for the reason that they vote the
						Democratic ticket. </p>
					<p>These are the principles which made the Republican party the <emph
							rend="italic">Radical </emph> party. </p>
					<p>Meanwhile the Democratic party maintained its organization. Its ranks were
						thinned. Its numbers were reduced. Silently and without ostentation it sent
						its members to the field. On every battle-ground they lie. Their bones lie
						bleaching side by side with those of their political opponents. Southern
						soil has drunk up the commingled blood of the Democrats and Republicans.</p>
					<p>At home, the party struggled earnestly for the ascendancy of its ancient
						political faith. Patiently it bore slander and contumely unprecedented in
						our history. Time and again it was defeated, but calmly it gathered up its
						strength for each succeeding conflict. It kept its eye on the Constitution.
						It felt that "Truth, crushed to earth, will rise again."</p>
					<p>It had faith in its destiny-faith in the ultimate success of its principles.
						Through sore trials and bitter reverses, it kept straight on its way,
						earnestly looking forward to, and longing for, the day when the mists of
						passion should be dissipated; when the terrible political delusions, which
						have hung like a nightmare upon the people should be dispelled, and the
						bright day of harmony and good-will among the people of the North and the
						South, and of prosperity to the nation, should be ushered in.</p>
					<p>At last, the reaction has come. The "sober, second thought" has been
						awakened. The night of our political darkness is over. The tide of
						Radicalism has been stemmed. From the Pacific shores, California sends her
						greeting to the conservative men of the country. She has hurled back the
						current of fanaticism. The Democratic party is triumphant. There is hope for
						the Republic.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>When the South left the Union, say the new editors of the Valley Spirit,
					the "influence of seccession extended beyond the limits of the seceding States."
					Indeed, that decision "hung mill-stones around the necks" of northern Democrats,
					who were implicated and persecuted as a consequence of their association with
					southern wing of the party. But now, after seven years of defeat and
					marginalization, the Democrats have been resurrected.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Democrats , Prepare For Action</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The action of the Democratic County Convention last week was all that was
						wanting to make up the issue for the approaching election. Both parties have
						nominated their tickets, and the preliminary arrangements are being made for
						a campaign which is to be short, sharp and decisive. Already the Radicals
						are moving. Their County Committee has been devising ways and means-their
						Grand Army of the Republic has been holding its secret conclaves-their
						runners are out trying to stir up the sluggish-their organ is hurling its
						stereotyped epithets. All the "surface indications" disclose an intention on
						the part of the leaders to exert themselves with unusual activity. Their
						candidates are fired with rather unwonted energy. There seems to be an
						apprehension in their minds that to achieve a victory at the coming
						election, will require all their best efforts. They evidently see that the
						masses of their party are sluggish. They know that our honest,
						straightforward white laborers are not in sympathy with their project to
						enfranchise the negro in Pennsylvania.</p>
					<p>They know that our plain, upright farmers are not overjoyed at the
						unparalleled extravagance which meets them everywhere. They know that the
						taxpayers do not exult over the large amounts scored opposite their names in
						the shape of grievous taxation. They know that the query is beginning to run
						from mouth to mouth, what is all this for? How long must we appropriate our
						hard earnings to feed the negro in the South and to support swarms of
						useless officers of the Freedman's Bureau? And they know that the answer to
						those questions is not calculated to increase their chances of success.</p>
					<p>On the other hand, never were the Democrats in higher spirits, and never did
						they have better reason to be so. There is not a fundamental principle put
						forth by the party, with which they have not always been in sympathy. Every
						plank in its platform is hewn from the Constitution of the United States. To
						a Democrat love for the Constitution is natural. He takes it into his system
						with the first breath of life that is breathed into him, and he never needs
						any other stimulant to political action. He always judges of every political
						principle by its provisions, and refuses his support to it, unless convinced
						that it is in accordance with them. His highest political aim is to maintain
						that system of government which guarantees to the citizen "life, liberty,
						and the pursuit of happiness.' That system he finds embodied in the
						Constitution of the United States. To it, therefore, he gives his unchanging
						fealty.</p>
					<p>Up Democrats, then, and arm yourselves for the contest. The Radicals have
						"repudiated" your Constitution. They have been "acting outside of it"-they
						are acting outside of it now-they intend to act outside of it hereafter.
						They ignore it altogether. They seek to substitute the might of the
						conqueror for the written law. Gird up your loins for the fight. Determine
						to win. Fire the heart of your neighbor with enthusiasm. Induce him to read.
						Read to him yourself. Shew him the hypocrisy of Radical professions
						heretofore, warn him of the imminent danger to free government.</p>
					<p>Your candidates are worthy-they are honest and capable. Discuss their
						qualifications as contrasted with their opponents. Try the sincerity of
						Radical boasts of love for the men who have hazarded their lives for the
						Union. Be active, vigilant persevering. "Quit yourselves like men," and
						victory will be ours</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>With the election only weeks away, Republicans are moving feverishly ahead
					to rally the party's rank-and-file members. Their diligence is required, the
					editors avow, because they know that "honest, straightfoward white laborers are
					not in sympathy with their project to enfranchise the negro in Pennsylvania." By
					contrast, the Democrats "have never been in higher spirits."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>The Pacific Railway</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A group of congressmen recently completed a survey of the work thus far
					completed on the Union Pacific Railway and have offered a laudatory report that
					highlights the railroad's importance to the nation's future economic
					development.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>Proclamations By The President</head>
				<origin>Washington</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Proclamation of Amnesty.</p>
					<p>WASHINGTON, Sept. 8-The following pardon proclamation, although prepared
						yesterday, was not issued until this afternoon:</p>
					<p>By the President of the united States:</p>
					<p>
						<emph rend="italic">A Proclamation.</emph>
					</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, in the month of July, Anno Domini 1861,
						the two houses of Congress with extraordinary unanimity, solemnity declared
						"that the war then existing was not waged on the part of the government in
						any spirit of oppression, nor for any purpose of conquest or subjugation,
						nor purpose of overthrowing or interfering with the rights or established
						institutions of the States, but to defend and maintain the supremacy of the
						Constitution, and to preserve the Union, with all the dignity, equality, and
						rights of the several States unimpaired, and that as soon as these objects
						should be accomplished the war ought to cease; and, </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, The President of the United States, on
						the 8th day of December, Anno Domini 1863, and on the 26th day of March,
						Anno Domini 1864, did with the objects of suppressing the then existing
						rebellion, of inducing all persons to return to their loyalty, and of
						restoring the authority of the United States, issue proclamations, offering
						amnesty and pardon to all persons who had directly or indirectly
						participated in the then existing rebellion, except as in those
						proclamations was specified and reserved; and </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, The President of the United States did,
						on the twenty-ninth day of May, Anno Domini, 1865, issue a further
						proclamation with the same objects before mentioned, and with the same
						objects before mentioned, and to the end that the authority of the
						government of the United States might be restored, and that peace, order,
						and freedom might be established; and the President did by the said last
						mentioned proclamation proclaim and declare that he thereby granted to all
						persons who had directly or indirectly participated in the then existing
						rebellion, except as therein excepted, amnesty and pardon, with restoration
						of all rights of property, except as ofo slaves, and except in certain cases
						where legal proceedings had been instituted, but upon condition that such
						persons should take and subscribe an oath therein prescribed, which oath
						should be registered for permanent preservation; and, </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, In and by the said last mentioned
						proclamation of the twenty-ninth day of May, Anno Domini 1865, fourteen
						extensive classes of persons therein specially described were altogether
						excepted and excluded from the benefits thereof; and </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, The President of the United Sates did,
						on the second day of April, Anno Domini 1866, issue a proclamation declaring
						that the insurrection was at an end, and was thenceforth to be so regarded;
						and </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, There now exists no organized armed
						resistance of misguided citizens or others, to the authority of the United
						States, in the States of Georgia, South Carolina, Virginia, North Carolina,
						Tennessee, Alabama, Louisiana, Arkansas, Mississippi, Florida and Texas, and
						the laws can be sustained and enforced therein, by the proper civil
						authority, State or Federal, and the people of said States, are well and
						loyally disposed, and have confirmed, or if permitted to do so, will conform
						in their legislation to the condition of affairs growing out of the
						amendment to the Constitution of the United States prohibiting slavery
						within the limits and jurisdiction for the United States; and, </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, There no longer exists any reasonable
						ground to apprehend within the States, which were involved in the late
						rebellion, any renewal thereof, or any unlawful resistance by the people of
						said States, to the Constitution and laws of the United States; and </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, Large-standing armies, military
						occupation, martial law, military tribunals, and the suspension of the
						privilege of the writ of <emph rend="italic">habeas corpus</emph> and the
						right of trial by jury, are in time of peace dangerous to the public
						liberty, incompatible with the individual rights of the citizens, contrary
						to the genius and spirit of our free institutions, and exhaustive of the
						national resources, and ought not therefore to be sanctioned or allowed
						except in cases of actual necessity for repelling invasion or suppressing
						insurrection or rebellion; and, </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, A retaliatory or vindictive policy,
						attended by unnecessary disqualifications, pains, penalties, confiscations
						and disfranchisements now, as always, could onlp tend to hinder
						reconciliation among the people and national restoration among the people
						and national restoration, while it must seriously embarrass, obstruct and
						repress popular energies, and national industry and enterprise; and </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas </emph>, For these reasons it is now deemed
						essential to the public welfare, and to the more perfect restoration of
						constitutional law and order, that the said last mentioned proclamation so
						aforesaid, issued on the twenty-ninth day of May, Anno Domini 1865, should
						be modified, and that the full and beneficient pardon conceded thereby
						should be opened and further extended to a large number of the persons who
						by its aforesaid exceptions have been hitherto excluded from Executive
						clemency. </p>
					<p>Now, therefore, be it known that I, Andrew Johnson, President of the United
						States, do hereby proclaim and declare that the full pardon described in the
						said proclamation of the 20th of May, Anno Domini 1865, shall henceforth be
						opened and extended to all persons who directly or indirectly participated
						in the late rebellion with the restoration of all privileges, immunities,
						and rights of property, except as in cases of legal proceedings under the
						laws of the United States, but upon this condition, nevertheless, that every
						such person who shall seek to avail himself of this proclamation, shall take
						and subscribe the following oath, and shall cause the same to be registered
						for permanent preservation, ion the same manner and with the same effect as
						with the oath prescribed in the said proclamation of the 29th day of May,
						1865, namely:</p>
					<p>"I,-------, do solemnly swear (or affirm), in the presence of Almighty God,
						that I will henceforth faithfully support, protect, and defend the
						Constitution of the United States, and the Union of the States thereunder,
						and that I will, in like manner, abide by and faithfully support all laws
						and proclamations which have been made, during the late rebellion, with
						reference to the emancipation of slaves. So help me God,"</p>
					<p>The following persons, and no others, are excluded from the benefits of this
						proclamation, and of the said proclamation of the 20th day of May, 1865,
						namely:</p>
					<p>First-The chief or pretended chief executive officers including the
						President, the Vice-President, and all heads of departments of the pretended
						Confederate or rebel government, and all who were agents thereof in foreign
						States and countries; and all who held or pretended to hold, in the service
						of the said pretended Confederate government, a military rank or title above
						the grade of brigadier general, or naval rank or title above that of
						captain; and all who were or pretended to be "Governors of States" while
						maintaining, abetting, or submitting to, and acquiescing the rebellion.</p>
					<p>Second-All persons who in any way treated otherwise than as lawful prisoners
						of war persons who in any capacity were employed or engaged in the military
						or naval service of the United States.</p>
					<p>Third-All persons who at the time they may seek to obtain the benefits of
						this proclamation, are actually in civil, military, or naval confinement or
						custody, or legally held to bail either before or after conviction, and all
						persons who were engaged directly or indirectly in the assassination of the
						late President of the United States, or in any plot or conspiracy in any
						manner therewith connected.</p>
					<p>In testimony whereof, I have signed these presents with my hand, and have
						caused the seal of the United States to be thereunto affixed.</p>
					<p>[L. S.] Done at the City of Washington, the 7th day of September, 1867,</p>
					<p>By the president ANDREW JOHNSON</p>
					<p>WILLIAM H. SEWARD, Secretary of State.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Provides a copy of President Johnson's Proclamation of Amnesty, issued
					Sept. 9th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.09.11.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--The County Committee</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hamsher</ln>
						<fn>B. Y.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brewer</ln>
						<fn>George W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duncan</ln>
						<fn>C. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wunderlich</ln>
						<fn>D. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shillito</ln>
						<fn>J. Newton</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Breckenridge</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duffield</ln>
						<fn>Pharez</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hafer</ln>
						<fn>Abraham</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hunter</ln>
						<fn>W. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McKinistry</ln>
						<fn>William D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Goetz</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Johnston</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Small</ln>
						<fn>E. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bitner</ln>
						<fn>Simon</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Keyser</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stitzel</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hammond</ln>
						<fn>Martin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bear</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Blair</ln>
						<fn>William H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nimmon</ln>
						<fn>J. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Lindsay</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stake</ln>
						<fn>Daniel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Jarrett</ln>
						<fn>John H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sellers</ln>
						<fn>John A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gilbert</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lists the men selected to serve on the Democratic County Committee for the
					ensuing year. The men are requested to meet at C. M. Duncan's office on Sept.
					14th to organize the upcoming campaign.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Farm Sold</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Tritle</ln>
						<fn>Daniel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Singer</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On August 30th, Daniel Tritle sold his 105 acres farm near Mt. Hope to
					David Singer for $120 per acre.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Property Sold</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hutz</ln>
						<fn>H. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Huber</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that H. H. Hutz sold his house and lot on Main St. to John Huber,
					of Letterkenny township, for $7,000.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Balloon Ascension</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Light</ln>
						<fn>John A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that John A. Light made his sixth ascent in a hot-air balloon on
					Sept. 19th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Base Ball</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>On Sept. 7th, the "Printers," of Chambersburg, defeated the "Snowballs," of
					Shippensburg, in a game of baseball. The Printers won by a score of 21 to 16.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Narrow Escape</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Dick</ln>
						<fn>Samson</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Berger</ln>
						<fn>Lawrence</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Samson Dick almost suffered a fatal accident on Sept. 7th when his pants
					got caught in the tumbling shaft of the threshing machine at Lawrence Berger's
					farm, in Hamilton. Luckily, Dick managed to avoid injury when his pants tore
					"competely off, and wound around the shaft, leaving him standing in a state of
					nudity."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Sudden Death</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Rhodes</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>John Rhodes, "a well-known and respected resident," died suddenly on Sept.
					9th. The night before his death, Rhodes attended church where he lapsed into a
					coughing fit "which brought on hemmorhage of the lungs and terminated his life
					in a few minutes."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Great Flood</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Greenawalt</ln>
						<fn>S. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wanamaker</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Forbes</ln>
						<fn>Wilson</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The heaviest rain in recent memory caused considerable damage in town on
					Sept. 6th. The storm pushed the Conococheague to an unprecedented height,
					flooding low grounds along the creek bed. The editors praise William Wanamaker,
					S. F. Greenawalt, and Wilson Forbes for their "benevolent enterprise,"
					evacuating residents from the hardest hit areas, particularly the black enclave
					of Wolffstown.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="l">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Letter of Declination</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer>Samuel Fisher</trailer>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Fisher</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Contains a letter from Samuel Fisher requesting that, due to prior business
					engagements, his name be withdrawn from consideration as a possible candidate
					for Treasurer.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--New Enterprise</head>
				<origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Frick</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Informs readers that Messrs. Geiser, Price, &amp; Co. have purchased
					George Frick's machine shop in Waynesboro where they will begin construction on
					a foundry and additional iron, wood, and paint shops. The men paid $11,500. It
					is expected that the new enterprise will employ between two and three hundred
					workers.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Passed Through</head>
				<origin>Fulton Democrat</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Chambersburg Silver Cornet Band passed through Fulton on its way to
					Antietam where it will participate in dedicatory ceremonies on Sept. 17th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Arrest Of Escaped Prisoners</head>
				<origin>Somerset Democrat</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Williams</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On August 21st, several prisoners escaped from a prison in Moundville, W.
					Va., near Wheeling, including John Williams, formerly of Chambersburg. Williams,
					who was convicted of murder, was re-captured several days later at Samuel
					Dickey's residence in Middlecreek township. Dickey is awaiting the arrival of
					the prison authorities to take him back to Moundville.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Oaks</ln>
						<fn>D. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Carlile</ln>
						<fn>S. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Carlile</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Carlile</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Sept. 3rd, D. B. Oaks and S. A. Carlile were married at the house of
					Thomas Carlile by Rev. William Carlile.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>Lewis</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Remley</ln>
						<fn>Sarah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Dickson</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On August 22nd, Lewis Miller, of Washington county, Maryland, and Sarah
					Remley were married by Rev. J. Dickson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>On Sept. 3rd, John A. Noll and Maggie Honoble were married by Rev. J.
					Dickson at the residence of William McCleery.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Snyder</ln>
						<fn>Henry B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Walk</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Walk</ln>
						<fn>Charlotte A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Dickson</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Sept. 5th, Henry B. Snyder, of Lancaster county, and Charlotte A.,
					daughter of Samuel Walk, were married by Rev. J. Dickson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Saum</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>George</ln>
						<fn>Anna</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Davis</ln>
						<fn>P. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On August 27th, John Saum and Anna George were married by Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stair</ln>
						<fn>Mary E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Davis</ln>
						<fn>P. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Sept.7th, William Stumbaugh and Mary E. Stair were married by Rev. P. S.
					Davis.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Little</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Keefer</ln>
						<fn>Hannah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kennedy</ln>
						<fn>James F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Sept. 5th, Samuel Little and Hannah M. Keefer were married by Rev. James
					F. Kennedy.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Reifsneider</ln>
						<fn>Enos P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Elm</ln>
						<fn>Rebecca J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>S. H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Sept. 5th, Enos P. Reifsneider and Rebecca J. Elm were married by Rev.
					S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Mahon</ln>
						<fn>Thaddeus M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Robinson</ln>
						<fn>Mattie M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>S. H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Sept. 8th, Thaddeus M. Mahon and Mattie M. Robinson were married by Rev.
					S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stenger</ln>
						<fn>Bessie C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stenger</ln>
						<fn>William S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stenger</ln>
						<fn>Helen M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Sept. 6th, Bessie C., child of William S. and Helen M. Stenger, died of
					"Cholera Infantum." Bessie was 6 months old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.09.11.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
