<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.10.16">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-10-16">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="10"/>
            <day norm="00">16</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.10.16.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.10.16.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Own Triumph</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We extend our heartiest congratulations to the Democracy of Franklin county.
                        We have achieved a glorious victory. We have substituted a Democratic
                        majority of 189 for last years Radical majority of 19. We have elected our
                        whole county ticket, every man leading the vote for Judge Sharswood. The
                        majorities range from 189 to 337. Our opponents held meetings in every
                        school district in the county. The expended large sums of money. Their
                        orators delivered speeches filled with the foulest abuse of the Democratic
                        party. Some of them coined and circulated the basest slanders. They
                        misrepresented the past record of our grand old organization. They misstated
                        our present position. They attempted to frighten the people as to our future
                        designs. But all would not avail. The masses knew by the jingle of their
                        coin that it was counterfeit. They rejected it as spurious, and refused to
                        assist in circulating it. All glory to the conservative people of this
                        county! You have done nobly. You have assisted in placing "the old Keystone"
                        by the side of Connecticut, Kentucky, Maryland and California, in the battle
                        for the preservation of the Union. The voice of Pennsylvania has mingled in
                        harmony with the voices of these sister States and have swelled the grand
                        diapason [UNCLEAR] of victory which is rolling in sublimity from the St.
                        Lawrence to the far off Pacific shores.</p>
                    <p>For many years, Franklin county has been under the thralldom of
                        Republicanism. It is refreshing therefore to hear her speak, and speak in
                        such emphatic tones, in favor of conservatism. There are but two Democratic
                        districts in the county which have faltered in the good work to any extent.
                        Letterkenny and Guilford--both townships in which we should have made
                        considerable gains--show reduced majorities as compared with the vote of
                        last year. There may be local causes for this. We do not know. At any rate,
                        we are not inclined to find fault since the result is so gratifying. We hope
                        they will strive to emulate the example of our other Democratic Districts
                        and do better in the future.</p>
                    <p>As all the others have done so well, it may be unjust to mention any. But we
                        cannot help complimenting the Democracy of Hamilton upon their gallant
                        fight, and rejoicing with them over their signal victory. From 45 they have
                        increased their majority to 81. Quincy too, has done well. Our opponents
                        poured out their money there like water. And yet our returns exhibit an
                        increased majority. In Greenvillage, Waynesboro, Montgomery, Peters, and
                        this Borough--the Radical strongholds--we have made immense gains. In the
                        North Ward of this Borough, the aggregate vote polled is larger by seven
                        than the vote of last year and yet the Radical majority is diminished by 31
                        votes. This demonstrates the fact conclusively that our triumph was not
                        entirely owing to <emph rend="italic">apathy </emph> in the Republican
                        party, but that men who have heretofore acted with that organization broke
                        loose from it, and identified themselves with the great party which is
                        destined to control the government of this country. We extend a thrice
                        hearty welcome to all such. By their prompt action in the hour of need, they
                        have helped to save the liberties and preserve the dignity of the republic,
                        and to assert the superiority of the proud race to which we belong. Franklin
                        county has taken a decided position in favor of Constitutional government.
                        Long may the Democratic flag wave in triumph over the "old Green spot!" </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors celebrate the Democratic victory in the late election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Result in Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have already published in our columns and in our extra slips, the
                        gratifying intelligence that victory has crowned the efforts of the
                        Democracy in our State. Pennsylvania has thundered her denunciations of the
                        Radical Congress. She has arrayed herself on the side of the Constitution.
                        She has spoken in favor of the union of the States. She has expressed her
                        condemnation of the doctrine of "taxation without representation/" She has
                        turned her huge battering ram against the military despotisms which have
                        been erected in the South upon the ruins of the civil government. She has
                        scouted the idea that the Southern States are nothing but conquered
                        territories, only entitled to the rights which the victor may see fit to
                        extend to the vanquished. She has declared against the mischievous
                        legislation of Congress, which has thrown a thousand obstacles in the way of
                        the restoration of the rebel States to the Union. She has spurned the
                        doctrine of negro-suffrage and negro equality. Although the issue was not
                        presented directly, and although ingenious arguments were used to deceive
                        the people and persuade them that the Radical leaders meditated no such
                        extension of the right of suffrage, yet the intelligent masses have refused
                        to be hood-winked any longer. They have recognized the importance of taking
                        action in time, and they have acted. They said to the angry passions of the
                        Radicals, "peace, be still." They have spoken to the wild fanaticism which
                        has been sweeping over the land, "thus far shalt thou go, and no
                        farther--here shall thy proud waves be stayed." They have declared that it
                        is time to stifle bitter enmities, to quench the unnatural thirst for
                        vengeance, and to proffer the hand of friendship to submissive and penitent
                        rebels. It is high time that a better feeling should prevail between the
                        North and the South. Private business interests, as well as national
                        prosperity demand it.--The sooner we leave behind us the bloody scenes of
                        the late war, the better for us as a nation. Heart-burnings there will be
                        always Americans of the present generation. We can not expect men to efface
                        entirely from their memories the reconciliation of terrible sufferings which
                        they have endured and grievous wrongs which they have borne. But we can ask
                        them to cease from adding fuel to the flame of passion--to refrain from
                        appeals to the animosity and cupidity of the masses, and to strive to bring
                        back the old days of peace and happiness to our country. We have no doubt
                        but that moderation on the part of Democrats will mark this triumph. Our
                        opponents, have never respected our feelings in the hour of their victory.
                        They have stigmatized us as Copperheads. They have hooted at us upon the
                        streets as traitors. They have chuckled with inordinate glee, over our
                        defeats, wondering "how the infernal traitors relished the news." We trust
                        there is no disposition to retort in this way. Let the Democracy be
                        satisfied with their victories and refrain from indulging in language
                        calculated to insult and enrage their opponents. Of course the Radicals have
                        every sore heads. We are not expected to heal them. An overwhelming sorrow
                        has overtaken them. We can not assuage their grief. We can not administer
                        any comfort. We see no hope for them in the future.--They have been weighed
                        in the balances and found wanting. Their days are numbered. Their peans of
                        victory are changed into the wailings of defeat. They are of those "who
                        sorrow without hope." Let them throw their fortunes with the Democratic
                        party hereafter, and in the ranks labor for the country's good.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the wake of the Republicans' defeat, the article reports that
                    Pennsylvania "has thundered her denunciation of the Radical Congress" and
                    "spurned the doctrine of negro suffrage and negro equality."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Victory In Ohio</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the "thrilling news" that the Democrats were victorious in the
                    recent election in Ohio. According to the editors, the Radicals' recent string
                    of poor results can be attributed to a single issue: their stand on black
                    suffrage</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Radical Sensitiveness.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some of our Radical orators were terribly exercised at the SPIRIT for harping
                        upon the negro question so persistently during the canvass. They thought it
                        was very undignified--that we ought to elevate our standard, of taste. We
                        feel sorry that we have hurt their feelings. We would not, for the world,
                        violate their sense of propriety. But we submit that it is the "galled jade
                        that winces." And we are inclined to think that they were sensitive on this
                        subject for the reason that the negro was their weak point. Now, our aim is
                        to discuss the topics which are most interesting to the public--to endeavor
                        to throw light upon the questions which the masses are agitating among
                        themselves. In this campaign, the negro question was predominant. In
                        dwelling upon it particularly, we dwelt upon the absorbing topic of the day.
                        The people have endorsed us. They have declared their sympathy with our
                        sentiments on this subject, as shown by the result in our own county.--Our
                        Radical friends will, therefore, please remember that while we would not
                        intentionally give them pain. we will, nevertheless, take the liberty of
                        discussing such subjects as we prefer to discuss, and of treating them in
                        whatever manner we choose, whether it is in accordance with their ideas of
                        propriety or not. This being an independent journal, we intend to be the
                        sole judges as to how its columns shall be filled. But, if it will be any
                        comfort to those whose sense of propriety is shocked by the discussion of
                        the negro's qualifications for equality of political and social rights with
                        the with man, we promise to quit writing about him just as soon as they take
                        him out of politics.--We bear no ill-will to the black man. We are ready to
                        do him a favor, or to extend the hand of charity to him whenever he needs
                        it. we claim for him the same protection as to his rights of life, liberty
                        and property as is given to the white man. The negro is not to be treated as
                        a brute. The recent verdict of the people is not to be so interpreted. <emph
                            rend="italic">But there is an earnest determination on the part of the
                            whites of the North, that the exclusive franchise is not to be extended
                            to the negro--that the right of suffrage remain the exclusive privilege
                            of the white man.</emph> This is the verdict which the freemen of
                        Pennsylvania and Ohio have rendered at the ballot box.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors dismiss the criticism lodged by local Radicals that they
                    focused an inordinate amount of coverage to the issue of black suffrage.
                    According to the editors' rationale, the Democrats' resounding victory justified
                    their emphasis on the highly controversial topic and proves that they have
                    nothing to be apologize for.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>In Trouble</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors "revel in supreme felicity" that the tables have been turned
                    and it is now the Radicals who have come up short at election time. Throughout
                    the country, they note, Republicans are now scrambling to account for their
                    string of defeats in the recent elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Bridges</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the Valley Spirit.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. Editors:--Under the above caption an article appeared in your issue
                        of last week. It is a hopeful sign when any subject, either moral,
                        political, or municipal, is of sufficient importance to elicit agitation or
                        discussion. It is gratifying to any true son of Chambersburg that you
                        introduced into your columns a subject so interesting to many citizens. And
                        we agree in the main that it would be rashness and folly needlessly to
                        increase the burden of taxes upon our suffering people for useless purposes.
                        Our Town Fathers have displayed a commendable zeal in building brid es and
                        opening avenues for wealthy corporation, and the tax-payers have not
                        complained, trusting to their discretion although we can not see the wisdom
                        of some of these measures. They may, however, ultimately prove a benefit.
                        And while we thus accept their action in developing almost untenantable
                        districts. we urge upon the notice of the council a beautiful, necessary and
                        permanent improvement to Chambersburg--the construction of an iron bridge
                        over the Couocoelleague creek at Queen street, and the opening of the street
                        to its terminus. This improvement will be an ornament to the town, a
                        convenience to its citizens, and add to the advancement and prosperity of
                        the place. I agree with the writer that it would be follies; yea, madness to
                        bridge the Spring and increase of burdens for no practical purpose nor
                        benefit. The crossing of the Spring at King street is narrow, solid and very
                        shallow, with no impediment except a few logs therein, to divide the water.
                        This obstacle might easily be obviated by filling, with fine stone, on each
                        side of the legs, at small expense, which would make the crossing easy and
                        durable. Besides such a bridge independent of its usefulness, would be a
                        serious obstacle to the use of the Spring for other purposes. But the
                        proposed improvement at Queen street will not materially increase our taxes.
                        The increase of valuation, and of taxable property will soon pay the cost of
                        construction.</p>
                    <p>I conceive that R is it is not wisdom do circumscribe the limits of the town,
                        and drive its laboring population to more thrifty and prosperous localities.
                        True, our community has debt; but it is wisdom to give our population labor
                        to help pay that debt. Make Chambersburg by labor and skill what she is by
                        nature--one of the most beautiful towns in the state, watered by noble
                        streams, skirted by majestic mountains, surrounded by highly cultivated
                        land--the Queen of the Cumberland Valley. Make her the the home and delight
                        of her sons, the workshop of her laborers, the residence of the citizen, and
                        the desire of the stranger. We cannot retain our families in a cheerless
                        town when cities are growing at magic rate in western wilds with not a tithe
                        of our advantages. We cannot retain the poor and deny them bread; we can not
                        invite the man of taste and culture hither, and manifest no spirit for the
                        useful and beautiful.</p>
                    <p>JUSTICE.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Justice</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Justice" agrees with an editorial in last week's edition of the Spirit,
                    decrying the initiative to bridge the spring at King St. as sheer "folly."
                    Justice does, however, offer an alternative proposal: he advocates constructing
                    an iron brigde over the Conococheague Creek at Queen St. This project would "be
                    an ornament to the town, a convenience to its citizens, and add advancement and
                    prosperity of the place."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.10.16.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Numbering The Streets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Town Council has completed the "very sensible" work of numbering the
                    doors on Front St. To obtain correct numbers, readers are advised to contact
                    John A. Seiders, Secretary of the Council.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Negro Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece sarcastically notes the appearance last Friday of a company of
                    black troops on the streets of Chambersburg. Apparently, the soldiers had
                    returned from a celebration in Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--School For The Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKeehan</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that a free school for poor white girls and women will open on
                    Oct. 21st. in Jennie McKeehan's school room. Classes will be held three evenings
                    a week during the winter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Rejoicing In Waynesboro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Waynesboro on Oct. 14th, the Democrats and Conservatives of Washington
                    township held a rally in honor of the recent election victories. Included in the
                    festivities were a torch-lit procession and addresses given by F. M. Kimmell and
                    George W. Brewer, both of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Escape Of A Prisoner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Joseph Worthington, alias Joseph Wise, escaped from
                    Chambersburg's jail last Thursday night. In March, Worthington was convicted of
                    larceny in Washington county, Maryland. Upon his release from the penitentiary
                    last September, he was charged in connection with the theft of a carpet from the
                    German Reformed Church in Franklin county. The case was pending when he took
                    flight. His whereabouts are unknown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Official Returns</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frank</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mower</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imbris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shenafield</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the official election results for Franklin county, including the
                    individual tallies for each district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Political Proscription</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several workmen employed at the Mont Alton Iron Works were reportedly fired
                    because they voted for the Democratic ticket in the recent election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hampsher</ln>
                        <fn>Amos C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 10th, Amos C. Hampsher and Mary E. Seiders were married by Rev. J.
                    Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoup</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 10th, John C. Snider and Hannah Shoup were married Rev. P. S.
                    Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keiner</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sponsler</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 8th, Michael Keiner and Amanda C. Sponsler were married by Rev. W.
                    E. Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Feldman</ln>
                        <fn>Emma L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 13th, John Smith and Emma L. Feldman were married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.10.16.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
