<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.08.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/25</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-08-07">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="00">07</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="1" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.08.07.1">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.08.07.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Tennessee Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the wake of Gov. Bronlow's re-election in Tennessee, the editor asserts
                    that his victory was secured through "fraud and force."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Mongrel Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Virginia Republican Convention was marred by strife between the two
                    competing factions within the state party. According to the article, Hunicutt,
                    the leader of the minority faction, enlisted the support of blacks to help
                    disrupt the proceedings once it became apparent that his opponents would control
                    the convention. Apparently, Hunicutt's "tactics" proved successful.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Trip For General Grant</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With rumors swirling that the Republicans will nominate Gen. Grant as their
                    presidential candidate, the article declares that, since "there is nothing in
                    his character or his antecedents which can recommnend him to the Republicans,"
                    their sole motivation for such a move is "to remove the danger of his nomination
                    by the Democrats."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Firing Over The Grave Of Liberty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Had the vast majority of white men in Tennessee not been illegally
                    disfranchised, Etheridge, the Democratic candidate, would have won the recent
                    election for governor by a margin of over 80,000 votes, avers the article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary>"We find in the National Intelligencer the following article which
                    should be read by every business man in the country. The Radical Convention
                    endorsed the action of Congress, and what Congress has done for the business
                    interests of the people is thus pointedly and plainly stated by the
                    Intelligencer:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The great depression of business throughout the country is the subject of
                        much remark. It is not confined to any one section or to any one branch of
                        industry. Commerce, navigation, shipbuilding, and manufactures of all kinds
                        are almost at a standstill, and jobbers and retailers of goods are not
                        better off. We published a statement in yesterday's paper showing the great
                        decline in the manufacturing business in New England. The cotton, woolen,
                        leather and shoe trade are all declining. Colleries and Iron foundries in
                        Pennsylvania have stopped work as well as the Eastern cotton mills. In the
                        South, as is well known, there prevails an utter stagnation of business.
                        There is no commerce and no money for the South. Cotton is very low-nearly
                        one-half lower for some grades than the price of last January-and the
                        growing crops will not be remunerative to the planter, though it will be
                        smaller by one seventh than the crop of last year.</p>
                    <p>When we inquire into the causes of the depression of trade we will find that
                        political uncertainty is the most active and influential of any that can be
                        named. Congress has seen fit to quarrel with the President in regard to
                        Southern reconstruction, and has sought to keep the South out of the Union
                        until it could be admitted without danger to the continuance of the Radical
                        party in power. Congress endeavors to perpetuate disunion until its
                        usurpations of the whole power of the government shall be confirmed and
                        upheld. That is, Congress says; We will retain our two-thirds' power, and
                        will not admit the excluded Southern States until they embrace our policy,
                        and send Radical men to Congress to unite with us in support of Radical
                        measures. There is no prospect before the country but that of disunion,
                        anarchy, profligate and corrupt appropriations of public money, the final
                        obliteration of State governments, and the establishment of a great central
                        despotism.</p>
                    <p>The North has much capital yet, and much enterprise, both of which would be
                        employed in the South, to the advantage of both sections, if Congress would
                        give us peace and restoration of the Union. This is necessary to give the
                        country confidence in the future. Trade will not revive while the Radical
                        rule prevails. That is a business and political fact. That a fair crop of
                        grain will put starvation from our doors is very true; but it will not be
                        sufficient of itself to set in motion the capital, labor and industries of
                        the country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece decries the current state of the American economy and ascribes
                    blame for the predicament to the "political uncertainty" induced by Radical
                    rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
                <commentary>"In a late number of Lynchburg Virginian, we find the following:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At a cost of $60,000 a month, the government is feeding 28,000 freedmen and
                    women who have encamped between Williamsburg and Hampton, says the article.
                    Allegedly, the ex-slaves have refused all entreaties to find employment in the
                    region and have also rebuffed an offer made by General Armstrong, of the
                    Freedmen's Bureau, to re-settle in Florida. "Radicalism," the piece expounds,
                    "is a dear experiment, taxing the patience and the pockets of the people to a
                    degree unprecedented in the history of any country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.08.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Degrees Conferred</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Higbee</ln>
                        <fn>E. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that Prof. E. E. Higbee, of Mercersburg, received a Doctorate of
                    Divinity and Col. D. Watson Rowe, of Greencastle, was awarded an honorary degree
                    of Masters of Arts at the commencement ceremonies of Franklin and Marshall
                    College.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Good Templars' Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The quarterly meeting of the Cumberland Valley Good Templars Convention
                    will meet in Mercersburg on August 14th. Delegates from lodges in Cumberland,
                    Franklin, and Fulton counties are expected to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Maria Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 30th, Benjamin Shatzer and Maria Ann Miller were married by Rev. P.
                    S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiffer</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etchberger</ln>
                        <fn>Annie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 12th, John F. Peiffer and Annie M. Etchberger were married by Rev.
                    J. A. Kunkelman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 6th, John W. Rodgers and Amanda Brown were married by Rev. J. A.
                    Kunkelman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 30th, George Kyner, 90, died in Southhampton township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 25th, the infant son of Joseph Martin died at 3 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Eve</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 27th and 28th, Adam and Eve, son and daughter of Rev. Isaac Shank,
                    died at a 3 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mosser</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 16th, Catherine Mosser, 44, died near Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Werdebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 19th, Charles W. Werdebaugh, 3, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laidig</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 5th, David Laidig, formerly of Franklin county, died in Fulton
                    county at age 66. Laidig was a respected member of the Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.08.07.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
