<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.11.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/12</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-11-06">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="11"/>
            <day norm="00">06</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.06.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Seven Years of Radicalism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It was just seven years yesterday since Abraham Lincoln was elected President
                        of the United States. Although a Western man himself, with a possible
                        inclination to conservatism, his accession to the Presidential chair put the
                        government completely under the control of the fanatical Radicals of New
                        England. These authors of the Kansas troubles and patrons of the John Brown
                        raid into Virginia had made up their mind to revolutionize the government,
                        and in Abraham Lincoln they found an instrument adapted to their purpose. As
                        first as his dull intellect was able to comprehend their designs, he fell in
                        with them and used all his official power to crush the Constitution, under
                        whose <emph rend="italic">forms</emph> he had been elevated to the Chief
                        Magistracy, against the will of a large majority of the people. War came
                        because the Radicals wanted it, and lasted four years because the Radicals
                        were unwilling to end it in two. It required <emph rend="italic">time
                        </emph>, even under the demoralizing influences of a gigantic civil war, to
                        bring the people to look with complacency upon the destruction of a
                        government which they had so long been accustomed to regard as "the best
                        ever devised by the wisdom of man." New England ideas prevailed at last, and
                        at the end of these eventful seven years we find ourselves with a dissevered
                        Union, a subverted Constitution, and an altered form of government. </p>
                    <p>This is what seven years of Radicalism have ended in, but this is not all
                        that Radicalism has cost us. We have paid out over four thousand million
                        dollars in money, at least one-half of which went as stealing to shouting
                        "patriots." We have sacrificed hundreds of thousands of lives, dotted the
                        country over with mutilated human beings, and with helpless widows and
                        children. Property to an immense extent has been destroyed, and the
                        productive industry of the country has sustained injuries which fifty ears
                        cannot repair. From a lightly taxed people we have become the heaviest taxed
                        in the world. All that we eat and all that we wear--all that we produce and
                        all that we consume--is taxed. From the swaddling clothes of the new-born
                        babe down to the last nail in the coffin's lid everything is taxed to pay
                        the cost of these seven years of Radicalism. The picture of the last seven
                        years is dark, but a gleam of sunshine has been thrown upon us at last. This
                        fall's elections show that the public mind is awakening to the enormities of
                        Radical misrule. Honest, fair-minded and well-disposed Republicans are
                        beginning to see through the schemes of the New England revolutionists. The
                        candid admission of Thaddeus Stevens that the Rump Congress has been acting
                        outside of the Constitution, and that he and his associates want no reunion
                        that does not bring negro equality with it, has given them a new view of
                        public affairs. Their eyes will be still further opened during the
                        approaching session of Congress, and thee is reason to hope that the
                        elections of next year will seal the doom of Radicalism and rescue our
                        government from the evil control of the malignant fanatics of New
                    England.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the editors, Republican rule has had a devastating effect on
                    the country. They have burdened the American public with bloody conflict,
                    rampant corruption, and costly taxes. But now, the editors say, it appears as
                    though the "doom" cast by Radical rule is approaching an end.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Money</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Money is so abundant in England, according to the London <emph rend="italic"
                            >Star</emph>, that it goes begging for borrowers at 1 and 1 1/2 per
                        cent. interest, per annum! Its superabundance has an unfavorable effect on
                        trade. People who live on the interest of their money are compelled to
                        economize to an extent never before heard of, because, at the reduced rate
                        of interest, their income is cut down almost to nothing. </p>
                    <p>In the United States, on the other hand, notwithstanding the amount of paper
                        issued by the government and the National Banks, there is a great complaint
                        of scarcity of money, and the prevailing rates of interest are from 6 to 10
                        per cent., with many transactions at even higher figures.</p>
                    <p>The plethora of cash capital in England and the scarcity of it in this
                        country are owing in a great measure to the reconstruction policy of the
                        Radicals. The war cut off shipments of cotton to England, our best customer,
                        and we were obliged to send our gold and silver there in payment of our
                        purchases. The drain has gone on without interruption for seven years, and
                        we have not yet reached the end of it. If the Radicals had promptly restored
                        the Union after the surrender of Lee and Johnston, and allowed the Southern
                        people to sit down again quietly under their own vine and fig tree, with
                        none to molest them, we should ere this have drawn four or five hundred
                        million dollars of English capital here to buy our cotton. This transfer
                        would have relieved the English money market of its superabundance of cash
                        and kept the rate of interest up to it usual point. It would also have
                        averted the stringency in the money market of this country, and prevented
                        the rate of interest here from rising to the ruinous height of 10 and 12
                        percent.</p>
                    <p>Thus the Radical policy is working injury to business, both at home and
                        abroad. The only persons benefited by it are plundering officers of the
                        Freedmen's bureau and low politicians like Brownlow and Hunnicutt</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors attribute the current economic problems in England and the U.
                    S. to the Republicans' "disastrous" economic policies. Of particular concern for
                    the editors is the failure to revive cotton production, which, they say, could
                    have alleviated most of the difficulties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Negro Supremacy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In elections throughout the South, voters have come out in favor of holding
                    constitutional conventions, but, contend the editors, blacks constituted the
                    vast majority of those who cast ballots. Thus, the editors claim, the "effect of
                    the election is that the negro has not only been made the equal of the white
                    man, but has become his lord and master."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Centenary Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the centenary celebration of the Presbyterian congregation
                    of Upper Path Valley will be held on Nov. 19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Richard Woods, Sr., suffered a serious injury last Saturday when the front
                    axle of the buggy he rented from Samuel Brandt broke, throwing him from the
                    vehicle. He is expected to recover.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Admitted To Bar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that Joseph McClure was admitted to the bar on Oct. 31st. A
                    celebration was held after his exam at the Mr. Gelwicks's restaurant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Substantial Regards For A Pastor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 29th, Josiah McDowell's will was admitted to probate. McDowell left
                    a 200 acres farm to Rev. Thomas Creigh and made a woman in Mercersburg a "tenant
                    for life" in one of his houses. Additionally, the will makes Creigh the executor
                    of his personal estate and invests him with the power to designate the proceeds
                    from it as he sees fit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Phonographic Reporter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that William H. Duffield was named the phonographic reporter for
                    the Court of Common Pleas in Franklin county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneider</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that William Ackerman arrived in town on Oct. 30th in the custody
                    of Officer Michael W. Houser. Ackerman and his brother, Peter, were charged with
                    conspiracy to defraud Peter Schneider of $1,500. William fled before he could be
                    arraigned, but was arrested in Illinois and extradited from there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Henry Rohrer, 60, died suddenly near Pleasant Hall last Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bricker</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kean</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Simon P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallach</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Solander</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kalp</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swartle</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Carson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Verdier</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pink</ln>
                        <fn>Pendleton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fendricks</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Obed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dietrick</ln>
                        <fn>Melchior</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Isaiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayhew</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heider</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Noah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kean</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stull</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Ann C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hovis</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skipp</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hisey</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Langheine</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Godfrey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forthman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speelman</ln>
                        <fn>Melchior</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morton</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hernlaben</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A listings of the criminal cases tried and otherwise disposed of. "Com. vs.
                    Mary Hays and Bettie Johnson. Charge assault and battery. Defendants pleaded
                    guilty and were sentenced to pay costs. Com. vs. Margaret Bricker. Assault and
                    Battery. Catherine E. McKee, Prosecutrix. A true bill. Defednat pleaded not
                    guilty. Verdict not guilty--costs equally divided between Prosecutrix and
                    Defendant. Com. vs. Dr. John E. McKee. Assault and battery. A true bill.
                    Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict guilty. Sentenced to pay a fine of five
                    dollars and costs of prosecution. Com. vs. Jesse Kean. Charge of larceny of
                    pocket book containing $130 form J. McDowell Sharpe, Esq. A true bill. Defendant
                    pleaded not guilty. Verdict not guilty. Com. vs. Simon P. West. Assault and
                    battery with intent to ravish a little girl, 12 years of age, the daughter of
                    Jeremiah Ashway, Prosecutor. A true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict
                    not guilty. Defendant to pay half of the costs and the Prosecutor the balance.
                    Com. vs. Joseph Wallach. Surety of the Peace. Case dismissed--Costs equally
                    divided between the parties. Cases Settled--Com. vs. James B. Smith, Com. vs.
                    John Solander, Com. vs. Henry X. Stoner, Com. vs. John Kalp, Com. vs. Benjamin
                    Rhodes, Com. vs. Aaron Swartle, Com. vs. Carson McFerren and Jackson Shank, Com.
                    vs. Eliza Thompson, Com. vs. William H. Verdier, Com. vs. Relsher and others,
                    Com. vs. Pendleton Pink. Bills Ignored--Com. vs. Philip Fendricks, Com. vs. John
                    Etter and George W. Bowers, Com. vs. John Powell, Com. vs. Obed Gsell, Com. vs.
                    Susan Howard, Com. vs. Melchor Deitrick, Com. vs. Leonard Cauffman and Isaiah
                    Cauffman. There were several true bills found by the Grand Jury which were
                    continued to January term. There are others found which the Defendants have not
                    been arrested. Civil Causes tried--Sarah Mayhew vs. Ephraim S. Shank. Summons
                    case in assumpeit. This was an action brought by the Plaintiff, Sarah Mayhew,
                    for money claimed to be due her for services tendered the Defendant in the
                    capacity of a servant. Verdict for the Plaintiff for $54.87. Miller &amp;
                    Helks vs. Jacob Lesher. This was an appeal by Defendant from the judgement of
                    Justice P. Hamman. The Plaintiffs claimed $85 for a clover-huller sold by them
                    through their agent, David Heidler, to the Defendant. The defence was that the
                    huller was sold to Defendant on condition that he was to keep it in case it
                    worked well--that it did not work well, and that notice of the fact was given to
                    Plaintiff's agent. Upon proof of these facts, the plaintiff's attorneys "threw
                    up the sponge" and took a non-suit. Daniel Hawbecker, Administrator of Noah
                    Myers, dec'd, vs. Frederick Foreman. This was an appeal by Defendant from the
                    judgment of justice John A. Hyssong--The claim of Plaintiff was for $98.68 for
                    hogs sold to Defendant at the sale of the property of Noah Myers, dec'd. The
                    defendant claimed to have paid the claim in full. Verdict for the Plaintiff for
                    $98.68. Jesse Kean, Administrator of James W. Palmer, dec'd, vs. Daniel Palmer.
                    This was an action to recover $475, which Plaintiff alleged that the Defendant
                    had received from the Bounty Fund Committee, of Southhampton township, as the
                    local bounty of Plaintiff's intestate, James W. Palmer--The Defendant admitted
                    the receipt of the money but pleaded payment. Verdict for Defendant. C. C. Stull
                    vs. Andrew S. Monn, and Daniel Bricker. This was an action to recover damages.
                    The plaintiff hitched his horse and buggy in front Jones' Hotel in Quincy.
                    Deft's took it in the absence of the Plaintiff, and went out riding. The horse
                    ran off and broke the buggy to pieces, he being injured also. The case
                    progressed part of the way, but was not concluded, being continued at the costs
                    of the Defendants, on account of their filing additional special matter. Ann C.
                    Funk and James Hovis vs. David Miller adn William F. Horner. Summons in
                    trespass. Defendants confessed judgment for $30 and costs. James Shipp vs. Jacob
                    Hisey. Appeal from judgment for John Kauffman, Esq., Justice of the Peace.
                    Defendant confessed judgment for $20 and costs. The following licenses have been
                    granted at the present term of the Court; Dr. H. Langheine, Wine Store.
                    Chambersburg, N. W.: George Rodgers, Restaurant, Chambersburg, N. W.: Godfrey
                    Greenawalt, Restaurant, Chambersburg, S. W.; Michael Miller, Ale House,
                    Chambersburg, S. W.; George Forthman, Ale House, Waynesboro; Melchior Speelman,
                    Restaurant, Waynesboro. The petition of David Harper for license to keep a
                    Restaurant in Greencastle was withdrawn. The Court refused to grant licenses to
                    Maria Morton, Greencastle; James Snyder, Mercersburg, and Catharine Hernlaben,
                    S. W., Chambersburg."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zollinger</ln>
                        <fn>F. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rigner</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 24th, F. L. Zollinger, of Strasburg, and Sarah P. Rigner were
                    married by Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtzworth</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsey</ln>
                        <fn>Evaline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 29th, William D. Holtzworth, Register and Recorder of Adams County,
                    to Evaline Lindsey, oldest daughter of John Lindsey, were married by Rev. W.
                    Howe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moulder</ln>
                        <fn>Wilmer</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Clarinda A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 30th, Wilmer Moulder and Clarinda A. Harrison were married by Rev.
                    William West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dilp</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 28th, Philip Kramer and Catharine Dilp were married by Rev. G.
                    Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Martin V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, Martin V. West and Sophia Yost were married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 23rd, Ann, wife of Solomon Crouse, died at age 39.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 1st, Samuel Shafer, 65, died near St. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.06.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
