<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.02.15">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/18/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-02-15">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="00">15</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.15.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Conscription Laws</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Sir, on behalf of the Freemen of this Commonwealth, who have always given
                    a cheerful and hearty support to your Government in the prosecution of this war,
                    -- it is my duty to insist, -- and I do insist -- that you enforce upon your
                    subordinates that obedience to the law, which you owe, as well as they and all
                    of us."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. G. Curtin</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a letter to Abraham Lincoln, Pennsylvania's Governor Curtin criticizes
                    the President's administration for miscalculating the draft quotas for each
                    congressional district. Specifically points out that government officials
                    violated the most recent Enrollment Act by not taking into account the numbers
                    of years already served by men in each district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Previously published county financial reports, columns 1-4, classified ads,
                column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Although the conference failed in bringing about a termination of the
                    present deplorable war, or in initiating any movement calculated to bring about
                    the most desirable result, yet we feel confident that these documents will be
                    read with greater interest than any matter which might occupy the same space."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that transcripts of the messages of Presidents Lincoln and Davis
                    in response to the recent peace conference are published elsewhere on this page.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>(No Title)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It will cost Massachusetts and her 'hub' many a pang now that they will
                    have to fall back upon their own raw material, but as they yet have the
                    comforting assurance of a surplus credit of about 8,000 'black loyalists'
                    fortunately secured on Sherman's raid before this embargo was laid."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the U.S. Senate on Monday Mr. Buckalew's amendment, striking out the third
                        section of the enrollment law of last winter--which permits recruiting
                        agents to visit Southern States to obtain recruits for State credit--was
                        adopted by a vote of 28 yeas to 12 nays--9 of the nays being cast by New
                        England Senators. Both Massachusetts Senators--Wilson and Sumner--opposed
                        the amendment. The reason for this opposition, says the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Patriot &amp; Union</emph>, is not hard to understand by those who
                        know that Massachusetts has, during the past year, been doing most of her
                        fighting on a German and negro basis.</p>
                    <p>During the discussion it was stated, by Mr. Saulsbury, that immediately on
                        the fall of Savannah, Massachusetts had her agents on hand, without
                        authority, to fill her quotas; that after the slaves had been put on
                        shipboard Gov. Andrew made application to the President for permission to
                        enlist them and it had been granted. Mr. Wilson "did not know anything about
                        it; Gov. Andrew was an earnest, determined man, and would enlist loyal black
                        men; and that if Massachusetts agents got there first it showed that they
                        traveled faster than other agents."</p>
                    <p>It will cost Massachusetts and her "hub" many a pang now that they will have
                        to fall back upon their own raw material; but as they yet have the
                        comforting assurance of a surplus credit of about 8,000 "black loyalists"
                        fortunately secured on Sherman's raid before this embargo was laid. What the
                        "hub" will do for the future emergencies, is hard to say. Perhaps it may
                        determine to import a few cargoes of John Chinamen; or, better yet, to ship
                        a few cargoes of the surplus old maids to California and Oregon, as
                        recommended by the Governor, and, by a sharp arrangement of exchange, get
                        able-bodied male recruits for them. This would be quite up to the usual
                        style of Massachusetts financiering, and the world would not be in the least
                        astonished to hear of its successful accomplishment. The wonder is that it
                        has not already been attempted.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the US Senate voted to prohibit Northern recruiting agents
                    from going South to enroll soldiers. Points out that Massachusetts members have
                    been supportive of taking recruitment South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Why Shoddy Wants to Abolish Slavery</head>
                <origin>Patriot &amp; Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Shoddy leaders care nothing for the abolition of slavery as a measure of
                    philanthropy, but everything for it as a political measure."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Let every Democrat in the land keep this fact steadily in view: That the
                        Shoddy leaders care nothing for the abolition of slavery as a measure of
                            <emph rend="italic">philanthropy</emph>, but everything for it as a
                            <emph rend="italic">political</emph> measure. All their fine blather
                        about "universal freedom," the "rights of man," the "barbarism of slavery,"
                        &amp;c., is but the thin varnish over a magnificent political scheme by
                        which they hope to destroy the Democratic party, and retain control of the
                        reins and patronage of the Government. Now and then the confession slips out
                        of one of their too-well greased organs. For instance: The shoddy postal
                        organ of Thursday, in a howl about the failure of the ratification
                        resolution in the State Senate, for want of a quorum, says:</p>
                    <p>"It only delays the triumph, which is to rid the land of slavery And Thus
                            <emph rend="italic">save the Government for all time, from the
                            pollutions of modern</emph> Democracy."</p>
                    <p>Is anything more needed to convince any Democrat of the despicable designs of
                        the shoddy politicians? Through this "triumph" (i.e. the abolition of
                        slavery) "the Government for all time" is "<emph rend="italic">thus</emph>"
                        to be saved from the "pollutions" of "Democracy." The Negro is not to be
                        benefitted--oh no! The "rights of man" are not to be thought of, if the man
                        is a "Nigger." Only the "rights" of the Shoddy "man" to govern, speculate
                        and plunder the Government are to be considered. The all important object in
                        the destruction of slavery is, therefore, the destruction of the Democratic
                        party and the elevation of Shoddy.</p>
                    <p>We long ago said, and repeatedly, that the crusade carried on against slavery
                        was really to destroy democracy. The war has been conducted, for the past
                        four years, not against the Southern people as <emph rend="italic"
                        >rebels</emph> but as <emph rend="italic">Democrats</emph>. The shoddy
                        leaders feared to restore the Union until after they had destroyed slavery
                        (which, they believed made Democrats of nearly all the Southern people.)
                        After they have destroyed Democracy, then, and not till then, will a single
                        shoddy leader consent to a re-union of the States. They are not patriots;
                        they are not "loyalists;" they are demagogues and cormorants. They care
                        nothing for the negro--nothing for their country. Self, self, self--is their
                        stole animating principle. Time will most fully expose their schemes of
                        ambition and cupidity.--<emph rend="italic">Patriot &amp;
                    Union</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Republican supporters of abolition of caring "nothing for the
                    negro."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Democracy must, indeed, be diminished in numbers and influence, or
                    these sad results would not exist. Under Democratic rule we had peace,
                    confidence and plenty. We see what we have now."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that diminishing numbers of Democrats only prove that Republicans
                    should be blamed for "the calamities of the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Tuesday evening, the Senate resolutions ratifying the amendment to the
                    Constitution abolishing slavery, came up in the House for final action. The
                    discussion was opened on the Republican side by the reading of some three or
                    four long and prosy essays on the evils of slavery, the last, and longest, and
                    dullest of which was read by a youthful looking member from Crawford, whose
                    appearance, manner, and matter indicated that he had but recently been
                    discharged from the sophomore class of some western college."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Resolution of Thanks to Governor Curtin--Discussion on the Constitutional
                        Amendment--The River Bed Bill.</p>
                    <p>Correspondence of the Valley Spirit.</p>
                    <p>Harrisburg, Feb. 11, 1865.</p>
                    <p>Both Houses of the Legislature re-assembled on Monday evening at 7 1/2
                        o'clock. The session was consumed in going through with the regular order of
                        business. Quite a number of bills were read in place, none of which,
                        however, are of any general importance. A resolution was introduced and
                        passed in the House, tendering the thanks of the House and the people of the
                        State to Governor Curtin for his letter to President Lincoln, and for the
                        correct position taken in that letter in defence of the citizens of
                        Pennsylvania. This resolution was permitted by the Republican members to
                        pass, not, however, without some very wry faces on their side of the House.
                        When the vote was taken the Democrats unanimously voted "aye," whilst the
                        Republicans, with the exception of a few faint "noes," refused to vote at
                        all, thus showing that they were ready to "lick the hand that smites them,"
                        but lacked the moral courage to make an open issue with the Governor of
                        their own choosing.</p>
                    <p>On Tuesday evening, the Senate resolutions ratifying the amendment to the
                        Constitution abolishing slavery, came up in the House for final action. The
                        discussion was opened on the Republican side by the reading of some three or
                        four long and prosy essays on the evils of slavery, the last, and longest,
                        and dullest of which was read by a youthful looking member from Crawford,
                        whose appearance, manner, and matter indicated that he had but recently been
                        discharged from the sophomore class of some western college. The young man
                        had about two quires of closely written pages of foolscap before him, which
                        he read to a wearied and "bored" audience in true sophomoric style, but
                        evidently to his own infinite satisfaction. After the herculean task was
                        ended, he wiped the profuse perspiration from his brow and smiled most
                        graciously upon the audience, looking as well pleased with himself as a
                        young bride during the first week of her honey-moon. The debate was
                        continued on the Democratic side by Messrs. Hakes and Boyer in able and
                        forcible speeches against the amendment. The resolutions were passed by a
                        strict party vote. Mr. Sharpe was not present to participate in the
                        discussion, (having been unavoidably detained on account of sickness in his
                        family), but asked leave the next day to have his remarks published in the
                            <emph rend="italic">Legislative Record</emph>, which was granted.</p>
                    <p>The house on Thursday and Friday was mostly occupied in considering bills on
                        the public calender [sic]. The bill which excited the most interest and
                        elicited the most discussion was that in relation to the river beds in the
                        oil region. The discussion on this bill was at times quite animated and
                        exciting. It was defended by Messrs: Searight, McClure, McAfee, Pancoast and
                        Allen, and opposed by Messrs. Burgwin, Sharpe, Cochran (Erie), Cochran
                        (Phila.), Wells, Waddell, Satterthwait, Thonas [sic] and Markley, Mr.
                        Cochran (Phila.) moved to refer the bill to the Committee on Ways and Means,
                        which was carried by a vote of 47 yeas to 43 nays. It will probably pass
                        eventually. Both Houses have adjourned over from Friday to Monday evening at
                        the usual hour,--7 1/2 o'clock,--and most of the members have gone home.</p>
                    <p>The weather is very cold, snow a foot deep and sleighing excellent.</p>
                    <p>Brutus.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Brutus</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reviews the recent proceedings of the Pennsylvania legislature, including
                    the passage of a resolution thanking the Pennsylvania Governor for lodging a
                    complaint to Abraham Lincoln about draft quotas. Also notes that both houses
                    passed resolutions favoring a constitutional amendment to abolish slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Peace Conference: Message of the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They [Confederate leaders] seemed to desire a postponement of that
                    question [reunion] and the adoption of some other course first, which as some of
                    them seemed to argue, might or might not lead to reunion, but which course we
                    thought would amount to an indefinite postponement."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a transcript of President Lincoln's message to the US House of
                    Representatives about the recent peace conference. The message consists mainly
                    of excerpts of dispatches between Lincoln, his assistants, and the Davis
                    administration, as well as Lincoln's description of why the discussions came to
                    an impasse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Southern Account of the Peace Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The enemy refused to enter into negotiations with the Confederate States,
                    or any one of them separately, or to give to our people any other terms or
                    guarantees than those which a conqueror may grant, or to permit us to have peace
                    on any other basis than our unconditional submission to their rule."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Publishes transcript of Confederate President Davis' message to the
                    Confederate Congress about the attempt at peace. In his remarks, Davis accuses
                    the US government of refusing to negotiate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Peace</head>
                <origin>Daily Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that too much blood has already spilled to expect that the North and
                    South will reach a peace easily. Suggests that the only options for peace are a
                    recognition of Southern independence or the "annihilation of the Southern
                    armies."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Presidents' messages cover columns 2-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.15.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Escaped</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"God grant them a speedy and safe arrival among their friends."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. Porter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that a letter from a Chambersburg citizen currently imprisoned in the
                    South reports that three of his companions, J. Porter Brown, Thomas McDowell,
                    and George Kauffman, recently escaped from prison at Salisbury and are making
                    their way toward the Union lines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Important to Everybody</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that beginning February 1, 1865, all citizens executing receipts
                    for the delivery of any property must attach a two cent stamp to such receipts.
                    Anyone who fails to comply will be fined $22, as stipulated in state law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Singing School</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Robert A. McClure will start a singing class for "ladies and
                    gentlemen" next Thursday evening in the lecture room of the Lutheran church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerby</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. Dickson married George W. Kerby, of Baltimore county, Maryland, and
                    Mary C. Moore on February 5 at the residence of the bride's father.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whetstone</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarret</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 2, Rev. A. M. Whetstone married John Jarret and Nancy
                    Burkholder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>F. W.</fn>
                        <sf>D.D.</sf>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunting</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 13, Rev. F. W. Conrad, D.D., married Cornelius Hunting, of
                    Freeport, Illinois, and Mary Mull, eldest daughter of John Mull, Esq.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>Kate E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Amos Knepper and Kate E. Lowry were married by Rev. S. McHenry on February
                    2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Byers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Byers Wingert and Anna M. Shively were married on February 9 at Brown's
                    Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCullough</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 9 at Brown's Hotel, Eli McCullough and Rebecca Potter were
                    married.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ault</ln>
                        <fn>Amelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel J. Aughinbaugh and Amelia Ault were married on February 5 by Rev. J.
                    M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zann</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. M. Snyder married Simon Glass and Sarah P. Zann on February 9 at the
                    residence of the bride's father.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 9, Rev. W. E. Krebs married Jacob M. Barr and Mary Shockey at
                    Bowden's Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dietrick</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Dietrick died on February 4 at age 63 years, 9 months and 4 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strealy</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred Herman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strealy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strealy</ln>
                        <fn>Ann C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alfred Herman Strealy died on January 27 at age 6 years, 3 months and 20
                    days. He was the son of Jacob C. and Ann C. Strealy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metz</ln>
                        <fn>Lilly Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metz</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lilly Elizabeth Metz, daughter of John and Barbara Metz, died on February 6
                    at age 8 months and 6 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layman</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rebecca Jane Layman died on January 30 at age 17 years, 4 months and 13
                    days. She was the daughter of William and Catharine Layman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Dispatches reporting on troop movement in Virginia, column 1, reports from
                Congress, column 2, classified ads, columns 3-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.15.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
