<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.09.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/11/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-09-06">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="00">9</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.09.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Speech of Hon. George H. Pendleton at the Ohio State Convention.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a transcript of George H. Pendleton's speech at the Democratic
                    State Convention in Ohio. The address calls for national reconciliation and
                    touches upon the party's customary issues -- a return to civil law, freedom of
                    the press, and state's rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>South Carolina: Another Speech of Governor Perry--Interview with the President
                    and the Members of his Cabinet--Their Opinions on Affairs in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article includes a copy of an address delivered by Gov. Perry, of South
                    Carolina, following his return from Washington City. Perry states that he left
                    his home state as a member of a delegation whose goal was to impress upon the
                    President South Carolina's desire to be appointed a Provisional Governor, a
                    position Perry learned he had been named to while en route to the capital. While
                    there, Perry and the delegation met with President Johnson and several cabinet
                    members, including the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury.
                    According to Perry, the delegation's effort to convince Johnson of South
                    Carolina's commitment to transform itself from the "most rebellious State in the
                    South" to "the most loyal of the Southern States" was largely successful.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Southern View</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Ledger</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Southern States may recover their loss of political power, but it
                    would be in possession of people who have no longer the same interest to
                    subserve the slave owner."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p> A dispatch unit from Raliegh, North Carolina, gives the substance of a
                        letter which it is said Gen. Kilpatrick, who is now traveling through the
                        state has written one of its prominent citizens, in which he expresses his
                        opinon that reconstruction there as well as in the remainder of the South,
                        has been commenced at least four years too soon.- He is represented as
                        stating it as his belief that the majority of people of that section are not
                        to be trusted, and will, as soon as the recover their lost political power,
                        commence a persecution of all Union men as well as the negroes, endeavor to
                        re-enslave the latter, and in conjuction with the North attempt to secure a
                        repudiation of the national debt, and ultimately make another desperate
                        effort to effect their separation from the Union. <emph rend="italic"
                            >-Exchange Paper</emph></p>
                    <p>If General Kilpatrick ever said anything like this, it shows that a good
                        soldier may be a very bad political prophet. The South <emph rend="italic"
                            >has</emph> made its "most desperate effort to effect separation" and
                        failed. The extent of its disaster to itself would be an effectual argument
                        against any renewed effort of the kind, even if the changes it will produce
                        socially and otherwise, would not be additional securities for peace. A man
                        who predicts similar results must imagine similar causes to exist. But with
                        every step now towards restoration politcally, and reorganization is
                        socially introduced new and different elements into Southern society, which
                        will tend to make the population, North and South, homogenous in character,
                        with interests and social interactions nearly identical. Slavery gone, a new
                        system of labor, the white element, which has given such strength to the
                        social fabric of the Northern States and so largely introduced which will
                        not only change the whole structure of the Southern society, but will
                        exercise an influence changes its necessities effect. The Southern States
                        may recover their loss of political power, but it would be in possession of
                        people who have won no longer the same interest to subserve as the
                        aristocratic slave owner. </p>
                    <p>The power of the latter being gone, he will not be able to persecute the
                        Union men, for they will consititute the majority, and will have things very
                        much to their own liking. The idea that the broken down aristocracy can
                        restore slavery after the social convulsion which the war of rebellion has
                        produced, is preposterous. It will have enough to do to take care of itself
                        and will be compelled of necessity to rely upon its own labor for its own
                        maintenance. The power which made the national debt to preserve the national
                        rights, the people who preferred temporary pecualary burdens to political
                        ruin and national destruction, will be jealous hereafter against any
                        political combinations which threatens to transfer their power and control
                        to the hands of faction. General Kilpatrick, we think, may dismiss his
                        fears, and leave the Southern States to resume practical relations with the
                        Government upon plan recommmended by President Johnson, as the nost eligble
                        means of restoring the country to harmony, and repairing all the future
                        benefits that change, circumstances and conditions promised. -<emph
                            rend="italic">Philadelphia Ledger (Republican) 22nd</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article disputes a variety of claims made by Gen. Kilpatrick in a
                    letter reportedly circulating in North Carolina. Dispatches from the state
                    contend that the contents of the general's communication indicate his
                    apprehension about the future of reconstruction in the South, which he feels
                    should be put off for another four years because of the continued dominance of
                    the region's antebellum leadership.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.09.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Election--The Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> At the head of our columns will be found the names of the gentleman who have
                        been chosen by the Democratic Covention, State and County, as our standard
                        bearers in the contest to be decided on the 2d Tuesday of October next. All
                        political contest in this county are of immenese importance to its people.
                        From the very commencement of our government aprinciple has been at work in
                        conflict with the spirits and intent of its framers. This principle has had,
                        at differnt periods, many advocates, banded together under various party
                        names seeking to obatain control of the governement, with the intent
                        gradually to absord the liberties of the people and to change our free
                        Constitutional Repoublic- in fact in not in form, - into a "strong
                        government", a "parental government", a centralized government at the city
                        of Washington, to which the Startes must be made to yield to reserved rights
                        not delegated at the formation of the Constitution. Against the party
                        advocating this principle- which is nothing more or less than old
                        fedralkism- the Democracy have, until within a few years, contended
                        successfully, and have kept its adherents out of power, except in a few
                        instances of too short a duration ib which to effect their purposes. In
                        1860, owing to discord, and division in the Democratic ranks, this old
                        federal party, under the name of Republicanism, suceeded in obtaining full
                        and complete control of the machinery of the national governement.- What
                        result of its rule has been is apparent ot every one. Disdaining anything
                        looking to a comprimise with, or conciliating a discontented or rebellious
                        prople in the sotuhern Statesm some of those high in power fostered their
                        discontent and encoraged thier rebellious spirit, untilm the country was
                        plunged into civil war, the paralell which is not to be founf in the history
                        of the world. During the progress of the was for the suppression of
                        rebellion, and the restoration of the rightful authority of the Union oveer
                        the seceded States, this party steadily aimed to divert it from its
                        legitimate and rightful purpose to a crusade for the aboliton of African
                        slavery, and the subjugation of the Stat4es in rebellion, while at the same
                        time, they were usurping the rights and the liberties of the people at the
                        North, as well as infringing on the sovereignity of the States, until they
                        have in fact; rendered them nothin more than Provinces or "Departments" of
                        the grand central despotism at Washington. Now that the war is over, we find
                        this same party organizing opposition to the wise and magnanimous
                        restoration policy of an execcutive whom they assisted to elect, but who it
                        seems has very little "federal blood in his veins". Thier views in regard to
                        the Sothern States differ materially from thsoe that have become "educated
                        up" to conferring the right of the suffrage on the negro "freedmen". If they
                        are successful in this, and their colored brethren have the right of
                        suffrage confreed upon them, they confidently expect a long lease of power,
                        during which they may be enabled to usurp powers enough to retain
                        governmental control by <emph rend="italic">force</emph>, if not by popular
                        favor. If then elections heretofore have been so important in their results,
                        how much more so must prove those of the immediate future. On one hand we
                        have a party rallying in favor of negro suffrage in the South, by and though
                        which they expect to retain political power and degrade the government
                        formed by Washington, Jefferson, Franklin and other partiots into a black
                        republic. On the other is the old Democratic party, heartily sustaining the
                        President in his effort to restore "our erring sisters" to equal rights with
                        their Nothern sisters; and maintaining intact the great WHITE REPUBLIC
                        established by the men of '76. The <emph rend="italic">great</emph> issue
                        claiming the attention of the people just now is, in few words, whether
                        white men are to continue to rule, or whether the miserable African race
                        shall be accorded a share in the government of white people. </p>
                    <p>In the view of the importance therefore of the pending contest, our
                        convention have put forward candidates worthy of the great issues involved,
                        and of the party of the white people. In our last issue, we gave a
                        biographical sketch of our State candiates Colonels DAVIS and LINTON. They
                        are both brave and gallant men who have served thier country in her hour of
                        need well and faithfully. They bear upon their bodies scars recieved in
                        battle with the foes of the Union, and with maimed limbs they have returned
                        to their homes to recieve we hope a reward to the esteem and gratitude of
                        their fellow citizens. They are men of honor, integrity and ability,
                        possessing in an eminent degree those elements of character which should
                        commend them to the heart support of all who desire faithful and competent
                        officials. As solidiers, there were none braver in the field, as men and
                        citizens, there are none more honest and deserving, and as candiates, none
                        that should or will, recieve a more hearty support from the great names of
                        the Democratic party.</p>
                    <p>The County and District tickets are composed of men well known to the
                        people.- To them we can point with feelings of pride and gratification. From
                        Senator to Coroner, they are exceptional in every respect. The agiatation?
                        which placed there in nomination and their whole days?, presented such a
                        ticket that will command the respect of even their opponents. Although many
                        other good men, were named before - men who had many and ardent personal
                        friends, and who were in every respect deserving, yet some had trouble
                        necessarily be set aside for the time and the others were nominated. The
                        ticket is such that every supporter of the Democratic principles- every
                        lover of truth, honor and integrity, every man who would see the government
                        of oour fathers restored and perpetuated, every one who would see the
                        advocates of negro equality rebuked at the polls-can support with an
                        enthusiam which can have no other result- except for a glorious victory.</p>
                    <p>The candidate for Senator CALVIN M. DUNCAN Esq., is well known throughout the
                        senatorial district. Born and reared in the district, he is throughly
                        conversant with the interests and wants of its people. He has ever been an
                        able consistant and fearless advocate of the Democratic principles. In the
                        dark days which tried men's faith, he never quailed before the threatenings
                        of fanaticism, or fawned at the footstool of power that the thrift night
                        follow. On all proper occasions his voice has been heard in defense of the
                        true principles of Democarcy and the rights of the people. Perhaps no man in
                        the district is better acquainted with the wants, interests and desires of
                        the masses as he and as Senator, his ability and zeal will be made available
                        in care of them. Mr. Duncan is in full sympathy with the people of the
                        border counties who have been despoiled of their property by the public
                        emeny, and if elected - of which we feel assured - will devote his energies
                        and abilities in an earnest endeavor to obtain from the State government
                        indemnification for all losses sustained by our people, by reason of relief
                        invasions and military occupations. If therefore, the sufferers from these
                        causes along the border, desire to have their claims on the State properly
                        and euergetically pressed, they will aid in the election of Mr. Duncan.</p>
                    <p>Of our candidate for Assembly, WM. MCLELLAN, Esq., it would seem almost
                        superfluous that we should say anything in the way of commendation. Every
                        man in the county is well acquainted with his great professional ability,
                        his high character for integrity, his worth as a man and citizen. There is,
                        at the present juncture, no man in the county better qualified to represent
                        the wants, interests and wishes of the citizens of Franklin county in
                        legislature, than Wm. McLellan. He has lived our midst all his life; has
                        seen his friends and his neighbors reduced from affluence to penury, by the
                        torch of rebel incendiaries, and their property carried away by rebel
                        mauraders; he has given of his means and devited his time to affording
                        relief to the sufferers of the terrible conflagaration on the 30th day of
                        July 1864, and his implelling motive in accepting the position on the ticket
                        assigned to him by the convention, was that he might be useful to his fellow
                        citizens in pressing before the legitslature, with all his ability and zeal,
                        their just claims for indemnity. Every man who lost his property from these
                        causes has in Mr. McLellan, a friend whi will faithfully represent his
                        interests.</p>
                    <p>SAMUEL R. BOYD is the nominee for Sheriff. In the convention he had so many
                        estimatiable competitors, and is no small compliment that he gained the
                        prize in a contest where so many were deserving. - We have known Mr. Boyd
                        for a number of years; dating from the time that when we used to meet him in
                        a neighboring village wending his way westward with a load of stoves and
                        tinware, stowed in a wagon drawn by a team of bays. In our intercourse, we
                        find him a clever, socialable gentleman, honest and upright in all his
                        dealings and possessed of business qualifications which cannot fail to
                        enable him to fill the office of the sheriff with credit to himself and
                        satisfaction to the public. His popularity whereever he is known will insure
                        his triumphal election.</p>
                    <p>For Treasurer we have JOESPH M. DOYLE, of Fannet township, a gentleman of
                        excellent character for honesty and integrity, possessing business
                        qualifiactions of the highest order and every way competent to make an
                        efficent Treasurer. Mr. Doyle has for years back, carried on the tanning
                        business extensively in the village of Doylesburg, and is highly esteemed by
                        all who know him. He will lead the ticket considerably in his locality, and
                        we entertain no doubt at the success at the polls.</p>
                    <p>W.S. Stenger Esq., the present incumbent, has been renominated for District
                        Attorney. The ability and zeal by him in the prosecution of offenders
                        against the law during the last three years, has been recognized by his
                        unanimous renomination. Of his ability as a lawyer, his eloquence before the
                        jury and on the stump, hs uniform attention to business, and his courteous
                        manner to all having business in his office, it is unecessary to speak,
                        being universally acknowledged.</p>
                    <p>The choice of the convention for the important officer of Commissioner, was
                        an excellent one. CHRISTIAN D. LESHER, the nominee, is an intelligent farmer
                        of the Antrim township; a practical business man, with all the necessary
                        business qualifications, to make a good trustee of interest of the
                        tax-payer. For many years he has been a farmer and a tax-payer, and such
                        knows the importance of the economy in the expenditure of public money and
                        the necessity for making burdens on people as light as possible. He has been
                        for years, a firm and consistent democrat,and as a man and a citizen without
                        a blemish. He will make an excellent Comissioner, and those desiring such a
                        one should vote for Mr. Lesher, regardless of party ties.</p>
                    <p>Our candidate for Director of the Poor, MR.SAMUEL SECHRIST, of Quincy
                        township, is at present a member of the board. He has by his strict
                        attention to his duties, careful regard for welfare of the unfortunate
                        objects of public charity, obtaining an unanimous renomination without
                        asking for it. We think this one of the strongest evidence of his fitness
                        for the postion, and the propriety of his re-election.</p>
                    <p>For Auditor JOHN A. SELLERS,of St. Thomas, has been nominated. Mr. Sellers is
                        a mechanic, intelligent, upright and an excellent business man. No other
                        person (?) in a greater degree, the confidence and respect of the community
                        in which there is no better than he.</p>
                    <p>HUGH AULD, of Chambersburg, and Dr. W.A. HUNTER, of Straburg(?), the
                        candidates for the County Surveyor and Coroner, are gentlemen of sterling
                        demcracy and unexceptional character. They are both well qualified to fill
                        the respective positions for which they have been named, and are in every
                        respect worthy of the confidence of the people.</p>
                    <p>Such Democrats of Franklin County, is the ticket presented for your support.
                        It is composed of good men and true; men of every respect worthy of your
                        suffrage. It is such a ticket as will call to its support all who would have
                        merit, truth and right succeed at the polls. It represents honor, integrity
                        and ability. Those who help to have these succeed, will give it their ardent
                        support, whilst those who believe in shoddy and negro suffrage, will oppose
                        them. We say then, Democrats to work. Organize in every county: see to it
                        that every man is impressed with the duty with attending the elections and
                        that he is properly assessed. Let every one do his whole duty and such
                        majority for the ticket, will reward your efforts as will forever dismay the
                        advocates of negro suffrage and official profligacy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Christian D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Secrist</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>After a sanctimonious assault on the Republicans, the Spirit endorses the
                    recently selected Democratic slate of candidates for the upcoming election.
                    Colonels Davis and Linton were selected to run for the state house and eight
                    other Democrats were nominated for the county and district ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mercersburg College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Mercersburg classis of the German Reformized Church, has purchased the
                        old Marshall college property at Mercersburg, with the intention of opening
                        a school of the high order in that place. The fine buildings and the five
                        acres of land have been bought at a very low price and will be paid for by
                        shares of stock, a large part of whcih has already been taken by the
                        citizens of this county and of Washington County, Maryland.</p>
                    <p>It might easily be shown that this is a good promising investment, but the
                        prime object of the school is not to make money. The main design is to
                        supply the pressing demand for the facilities of a Christian education all
                        along our borders. The stockholders thus far are those who have children and
                        grandchildren to educate, and feel the necessity of having some safe retreat
                        where this great matter so unavoidable neglected during the war, may be
                        properly attended to. The enterprise, therefore, backed as the saying is, by
                        the substantial old elders and other members of several congregations of
                        different churches, who are urged to do it by themselves, not by any spirit
                        of speculation, but a felt want of of some such help to fit their children
                        and wards by charcters and education, for usefuleness in life.</p>
                    <p>It is the purpose of the board of control; to whose care all the interests of
                        the school are entrusted to secure the services of a corps of the best men
                        they can find- not selected from those who may desire to make the
                        proposition a stepping stone to wealth or worldly preferment, or from such
                        as may happen to be disqualified for the active duties of the other
                        profession, but men who will be satisfied with fixed competent salaries, and
                        who in the fear of God, and for the love of the work, will consecrate all
                        their energies and the responsibilities trust commited to them.</p>
                    <p>The course of study will be well settled, thorough and complete, but above
                        all the mere intellect will not be cultivated to the neglect, and therefore
                        at the expense of the best affections of the heart. It is hoped that the
                        spirit of cheerful, healthy piety will be infused into every educational
                        operation so that the religous element will be the underlying and controling
                        one, or in other words, that the law of the school will be "the law of life
                        and grace as it is in Christ, Jesus our Lord." and not mere pamphlet laws
                        enforced arbitarily from without by an occasional lecture from a
                        grim-visaged monitor.</p>
                    <p>Such a school cannot want patronage.- There are scores and perhaps hundreds
                        of parents within a radius of a hundred miles of Mercersburg, who are
                        anxious to habe just such an institution, and the healthful and quietude,
                        the places and the associations of the past, together with the Christian
                        culture and edcuational advantages offered will attract many students. It is
                        expected that the first session will commence about the last week in
                        September. Rev. E.E.Higbee, Prof. of Theology at Mercersburg, is President
                        of the Executive Commitee.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mercersburg Chassis of the German Reformed Church has purchased the
                    property where the old Marshall College once stood. The religious organization
                    plans to open a school on the grounds to train "men who will be satisfied with
                    fixed competent salaries" and who "will consecrate all their energies to the
                    responsible trust committed to them." The first session is expected to begin in
                    the last week in September.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the details of a speech delivered by the former Postmaster General,
                    Montgomery Blair, in which he blasts several of his former government
                    colleagues. In his address, Blair was particularly critical of Secretaries
                    Stanton and Seward. Others suffering his wrath were Thaddeus Stevens and Jo
                    Holt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Andersonville prison records have mysteriously disappeared. The clerk
                    entrusted with the documents has been placed under arrest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Col. Whittlesey, of the Freedmen's Bureau in Raleigh, has issued a circular
                    informing blacks that the federal government will not provide them with land and
                    that they will have to work for a living.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Outlook and Resolves</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>So far as has been already ascertained the Democratic nominations and the
                        resolutions passed by the Convention meet the cordial and enthusiastic
                        approval of every Democrat. This angers well for the success of the
                        Democratic ticket in October. There seems to be one thought inspiring the
                        membership, and that is a determination to destry the supremacy of that
                        Northern faction of demagogues, which hearing brought disasterous war into
                        the land, has left the Government almost stranded and distrupted. Should the
                        prospect continue equally bright until the day of struggle, all will be
                        well.</p>
                    <p>The democratic candidates are all that any Democrat or any liberal minded
                        conservative could desire. Colonels Davis and Linton, in all private
                        relations, are pure and upright men. As citizens they have always discharged
                        their duties as became men of good and high resolves. Their characters are
                        not only the very best, but they are always above suspicion. As lovers of
                        their country, their war record is all that could be desired. They never
                        deviated from their love for the glorism of the old Union and their devotion
                        to it is now written in scarred and maimed limbs on their bodies.</p>
                    <p>Though the war was conducted by a party antagonistic to his principles to
                        their own, and as true intent of the strife turned from a "War from the
                        Union" to a "War for the African Race". They did not desert the flag, but
                        tried through act and influence to bring the controlling party within the
                        limits of the Constitution. They never deserted the party to which they were
                        allied by principle, but, while on the battle field sacrificing blood and
                        limb against the open and declared sucession enemy of the Union, they were
                        not idle in combatting the Abolition heresies, which secretly and
                        insidiously were destroying the constitution and laws and sapping from the
                        very foundations of the Republic. They knew and declared that Abolitionism
                        was disunion; that the tendencies of ruling policy of the dominant party
                        could end in nothing short of a destroyed Union or a consolidated despotism;
                        and though they cleary saw the even designs of the Abolition party, they
                        resolved first to destroy the armed foe and then direct their undivided
                        efforts against the "sixteen-starred" Northern faction, which has labored
                        for twenty years to destroy the Union.</p>
                    <p>They are now before the people for that purpose. They are prepared to fight
                        gallantly against the black legions of Abolitionism, as they were against
                        the armies of succession. They helped to bring in the rebellion to its end,
                        and now they are in the field to overthrow the negro supremacy, which is
                        laboring to keep alive dissension and to stir up another rebellion at the
                        South.- They are on the tall Union Platform - where they have been prepared
                        to uphold the honor of the Government and the Federal authority in the hands
                        of President Johnson, so long as he shall pursue the work of restoring the
                        Union constitutionally and lawfully; but equally determined to oppose any
                        deviation from that course by the adoption of the disunion dogmas enunicated
                        in the Radical platform of the Pennslyvania Reepublicans.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Patriot and Union casts its support for the Democratic County ticket.
                    The article predicts the election will have serious repercussions for whites,
                    both northern and southern, should the Republicans prevail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Two Parties</head>
                <origin>Raleigh Standard; Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article declares that two parties have sprung up within the
                    government--one conservative, with President Johnson as its head, the other
                    radical, led by Chase and Sumner. The article also criticizes the Radicals for
                    their views regarding black suffrage, a position supported by the Richmond Whig,
                    which asserts that it "is the duty of all good men everywhere to stand by
                    Johnson." The Whig also endorses ratification of the constitutional amendment so
                    that "as a State and a people, we shall be at once out of the woods" with the
                    federal government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Remarks of Wm. McLellan, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"At the close of the labors of the Democratic County Conference, Wm.
                    McLellan, the nominee for the Assembly, being present, was called upon for a
                    speech. He made the following remarks accepting the nomination and giving the
                    persons who induced him to do so. Wm. McLellan said:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Mr. President and Gentlemen of the Convention:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>I feel gratified for the honor conferred and yet it is with reluctuance that
                        I accept the nomination tendered to me. There is but one consideration
                        prompting me to an acception and that is a desire (if elected) to secure
                        some compensation to our citizens for their losses sustained during the
                        terrible rebellion whcih has just been brought to a happy issue. The people
                        of the border have been as it were the break-water of this civil strife, and
                        open them to a great extent have been improved the burthens of this
                        conflict, apart from the weighter consideration of having been despoiled of
                        a large amount of their property. Ought not some compensation made for their
                        losses by a generous Government?- Will not the people of the other sections
                        of this union feel willing to contribute our necessities, since they have
                        already been enirched whilst they be impoverished? We think that the
                        sympathy of every right thinking man must be awakened for that worthy and
                        industrious citizen who has been rendered penniless and almost crucial into
                        the earth, by no act of his own, but by the wicked conduct of relentless
                        foe. The great Creator has implanted in our bosoms feelings and sentiments
                        which ought to be aroused by considerations of this character. But apart
                        from this can we not compensatation as a matter of right? We have furnished
                        the National Government with our quota of our men and means to carry this
                        struggle to be a successful issue, and we are now contributing our share to
                        pay the interest and principal of the debt incurred. Support and protection
                        are the mutual duties of government and governed, and if the government
                        failed or was unable to give us protection in time of need, the duty
                        certainly devolves upon it to compenstate our citizens for any loss
                        sustained by reason of the withdrawl of that protection. The question may be
                        asked, why apply to the State, as the National Government is ultimately
                        responsible for these losses. In answer I would simply say that our
                        relations are more intimate with the State that the National Government, I
                        believe the duty of the protection is incident to both. Every State within
                        the sphere of its action ought to take care of its citizens, and when it
                        fails to do so its constituted authorities incur responsiblity to the
                        citizen. In this case the responsibility may be a secondary one, but if our
                        people were compelled to appeal to Congree for redress, the delay and
                        expense incident to such an effort would be so great as almost to deter them
                        from the attempt, whereas the if the State interpose in our behalf, there
                        will be but little difficulty in her authorities securing restution from the
                        General Government. Besides, our Legislature has, to a certian extent
                        recognized this responsibility by appropriating of 3,000,000 for State
                        defense at the time of the organization of the Pennslyvania Reserve Corps,
                        and a further appropriation of 3,000,000 for the dame object at a subsquent
                        period.</p>
                    <p>In relation to the national issues I must say with candor to the Convention
                        that the reconstruction policy inaugurated by President Johnson meets my
                        hearty approval. - He totally ignores that hydra succcession , which the
                        onset of this war was looked upon by all considerate men as most dangerous
                        innovention ever attempted in the progress of this government. Had it been
                        successfully maintained it would have been rendered our Union most unstable,
                        liable to be severed by the merest whim of caprice. We should have witnessed
                        the States, like comets flying off in unknown paths, and not(as intended by
                        the founders of our government) revolving like the planets round a great
                        center of attraction, and kept in position by mutual affinities.- The
                        President takes hold of the Southern States where rebellion found them, and
                        recognizes their State governments as then existing, with single restriction
                        imposed that before again they become partipants in the bebefits of the
                        Union, they abolish human slavery.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contains a transcript of William McLellan's speech at the Democratic County
                    Convention. McLellan discussed the issues that will form the core of the party's
                    platform in the upcoming election, including compensation for farmers from the
                    state's border region, black suffrage, and President Johnson's Recontruction
                    policies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Treasury Department is printing compound interest bearing notes. Ten
                    million have already been produced and another forty million were recently
                    ordered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rebukes Republicans for reportedly defeating all proposals to provide
                    relief for people living on the state's border. The article castigates
                    Republicans in Franklin county for trying to solicit votes on that issue, having
                    only recently changed their position after voting two years straight against
                    such a provision.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Our Platform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the resolutions adopted by the Democratic State Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.09.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Democratic County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sensony</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCrory</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goots</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbet</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coon</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sowers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Liun</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckinridge</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKim</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>D. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmon</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>North</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinstry</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the men were appointed to serve on the county's Democratic Executive
                    Committee in the ensuing year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--The Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At the last session of the state legislature, the minimum age for admission
                    to school was raised to six from five, as had been the case. The brief piece
                    supports the change "as a good one" since the state's schools were "never
                    intended to be used as public nurseries for the reception and care of infants."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Robbed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. J. Bowers, a traveling dry-goods dealer, was robbed of his carpet bag in
                    McConnelsburg on August 28th. Mr. Bowers's sack contained between $300 and $400.
                    Thus far, there are no clues in the case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal</head>
                <origin>Maysville (Ky.) Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a satiric letter written by an imaginary black politician ten
                    years in the future. The letter details his position on the political issues of
                    the day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>White Trash</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"White trash is at a discount."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Redpath, of John Brown fame, has written a long letter extolling the
                        negro and instituting comparisons to the disadvantage of the white man. It
                        is not easy to discover the wit of this herculean endeavor, though his
                        object is apparent in the effort made to demonstrate the superior claims of
                        the colored citizen African 'scent, so far as concerns the exercise of
                        political rights by the two classes respectively. In support of his
                        position, he quotes from a letter from the superintendent of the home for
                        refugees in Nashville, showing by exact figures, that the precentage of
                        black population dependent on rations is comparatively small- only "about
                        .036-telling badly for whites." And then as to the inferiority of the Irish
                        element, subjected to the same comparison he says:</p>
                    <p>I promised you some statistics comparing the blacks and the Irish. I am told
                        the Irish population of the city is about 3,000. The population therefore is
                        one to three of the blacks. Now, more than sixty percent of the city poor
                        are Irish; and taking the comparative number relieved, we have six Irish to
                        one negro, or as a disproportion against the Irish as eighteen to one
                        eighteen Irish paupers to one negro pauper. Truly it may be said, as one
                        friend remarked to me a few years ago, 'Better let the blacks take care of
                        themselves and put some one to hiring out and providing for the whites.'</p>
                    <p>White trash is at a discount.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on a letter written by Mr. Redpath, an associate of the late John
                    Brown, praising the achievements of the freedmen. Using figures provided by the
                    superintendent of the home for refugees at Nashville, he asserts that blacks,
                    collectively, are less reliant on government aid than the Irish.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.06.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
