<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.02.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/18/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-02-22">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="00">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Louisville Journal</head>
                <origin>Louisville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Not more than half a mile this side of the village a terrible scene was
                    presented to view. The ground was stained with blood, and the dead bodies of
                    negro soldiers were stretched out along the road. It was evident that the
                    guerrillas had dashed upon the party guarding the rear of the cattle and taken
                    them completely by surprise."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A wholesale slaughter of negro soldiers who were driving cattle near
                        Simsonville, in that State, is noticed by the Louisville <emph rend="italic"
                            >Journal</emph>, as follows:</p>
                    <p>Not more than half a mile this side of the village a terrible scene was
                        presented to view. The ground was stained with blood, and the dead bodies of
                        negro soldiers were stretched out along the road. It was evident that the
                        guerrillas had dashed upon the party guarding the rear of the cattle and
                        taken them completely by surprise. They could not have offered any serious
                        resistance, as none of the outlaws were even wounded. It is presumed that
                        the negroes surrendered and were shot down in cold blood, as but two of the
                        entire number escaped--one of them by secreting himself behind a wagon, the
                        other by running, as he was met several miles from the scene of the tragedy
                        wounded and nearly exhausted. Thirty-five dead bodies were counted lying in
                        the road and vicinity. The outlaws were but fifteen in number--one of them a
                        black scoundrel, who boasted on the return of the band to Simsonville that
                        he killed three of the soldiers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the killing of thirty-five black soldiers by guerrilla soldiers
                    near Simsonville, Kentucky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Alarming Desertions</head>
                <origin>Hartford Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that more men desert from the Union army to the Confederate army than
                    from the Confederate side to the Union side.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Previously published county financial report, columns 1-3, classified ads,
                columns 4-5, fiction and poetry, columns 6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Word To Our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that the costs of rebuilding the Valley Spirit's office and
                    presses have been great, and encourages readers to help boost the paper's
                    circulation by recruiting new subscribers. Suggests that among the 3,500
                    Democrats in the county, there must be four to five hundred willing to subscribe
                    that have not already done so.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Late Peace Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is evident then that the conference failed to produce any good result,
                    not because an honorable peace was unattainable, but because the infernal and
                    ruinous negro policy of this administration stands in the way of so desirable a
                    consummation."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When the news flashed across the wires a short time ago that Peace
                        Commissioners were on their way from Richmond to Washington, the hearts of a
                        suffering and distressed people were made to beat high with joyful emotions
                        in anticipation of an early return of peace. The news was hailed as the dawn
                        of a brighter day, which should soon succeed this night of death and blood,
                        and carnage, which for the last four years has made this fair land of ours
                        one vast sepulchre filled with the mouldering bones of thousands of brothers
                        slain in an unnatural, fratricidal war. Hope beamed from every face, and the
                        eagerness with which every item of intelligence was sought after by the
                        multitude, shows how ardently the public heart longs for peace.</p>
                    <p>The commissioners were not permitted to come to Washington, but were met at
                        Fortress Monroe by president Lincoln and Seward; a conference of four hours
                        duration was had on board a steamer in Hampton Roads, which, according to
                        the testimony of both parties, proved a total failure. Upon whose shoulders
                        the responsibility for the failure rests is a matter which, in our judgment,
                        can easily be determined by any one who will carefully, candidly and
                        critically examine the message of the President to Congress embodying the
                        preliminary correspondence in relation to the interview, published in our
                        issue of last week. This correspondence needs but to be read to see what
                        grand results <emph rend="italic">might</emph> have followed this effort at
                        peace, had it been conducted on the principles of liberal and enlightened
                        statesmanship. That this informal conference might have been so managed by
                        President Lincoln as to have led very soon to a lasting and honorable peace
                        between the two billigerent [sic] sections of our common country, and to the
                        restoration of the Union of our fathers, we think will scarcely admit of a
                        doubt. For the proof of this position we appeal to the record.</p>
                    <p>In the early part of January Mr. F. P. Blair, Sr., goes to Richmond with the
                        knowledge and consent of the President. He is passed through the rebel lines
                        without any conditions or stipulations, (and in this particular the conduct
                        of the rebel authorities stands out in striking contrast with the miserable
                        quibbling and pettifogging of Lincoln and Stanton when Messrs. Stephens,
                        Hunter and Campbell applied for permission to pass our lines,) he is kindly
                        received by the authorities at Richmond; has several protracted interviews
                        with Mr. Jefferson Davis, during which questions in relation to the war were
                        doubtless discussed in all their bearings. Mr. Blair returns to Washington
                        with a letter from Mr. Davis designed to be shown to President Lincoln,
                        stating that he was ready to send or receive a commission "to enter into a
                        conference, with a view to secure peace to the two countries." Mr. Blair
                        returns to Richmond with Lincoln's reply to Davis, stating that he would
                        receive any agent which he (Mr. Davis) might send with the view of securing
                        peace "to our common country." This letter Mr. Davis read over twice, when
                        Mr. Blair remarked that the part about "our common country" related to the
                        part of Mr. Davis' letter about the "two countries." Mr. Davis replied that
                            <emph rend="italic">he so understood it</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Now, let us examine this point for a moment, and see what conclusion an
                        honest man must arrive at. On the strength of this letter of Mr. Lincoln,
                        explicitly stating the conditions upon which he would receive an agent or
                        agents of the Confederate Government, Jefferson Davis appoints A.H.
                        Stephens, R.M.T. Hunter and J.A. Campbell, commissioners to proceed to
                        Washington to confer with President Lincoln on the subject of peace; and the
                        commissioners themselves, in their note to Maj. Eckert dated February 2nd,
                        say that they were seeking an informal conference with President Lincoln "on
                        the basis of his letter to F.P. Blair of the 18th January." Now, what does
                        all this mean? What did these men come for? They are not ninnies and fools
                        that they would leave Richmond for Washington on a fool's errand--to talk
                        about a recognition of the Southern Confederacy--for they were fully advised
                        in regard to the position of the Government and people of the Untied States
                        on that point before they started. What then was the object of their
                        mission? The conclusion is irresistible that they came with a view of
                        securing peace to "once common country." In other words, they came prepared
                        to enter into negotiations for a re-construction of the Union, in case they
                        were met with just and liberal terms on the part of the Washington
                        administration. But the harsh and imperious demands of Mr. Lincoln, inspired
                        by the blood-thirsty radicals in Congress, repelled them at once. Before he
                        reached Fortress Monroe, and for fear Mr. Seward might compromise him on his
                        daring idea of negro freedom, he telegraphed the Secretary of State that
                        there must be "no receding on the slavery question." Here the inevitable
                        negro comes in again as the barrier thrown in the way of a just and
                        honorable peace by the miserable demagogues and fanatics which now,
                        unfortunately for the country, control the Federal Government. With
                        practical statesmen instead of visionary theorists at the head of the
                        Government, with the light we now have, this whole difficulty could be
                        adjusted in less than thirty days.</p>
                    <p>But the most conclusive evidence that these commissioners were honestly and
                        earnestly desirous of peace, and were willing to negotiate on the basis of a
                        re-construction of the Union, is the dispatch of General Grant to the
                        Secretary of War; and but for it they would have been sent back without even
                        a hearing. "I am convinced, upon conversation with Messrs. Stephens and
                        Hunter, that their intentions are <emph rend="italic">good</emph> and their
                        desire sincere to restore <emph rend="italic">peace and Union</emph>," says
                        General Grant, and adds, "I have not felt myself at liberty to express any
                        views of my own or to account for my reticence." Can any one doubt the
                        correctness of the position we have assumed, when it is sustained by the
                        testimony of so high and responsible a witness as General Grant? Or will it
                        be alleged that he was deceived or willfully telegraphed what was false? We
                        think it hardly possible that any sane man will be bold enough to make any
                        such foolish accusation against General Grant's high character for wisdom
                        and sagacity.</p>
                    <p>It is evident then that the conference failed to produce any good result, not
                        because an honorable peace was unattainable, but because the infernal and
                        ruinous negro policy of this administration stands in the way of so
                        desirable a consummation. Abraham Lincoln is clearly responsible for the
                        failure, and a fearful responsibility it is he has assumed. Let him beware
                        how he trifles with the lives of his fellow men. The tears and sighs and
                        groans of the thousands of widows and orphans in the land, made such by the
                        unnecessary protraction of the war, will some day, sooner or later, come up
                        in judgment against him. It is a monstrous crime against civilization and
                        christianity to continue the war a day longer than is necessary to secure an
                        honorable peace, on the basis of the Constitution and Union as framed and
                        organized by the fathers of the Republic. The people will not hold them
                        guiltless who have the power honorably to stop this effusion of blood and
                        yet persistently refuse to do so.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blames the recent impasse in peace talks on the Lincoln administration.
                    Suggests that its unwillingness to compromise on the slavery question is the
                    reason for the failure of negotiations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Unfortunate Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"While lack of brains predominates in one department, thieving and
                    licentiousness runs riot in another."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Lincoln's administration of being rife with corruption and
                    mismanagement. Cites the drafting department's handling of conscription as the
                    best example of the "blunders" common with this administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The whole Sanitary Commission is a humbug."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from a soldier in the Army of the Cumberland criticizes the Sanitary
                    Commission for failing to deliver supplies to men outside of hospitals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Brutus</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the recent proceedings of the Pennsylvania legislature,
                    including consideration of a bill that would allow local school districts to
                    levy a bounty tax sufficient for paying soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Convention of Publishers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the state convention of publishers, which met last week in
                    Harrisburg. Notes that B.Y. Hamsher of the Valley Spirit was elected secretary,
                    and publishes a resolution passed by the convention calling for the repeal of
                    the duty on printing paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Congressional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reviews the latest proceedings of the US Congress, including the
                    consideration by the House of a resolution declaring it against the "honor and
                    dignity" of the Union to offer any peace short of "entire submission" to the
                    Federal Government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Dispatches reporting on troop movement in South Carolina and Virginia, columns
                6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Oleaginour</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Compares investments in oil stocks to gambling in an essay condemning the
                    current "mania" over oil.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Home Guards</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Chief</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Chambersburg Home Guards went into winter quarters several
                    months ago and compares the soldiers to groundhogs to explain why they have not
                    yet reappeared.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Military Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the second Lieutenant of company C, Chambersburg Home Guards,
                    arrived at headquarters last Friday evening. In jest, suggests that the corps is
                    getting ready to "fracture the backbone of the rebellion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gound-Hog Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that the second day of February is Ground-Hog Day, during which
                    the length of winter is determined.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A New Bank</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The amount of business now transacting in the town, would seem to require
                    additional banking facilities, and we have no doubt the enterprise would prove
                    profitable to the originators and beneficial to the public."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a number of men "of capital" in Chambersburg are considering
                    establishing another bank under the National Banking Law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of Robert Earley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"About ten years since he removed to Evansville, where his many good
                    qualities soon acquired for him a high position in the esteem of his fellow
                    citizens, and he was rapidly achieving a deserved success in the battle of life,
                    when death put an end to his worldly career in the prime and vigor of his early
                    manhood."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Early, a native of Chambersburg, died on February 7 in Evansville,
                    Indiana. He will be buried in the cemetery of the German Reformed Church in
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Orphan Children of Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Those entitled to aid are 'children of either sex, under fifteen years of
                    age, residents of Pennsylvania, and dependent upon charity or upon the exertions
                    of a mother or other persons who are not able to educate and maintain them
                    properly, whose fathers have been killed, or who have died of wounds or of
                    disease contracted while in the service of the United States, in the army or
                    navy, and who were at the time of entering the service, actual residents of
                    Pennsylvania.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Pennsylvania Railroad made a donation of a large sum of money for the
                        education of the orphan children of soldiers. An act was passed by the State
                        legislature for the enlargement and judicious management of the donation.
                        Mr. Thom. H. Burroughs, of Lancaster, was appointed Superintendent of
                        Orphans in the State, and subordinate committees were appointed for the
                        different districts, or counties. When persons desire to have orphan
                        children receive the benefit of the donation, they should make application
                        to a member of the subordinate committee of their county. Those entitled to
                        aid are "children of either sex, under fifteen years of age, residents of
                        Pennsylvania, and dependent upon charity or upon the exertions of a mother
                        or other persons who are not able to educate and maintain them properly,
                        whose fathers have been killed, or who have died of wounds or of disease
                        contracted while in the service of the United States, in the army or navy,
                        and who were at the time of entering the service, actual residents of
                        Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p>The State will furnish tuition, boarding, clothing, books &amp;c., in the
                        schools, but the children must be sent on by the friends at their own
                        expense, with such clothing as they may have, in good order for use until
                        others can be provided. There is no restriction of the number which may be
                        sent from a family, but none must be over fifteen years old. When the
                        application is properly made according to the instructions of the committee,
                        it will be sent to the Superintendent of Orphans, and if accepted, he will
                        notify the mother, or other friend, telling what school the children must be
                        sent to, with all other necessary directions.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains what educational benefits are available to orphan children from
                    the state government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Young Man</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges every young man to keep busy and avoid becoming a "loafer."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Postponement of the Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites a report from the Washington Republican that states that the Provost
                    Marshal has delayed the draft and is encouraging districts to continue
                    recruiting volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Communication</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Long and ably written editorials appeared weekly, showing how money could
                    be safely invested in oil stocks, provided you carefully followed the Editor's
                    advice. Unfortunately the advice was like the footsteps about the sick lion's
                    den, they all turned the one direction, towards Sterling and Imperial. It will
                    be a good day for the widows, orphans and other holders of the stock of these
                    companies when they show any vitality."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors of the Valley Spirit:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Permit me, through the medium of your paper, to call the attention of the
                        public to an article which appeared in the last week's issue of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Franklin Repository</emph>, under the head of "Finance and
                        Trade."</p>
                    <p>It is not my purpose to defend the people of Greencastle for their
                        determination to organize a National Bank, without first obtaining a permit
                        from the Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Franklin Repository</emph>;
                        nevertheless, if it were not for the fact that under the existing laws, they
                        are not required to obtain a charter from the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania,
                        they would certainly have erred in not first securing the favor of said
                        Editor. Nor do I propose to put in a defense for Messrs. Stumbaugh &amp;
                        Gehr who are so covertly and cowardly attacked in said article for doing
                        what the law required at their hands and which others; and some of them law
                        makers, have not done, though they have sold stocks on commission; but I
                        come at once to that part of the article which cautions our country cousins
                        against purchasing the Cherry Run and Pittsburg [sic] Petroleum oil stock. I
                        am well aware that since the first offer of sale of this stock in this said
                        to be "unimportant market," there has been a persistent effort on the part
                        of certain individuals to prevent the sale thereof, and is it any wonder
                        that there should be such a howling now by the big "Bull" and the very few
                        little "Bulls" of the same ilk, since the "fancy" Cherry Run and Pittsburg
                        Petroleum oil stock has advanced 100 per cent., or even according to the
                        author of the article referred to, 40 per cent, while the "pet Sterling,"
                        the original cost of which was $2.00, has depreciated and is now freely
                        offered in this distant "unimportant market" for $1.80 and at Greencastle at
                        $1.50 per share; and the other pet Imperial which originally cost $5.00 is
                        offered here at $4.75 and indeed holders of the same in this county, have
                        offered to exchange for Cherry Run and Pittsburg, share for share. "Good
                        stock is not kicked about in this way."</p>
                    <p>Now, as the author of the article says the Cherry Run and Pittsburg has been
                        tossed and tumbled by the "Bulls and Bears" of Chambersburg, and our country
                        cousins would do well to let it rotate amongst the speculators themselves,
                        does he know that weeks ago the books for the sale of the Imperial were
                        advertised "closed," and yet any person desiring to subscribe for the same
                        could be accommodated at the office of the <emph rend="italic">Franklin
                            Repository</emph>, and if so, will the certificates of either Imperial
                        or Sterling, or both, entitle the holder thereof to an interest in river
                        beds about to be donated by the Commonwealth, (said to be too poor to make
                        restitution to her citizens for losses sustained by the rebels,) through the
                        influence of the distinguished Editor of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph>. If so, would it not be well for the Editor to inform the
                        public of the same through the medium of his paper.</p>
                    <p>No one in reading the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> for the past two
                        months would have supposed for a moment that this is so very "unimportant a
                        stock market." Long and ably written editorials appeared weekly, showing how
                        money could be safely invested in oil stocks, provided you carefully
                        followed the Editor's advice. Unfortunately the advice was like the
                        footsteps about the sick lion's den, they all turned the one direction,
                        towards Sterling and Imperial. It will be a good day for the widows, orphans
                        and other holders of the stock of these companies when they show any
                        vitality. If it would only fluctuate a <emph rend="italic">little</emph> it
                            <emph rend="italic">might rise</emph>. If the more distant from each
                        other the dividends are, be an advantage, why not make them annual instead
                        of quarterly? it would afford evidence of even greater substantiality than
                        possessed by any other companies that ever intend to pay at all. Who are
                        more properly speculators in stock, the half dozen who purchased land at
                        $140,000 and converted it into $1,000,000 of capital for an oil company, or
                        the persons believing the statements made to the public by the originators
                        of the enterprise and who purchase a portion of the stock expecting to sell
                        at an advance.</p>
                    <p>Our country cousins no doubt understand the <emph rend="italic">animus</emph>
                        and motives of the author of the article referred to.</p>
                    <p>Stockholder of the Imperial and Cherry Run and Pittsburg.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Stockholder of the Imperial and Cherry Run and Pittsburg</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the Greencastle citizens who are considering opening a new bank
                    against criticism from the Repository editor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>George K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>Emily</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Thomas Barnhart married George K. Woodward, of Wilmington, Delaware,
                    and Emily Switzer on February 15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moller</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Martha Smith, daughter of Hugh Smith, Esq., and Frederick Moller, were
                    married on February 12 by Rev. J. N. Hays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keckler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hepfer</ln>
                        <fn>Matilda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William Keckler and Matilda Hepher were married on February 13, at the
                    residence of the bride's parents, by Rev. S. McHenry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baum</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lydia Baum died on February 17 at age 45.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bohn</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas D. Bohn died on February 6 near Charlestown, Virginia, at age 22
                    years, 1 month and 10 days. He was shot accidentally by one of his comrades,
                    with the ball entering his left side and leaving through his right shoulder
                    blade. He was buried on February 16 in the Mentzer graveyard near Fayetteville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 4-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.02.22.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
