<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.03.01">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/18/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-03-01">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.03.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The President's Message on the Peace Conference</head>
                <origin>World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is nothing in the narration and letters thus communicated
                    inconsistent with the supposition that the whole affair was an artful maneuver
                    by the friends of the President to hoodwink and deceive the country for his
                    benefit. Its purpose was not peace, but to silence hostile criticism on his
                    administration."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says President Lincoln's latest message to Congress is proof that his
                    attempts at peace were insincere. Argues that he lured southern leaders to peace
                    talks on the promise of peace by reunion, only to then demand the abolition of
                    slavery as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>(No Title)</head>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It will be observed soon that there are other enormities beside
                    slavery--Catholicism is one of them. There is room for another irrepressible
                    conflict when the present one is over."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>[From the Louisville Democrat.]</p>
                    <p>A correspondent of a radical paper has made a discovery and revelation which
                        is quite startling. Intervention is to come, and the quarter it is to come
                        from is designated. The Roman Catholic Church is at the bottom of the
                        movement. We have noticed that this church is suspected of disloyalty in
                        inffluential [sic] places. The clergy of this church have not preached
                        loyalty as an essential article in the faith, and hence they are suspected
                        of being no better than they ought to be.</p>
                    <p>Now it is found out and disclosed to the world that the Catholic powers
                        sympathize with the rebellion, and have been caucusing as to what had best
                        be done, on the other side of the Atlantic.</p>
                    <p>It will be observed soon that there are other enormities beside
                        slavery--Catholicism is one of them. There is room for another irrepressible
                        conflict when the present one is over.</p>
                    <p>We have wondered what has been sending Blair back and forth, and Singleton,
                        too, between Richmond and Washington; what has converted the heads of the
                        dominant party into "peace sneaks," why commissioners can come now to
                        Washington, when, some time ago, Stephens was refused the privilege of
                        coming to Washington. What is the matter? We see Dr. Gwin is down in
                        Mexico--a very bad rebel that Gwin--and he is placed in a situation to cut a
                        figure of some sort. What do he, Napoleon and Maximilian mean by this snug
                        little arrangement right on our borders? Then those vessels of war on the
                        lakes do not promise tranquil[l]ity there. But these signs are not
                        sufficient to convert a party to the policy of their opponents in such a
                        hurry, with no explanation. True, it is wise to offer terms of peace and
                        Union in the hour of success; but who expected the dominant party to be
                        wise?</p>
                    <p>Perhaps Abraham Lincoln knows something that other people do not know; and as
                        he is a good deal smarter than the rest of his party he may anticipate the
                        evil to come, which they don't see, or would not appreciate if they did.</p>
                    <p>The fact is, we can't expect to keep other people out of this muss long, but
                        it is not worth while to ascribe what comes to Catholic powers, because they
                        are Catholic. Statesmen don't act on such principles now. Catholic France
                        aided Protestant Colonies against a Protestant King and Parliament. Catholic
                        nations war upon each other, and have Protestant aid in the contest. This
                        suggestion is intended to get up a new agony. Protestantism is in danger.
                        Start the cry and bring in sectarian bigotry to aid loyalty that does not
                        fill the armies as it used to. The Pope was a very dangerous individual some
                        years ago. He was going to gobble up the liberties of the country, and a
                        powerful organization was got up duly equipped with signs, grips and
                        passwords. The anti-Democratic party has always been hobby-riding. American
                        systems, banks and tariffs, were once their stock in trade. Subsequently
                        they had anti-Masonry, then the Pope and foreigners. They generally rode one
                        hobby to death, and then got up another. Nativeism [sic] promised well for a
                        while; but anti-slavery smothered it out for a time. Still the old hobby was
                        quite a pet; and it is considered worth while to saddle and bridle it again
                        in the anti-Catholic shape. It may serve a purpose to rouse up sectarian
                        resentment if foreign intervention is apprehended. Set it all down to the
                        Catholics--the natural allies of slavery. These anti-Democratic parties
                        can't do without hobbies. They must have bugbears and hobgoblins--things
                        outside of any object recognized in the Constitution and spirit of our
                        Government. The rebellion has been a godsend to them. How they could have
                        lived to this time in peace and without some new hobby, had it not been for
                        civil war, it is impossible to tell. Getting tired of the rebellion, they
                        are now looking up an old hobby, anti-Catholicism, and rubbing it down to
                        see if it will not bear another ride. They are getting it ready to ride
                        alone with the rebellion, or after the latter subsides.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Catholics of being sympathetic with the southern cause and of being
                    the "natural allies" of slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Political Preachers and Their Falsehoods</head>
                <origin>Clinton Democrat</origin>
                <commentary>"Our able contemporary, the Clinton Democrat thus truthfully and
                    forcibly sets forth the position of the Democracy in relation to the Church."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the Democratic party against charges that it has taken a stand
                    against the church. Explains that the party is a "strong protector of religion,"
                    which is why it has condemned preachers for using the pulpit for political
                    purposes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Internal Revenue Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains the recent changes made in the internal revenue bill, including
                    the amount of taxes to be paid on brandy, tobacco, and snuff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-3, fiction, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.03.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Gloomy Picture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges blame to be placed upon the Lincoln administration for accumulating a
                    huge wartime debt and leaving the nation in a "wretched" economic state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>An Eve, and a Duty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Republican leaders of accumulating huge profits by giving their
                    friends lucrative war contracts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Applauds Governor Curtin for defending Pennsylvanians against the
                    "subordinate" officials in the Lincoln administration who are arresting citizens
                    "without authority of law."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Black Millennium</head>
                <origin>Savannah Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Northern young men -- especially the married ones -- who voted for Mr.
                    Lincoln will doubtless be delighted to learn that while they are subject to a
                    ruthless and inexorable conscription, their freed 'brothers' in Georgia will not
                    be forced to enlist."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Savannah <emph rend="italic">Republican</emph> of February 5, contains a
                        report of a "freedmen's meeting" held in that city. The place of meeting was
                        the Second Baptist church, and the <emph rend="italic">Republican</emph>
                        informs us that "while the people were gathering"--</p>
                    <p>The organ was played by a colored man, accompanied with male and female
                        singers; the instrumental and vocal music afforded evidence of the truth
                        that Africa will yet excel in the imaginative arts.</p>
                    <p>After prayer by "Rev. Mr. French, Chaplain U.S.A., General Saxton was
                        introduced. He told the negroes they were free, and added--</p>
                    <p>And now I want to tell you, <emph rend="italic">you may own the soil.</emph>
                        [Deep sensation.]</p>
                    <p>In the proclamation of the President, and in the order of General Sherman,
                        are the means to make you <emph rend="italic">Freemen and to own the soil
                            you live on. All these beautiful, fruitful islands spoken of are
                        yours.</emph></p>
                    <p>The Northern young men--especially the married ones--who voted for Mr.
                        Lincoln will doubtless be delighted to learn that while they are subject to
                        a ruthless and inexorable conscription, their freed "brothers" in Georgia
                        will not be forced to enlist. General Saxton said:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">You are not to be forced into the army service</emph>. If
                        you want to enlist I will be glad to have you do so. <lb/>* * * * *</p>
                    <p>It is the duty of the <emph rend="italic">young</emph> man, who is able, to
                        enlist in the service of the country. I mean the young man without wife or
                        family. <emph rend="italic">The first duty is to take care of the
                        family</emph>. He that has a large family should first provide for them. The
                        young man, without family, should enlist at once. <emph rend="italic">But
                            you will not be forced to enlist</emph>. Not only does the government
                        give you a chance to enlist but it gives you a bounty of $300, and wages,
                        and clothes and rations as other soldiers have.</p>
                    <p>The General then told the negroes how to possess the land:</p>
                    <p>I have been appointed by Gen. Sherman as Inspector of Plantations; and will
                        aid you in the getting of 10 acre farms as homes. Now, do you know how much
                        a 40 acre lot is? or how to measure it? Pace off four hundred paces one way;
                        and four hundred the other way; and you have 40 acres; only be sure that you
                        step long, so as to have a good big tract. [Cheers.] If the land where you
                        wish to go is so located, that you do not wish to have the whole 40 acres in
                        one lot, you can pace off in the same proportions. You ought to have some
                        wood land. I recommend each family to have ten acres of wood land, and
                        thirty acres of tillable land? Two hundred paces each way will give ten
                        acres &amp;c. When you go on the large plantations you will find a great
                        many forty acre lots, and should divide accordingly.</p>
                    <p>You are to have a <emph rend="italic">certificate</emph> that this land has
                        been given you according to General Sherman's order. The officer having the
                        matter in charge will explain all to you.</p>
                    <p>There need not be any <emph rend="italic">hurry,</emph> keep cool, but busy,
                        kind, and patient; and bye and bye you will have the deed given you. <emph
                            rend="italic">Go and settle on the land at once</emph>, and in the
                        proper time you will have the <emph rend="italic">deeds.</emph></p>
                    <p>Saxton, who is evidently something of a theologian, let in a little light
                        upon his hearers, in regard to slavery:</p>
                    <p>God cursed the south on account of slavery, He cursed Egypt for making
                        bondmen of the Israelites, and He will curse any nation that has slavery. I
                        wish I could explain all this to you, but I have not the time to do it.</p>
                    <p>When the General had said all that he had to say, he took his seat, according
                        to the report--</p>
                    <p>Amid much applause, <emph rend="italic">and ascriptions of praise to God, and
                            the President, General Sherman and General Saxton</emph>.</p>
                    <p>[Powers Eternal! such names mingled.]</p>
                    <p>The next speaker was Chaplain French. His speech, as was proper, was in a
                        pious vein, and contained much "cute" Yankee advice. We give some extracts,
                        from which it will be seen how close the negro millen[n]ium is at hand:</p>
                    <p>Your status as yet is not fully defined; it is somewhat like that of the
                        Israelites, <emph rend="italic">had left Egypt, and had not reached
                        Canaan</emph> their future, permanent home, but were in the wilderness. They
                        had to make a long journey to reach their homes. <emph rend="italic">You,
                            more favored, are freed on the very soil you are to possess and
                            cultivate as your own</emph>. The first provision for the Israelites, on
                        reaching the land of promise, was a homestead. This was the arrangements of
                        Providence. Such also are the arrangements of our government for you, and
                        that too, on a liberal but just scale.</p>
                    <p>Not long ago since, and the government, with the entire army and Navy, were
                        pledged to keep you in <emph rend="italic">slavery</emph>. But now, our
                        government, with its five hundred thousand bayonets and immense navy, is
                        equally pledged to preserve you in your freedom. General Sherman and his
                        mighty army has left you and will carry freedom to others, but the
                        government has sent, in their stead, General Grover, who is now here, with
                        many thousand brave troops to protect, not only the citizens of Savannah,
                        but to protect you in your freedom. [Shouts, &amp;c., abundantly] You
                        see, then how abundantly the Lord has provided for you.</p>
                    <p>But there is another great work to be done. This Southern country is to be
                        taken care of after the war, by soldiers, <emph rend="italic">and these
                            soldiers in part at least will be colored men</emph>, who must help to
                        protect not only the interests of the government, but your rights and
                        liberties. Your young and able bodied men must therefore, enter the war
                        school, the army at once. I would advise, however, that those who have
                        families should first secure comfortable homes for them, and when this is
                        done, that they enter the service of the country immediately. You see here
                        today the General and many other officers with stars and bars on their
                        shoulders. Now, white men think a great deal of these honors; but if I were
                        in your place, I would rather have forty acres of land under my feet that I
                        could walk on as my own than to be covered all over from head to foot with
                        stars. <emph rend="italic">Let white men fight for these honors, but be sure
                            and get your lands</emph>--and you must be in a hurry about it, too, for
                        only this morning I heard of a flat boat coming down the river full of
                        people who have asked for a pass to go right down, without even landing in
                        the city. I like to see this wide awake spirit. You must not wait for the
                        General to send a large steamboat to take you down in grand style. No, no;
                        go at once, and if there is no other way get a rail and swim down on that.
                        [Many hearty shouts.] I see already the fire burning in your eyes, and many
                        a one appearing to say "I want to leave the church now and go." Well, I
                        shall not be surprised to hear of some of you getting wagons and boats, and
                        hoes and seeds, and when inquiry is made for you, if it should be said "Oh!
                        they are down already on their farms."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a meeting of freedmen in Savannah, Georgia, during which former
                    slaves were promised land and other forms of aid from US General Saxton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Hospital for the Insane</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Of the 4,323 patients admitted into the institution since its opening, 727
                    appear to have become insane from ill-health of various kinds; 286 from
                    intemperance; 149 loss of property; 5 dread of poverty; 64 disappointed
                    affections; 45 intense study; 94 domestic difficulties; 35 fright; 227 grief,
                    loss of friends, etc.; 35 intense application to business; 146 religious
                    excitement; 12 political excitement; 1 metaphysical speculations; 8 want of
                    exercise; 1 engagement in a duel; 17 disappointed expectations; 6 nostalgia; 2
                    stock speculations; 37 want of employment; 3 mortified pride; 1 celebacy [sic];
                    2 anxiety for wealth; 15 uss [sic] of opium; 6 use of tobacco; 3 use of quack
                    medicines; 169 puerpal state; 12 uncontrolled passion; 1 tight lacing; 54
                    injuries of the head; 278 mental anxiety; 4 exposure to cold; 38 exposure to
                    direct rays of the sun; 1 exposure to intense heat; 4 exposure in the army."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the opening of this institution in 1844, no less than 4,323 patients
                        have been admitted within its walls. Of this number, 4,044 have been
                        discharged, leaving 279 patients still in the hospital at the beginning of
                        the present year. The annual report of Dr. Kirkbride, who has control of
                        this asylum, contains some singular and interesting figures. Of the 4,323
                        patients admitted into the institution since its opening, 727 appear to have
                        become insane from ill-health of various kinds; 286 from intemperance; 149
                        loss of property; 5 dread of poverty; 64 disappointed affections; 45 intense
                        study; 94 domestic difficulties; 35 fright; 227 grief, loss of friends,
                        etc.; 35 intense application to business; 146 religious excitement; 12
                        political excitement; 1 metaphysical speculations; 8 want of exercise; 1
                        engagement in a duel; 17 disappointed expectations; 6 nostalgia; 2 stock
                        speculations; 37 want of employment; 3 mortified pride; 1 celebacy [sic]; 2
                        anxiety for wealth; 15 uss [sic] of opium; 6 use of tobacco; 3 use of quack
                        medicines; 169 puerpal state; 12 uncontrolled passion; 1 tight lacing; 54
                        injuries of the head; 278 mental anxiety; 4 exposure to cold; 38 exposure to
                        direct rays of the sun; 1 exposure to intense heat; 4 exposure in the army.</p>
                    <p>Of the whole number of patients admitted from the beginning, 323 were
                        farmers; 217 merchants; 176 laborers; 174 clerks. The other occupations are
                        not so heavily represented. For instance, there are 45 physicians; 41
                        lawyers; 25 clergymen; 36 teachers; 78 carpenters; 36 machinists; 26
                        weavers; 29 blacksmiths; 30 hotel keepers; 38 tailors; 75 shoemakers. Of the
                        females admitted, 205 were seamstresses or mantuamakers; 229 domestics; 99
                        daughters of farmers, and 180 widows of farmers; 107 daughters of merchants;
                        40 widows of merchants, and 128 wives of merchants.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a statistical breakdown of the patients that have been admitted to
                    the Pennsylvania Hospital for the Insane since it opened in 1844. Of the 4,323
                    total patients admitted for insanity, 727 were the result of ill-health of
                    various kinds, 286 from intemperance, 149 from loss of property, 5 from dread of
                    property, 64 from "disappointed affections," 45 from "intense study," 94 from
                    "domestic difficulties," 35 from fright, 227 from grief over the loss of
                    friends, 35 from "intense application to business," 146 from "religious
                    excitement," 12 from "political excitement," 1 from "metaphysical speculations,"
                    8 from "want of exercise," 1 from engagement in a duel, 17 from "disappointed
                    expectations," 6 from nostalgia, 2 from stock speculations, 37 from want of
                    employment, 3 from mortified pride, 1 from celibacy, 2 from "anxiety for
                    wealth," 15 from use of opium, 6 from use of tobacco, 3 from use of "quack
                    medicines," 169 for "puerperal state," 12 from uncontrolled passion, 1 from
                    "tight lacing," 4 from exposure to cold, 38 from exposure to direct rays of the
                    sun, 1 from exposure to intense heat, and 4 from "exposure in the army."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report on the proceedings of the US Congress, columns 6-7, dispatches
                concerning troop movement in Charleston, South Carolina, and Maryland, column 5 and
                7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.03.01.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks the borough council to explain why the street lamps of Chambersburg
                    are not lit. Suggests that it is dangerous to walk around at night without them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Bad Practice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns readers against turning the wick of their lamps down low. Says that
                    it poisons the air, which can result in the irritation and inflammation of the
                    throat and lungs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>107th Regiment Penna. Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murphey</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Durkin</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sloughenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McBride</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roney</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitch</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Canhan</ln>
                        <fn>Henry E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trover</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tressler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blythession</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that in a recent engagement at Dabney's Mills near Petersburg, the
                    following men in Companies H and K, 107th Pennsylvania Regiment, were wounded.
                    Company H (recruited by Capt. John T. Dick): Privates William A. Murphey, James
                    Morris, Thomas Durkin, Levi Sloughenbaugh, Joseph McBride, James Roney, and
                    Henry Mitch. Company K (recruited by Capt. A. J. Brand): Privates Henry E.
                    Canhan, George Robison, George Trover, John Tressler, and Archibald Blythession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Twenty-Second</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Chambersburg residents celebrated the anniversary of George
                    Washington's birthday with a street parade of the soldiers stationed in the
                    town. Bells were rung in honor of recent victories, and a national salute was
                    fired by the battery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>James Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Susan A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. P. S. Davis married Lieut. James Thomas Long and Susan A. Greenawalt
                    on February 23.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitehead</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph L. Whitehead and Susan Wolf were married on February 26 by Rev.
                    Thomas Barnhart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William McElroy married Henry Myers and Sarah Harman on February 23.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sackman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine Sackman died on February 18 at age 39 years, 5 months and 22
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>List of drafted men already published in the Repository, column 1, Classified
                ads, columns 4-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.03.01.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
