<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.07.19">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/02/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-07-19">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="00">19</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.07.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Selling Paupers in New England</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union; Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Castigates the practice of selling off poor whites to the lowest bidder, a
                    yearly tradition in New England where paupers are forced to work for private
                    individuals to receive support. The article alleges that New Englanders are
                    hypocrites, or worse yet race traitors, for providing their unyielding support
                    for abolition while, at the same time, they fail to afford poor whites the same
                    concern.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Gen. Lee's Application for Pardon</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If this noble and famous Bayard of the South, without hesitation' [sic]
                    acknowledges the supremacy of the Government, seeks to be rehabilitated as a
                    citizen, and tenders his allegiance, who need entertain a doubt to his own
                    duty?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article venerates Gen. Lee for his decision to seek amnesty from
                    Johnson and applauds his efforts to restore "peace and tranquility."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Black Editor's Opinion</head>
                <origin>The Black Republican</origin>
                <commentary>"A Black Editor's Opinion.--The Black Republican is a newspaper in New
                    Orleans edited by a colored man (a clergyman) who it would seem, from the
                    following, does not think that they regeneration of his brethren is to be
                    accomplished by voting and tax-paying:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Black Republican, a New Orleans' newspaper, declares that blacks and
                    whites cannot live together in the United States. The editor, a clergyman,
                    asserts that blacks, like Native Americans, will become "extinct in this
                    country" unless they separate themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.07.19.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It would seem as if crime were running like an epidemic over the Northern
                    States, and scourging the land like moral cholera."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns the rising tide of lawlessness that appears to be sweeping across
                    the North. The article lays part of the blame for the current state of affairs
                    on the "Abolition press," which, it claims, has helped to foster the poisoned
                    atmosphere through its attacks on Democrats and anyone else who failed to agree
                    with its prognosis for ending the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Negro Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns the proposition floating around Washington that blacks will
                    comprise a significant proportion, if not majority, of the regular army once
                    excess troops have been mustered out. The article maintains the policy is
                    fraught with danger because it will lower the army's standards since no white
                    man will want to join the service once "black" and "soldier" become synonymous.
                    The article also rails against the possibility of creating an integrated force .</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Experience has shown that perfection of wisdom, the Constitution of the
                    United States, is a very poor document."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pointing to the Civil War as proof, the Spirit voices the opinion that the
                    Constitution should be modified since it is inadequate in emergencies. The
                    article calls for the enactment of an additional amendment to provide a clear
                    provision for the government to suspend parts of the Constitution in times of
                    war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Soldiers Read</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details a Fourth of July celebration in Farmington, Mass., where Wendell
                    Phillips declared that blacks bear "the palm in virtue, gallantry, and
                    patriotism" in the Civil War. According to the Spirit, this statement, as well
                    as one issued that same day by a black orator who avowed that black soldiers
                    would rise up should they be denied the franchise, indicates the manner in which
                    abolitionists are placing the achievements of blacks above those of whites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Soldiers! Heads Up! Eyes Front!</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls upon returning white soldiers to demonstrate to Republicans how they
                    feel about the prospect of black suffrage by voting against them in the upcoming
                    election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Numbers, Not Intelligence</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts a speech given by H. Winter Davis at a Republican meeting in
                    Chicago, where the politician declared his support for black suffrage. The
                    rationale for his decision lay not with the fact that blacks deserved the vote
                    because of their intelligence, or their gallantry during the war, but rested
                    instead with the fact that blacks constitute a significant percentage of the
                    southern populace and thus could be used to contain white resistance to
                    Republican rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The only elements of trouble in the South now are the radicals and
                    negroes, and the sooner they are put to the wall the better for the whole
                    country."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blacks convening in Alexandria, Va., have issued a statement blasting
                    Governor Pierpont and the state legislature. The group unanimously agreed to
                    "secure the elective franchise" for blacks "as soon as it can be safely done"
                    and to "establish a strong and loyal government, military or territorial."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Louisville Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Over the past twelve months at Camp Nelson in Kentucky, 1,200 blacks have
                    died. With such a horrific death rate, the Louisville Democrat sardonically asks
                    how long it will be before Kentucky is made a free state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Negro Suffrage in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[Radicals] appear to disregard the simplest dictates of prudence in their
                    infernal negro agitation, and will continue it, no doubt, until the whole
                    country turns upon them and the black objects of their commiseration and wipes
                    out both of the pests."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Reason</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter to the editor that rails against radicals and the prospect of
                    black suffrage which, the writer contends, is completely inappropriate since the
                    freedmen are incapable of exercising the right properly. The democratic system,
                    he avers, can only be preserved through restricting the franchise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Senator Wilson on the Rampage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At a Forth of July picnic in Washington attended by blacks, Senator Wilson
                    addressed the crowd and spelled out some of his views concerning the post-war
                    racial order. The article quotes Wilson at length, highlighting what it deems as
                    his "impudent" and "radical" threats to ensure that blacks have the right "to
                    vote, hold office, and generally to control the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Confiscation has begun in Richmond where the Tredegar Iron Works was
                    seized. A large amount of other property is expected to be confiscated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.07.19.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--William S. Stenger, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 25, William S. Stenger will deliver the oration before the literary
                    societies of Franklin and Marshall College at the school's commencement
                    exercises.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Consolidated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The 25th and 2nd Pennsylvania Cavalry have been consolidated and will now
                    be known as the 1st Provisional Pennsylvania Cavalry, 2nd division, 22nd Corps,
                    Dept. of Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Destroyed by Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper mill owned by Messr. Given &amp; Bros was completely
                    destroyed in a fire that occurred on the morning of July 12th. The damage from
                    the blaze is estimated to be between and $30,000 and $40,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Ulton P. Moore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Ulton F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Noah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ulton F. Moore has died from the wounds he suffered at the hands of his
                    brother-in-law, who shot him several weeks earlier. After the attack, Myers fled
                    the scene, prompting the issuance of a reward of $100 for his capture. The offer
                    proved unnecessary, however, as Myers turned himself in following his victim's
                    death. He is being held in jail near Hagerstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--No More Three and Five Cent Notes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Secretary of the Treasury is moving to discontinue the issuance of
                    fractional currency less than ten cents. The printing of three cent notes has
                    stopped and it is expected that this will soon be true for the five cent notes
                    as well. They are to be replaced with coins that are presently being minted, and
                    hoarded as fast as they are issued.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Female Medical College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[The Female Medical College] is an excellent institution and its objects
                    are deserving of public encouragement."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Female Medical College, located in Philadelphia, announces the start of
                    its upcoming session. The school has been in operation for 15 years, graduating
                    68 women over this period while nearly four times that number have matriculated
                    and attended lectures. The brief piece commends the school for its achievements
                    and encourages others to do the same.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--New Engines</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Railroad Company is acquiring two new engines from
                    the firm of Danforth, Cooke, and Co., of Patterson, New Jersey. The first
                    engine, named Gen. Grant, has arrived while the second, Gen. Sherman, is
                    expected later in the week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Presented For Treason</head>
                <origin>Hagerstown Mail</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freaner</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brien</ln>
                        <fn>L. Tierman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Baltimore newspapers are reporting that Robert Swan, George Freaner, and L.
                    Tierman Brien have been indicted in that city for treason. The trio has been
                    charged for actively supporting the Confederacy during the war. Swan allegedly
                    opened a recruiting office for the rebel army in Hagerstown in 1863; Brien is
                    accused of leading a rebel assault on Union troops that took place on September
                    11, 1862. The exact charge against Freaner is unknown. Bail has been set at
                    $2,000 and $3,000 for Swan and Brien, respectively. Freaner was non est.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Latest By Mails: Excitement at Charleston--Fight Between White and Colored
                    Troops--One Man Killed and Three Wounded--The Colored Troops Dispersed by the
                    Zouaves.</head>
                <origin>Charleston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mayhem erupted in Charleston's market after an altercation broke out
                    between a group of black soldiers from the 54th Mass. Vol. (col.) and the
                    Zouaves, who were patrolling the area. The melee resulted in the death of one
                    black soldier while three others suffered injuries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fennel</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 9th, Charles Jackson, of Stockbridge, New York, and his bride, Kate
                    Fennel were married by Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type=" ">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Youst, member of Co. G, 206th Regiment P. V., died on July 15th from
                    injuries he suffered after falling from his horse while riding through the
                    streets of Greenvillage on the 26th of June.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.07.19.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
