<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.11.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/21/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-11-08">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="11"/>
            <day norm="00">08</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.11.08.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.11.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Alleged Swindle in the Oil Business</head>
                <origin>Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Home of the of the numerous oil companies, which sprang up like mushrooms
                        during the past year or two, are getting into trouble. Some time ago,
                        several gentlemen engaged in that branch of speculation, were before the
                        courts in New York on charge of quite a number of dupes to the tune of
                        thousands, and recently some of the victims in Philadelphia have waked up to
                        the fact that they have been taken in and done for. Many of the companies
                        were the baldest kind of swindle-um-well company would, in a short time,
                        raise him to the position of a millionaire. The fondly cherished hopes of
                        speedy wealth are no passing away as the morning mist, and those who tempted
                        fortune by investing their hard earned cash in oil shares, are realizing the
                        fact that they have been overreached, and that they will see their money
                        again-no more forever.</p>
                    <p>Since the thing has been brought into the courts it may be expected that a
                        number of these swindles will be thoroughly ventilated, and such a rattling
                        of dry bones, as there will be among the oil stock operators, will astonish
                        the natives.</p>
                    <p>As a specimen of the way things have been done, we give the following
                        developments made at a hearing before Alderman Beitler in Philadelphia, a
                        few days ago, which we clip from the <emph rend="italic">Bulletin</emph>. A
                        perusal of which will be quite refreshing to those of our citizens who have
                        invested in "ile," particularly that part of it in relatition where the
                        dividends came from: </p>
                    <p>George H. Ashton, President; Fred. E. Swope, Treasurer; and T.R. Serrill, E.
                        B. Harper, S. C. Hansey and John V. Barton, Directors of the Atlas Oil
                        Company, charged with making a false statement in the prospectus, had a
                        further hearing yesterday before Alderman Beitler.</p>
                    <p>P. W. Wiltbankds, the Secretary of the company was examined among other
                        witnesses, and made some interesting and rich developments. He says: "The
                        Atlas Oil Company, I believe, owns one-sixth of the interest in the Jersey
                        well; it is nearly all paid for; he price was $190,000; I think $120,000 has
                        been paid; there was an agreement in writing; the original is in the hands
                        of the company's attorney (a copy was produced); by that agreement $100,000
                        was to have been paid on the 7th of October, 1864; $100,000 within twenty
                        days thereafter, and $100,000 in forty days; I think that the first and
                        second instalment were paid; I am not sure about the second; the company
                        never received any oil from the Jersey well; there were $100,000 shares of
                        stock issued; the corporators paid $1.50 per share; the corporators took all
                        the stock; the company then sold it to subscribers at $2.50 per share; when
                        parties came to the office I told them it was in the company's stock, and
                        not the corporators; about 20,000 shares were sold at $2..58 per share, and
                        the money was divided among the corporators.</p>
                    <p>The company was divided into 50 corporate interests of 6,000 shares, each
                        being entitled to hold 4,000 shares, making a total of 200,000 shares at
                        $300,000; don't know of any stock being issued which was not paid for; heard
                        of some; think it was 12,000 shares; it was to have been issued by the
                        Treasurer; the dividends were paid out of the money put into the treasury to
                        pay for the Jersey well; there were three dividends, amounting to $45,000,
                        declared; the fifty acres not mentioned in the prospectus is 500 yards from
                        Cherry Run, and is not described; it is more than a mile and half from the
                        Reed well, and is not bottom land; George H. Ashton, the President, received
                        dividends upon 21,600 shares-10,6000 in his own name, and 11,000 as trustee;
                        he originally owned 16,000 shares, which he got at $1.50 per share; don't
                        believe that over 4,000 of Ashton's shares were sold in the office; Serrill
                        and other of the defendants originally held 6,000 shares; at the first
                        dividend Serrill had none; Harker had 5,333 shares originally; at the first
                        dividend he had none; Barton held 4,000 shares; at the dividend he had
                        3,450; Swope had no stock when the first dividend was declared; he had a
                        great deal originally; I think about 20,000 shares.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article asserts that incidents of fraud have increased substantially
                    with the growth of the oil industry in Pennsylvania, as con men descend on the
                    state in search of easy riches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Interesting Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>127-11-5</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The last installment in a series of letters from a soldier serving in the
                    77th Pennsylvania regiment. The soldier describes his adventures in Texas and
                    Mexico prior to his return east, to Fannettsburg, Penn., where he is to be
                    mustered out.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Secretary Stanton has decided that blacks troops who were slaves at the
                    time of their enlistment are not entitled to their bounty, a position opposed by
                    the Attorney General. The President will resolve the dispute.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Treasury Department has projected the expenses for the government for
                    1866 to be $100,000,000, exclusive of the public debt, which is now
                    $165,000,000. It is believed that the internal revenue receipts will cover the
                    expenditures.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.11.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--The Courts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Courts-The October term of the several Courts of this county commenced on
                        Monday, the 20th ult. The new Court Hall being so far advanced towards
                        completion as to be prepared for the comfortable accommodations of the
                        Court, was for the first time used for that purpose. The Hall is beautifully
                        frescoed and when finished, will be one of the largest and best arranged
                        Court rooms in the State. The sessions were continued through the entire
                        week and quite a large amount of business was disposed of. The second week
                        of the term commenced on Monday last and Court is now in session with a long
                        list of causes to try which will occupy the entire week.</p>
                    <p>The following are the causes disposed of last week:</p>
                    <p>Common Pleas</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs A. H. &amp; G. H. Stump-Feigned issue to test the right
                        of the Commonwealth to Collateral Tax on the Estate of Abraham Stump,
                        dec'd-verdict for defendants.</p>
                    <p>George Zentmyer vs Daniel W. Royer-Action of Assumpsit on Note for $375. The
                        defence was that the note was a forgery-Verdict for deft.</p>
                    <p>Quarter Sessions</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth vs William Barger and John Riley (of H)-Malicious
                        Mischief-Lawrence Barger, Prosecutor-Verdict.-Guilty-Sentence each to pay a
                        fine of five dollars and costs of prosecution. Stenger for Com; Sharpe for
                        Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Dr. John Vandyne and Thomas D. French-Assault and Battery-Jemima
                        Scott, for Prosecutriz. Thomas D. French one of the defendants not havin
                        been arrested the trial proceeded as to Dr. John Vandyne. Verdict, not
                        Guilty, but deft to pay the costs of prosecution. Stenger and George Eyster,
                        Esq., for Com; Sharpe for deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs John Burkholder-Fornication and Bastardy-Rosanna Martin,
                        Prosecutrix-Deft pleads Guilty and the Court passed the usual sentence.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Jane Furley-Larceny of one bushel of Pears-Solomon Hollar,
                        Prosecutrix-Verdict, not Guilty. Stenger for Com; Sharpe for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Theodore Colby and David B. Greenawalt-Conspiracy to cheat and
                        defraud Dr. A. H. Senseny of $150 being the amount paid by Senseny to Colby
                        for a horse purchased from his which was afterwards seized by the
                        Government. The jury having been out about seven hours and failing to agree,
                        was discharged. Stenger, Kimmell and George Eyster for om; Sharpe and
                        Stumbaugh &amp; Gehr for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Samuel Richardson, William Cuff and William LeMott-Riot and Assault
                        and Battery-Samuel Johnson, Prosecutor-Defts found Guily of Assault and
                        Battery. Sentence of Richardson, a fine of eight dollars and costs of
                        prosecution-of Cuff and LeMott, a fine of ten dollars each and the costs.
                        Stenger and George Eyster for Com; Orr and Stewart for Defts.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Samuel Johnson-Surety of the Peace-William LeMott, Prosecutor-Court
                        refused to bind deft over to keep the peace but sentenced him to pay the
                        costs Stenger, Orr and Stewart for Com; Geo. Eyster, Esq., for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs John R. Turner-Assault and Battery-George Washington, Prosecutor-Deft
                        pleaded Guilty-sentenced to pay a fine of $5 and the costs. Stenger for Com;
                        Kimmell for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Same vs. Same-Assault and Battery-Wm. H. Davis, Prosecutor-Deft pleaded
                        Guilty-sentenced to pay a fine of $5 and the costs. Stenger for Com; Kimmell
                        for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Jame Andrews, John Andrews, and F. M. Andrews-Cruelty to
                        Animals-killing one hog and maiming another-Verdict, not Guilty-Prosecutor
                        to pay 2/3 of the costs, defts 1/3. Stenger and C. S. Eyster foor Com;
                        Sharpe for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs Joseph Thompson-Larceny of two turkeys-Benjamin Uglow,
                        Prosecutor-Verdict, Guilty. Deft decamped and the recognizance of bail was
                        forfeited.-Stenger for Com; George Eyster, Esq., for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Charles E. Wilder-Assault and Battery with intent to kill-Wm. E.
                        Hollowell, Prosecutor-Verdict, Guilty-not sentenced yet. Stenger and Kimmell
                        for Com; Brewer and Sharpe for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Same vs. same-Larceny of articles amounting to near $200-William E.
                        Hollowell, Prosecutor-Verdict, Guilty-not sentenced yet. Stenger and Kimmell
                        for Com; Brewer and Sharpe for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. William H. Boyd, William H. Boyd, Jr., John Reasner, Michael Houser
                        and Wm. H. Wannamaker-Charge of taking sand from the public road so as to
                        injure the road in divers ways-Samuel Keefer, Prosecutor-Defts pleaded
                        Guilty-a fine of five dollars and costs. Stenger, Brewer, and Kimmell for
                        Com; T. B. Kennedy, Stumbaugh &amp; Gehr for Defts.</p>
                    <p>Many cases were settled by the parties and several bills were ignored.</p>
                    <p>Dr. S. D. Kell, convicted at the April sessions of Perjury, was sentenced to
                        two years' imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary and to pay the costs of
                        prosecution.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stump</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stump</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stump</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zentmyer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Royer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barger</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vandyne</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holdry</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Furley</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colby</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenwait</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cuff</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>LeMott</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilder</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reasner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wannamaker</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The October term of several courts in the county opened on the 30th. The
                    following cases were disposed of: "Common Pleas--Commonwealth v. A. H. &amp;
                    G. H. Stump--feigned issue to test the right of Commonwealth to Collateral Tax
                    on the estate of Abraham Stump, dec'd--verdict for the defendants. Commonwealth
                    v. Daniel W. Royer--Action of Assumpsit on Note for $375--Verdict for Defendant.
                    Quarter Sessions--Commonwealth v. William Barger and John Riley--Malicious
                    Mischief--Sentence each to pay a fine of five dollars and costs of prosecution.
                    Commonwealth v. Dr. John Vandyne and Thomas D. French--Assault and
                    Battery--Verdict, not Guilty. Commonwealth v. Joseph Holdry--Assault and Battery
                    with intent to ravish Sarah J. Height--not Guilty on the grounds of insanity.
                    Commonwealth v. John Burkholder--Fornication and Bastardy--Deft pleads Guilty
                    and the Court passed the usual sentence. Commonwealth v. Jane Furley--Larceny of
                    one bushel of pears--Verdict, not Guilty. Commonwealth v. Theodore Colby and
                    David H. Greenwait--Conspiracy to cheat and defraud Dr. A.H. Senseny of $150
                    being the amount paid by Senseny to Colby for a horse purchased from him which
                    was afterward seized by the Government. The jury having been out about seven
                    hours and failing to agree, was discharged. Commonwealth v. Samuel Richardson,
                    William Cuff, and William Lemott--Riot and Assault and Battery--Deft found
                    Guilty of Assault and Battery. Sentence of Richardson, a fine of eight dollars
                    and costs of prosecution--of Cuff and LeMott, a fine of ten dollars each and the
                    costs. Commonwealth v. Samuel Johnson-- Surety of the Peace--Court refused to
                    bind deft over to keep the peace but sentenced him to pay the costs.
                    Commonwealth v. John R. Turner--Assault and Battery--Deft pleaded
                    Guilty--sentenced to pay a fine of $5 and costs. Commonwealth v. John R.
                    Turner--Assault and Battery--deft pleaded Guilty--sentenced to pay a fine of $5
                    and the costs. Commonwealth v. James Andrews, John Andrews, and F. M.
                    Andrews--Cruelty to Animals--killing one hog and maiming another--Verdict, not
                    Guilty. Commonwealth V. Joseph Thompson--Larceny of two turkeys--Verdict,
                    Guilty--Deft decamped and the recognizance of bail was forfeited. Commonwealth
                    v. Charles E. Wilder--Assault and Battery with intent to kill--Verdict,
                    Guilty--not sentenced yet. Commonwealth v. William H. Boyd, William H. Boyd,
                    Jr., John Reasner, Michael Houser, and William H. Wannamaker--Charge of taking
                    sand from public road so as to injure the road in divers ways--Defts pleaded
                    Guilty--a fine of five dollars and costs. Commonwealth v. S. D. Kell, convicted
                    at April sessions of Perjury was sentenced to two years imprisonment in the
                    Eastern Penitentiary and to pay the costs of prosecution."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Counterfeit Greenbacks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Philadelphia papers announce that a large number of counterfeit $20
                        greenbacks are in circulation in that city. They closely resemble the
                        genuine. 50s and 100s the same. 5s photographed, paper stiffer than the
                        genuine, and not so good. They have a blurred appearance, while the
                        signature show through more plainly than on the good note. 10s altered from
                        1s; vig. On upper left oval portrait of Chase, 10 below it; 10 on the upper
                        right; the signature of both Register and Treasurer are on the lower right
                        corner; they are well done and calculated to deceive the unwary; although
                        nothing like the genuine, which have for a vignette a spread eagle with 10
                        on each side; on the left is the portrait of President Lincoln, on the right
                        end a full length female figure; the signature of the Register is on the
                        lower left, and that of the Treasurer on the right; in the altered note they
                        are both on the right end, with two stripes of lath between them. 1s,
                        imitation of genuine. The green ink is somewhat lighter than the genuine;
                        some parts of the note are scratched. The head of Chase is darker. The bill
                        has a coarse appearance. 2s altered from 1s; portrait of Chase on upper left
                        corner.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that counterfeit $20 greenbacks have appeared in Philadelphia.
                    Though there are several discrepancies between the fake and authentic bills, the
                    copies "closely resemble the genuine."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--A Swindle</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Express</origin>
                <commentary>"A swindler, named Patterson, it appears, has been recently operating in
                    Lancaster county, pretending to be sutherland to collect money for the poor of
                    this place. The Lancaster <emph rend="italic">Express</emph> gives the following
                    account of his operation:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For some time past, the citizens of Manor township had reason to suspect that
                        a person calling himself Patterson, who was collecting money to that
                        township ostensibly for the relief of the Chambersburg poor, was an
                        imposter, and, accordingly, A. R. Witmer, Esq., set to work to ascertain
                        whether this man was an authorized agent to collect money for these
                        unfortunate people. He succeeded, after much difficulty, as the sequel will
                        show, in establishing the fact, beyond a doubt, that he was a swindler.
                        Patterson called on Mr. John H. Hershey, about the 25th of September, having
                        previously been collecting about Columbia. He had certificates signed by the
                        Cashier or President, or both, of Chambersburg Bank, the Prothonotary,
                        Sheriff, Judges of Court, and other public men of Franklin county, stating
                        that he was authorized by a committee there to collect for the suffering
                        poor of that place. Patterson is resident of Fawn township, York county,
                        where he owns property, but represented that he was from Chambersburg. Mr.
                        Hershey, who formerly resided in York county, said: "You are Bill Patterson
                        that I used to know in York county." Patterson answered: "No, I never lived
                        in York county, I live in Maryland." He, however, made no attempt to collect
                        more money in the neighborhood. He boasted after he went home, that he had
                        collected $600, in Manor township. He was so independent that he would not
                        take less than $5, in some instances. In other cases, where he was refused,
                        he wold afterards put down $5 or more to mislead others and induce
                        subscriptions. Several persons who had paid him money laid the matter before
                        A. R. Witmer, Esq., Justice of the Peace, who took means to ferret out the
                        matter, and delivered that Patterson still resided in York county; upon
                        which he issued a warrant for his arrest, had it backed by a Justice in York
                        county, and placed in the hands of J. B. Hess, the constable of Martie
                        township, for execution.-Mr. Hess proceeded to the village of Gatcheiville,
                        York county, where Patterson resides, on the 23 inst., and made the arrest.
                        Patterson professed to be able and willing to show that all was right, and
                        produced the certificate from the public men of Chambersburg, above referred
                        to, which Mr. Hess read and said he would keep; when Patterson snatched it
                        from him and a scuffle ensued. This took place in Patterson's house, and
                        Patterson's wife, two daughters and two sons, young men, coming to the
                        rescue, he finally got loose from the constable and ran for a thicket near
                        by, pursued by Mr. Hess, who tired three barrels of his revolver at him, and
                        he thinks hit him once, if not oftener; but his speed was too great to be
                        overtaken, and he got into the woods and made his escape.</p>
                    <p>It appears that there is a respectable man named Wm. Patterson in
                        Chambersburg, and who had authority to collect money for the sufferers , and
                        this man ascertaining this fact, forged the certificate referred to above
                        and personated the authorized collector.</p>
                    <p>A reward of $50 is offered for the arrest of Mr. Patterson.</p>
                    <p>We would say to our Lancaster county friends, that there is no "respectable
                        man named Wm. Patterson in Chambersburg, who had authority to collect money
                        for the sufferers, nor is <emph rend="italic">any</emph> person authorized
                        to collect money for any such purpose, at this time. If the Legislature, the
                        coming session, do an act of simple justice to our citizens by indemnifying
                        them for losses sustained through the public enemy, our people will be
                        abundantly able to take care of themselves, without appealing to the charity
                        of citizens of other portions of the commonwealth.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that a swindler by the name of Patterson is collecting money in
                    Lancaster county under the pretense that the donations are to be used to aid the
                    poor in Franklin county. A $50 reward is offered for Mr. Patterson's arrest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--The Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a highly critical review of the lecture given by G. O. Seilhamer,
                    Esq., on Oct 30th, which "failed entirely to instruct or amuse the audience of
                    about one hundred persons" who attended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Discharged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The battery at one time attached to the 77th Pa. regiment has been
                    discharged. The rest of the 77th is reportedly still in Texas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On Nov. 2nd, a boarder at Fisher's Union Hotel stole several furs and some
                    jewelry and clothing from the proprietor's wife. The culprit was caught the next
                    day in Carlisle and returned to Chambersburg to await a hearing. All of the
                    stolen items were recovered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Taxable Income</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists taxable incomes from Franklin county for the townships of Montgomery,
                    Warren, Peters, St. Thomas, Hamilton, Letterkenny, Fannett,and Metal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laverty</ln>
                        <fn>D. A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powders</ln>
                        <fn>D. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bean</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 30th, Lieut. D. L. Powders and Mattie E. Bean were married by Rev.
                    D. A. L. Laverty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>Elam G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elam G. Frantz and Mattie B. Funk were wed on Oct. 31st, by Rev. W. E.
                    Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>Bella C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bella C. Glass and John B. Allen, of Northampton county, were married on
                    Nov. 2nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>R. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rechdel</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 20th, R. E. Crooks and Kate Rechdel, of Washington county, Md.,
                    were wed in a ceremony presided over by Rev. William Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Stouffer and Mary Hoover were married by Rev. William Eyster, on Nov.
                    5th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoovee</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 5th, Rev. William Eyster presided over the ceremony that united
                    Thomas Cunningham and Rebecca Hoovee in matrimony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhnes</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Gordon and Catherine Kuhnes were married on Oct. 19th, by Rev.
                    William Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Kate C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. John C. Kennedy, of Washington county, Ill., and Kate C. Kennedy were
                    wed on Oct. 28th, by Rev. Wightman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Fry died on Oct. 27th, in Quincy township. Fry, 77, was a highly
                    respected member of the community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sumner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Sumner, 39, died on Oct 29th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Henry F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 26th, Henry Stover, 26, died in Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhea</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhea</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 14th, Maria Rhea, wife of John Rhea, died near Mercerburg. Mrs.
                    Rhea was 63 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Kennedy, 74, died on Oct 13th, in Mercerburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Miriam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Miriam Boyd, daughter of Capt. Robert Boyd, died on Oct. 22nd. Anna
                    was 8 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.11.08.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
