<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.09.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/15/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-09-20">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="00">20</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.09.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Address of the Democratic State Central Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the People of Pennsylvania:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>In accordance with its time-honored, annual custom, the Democratic party
                        reaffirms its principles and presents its candidates for your suffrages. Of
                        those principles and candidates it is our purpose now to speak.</p>
                    <p>Thanks to Almighty God, the patriotism of the people and prowess of our
                        citizen-soldiery, the terrible war that for four years has devastated our
                        country and repeatedly laid waste our own fair valleys has ended. The
                        Confederate Government, its armies and its animating doctrine, secession,
                        lie prostrate at the feet of the people of the Union. The tramp of armed men
                        and the crash of battle are no longer heard, and the recuperative energies
                        of the people will speedily fill the air with the sound of the busy arts of
                        peace. The soldier yields place to the citizen, the commander gives way to
                        the statesman. The power of force is succeeded by the power of reason,
                        justice and law. The soldier's duty of unquestioning obedience to the orders
                        of a superior is supplanted by the more rational but not less imperative
                        obligation of obedience to the law.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">The Supremacy of the Law.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Whether we be citizen or soldier, officer or statesman, ruler or ruled, this
                        obligation rests with equal weight on each and all of us. The doctrine of
                        implicit and unqualified obedience to the Constitution and laws of our
                        country is now, and in all time past has been, a prominent tenet in the
                        faith of the Democracy of Pennsylvania, and they have invariably been found
                        denouncing by voice and opposing by act those traitorous principles which
                        seek to weaken the blinding force of the Constitution, attempt to nullify
                        the plainest provisions thereof, or actuate those who aim to subvert it by
                        force of arms. The Federal Constitution had power enough, had its mandates
                        been observed in the spirit in which they were framed, and the warnings of
                        the Democratic party been heeded, to have preserved us from the war through
                        which we have just passed, and to have saved the nation from the stupendous
                        sacrifices of the blood of her slaughtered sons, the waste of her national
                        power and prestige, and the fearful load of debt and taxation that now
                        encumbers her. When the nation was precipitated into war, obedience to the
                        plainest provisions of that Constitution would have protected the most
                        precious privileges of a free people, and preserved to the patriotic people
                        of the country both the form and substance of the national bill of rights;
                        and now that "arms are silent and the laws resume their away," a strict
                        observance of its requirements, a rigid enforcement of its obligations in
                        all the States, and fealty to their official oaths by those in power, are
                        the indices which point the way to harmonious unity, permanent peace, and a
                        speedy resumption of our career of prosperity and progress. The arbitrary
                        and uncontrolled will of the temporary incumbent of place ought not to rule
                        our Government, and we hold "that the Constitution established by our
                        (revolutionary) fathers is entitled to our unqualified respect and
                        obedience, the oath to support it is binding, religiously, morally and
                        legally, at all times, under all circumstances, and in every part of the
                        country, upon all public officers, from the highest to the lowest, as well
                        as upon private citizens." The Democracy of Pennsylvania are for the
                        supremacy of the law.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Free Government.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p> The great central objects round which are grouped the materials, and for
                        which was constructed the simple and harmonious machinery of our system of
                        government are "the blessings of liberty for <emph rend="italic"
                        >ourselves</emph> and our posterity." They who formed it, created no
                        government to administer theories, or to protect imaginary rights from
                        imaginary enemies, but as brave and practical men, deeply imbued with the
                        spirit of liberty, and fresh from the bloody civil struggle of the
                        revolution, they knew from bitter experience the value of those blessings,
                        and in the light of that experience they formed a government of law, and not
                        of arbitrary power, a government to guard their civil liberties, and not to
                        overthrow them. The fundamental principles of free government guaranteed to
                        us by the plain words of the Constitution, distinctly reserved, and to be
                        forever held as inviolable, <emph rend="italic">habeas corpus</emph>, trial
                        by jury, the subordination of the military to the civil authority, free
                        speech and a free press, form the very essence of our institutions; and when
                        they who administer the government fail to protect us in the exercise of
                        these rights; when they who have carried on a gigantic war in the name of
                        the Constitution, not only fail to maintain its fuandamental principles, but
                        are habitually guilty of their violation, is it not our duty to turn them
                        from the seats of power they so shamefully misuse, and to require at their
                        hands reparation for the many wrongs unnecessarily inflicted?--'From the day
                        that Runnymede had its name linked with human freedom to this hour every man
                        of Anglo-Saxon blood has lifted his head more proudly when he heard the
                        great test of manhood repeated. <emph rend="italic">No man shall be taken or
                            imprisoned or disposessed of his free tenements or liberties, or
                            outlawed or banished, or by anywise hurt or injured, unless by the legal
                            judgment of his peers or by the law of the land.</emph> Dearer than
                        dynastics, dearer than forms of government, dearer than the inborn sentiment
                        of loyalty to the English heart, has always been the right of trial by jury.
                        For two hundred years it has been more than his crown was worth for an
                        English King to deny this right to an English subject." Yet these principles
                        inwrought with the vitals of our system, baptized with the blood of patriots
                        during six hundred years, and wrenched from the hand of tyranny for our
                        benefit, we have basely yielded to the unquestioned control of those in
                        power. And during the past four years again and again, have freemen,
                        American freemen, freemen of Pennsylvania, been "taken and imprisoned,
                        dispossessed of their free tenements and liberties," and "outlawed and
                        banished," and "hurt and injured," without "the legal judgment of their
                        peers," and contrary to "the law of the land." And this too within our own
                        Commonwealth, at a time when no hostile drum-beat was heard, and no armed
                        soldier lifted his hand against the government within all our borders. </p>
                    <p> At this hour, when military necessity can no longer be made the pretext for
                        their continuance, when the authority of the Federal Government is admitted
                        and recognized, in all the land, these abuses still exist. The courts
                        created by law are in abeyance, and tribunals unknown to the Constitution
                        and laws usurp their power over life, liberty and property. The great writ
                        of freedom that assures every individual the protection of civil authority
                        is fettered by the hand of arbitrary power, and the citizen is denied the
                        right of trial by a jury of his peers.--The Democratic party of Pennsylvania
                        believe that THE HOUR HAS COME in which murders by military commissions
                        should cease; the right of trial by twelve calm, impartial sworn citizens,
                        should be restored and the privilege of the writ of <emph rend="italic"
                            >habeas corpus</emph> be free as the air. </p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">The Rights of the States</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Aside from these great cardinal doctrines, the supremacy of the law and the
                        inviolability of the fundamental principles of free government, there is no
                        subject more closely allied with the preservation of our form of government
                        and the protection of our liberties, than that of the relations of the
                        states to the Federal Government. Both were created for the benefit of the
                        people and within the spheres of power granted or reserved to each, each is
                        supreme.</p>
                    <p> The obligation of the citizen to the Federal Government within the scope of
                        the powers granted to it is binding and imperative, and no one can absolve
                        him from his duty thereto. So, also, the power of the States over these
                        matters not expressly granted to the Federal Government or reserved to the
                        people, is equally clear, and the duty of the citizen thereto is equally
                        imperative and binding. Upon the other hand, in their attempt to interfere
                        with the powers granted to the Federal Government by the people, all
                        ordinances of secession were utterly void, and the insurrection being
                        suppressed, the States resume their place in the Union and the penalties
                        incurred fall upon the individuals engaged in the rebellion. So, too, upon
                        the other hand, it is the right of each State to determine for itself the
                        qualifications of its electors without interference by other States or by
                        the Federal Government. Such is the doctrine of the Democracy and such
                        appears to be the policy of the President, and yet, sectional prejudice, the
                        love of gain, increasing wrath and deeply masked political purposes,
                        seriously obstruct the process of reconstruction and reconciliation; and
                        they who should be foremost in attempting to restore the harmonious unity of
                        the nation are loudest in denunication and most zealous in pursuit of a
                        fallen foe. As between the Federal Government and the States in which the
                        people have been in rebellion against its authority, the only issue during
                        the war was how should be the restoration of that authority. The tread of no
                        hostile soldiery presses the soil of one of them <emph rend="italic"
                        >now</emph>. In no one of them is there aught of objection <emph
                            rend="italic">now</emph> to the assessment and collection of Federal
                        taxes, to the creation of Federal custom houses, courts and postoffices, or
                        to the peaceful transit of munitions of war and troops.--The wonderful
                        exhibition of a devastated country, of defeated armies, of a humiliated
                        people and of emacipated slaves, ought to be sufficient to arouse the
                        sympathies and engage the purest devotion of the Christian and the
                        statesman; but unconcerned at the condition of the white people of the
                        States, desirous only to perpetuate their political power, regardless of the
                        vital interests of six millions of their own race, and of the importance of
                        their rehabilitation in the Union, the leaders of the Republican party, as a
                        condition precedent to their restoration and to the release of the reign of
                        military authority over a conquered and submissive people, demand that the
                        negro shall be placed upon a political equality with the white man, and they
                        insist upon the use of the arm of the Federal Government to effect it, and
                        are moving for an an amendment of the Federal Constitution to perpetuate it. </p>
                    <p>Such a practical interference would be a palpable infraction of the
                        Constitution, a gross and unauthorized increase of central power, and a
                        wanton overthrow of the rights of the States. This doctrine gives to a
                        citizen of Massachusetts, the right to aid in prescribing the qualification
                        and color of the voter in North Carolina, and in practice will give to the
                        black man the control of the great States of Louisiana, Mississippi, and
                        South Carolina, and will send six black men to the Senate of the United
                        States.</p>
                    <p>This, in all its breadth and with a full understanding of its results is the
                        doctrine of the Republican party of Pennsylvania, for the 4th resolution
                        adopted by the Republican State Convention, held at Harrisburg, on the 17th
                        of August, 1865, distinctly so asserts. It is as follows:</p>
                    <p> "<emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That, having conquered the rebellious
                        States, they should be held in subjugation, and the treatment they are to
                        receive, and the laws which are to govern them should be referred to the
                        law-making power of the nation, to which they legitimately belong." </p>
                    <p>With this doctrine we take distinct issue. The States of the South are in the
                        Union, and the people thereof, excetp those on whom the penalties for
                        rebellion fall, are entitled to all their political privileges, and we
                        affirm that these States are entitled to all the reserved rights of the
                        States under the Federal Constitution, and within the spheres of those
                        reserved rights, they, and they alone, have the power to make and unmake the
                        laws that are to govern them.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Negro Equality and Negro Suffrage.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Negro equality and negro suffrage are no longer a mythical issue, but are
                        part of the vital, practical realities of the present hour. They are
                        demanded by the black man; they are advocated by white men high in power in
                        the National Government, AND WE CHARGE THAT they are endorsed and sanctioned
                        by a large majority of the Republican party of the North, including those
                        who govern and control that party in Pennsylvania. Let us examine some of
                        the evidences upon which we found this charge.</p>
                    <p>The States of Maine, New Hampshire, Vermont, Rhode Island and Massachusetts
                        by constitutional provision, give to the black man the unrestricted right of
                        suffrage. These States are all under Republican control, and their
                        politicians lead the van in the crusade they hope is to result in the
                        degradation of the white race to the level of the black.</p>
                    <p> The Senate of the United States, on the 31st of March, 1864 (see <emph
                            rend="italic">Congressional Globe</emph> p. 1361), had before it a bill
                        for the construction of the territory of Montano. Mr. Wilkinson moved to
                        strike from the second line of the fifth section (which defined the
                        qualification of voters) the words, "<emph rend="italic">white</emph> male
                        inhabitants," and insert the words "male citizens of the United States,"
                        &amp;c., which was agreed to as follows: </p>
                    <p>"YEAS: Messrs. Brown, Chandler, Clark, Colamer, Conness, Dixon, Fessenden,
                        Foot, Foster, Grimes, Hale, harlan, Harris, Howard, Howe, Morgan, Morrill,
                        Pomeroy, Sumner, Wade, Wilkinson, Wilson,--22.</p>
                    <p>NAYS: Messrs. Buckalew, Carlile, Cowan, Davis, Harding, Henderson, Johnson,
                        Lane, Nesmith, Powell, Riddle, Saulsbury, Sherman, Ten Eyck, Trumbull, Van
                        Winkle, Willey--17."</p>
                    <p>Those who thus voted to place the black man on an equality with the white in
                        one of the richest territories of the Union, will readily be recognized as
                        the leaders of the Republican party in the Senate.</p>
                    <p> This subject came up in the House of Representatives on the 15th of April,
                        1864, (<emph rend="italic">Congressional Globe</emph>, p. 1652), the motion
                        pending being the appointment of a committee of conference on the
                        disagreement between the Senate and House on striking out the word, "white."
                        Mr. Webster moved "that said committee be instructed to agree to no report
                        that authorizes any other than free <emph rend="italic">white</emph> male
                        citizens to vote." On the question of the adoption of these instructions,
                        the following named Republican Congressmen from Pennsylvania voted NAY:
                        Messrs. Broomall, Kelly, Myers, O'Nell, Stevens, Thayer and Williams. No
                        Pennsylvania Republicans voted YEA. </p>
                    <p>The Republican State Convention of Maine, lately in session, in the 8th
                        resolution declares in favor of negro suffrage, as follows: "That the
                        emancipation of President Lincoln, the enlistment of over 100,000 colored
                        troops, the good faith of the colored race amid treason, and their being
                        paid like whites and placed in the most dangerous places, has pledged the
                        national honor that these people shall have in fact, as well as name
                        conferred on them all the political rights of freedom, and that the people
                        of the United States will redeem this pledge."</p>
                    <p>The Republican Conventions of the States of Iowa and Vermont have
                        emphatically endorsed the doctrines of negro equality and negro suffrage,
                        and placed their candidates squarely upon that platform.</p>
                    <p>H. Winter Davis, of Maryland, at Chicago, said:</p>
                    <p> "<emph rend="italic">We need the votes of the colored people; it is numbers,
                            not intelligence, that counts at the ballot-box--it is the right
                            intention, and not philosophic judgement, that casts the vote</emph>." </p>
                    <p> Rev. Henry Ward Beecher, in the <emph rend="italic">Independent</emph> of
                        recent date, says: </p>
                    <p> "We are pleading earnestly with the State to abolish the distinction of
                        caste by universal suffrage. We see that this will inevitably lead, not to
                        the end the present Governor or Louisiana declares the surrender of that
                        country to the black man--<emph rend="italic">but the equality of black with
                            the white; the occupancy of office without regard to color; the
                            elevation of the negro to the Governorship, the Senatorship, the
                            Judgeship, by the side of his whiter kindred; the obliteration of all
                            marks of distinction and separation between men and men</emph>." </p>
                    <p>These are representative men of the Republican party, and they have wielded a
                        powerful influence in its ranks.</p>
                    <p>In our own State a number of Republican county conventions have fully
                        endorsed this doctrine. Crawford county, at convention held at Meadville,
                        June 27, 1865, resolved that</p>
                    <p> "Loyalty to the government should be the <emph rend="italic">only</emph>
                        test of the right of suffrage--those who have fought to preserve the Union
                        on the field of battle, whether white or <emph rend="italic">black</emph>,
                        are certainly worthy and fit to protect it through the <emph rend="italic"
                            >ballot-box</emph>--it is unworthy the age in which we live to deprive
                        men of voting who sustain the government by their treasure and blood." </p>
                    <p>The Republican County Conventions of Northampton, Union and Allegheny have
                        also broadly endorsed these doctrines.</p>
                    <p>The question of the right of the negro to social equality was before the
                        Legislature of Pennsylvania at its last session. On February 8th, 1865, the
                        bill to prevent any passenger railway company from excluding colored people
                        from their cars came up in the Senate, and finally passed that
                        body.--Seventeen Republicans (all who voted) voted for the bill, and
                        fourteen Democrats against it. It was sent to the House for concurrence; and
                        on the 23d of March, 1865, it came up in the House on a motion to discharge
                        the committee. Forty-six Republicans voted yea, and twenty-eight Democrats
                        voted nay. (See Leg. Rec., pages 210 and 710.)</p>
                    <p> Nearly all the prominent Republican newspapers of the State have also avowed
                        themselves favorable to negro suffrage, and yet, strange to say, the
                        Republican State Convention failed to meet the issues, and seek to conceal
                        their true sentiments beneat the ambiguous working of a resolution. The
                        third resolution declares that the Southern people "cannot safely be
                        entrusted with the political rights which they forfeited by their treason,
                        until they have proven their acceptance of the <emph rend="italic">results
                            of the war</emph> by incorporating them in constitutional provisions,
                        and securing to <emph rend="italic">all</emph> men within their borders
                        their inalienable right to life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness. </p>
                    <p>Who so blind as not to see that this may or may not be a declaration in favor
                        of negro suffrage? Can any man doubt that this means when he remembers that
                        Thaddeus Stevens, the radical leader of the last National House of
                        Representatives, was a prominent member of that convention?--Can any man
                        doubt what Henry C. Johnson, the President of the convention meant and
                        expressed when he declared the passage of this two-faced resolution. If he
                        remembers that Mr. Johnson received his credentials from that very
                        convention in Crawford county which declared that "loyalty should be the
                        only test of the right of suffrage."</p>
                    <p>Pennsylvanians, the serious importance of the issue involved, and a just
                        regard for your intelligence, demanded a manly declaration of opinion upon
                        this subject; but the leaders of the Republican party know your detestation
                        for their degrading doctrines, and they seek to obtain by double dealing
                        your support to sentiments they dare not avow.</p>
                    <p> The problem of the capacity of man, the white man, for self-government is
                        being solved in the history of the American Republic, and in the face of the
                        recent exhibition of the physical and mental qualities of the Causasian
                        race, in view of the mighty power of the nation as displayed in the heroism,
                        endurance and indomitable energy of the white soldiers of our armies, and in
                        the stupendous sacrifice of the blood and treasure of the people, the
                        Democracy of Pennsylvania unhesitatingly announce their belief in its
                        successful result. "We will not acknowledge the incapacity of our own race
                        to govern itself, nor surrender the destiny of the country into the hands of
                        negroes, nor put ourselves under their guardianship, nor give up to them the
                        political privileges which we inherited from our fathers." Whether the blood
                        of the Anglo-Saxon, the Celt or the Teuton flows in our veins, there are but
                        few among us who do not feel it tingle with a thrill of just shame when he
                        is pronounced to be <emph rend="italic">only</emph> the equal of the negro
                        of Dahomey or of Congo. Call this prejudice, or what you may, it exists, and
                        the statesman who desires the peace, and happiness and the prosperity of boh
                        races can not ignore it. Give the black man equal political rights in our
                        country and you give him equal social rights. Give him equal political
                        rights, and you multiply the points of contrast between the races, and the
                        weaker and inferior must yield place to the stronger and superior. The law
                        must recognize his equality or his inferiority; there is no middle
                        ground.--We believe in the superiority of our race, and we are unwilling to
                        degrade ourselves either socially or politically. </p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Retrenchment.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The Democratic party have ever been zealous for the preservation of the
                        national credit, and this hour demand rigid economy in the expenditure of
                        the public money and a prompt revision of our cumbrous and inquisitorial
                        system of taxation; a just regard for an already burthened people demands
                        that a horde of Federal office holders, assesssors and tax-collectors, be
                        dispensed with, and the machinery of the State Governments used in their
                        room. The retention by the Federal Government of large numbers of officers
                        of the army, whist the private soldier is discharged and sent to his home,
                        also imposes additional and unnecessary burdens upon the people. Can the
                        people expect these reforms to come whilst the men who created the abuses
                        remain in power?</p>
                    <p> The Democracy of Pennsylvania have no reply to make to denunciation or
                        invective. They <emph rend="italic">refer with pride</emph> to their record
                        during the past four years. Like the historic people of the scriptures,
                        whilst engaged in the repair of the walls that protected their Holy City,
                        they have with one hand engaged in earnest toil in protecting and preserving
                        the Constitution and laws of their country, whilst the other grasped the
                        sword that aided in destroying those who violently assailed them. Amid the
                        blandishments of power, the persecutions of official tyranny and the corrupt
                        and reckless use of the public money, they have been ever bold in the
                        expression of their opinions, and have unswervingly maintained their
                        principles and their integrity. During that time they have once elected
                        their ticket, twice carried the State on the home vote, and at the last
                        election polled over 276,000 votes for the candidate of their choice. </p>
                    <p>Such a body of men, tried, determined, and organized, a unit in support of
                        their glorious principles, must ever be a power in the State, and will be
                        feared by its enemies, and respected by all.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Our Statndard Bearers</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>For Auditor General, Colonel W.W.H. Davis, of Bucks county, heads the
                        ticket.--Colonel Davis is a sound, practical man, well qualified for the
                        position, and of that stern integrity of character so much needed in this
                        day of official prostitution and degeneracy. As a soldier, his record stands
                        equal to that of the best and purest. When the war broke out, he raised a
                        company and served for a term of three months. At the expiration of that
                        term of service he raised a regiment--the 104th Pennsylvania--and as Colonel
                        of that regiment went through the war. He was in many of the most severe
                        battles; was wounded severely at the desperate affair at Fair Oaks, before
                        Richmond, and lost a hand in the neighborhood of Charleston, South
                        Carolina.--Maimed as he was, Colonel Davis remained in the field until the
                        three years for which his regiment was raised had expired, when as the war
                        was then virtually at an end, he returned to private life. Such is the
                        record of the honest man and brave soldier who heads the State ticket of the
                        Democratic party of Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p>The nominee for Survyeor General is Lieut. Col. John P. Linton, of Cambria
                        county. Like Col. Davis, this gentleman is an honest, intelligent, upright
                        citizen, and a brave soldier. He was chosen Major of the 54th regiment,
                        P.V., in 1861 and Lieut. Col. of the same regiment, in February, 1863. He
                        was constantly in the field, and bears upon his person numerous scars as
                        testimonials of his gallantry. Col. Linton had the honor of leading the 54th
                        in the battles of Newmarket and Piedmont. And most bravely and gallantly he
                        led his regiment on thos disastrous fields. In both these battles he was
                        severely wounded, but although for a time compelled to go home for
                        treatment, he scarcely remained long enough from his past to fully
                        recover--so wedded was he to his regiment, his duty and the serious work
                        required of him.--This gentleman is well worthy of the nomination he has
                        received, and of the suffrages of citizens of his native State. As our
                        standard has inherited [unclear] true principles of the Democratic party,
                        and its chosen bearers are brave, honest men, the Democracy of the State
                        must and will rally to its support with a zeal and determination that will
                        prove irrisistible.</p>
                    <p>Men of Pennsylvania: the issues are before you, fraught with the greatest
                        consequences to yourselves, your country, and your race. Weigh well your
                        action and decide as white freemen should.</p>
                    <p>By order of the Democratic State Central Committee. WILLIAM A. WALLACE</p>
                    <p>Sept 8, 1865 Chairman</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a transcript of the address given by William W. Wallace, Chairman
                    of the State Democratic Party, at the State Central Committee Meeting on Sept.
                    8th. In his speech, Wallace focused on several topics, including the supremacy
                    of the law, the importance of free government, and the rights of the states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Disposition of the South</head>
                <origin>Journal of the Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The leading men, especially the officers of the late rebel army, indicate
                    an earnest and faithful desire to carry out the views of President Johnson."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is not argueable to see in some Northern quarters a manifest determination
                        to keep up a sectional contest. It is not surprising that men should be
                        found to publish such statements as abound in papers of a certain class, but
                        it will be very surprising if, in the face of evidence so overwhelming,
                        these falsehoods obtain any belief among the mass of the people. The
                        reiteration of the assertions that the Southern people intend to continue
                        rebellions, that they show no disposition to accept the Union as a fixed
                        fact, that they are sullen, ill disposed, fractious, violent when they
                        dare--all those frequently repeated statements are without support in fact,
                        and are contrary to the whole evidence which pours in on us from hour to
                        hour.</p>
                    <p>President Johnson's steadfast adherence to his own marked line of policy
                        ought to silence these slanders, since it cannot be doubted that the
                        President has the very best information in regard to the Southern people,
                        and his entire course seems based on the conviction that they are cheerfully
                        and in good faith engaged in the work of undoing the errors of the past and
                        restoring peace and prosperity in loyalty to the Union. It would seem
                        however that not a few of the Northern newspapers are engaged in a
                        systematic attempt to embarass the President. Hence these ingeniously
                        devised falsehoods, chiefly founded on letters professing to come from the
                        South and bearing date at Southern places but which have evidently been
                        written by the same hand which writes the commenting editorial.</p>
                    <p>From a careful observation of the condition of things at the South, and from
                        extensive correspondence and conversation with Southern men, we are
                        convinced that there is a determination in all minds to sustain heartily and
                        sincerely the Union and the Constitution. The results of the war are
                        accepted in their entirety. There is no disposition on the part of any one
                        to dispute cavil or resist. The leading men, especially the officers of the
                        late rebel army, indicate an earnest and faithful desire to carry out the
                        views of President Johnson. They are sometimes asked why they do not leave
                        the country and the reply is that they do not feel that they have a right to
                        go; they have a duty to perform as far as their influence extends in leading
                        the people to hearty submission and cordial support of the President and the
                        Union. In this spirit they deserve commendation, and we have reason to
                        believe that they are acting with perfect good faith and with an honest
                        desire to strengthen the Union cause. The idea of rebellion is dead. The
                        notion of secession is wholly obliterated. It does not exist and if it ever
                        rears its head again, it is infinitely more probable that it will be in New
                        England than in the South.</p>
                    <p>President Johnson's policy as indicated in his course thus far, is
                        unquestionably wise with reference to the state of things as we have viewed
                        it. The people of the South are as ready for self government as the people
                        of the North. Here and there military occupation continues a necessity from
                        local causes, but this necessity is rapidly disappearing and we have no
                        doubt the President is as anxious as any one for the total cessation of any
                        such requirements.</p>
                    <p>Still we find that men are busy at the North keeping up excitement and
                        enmity. The object is now apparent. With the opening of the next Congress
                        comes the question of the re-admission of Southern States and people to
                        representation at Washington. A law exists, to which our readers will
                        remember we have repeatedly called their attention, which was expressly
                        designed by its inventors to meet the present state of affairs. The more
                        readical members of Congress took advantage of a time of excitement to
                        secure the co-operation of some of the conservative, and passed an act
                        providing in substance that no man should hold office under the United
                        States who did not first take an oath that he had not voluntarily consented
                        to or had any part in the rebellion. This law excludes nearly all the South
                        from office. The President has already indicated his view of the
                        unconstitutionality or inoperative effect of this law in his appointment of
                        office-holders at the South, and it remains to be seen whether Congress will
                        or will not sustain the President. When members elect from Southern States
                        come to the House of Representatives, the question of administering this
                        oath will at once arise. The supporters of the President will vote to omit
                        the oath, and admit the representatives. The opposition will insist on the
                        oath, which will be substantially insisting on no representation of Southern
                        States at Washington. It is with reference to this state of affairs that a
                        portion of the Northern press is circulating the stories of continued
                        Southern enmity, and endeavoring to keep alive the fires of sectional
                        animosity. There can be but one result in national politics of such a
                        course. The democrats will sustain the President and the republicans must
                        sustain, or oppose, or divide. Those who vote against the admission of
                        representatives will not only take the position of opponents, but will
                        virtually censure the entire policy of the President. In the end, the
                        probability is that the President, with his supporters, will succeed and the
                        disunionist faction will fail.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarking on the negative impact of the Radicals' anti-Southern rhetoric,
                    the article urges the President to silence the most outspoken members of this
                    group. Pockets of resistance to Union authority remain, the article admits, but
                    the situation is not serious enough to warrant a large-scale, lengthy occupation
                    of the region.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.09.20.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The division line has been drawn. Consolidationists, centralizationists,
                    negrophilists, advocates of sweeping confiscation, unlimited executions, negro
                    suffrage, and territorial or provincial puilage [sic], are arrayed on one side.
                    On the other are the friends of the Republic--the admirers of Republican
                    institutions--the believers in the superiority of the white race and the
                    opponents of military tribunals."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p> THE "signs of the times" indicate an overwhelming triumph for the Democracy.
                        The disintegration of the Republican party has begun. the radical and
                        conservative wings are at daggers' points. The extreme shoddyites of New
                        England cannot see anything to admire in President Johnson. Ever since the
                        war began, they have been plotting and laboring for the total destruction of
                        the doctrine of State Rights. They have been fondly cherishing the idea of a
                        strong central government. Consolidation has been the object for which they
                        have been working. President Johnson, however, in the most emphatic
                        language, declares himself a friend to States' Rights. He announces himself
                        as an uncompromising enemy of consolidation or centralization; with one
                        sentence form his mouth he blasts the hopes of the radicals. The lovers of
                        miliatary despotism--the "higher law" advocates, who imagine that the States
                        have no rights which the Federal Government is bound to respect are silenced
                        by a single stroke of the Presidential pen. True to his old Democratic
                        antecedents, the President plants his foot upon the Constitution, adopts his
                        "restoration" policy in the light of the Constitution, and intimates very
                        strongly that he is not to be driven from his position by the lying
                        statements of unprincipled newspaper correspondents, the well-dissembled
                        thrusts of Pennsylvania politicians, under the leadership of Stevens, or the
                        open attacks of the New England fanatics, Sumner, Wilson <emph rend="italic"
                            >et id omne genus</emph>. </p>
                    <p> No one need fear that the President is wanting in "back-bone." Unlike his
                        predecessor, "the pressure" will never be so strong as to cause him to
                        violate his convictions of right, and to abandon the plain path of duty.
                        Howl on, ye never ceasing agitators--ye lovers of the filthy, greasy negro,
                        in preference to the noble Caucasian--ye greedy cormorants who hope to fill
                        your private coffers out of confiscated Southern estates--ye blood-thirsty
                        demons whose deep seated revenge would rejoice in the extermination of
                        helpless women and children--howl on--yes, weep and wail, and gnash your
                        teeth; for thank God, <emph rend="italic">your own</emph> President, the man
                        elected Vice-President by your own legal votes, has the spirit of "Andrew
                        Jackson" in him. His voice has the old "by the Eternal" ring in it. His
                        purpose once conscienciously formed, is as unchangeable as the laws of the
                        Medes and Persians. His policy once marked out, as well might you attempt to
                        move Gibralter as to alter it. Lay the flattering unction to your souls, ye
                        restless, revolutionary spirits, that you have an ally in the President. </p>
                    <p>The division line has been drawn. Consolidationists, centralizationists,
                        negrophilists, advocates of sweeping confiscation, unlimited executions,
                        negro suffrage and territorial or provincial ppuilage, are arrayed on one
                        side. On the other, are the friends of the Republic--the admirers of
                        Republican institutions--the believers in the superiority of the white race
                        and the opponents of military tribunals. Radicalism and conservatism are the
                        two hostile elements in the Republican party. It is in the pangs of
                        dissolution, the Democracy await its death with complacent satisfaction. It
                        is your fight, gentlemen.</p>
                    <p>Meanwhile, the Union is in imminent danger. The radical theory adopted, the
                        Republic totters to its fall; allow the Federal Government to control the
                        domestic affairs of the States, and they sink into a condition of the most
                        abject vassalage. Let Congress dictate as to who shall and who shall not
                        exercise the right of suffrage in the States, and the States are reduced to
                        mere dependencies upon a central despotism; admit the negro to the rights of
                        citizenship and the pride of our race is broken. This government, framed by
                        white men, to be administered by white men for the benefit of white men,
                        will become an instrument in the hands of New England fanatics, to be used
                        for the political and social equalization of the races.</p>
                    <p>Against all this, the Democratic party presents a solid, impenetrable front.
                        It goes into this contest believing that "thrice is he armed, who hat his
                        quarrel just," cherishing its own time-honored pricples. Drawn from the
                        Constitution of our fathers, its weapons are those of truth and justice. It
                        endorses the "restoration" policy of the President, because it believes it
                        to be the constitutional method of restoring the Union. It denies the right
                        of the Federal Government to exclude the citizens of the southern States
                        from the full rights of citizenship provided they comply with the provisions
                        of the Constitution and the requirements of the President under the
                        Constitution.</p>
                    <p>It seeks to heal the wounds of our unhappy civil strife. It would assuage the
                        bitterness which exists between the two sections. it rejoices in the fact
                        that from Maine to Florida, and form ocean to ocean, the broad land rests in
                        peace. The dove has come back from her flight over the wide range of carnage
                        and desolation, bearing in her mouth the olive branch. The Democratic party
                        seeks to introduce a new era of harmony and good will.</p>
                    <p>It denounces the greedy spirit which would enrich a few office-holders at the
                        expense, and to the infinite distress of the great body of the Southern
                        people.</p>
                    <p>It holds that sufficient blood has already been shed, and that the mantle of
                        a general amnesty had better be thrown over all political offenders.</p>
                    <p>Its peculiar duty is to see that the Republic receives no detriment--that
                        Republican institutions shall continue to be the boast of the American
                        citizen as they were in the days of Jefferson and Jackson, opposed to
                        treason as presented in the form of secession and consolidation, as urged by
                        the politicians of the New England school, it draws itself as a wall of fire
                        around the Constitution, determined to preserve, at any cost, the integrity
                        of our grand nationality.</p>
                    <p>It denies the equality of the black man with the white, and brands as an
                        atrocious lie, the statements that in our late bloody struggle, "the negro
                        has borne the palm." It accepts the issue made by the radicals and says
                        unhesitatingly, that Pennsylvania's white soldiers and white citizens ought
                        never to be degraded by the admission of the negro to the rights of
                        citizenship.</p>
                    <p>These are your principles, Democrats.--Rally around the good old Democratic
                        banner as in days of yore. Give utterance to your principles at the polls,
                        speak, write and work for the cause of Democracy which is the cause of your
                        country.</p>
                    <p>Turn the confusion of your opponents into an overwhelming defeat. Firm,
                        strong, united, make one brilliant chage upon the enemy and you will rout
                        him "horse, foot and dragoons."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After announcing the demise of the Republicans, the article castigates the
                    party's platform and predicts dangerous repercussions if the Radicals manage to
                    consolidate their power in the next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Northern Accomplice of Wirz</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The responsibility of the failure of an exchange of prisoners, says the
                        Pittsburg <emph rend="italic">Post</emph>, has been placed upon Edwin M.
                        Stanton with a force that cannot be controverted.--This Wirz trial at
                        Washington is, in great part, a mere attempt to shift the blame from Stanton
                        to a rebel officer who has made himself odious, or been made so, by the
                        industrious circulation by the War Department of <emph rend="italic">ex
                            parte</emph> statements. Stanton could have affected an exchange of
                        prisoners--was invited by the rebels to do so. All that was wanted was his
                        assent to the rebel proposition. They waved every point on the negro soldier
                        and agreed to exchange man for man. <emph rend="italic">But Stanton
                        refused</emph>.--Thirty thousand of our bravest soldiers were permitted by
                        this detestable tyrant to rot and die in the rebel prisons; and for what
                        reason? Clearly because the terms of enlistment of most of them has expired,
                        and Statnton was unwilling to permit an exchange, as the rebel soldiers
                        released by the proposed cartel, would be again forced into the insurgent
                        armies, while our men would return to their homes. That our men were treated
                        badly at the South is true; but whatever suffering they underwent, Stanton
                        had the power at at any moment to relieve, by assenting to their immediate
                        release. </p>
                    <p>The Radical Convention of Pennsylvania adopted a resolution laudatory of this
                        accomplice of Wirz in the murder of the Andersonville prisoners.</p>
                    <p> The Cincinnati <emph rend="italic">Commercial</emph> the leading Republican
                        journal of the North-west, has this article in reply to Charles A. Dana,
                        late Assistant Secretary of War, who has lately been laborious in Stanton's
                        behalf, in battling the torrent of public sentiment which is accumulating on
                        this subject from day to day: </p>
                    <p> "If the ex-Assistant Secretary of War could not have done better than this
                        for Mr. Stanton, it would have been well for him to have kept silence.
                        General Butler in his Lowell speech, last winter, says that the difficulty
                        about the exchange of negro soldiers, was argued obstrusively and
                        demonstratively, with the express purpose of prevent any exchanges whatever.
                        Col. Streight, of Indiana, who escaped from Libby Prison, says Stanton told
                        him that the healthy rebels in our prisons would not be exchanged for the
                        skeletons that were in rebel prisons. It was proper and necessary, of
                        course, to protect the negro soldiers, but how was that object accomplished
                        by starving thousands of white soldiers to death? What did the horrible
                        martyrdom of tens of thousands of white men at Salisbury and Andersonville
                        do for the negro, we should like to know? Can the editor of the Chicago
                            <emph rend="italic">Republican</emph> tell us? There were but few
                        negroes made prisoners of war--not one to a score of the white soldiers who
                        sickened and died in the pestilential prison-pens of the South. The
                        Secretary of War and his assistants had better not pretend that multitudes
                        of white soldiers were permitted to be put to death because there were a few
                        dozen negroes not satisfactorially accounted for. They should not try to put
                        such a club as that into the hands of the enemies of the Administration; and
                        they cannot do it because the facts will not warrant it. The truth is, we
                        held, during the year of 1864, a very large number of rebel prisoners, who
                        were kindly treated and in good condition. As soon as exchanged they were
                        available to fill the ranks of the rebel armies. The rebels also held a
                        large number of our men, many of whose terms of service had expired, while
                        others were emaciated by the hardships to which they were subjected, and
                        were not able to go at once to the front when they were restored to us. </p>
                    <p> Exchanging prisoners was therfore reinforcing General Lee, without a
                        corresponding gain for General Grant. And that is precisely why our
                        Government was not disposed to make exchange, and why our men were horribly
                        abused by the rebels, in the hope that the story of their sufferings would
                        compel a general exchange. The negro difficulty was all a pretense, and the
                        editor of the Chicago <emph rend="italic">Republican</emph> ought to know
                        it. It must be admitted that if Lee had fifty thousand of the Southern
                        soldiers held in Northern prisons, on the 9th of May last, that he would not
                        have been surrendering at Appomattox court House. But it was clearly the
                        duty of our authorities to do one of two things--exchange well men for
                        skeletons or retaliate. There was no duty more sacred than the protection of
                        the poor fellows who were being put to death in the prison pens; and as we
                        now know that there was more than one million men on the pay rolls of the
                        Union army at the close of the war; it will be difficult to convince anybody
                        that we could not have afforded to make a general exchange. If this matter
                        is to be discussed, we insist it shall be done upon the basis of the facts."
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Endorses an article in the Pittsburgh Post that attributes responsibility
                    for the horrors committed at Andersonville to Secretary Stanton. The Spirit
                    maintains that his refusal to exchange prisoners with the Confederates resulted
                    in the unnecessary deaths of 30,000 Union soldiers. Stanton could have averted
                    this outcome but chose not to because "the terms of enlistment had expired for
                    most" of the men in the Confederate camps and, in contrast to the rebel soldiers
                    who would have been sent back to the army following the exchange, they would
                    have returned to their homes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Facts for White Voters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> No Republican newspaper in this State, as far as we have seen, has declared
                            <emph rend="italic">against</emph> negro suffrage. Most of the journals
                        of that party have expressed themselves <emph rend="italic">in favor</emph>
                        of it. </p>
                    <p> The Republicans, in their county conventions and meetings, have not resolved
                            <emph rend="italic">against</emph> making the negro the political equal
                        of the white man. Some of them have resolved, openly, <emph rend="italic">in
                            favor</emph> of it, and others indirectly so. </p>
                    <p> The Republican State Convention, did not utter a word <emph rend="italic"
                            >against</emph> giving the right of suffrage to the negro; but did say a
                        word indirectly <emph rend="italic">favoring</emph> that doctrine. </p>
                    <p> No prominent Republican politician in this State, has avowed himself <emph
                            rend="italic">opposed</emph> to putting the negro upon the same paltform
                        with the white man, <emph rend="italic">Stevens, Cameron Kelley</emph>, and
                        others of them, are known to be <emph rend="italic">in favor</emph> of it.
                        The Republicans in our last legislature, voted to compel the Street Railroad
                        Companies of Philadelphia, to carry negroes in the same cars with white men
                        and women! </p>
                    <p>Now on the other hand, the Democratic Newspapers, the Democratic County
                        Conventions and meetings, the Democratic State Convention and the Democratic
                        members of the Legislature are out squarely and unmistakably against the
                        Republican plan for equalizing the negro with the white.</p>
                    <p>These are FACTS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thus far, the article reports, no Republican journal in Pennsylvania has
                    openly opposed black suffrage. In fact, it continues, at various party
                    conventions and meetings, Republicans have "not uttered a word against giving"
                    blacks the vote, a position Democrats have vigorously condemned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A "reliable gentleman" has informed the Spirit that the people living in
                    the vicinity of Plough's School House in Green township are "enthusiastic in
                    their support" of the "abolition" candidate for District Attorney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Thoughts for Pennsylvanians</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No State in the union has more reasons to desire a speedy settlement of
                    the pending issues between the North and South than Pennsylvania. All her
                    interests are identified with a perfect Union--Her vast resources need a wide
                    market."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Practical Republicanism means negro equality, and negro equality means
                        opposition to pacification and reorganization--to peace, Union and
                        prosperity. Those who are opposed to the President's plan for [unclear] the
                        difficulties which have disturbed the country, are sure to be found
                        advocating negro suffrage and equality. The reason is plain. Chief Justice
                        Chase, and Senator Sumner, and Thaddeus Stevens understand perfectly the
                        game they are playing, and the instruments they need to effect their
                        treasonable purpose. The stories of cruelty to negroes, the tales of secret
                        plots in the Southern States against the Union and the government, the
                        constant agitation of the old <emph rend="italic">res adjudicata</emph> by
                        the Republican clergy, the hatred and malice exhibited in Republican
                        journals, are all intended to keep open the bleeding wounds of the nation,
                        and, if possible, prevent the sections from once more uniting under the
                        Constitution. But mischeivous as thse agencies are, they are barren and
                        innocuous when compared with negro equality. That is the thorn which rankles
                        and festers in the minds of the Southern people; and hence it is turned and
                        twisted incessantly by Republicans. They continue this devilish operation in
                        order, if possible, to disturb the relations which now exist between the
                        South and the General Government, and thus afford a pretext for the use of
                        the military power in holding the States as provinces, and the people as
                        vassals. </p>
                    <p>This being the evident use which the Republican party mean to make of the
                        doctine of negro suffrage and equality, are the people of this State
                        prepared to endorse it at the polls by voting the Republican ticket? No
                        State in the Union has more reasons to desire a speedy settlement of the
                        pending issues between the North and South than Pennsylvania. All her
                        interests are identified with a perfect Union.--Her vast resources need a
                        wide market. This can only be obtained by a union of all the people north
                        and south of her, on a basis that will hide the past, and restore
                        practically the equality of the States under the Constitution. The attempted
                        degredation of any portion of the white people of this country, whose
                        government rests upon the popular will, is a war against the purity and
                        perpetuity of a representative system; and if the attempt be successful, the
                        result must be the disturbance and destruction of of the whole fabric of
                        society, political, social and industrial. Under our present system the
                        interests of the whole people, North, South, East and West, are linked
                        together by common hopes, fears and interests. What affects injuriously one
                        section reduces its products, uproots its industrial system, prostrates its
                        trade, destroys its business, must and will affect the whole.</p>
                    <p> These thoughts are pertinent to the occasion and the duties that are
                        pressing upon the people of this State. The people of the South are honestly
                        and faithfully laboring to tranqilize that section. They are succeeding
                        admirably under the plan proposed by the President. Delegations, composed of
                        leading men from that section, have called upon the Presdident and given
                        assurances that the whole people of the South are willing to accept the plan
                        proposed and labor to put it into early and efficient operation. But they
                        need the cooperation of the true Union men of the North, in order to prevent
                        the Radicals from arresting the progress of the patriotic work.--<emph
                            rend="italic">Age</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Age</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Labels stories of Southern intransigence and reports of violence committed
                    against blacks as evidence of Radicals' propaganda, which is designed to inflame
                    northern sensibilities. To speed reconciliation, a necessity for Pennsylvania
                    since it is reliant on access to wide markets for its continued prosperity, the
                    article asserts that Johnson's prescription for reunification must be adhered
                    to.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit asks readers whether it is fair for a wealthy man owning $50,000
                    in government bonds to pay no taxes while a "mechanic who holds a $500 bond from
                    his neighbor is required to pay State, County, School, Road, and City tax upon
                    his small investment." The article calls for the enactment of a tax code that
                    treats everyman according to his wealth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Admonishes residents, particularly those who were away serving in the army,
                    to get their property assessed so that they can vote. All assessments must be
                    completed by Sept. 30th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Shoddy Speculation Scheme</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union; Cincinnati Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary>"We find the following suggestive paragraph in a late number of the
                    Cincinnati <emph rend="italic">Enquirer:</emph>"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Some gentlemen interested in the iron manufactories, who have large stocks
                        on hand, have devised a very handsome scheme to fill their pockets at the
                        expense of the public. They propose to Congress to add largely to the duty
                        on iron. This would immediately put up the price, and they would realize
                        their millions of dollars from the rise of their stocks on hand out of the
                        farmer and consumers of iron. It is the old whisky dodge over again. They
                        have already some newspapers advocating it, and will doubtless be at
                        Washington next winter with a formidable lobby! Look out for them!"</p>
                    <p> We have no doubt that the tariff "plank" of the Pennsylvania Shoddy platform
                        is a part of the scheme. The nomination of Jacob M. Campbell--who, for a
                        number of years has been connected with, and, for all we know, largely
                        interested in, the Cambria Iron Works, <emph rend="italic">which have almost
                            double the producing capacity of any other works in the
                        country</emph>--may be another part of the scheme. There is no telling or
                        knowing the cunning tricks of the new shoddy aristocracy--the cotton lords
                        and iron kings. It is the tax-paying and laboring people's business to keep
                        on the alert for all sorts of schemes to make money at their expense--out of
                        their sweat and toil--and, at the ballot-box to circumvent the schemers by
                        overwhelming defeat. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides the details of a scheme devised by iron manufacturers to increase
                    the duty on imported iron, a plan that would greatly increase their profit
                    margin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Capt. David L. Tressler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tressler</ln>
                        <fn>David L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lauds David L. Tressler's character and proclaims his fitness for office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"All that is needed to give us victory at the Polls, is a full vote."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns Pennsylvania voters to cast their ballots to avert a Radical victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Election in South Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the election for delegates to the State Convention in South Carolina,
                    the "Union" ticket was soundly defeated in Charleston and throughout the state.
                    Many members of the antebellum elite have re-emerged as opposition leaders,
                    which, the article says, has "very much pleased" the "old resident citizens" of
                    the state. The "new settlers" from the North, however, are less thrilled at the
                    outcome. One hundred delegates attended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Gettysburg Compiler</origin>
                <commentary>"The following which we take from the Gettysburg Compiler does not speak
                    very favorably of the gentleman on the Republican ticket who is asking the votes
                    of the people for Senator."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Nine years ago this month, I, holding a Certificate Deed for 120 acres of
                        land in Iowa, meeting with David McConaughy, Esq., Attorney at Law, in
                        Gettysburg, and desiring a Patent Deed for the said land, the said
                        McConaughy mentioned that he was going to Washington city the next morning,
                        and he advised me to give him my Deed and he would get the Patent Deed for
                        me, and save me the expense of a trip to Washington myself. Supposing all
                        would be right I gave him my Deed for the purpose mentioned. Some time
                        afterwards I called upon him, and found that my Deed was still in his
                        possession. Whether he ever went to Washington or not, I do not know. Time
                        after time, hundreds of times I may say, I called on him for the Patent
                        Deed; just as often he would say, "I am busy, call some other day." Getting
                        no satisfaction, although I had paid him five dollars, and getting tired of
                        being put off in this way, I then demanded the return of my Certificate
                        Deed; the answer was to that, time after time, year after year, "just pass
                        out, call in again." This went on for eight long years, until last fall,
                        upon one of my visits to his office, upon my telling him positively, in the
                        presence of a witness, I was bound to have my Deed, I was ordered to leave.
                        About six weeks ago, having taken steps for the purpose, I discovered (not
                        through McConaughy, you may be sure) that my Certificate Deed was along with
                        said McConaughy's Deeds, at Council Bluffs, Iowa! Let the public make its
                        own comments upon such conduct. I presume the public verdict would be that I
                        should have my Deed, but is kept from me in the way stated.</p>
                    <p>I am a Republican, and a thorough one, and intend voting all the Republican
                        ticket except for David McConaughy for Senator. If he can treat me in the
                        way he has done, he can treat the public in the same way, if he gets the
                        chance. As far as I can prevent it, he can't have the chance. Calvin M.
                        Duncan is the man of my choice.</p>
                    <p>ROBERT MCGAUGHY.</p>
                    <p>Franklin tp., Sept. 16, 1865.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Robert McGaughy</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGaughy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConaughy</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In his letter, Robert McGaughy, a self-proclaimed "Republican," accuses
                    David McConaughy of stealing the deed to his property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Jeb Stuart ?</head>
                <origin>Compiler</origin>
                <commentary>"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the fall of 1862, the rebel cavalry under General J.E.B. Stuart made a
                        raid through Franklin and the western part of this county, carrying off
                        hundreds of horses. Many of our farmers lost heavily, some of them all the
                        horse stock they had.</p>
                    <p> Here a nice chance presented itself to McConaughy. A large number of horses
                        were taken, and a large number of dollars might be made out of the fact. It
                        was therefore noised abroad that he could secure compensation for the horses
                        stolen, from Harrisburg, or Washington, or somewhere; and, as a consequence,
                        the farmers came in by dozens and paid McConaughy <emph rend="italic"
                        >down</emph> a dollar for each of the horses taken from them. But to this
                        day they have never seen one cent of damages. </p>
                    <p> It was a rather hard case that the farmers should first lose their horses by
                        Jeb Stuart, and then their money by D. McConaughy. Probably some of them
                        will think of it when he asks them for their votes in addition. --<emph
                            rend="italic">Compiler</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConaughy</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Castigates David McConaughy for his failure to obtain compensation for
                    property lost by farmers during the attack led by Jeb Stuart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Privileged Classes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The privileged classes of this country may be classes as follows:</p>
                    <p> Class A--Abolitionists. <lb/> Class B--Bondholders. <lb/> Class
                        C--Contractors. <lb/> Class D--Dead men. <lb/> Class E--Exempts. <lb/> Class
                        F--Fanatics. <lb/> Class G--Good-for-nothing Generals. <lb/> Class
                        H--Hangmen. <lb/> Class I--Idiots. <lb/> Class J--Judge Advocates <lb/>
                        Class K--Know-Nothings. <lb/> Class L--Lunatics. <lb/> Class M--Members of
                        Congress. <lb/> Class N--Niggers </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the "privileged classes" in the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Assess the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Every returned soldier must be assessed or he will lose his vote. The
                        payment of the ten cent tax under the soldiers' voting law will not entitle
                        the soldier to vote as a citizen. The Democratic Ward and Township
                        committees should at once attend to this matter. No time is to be lost, as
                        the 30<emph rend="italic">th of September</emph> is the limit of time
                        allowed to do so. Within the ensuing three weeks every returned veteran
                        should be fully qualified as a civilian--a freeman--a voter against Shoddy
                        and Negro Suffrage! </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Instructs readers that returning soldiers must be assessed or they will
                    lose their right to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Mengel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mengel Reed, arrested a few days earlier for treason, has been pardoned by
                    the President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>All blacks troops, who enlisted in the North and are currently serving in
                    North Carolina, are to be mustered out immediately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports are circulating that the President will soon withdraw all federal
                    troops from the southern states, except those required for garrison duty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The 78th Pennsylvania regiment, currently in Nashville, will depart next
                    Friday for Pittsburgh, where the troops will be mustered out of service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In Arkansas and Mississippi, according to the Freedmen's Bureau, the
                    prejudice of the Union troops against blacks is so severe that blacks cannot
                    safely settle in the vicinity of the soldiers' camps.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dorance Attwater, the clerk charged with stealing the Andersonville
                    records, has been tried by a court martial in Washington. The sentence is not
                    yet known.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.09.20.03.">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Democratic County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCrory</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goetz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbet</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coon</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sowers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckinridge</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Siske</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKim</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>D. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmon</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>North</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinstry</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the men appointed to the County Democratic Executive Committee for
                    the ensuing year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--History of the Civil War in the United States by Samuel M.
                    Smucker, L. L. D.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Samuel M. Smucker has written a history of the Civil War, which will be
                    published by Jones Brothers &amp; Co., of Philadelphia. The book should soon
                    be available for purchase.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Special Adjourned Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Several courts held special sessions in the county on Sept. 13th. The most
                    important case was the Commonwealth vs. John Snyder. Snyder was convicted of
                    adultery in his first trial in August and fined $150 plus prosecution fees. The
                    defendant's motion for a new trial was denied.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenwalt</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A fire broke out at Moses Greenwalt's grocery store on Sept. 10th, causing
                    $3,000 worth of damage. The building was saved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that people are alarmed at the increased frequency of train related
                    accidents. From January 1 to August 28th, 1865, it is estimated that railroad
                    accidents caused 266 deaths and 1,109 injuries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerdemann</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weakly</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 12th, James Weakly wed Mary Sullivan, in a ceremony presided over
                    by Rev. J. Gerdemann.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerdemann</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoppe</ln>
                        <fn>Herman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berge</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 19th, Herman Hoppe, of New York, and Sarah Berge were married by
                    Rev. J. Gerdemann.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bettie E. Miller, infant daughter of Jacob B. and Mary C. Miller, died in
                    Chambersburg on Sept.4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 8th, Elizabeth Hollinger, 93, died in Chambersburg</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Clarke, 56, died on Sept. 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.20.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
