<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1865/pa.fr.vs.1865.04.05">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/18/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1865-04-05">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.04.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Governor Curtin</head>
                <origin>Bellefonte Watchman</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have condemned the Governor very often heretofore, but we applaud his
                    manliness now, and it gives us pleasure to bear this testimony to his moral
                    courage."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Governor Curtin for standing up for the rights of Pennsylvania
                    against President Lincoln's draft quotas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Inaugural Boiled Down</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Meanwhile, without malice, let us charitably and firmly continue to cut
                    each other's throats."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a satirical look at President Lincoln's second inaugural address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Radicals and the Negro</head>
                <origin>Pittsburgh Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The philanthropy of the Abolitionists is merely a sentiment; they care
                    nothing for the poor negro, and all their efforts for this enfranchisement is
                    prompted by a malicious hatred for the slave owner."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes with disdain that Radical Republicans have turned a fight to restore
                    the Union into a fight for emancipation. Laments in particular the recent
                    activities of Senator Charles Sumner, who is trying to have a "colored
                    gentleman" admitted to the bar of the Supreme Court. Suggests that these
                    Republicans do not have the true interests of blacks at heart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.04.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Victory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We feel assured, however, that the 'backbone' of the rebellion has at
                    length been broken beyond repair, and that though the way may continue for some
                    time, yet the probability is that it will soon end. In the near future we behold
                    visions of a restored Union and a prosperous, reunited and happy people."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under our Telegraphic head will be found the very latest intelligence of the
                        operations of the army investing Petersburg and Richmond. The official
                        despatches of President Lincoln from City Point are brief but satisfactory,
                        containing a succinct account of the results of the great struggle which
                        commenced on Friday last and culminated in the occupation of Richmond by a
                        portion of our army under Gen. Weitzel on Monday morning at 8.15. Victory,
                        entire complete and decisive has crowned our banners and Lee has been
                        compelled to yield the rebel capital to our victorious army after one of the
                        most desperate struggles of the war.</p>
                    <p>General Grant is now in hot pursuit of the retreating rebels and there is
                        every probability that he will succeed in overtaking and utterly destroying
                        the only great army of the "Confederacy," in point of numbers. Until the
                        pursuit is ended and the smoke of battle cleared away, we are unprepared to
                        indicate, with any degree of certainty, all the results likely to follow our
                        recent brilliant successes. We feel assured, however, that the "backbone" of
                        the rebellion has at length been broken beyond repair, and that though the
                        war <emph rend="italic">may</emph> continue for some time, yet the
                        probability is that it will soon end. In the near future we behold visions
                        of a restored Union and a prosperous, reunited and happy people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Celebrates reports of the Union victory in and occupation of Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Financial Panic--Fall in Prices</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speculates that the recent fall in the price of gold is only temporary
                    since the volume of paper money has not decreased with it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A History of the Pennsylvania Reserve Corps</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Condemns a recently published history of the Pennsylvania Reserve Corps for
                    containing an introductory chapter that is critical of the Democratic party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>An Idiot Soldier Boy Shot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Can anyone read the above shocking narrative without tears in his eyes?
                    God of our fathers, what are we coming to? A poor little 'not full witted' boy
                    -- perhaps an idiot -- a mere helpless child -- who had been enticed and sold
                    into the army by some burly brute, attempts to run home to his parents, and for
                    this his young quivering heart is blown into atoms and his soul sent to
                    eternity."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells the story of a New York boy, aged sixteen, who was paid to serve in
                    the Army of the Potomac as a substitute. The boy did not realize what he was
                    getting himself into, and, not long into his service, he deserted. He was later
                    executed for desertion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Republican Question Before the Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Would the 'Government' ever get drunk?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks what would happen to the government if President Lincoln died and
                    Andrew Johnson became president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Glorious News! Richmond is Ours!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Richmond Ours!/ Enthusiastic Reception of our Army by the People!/ The
                    City on Fire!/ The 'Backbone' Broken!/ Gen. Grant in Pursuit of Lee's Retreating
                    Army."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Richmond Ours! <lb/>Enthusiastic Reception of our Army by the People!
                        <lb/>The City on Fire! <lb/>The "Backbone" Broken! <lb/>Gen. Grant in
                        Pursuit of Lee's Retreating Army.</p>
                    <p>Washington, April 3.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To Major General Dix:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The following telegram from the President announcing the evacuation of
                        Petersburg and probably Richmond has just been received by this department.</p>
                    <p>E. M. Stanton. <lb/>City Point, April 3</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To Hon. E.M. Stanton:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>This morning General Grant reports Petersburg evacuated, and he is confident
                        Richmond also is. He is pushing forward to cut off if possible the
                        retreating army.</p>
                    <p>A. Lincoln <lb/>Washington, April 3, 10.45 A.M.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To Major General Dix:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>It appears from a dispatch of Gen. Weitzel, just received by this department,
                        that our forces under his command are in Richmond, having taken it at 8.15
                        this morning.</p>
                    <p>E.M. Stanton, Sec'y of War. <lb/>Washington, April 3-12M.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Major General Dix:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The following official confirmation of the capture of Richmond and announcing
                        that the city is on fire has just been received by this department:</p>
                    <p>City Point, VA., April 3-11 A.M.</p>
                    <p>General Weitzel telegraphs as follows: We took Richmond at 8.15 this morning.
                        I captured many guns. The enemy left in great haste. The city is on fire in
                        one place. We are making every effort to put it out. The people received us
                        with enthusiastic expressions of joy.</p>
                    <p>General Grant started early this morning with the army towards the Danville
                        road, to cut off Lee's retreating army if possible.</p>
                    <p>President Lincoln has gone to the front.</p>
                    <p>(Signed) T.S. Bowers, A.A.G. <lb/>E.M. Stanton, Sec'y of War</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">The Associated Press Report of Operations up to
                            Saturday, April 1st.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Hd.Qrs. Army of the Potomac, <lb/>April 1, 1865</p>
                    <p>The greater portion of this army has not been engaged with the enemy to-day;
                        the time being occupied in erecting works on the rear line, and repairing
                        the roads connecting the different corps.</p>
                    <p>The late rains rendered it impossible to to [sic] move the wagon trains as
                        fast as the troops advanced; one train taking forty-eight hours to move five
                        miles, one thousand men assisting, but through the untiring industry and
                        perseverence of the officers in charge of the Quartermaster's and Commissary
                        Departments, the army has been almost as well supplied as while in their old
                        quarters.</p>
                    <p>When the news of Sheridan's repulse reached here last evening a part of the
                        5th Corps was at once despatched to his aid and it is expected that to-night
                        or in the morning we shall receive good news from that quarter.</p>
                    <p>It appears that Sheridan was moving on the road leading to a place called the
                        Five Forks, which is about 3 miles from the Southside Railroad, where two
                        brigades of Picket's Division, which had been moved out in a great hurry,
                        came down on a road which runs from Sutherland Station to the one on which
                        we were. Sheridan's cavalry having for the greater part passed the junction.
                        This movement of the enemy threatened to cut him off. He, however,
                        discovered his danger in time to get his command off with only a slight
                        loss; at the same time taking about 1000 prisoners. Both the Lees were
                        present, but one of them at a respectful distance. On being reinforced this
                        morning by the 5th Corps, the enemy fell back so rapidly that their dead and
                        wounded fell into our hands, as well as those of our own unavoidably left
                        behind yesterday afternoon. The attack made on the enemy's line in front of
                        the 24th Corps, was by Foster'd Division and about 200 prisoners were
                        brought in, the 148th New York taking most of them. Some 300 or 400 yards of
                        ground was taken from them and our present line so much further advanced.</p>
                    <p>At 4 A.M. this position was assaulted and a few of our men captured, but in a
                        very short time it was retaken with about 50 prisoners and a stand of
                        colors.</p>
                    <p>Our loss up to the present time will not exceed 2500, while that of the enemy
                        on some parts of the line at least, was greater than our own but of course
                        the total cannot be given.</p>
                    <p>Major Dickinson, of the 15th New York heavy artillery, is reported wounded
                        and a prisoner.</p>
                    <p>The sharp shooters brought into the 5th Corps headquarters this morning, 15
                        cavalrymen belonging to Wm. Henry Lee's command. They had been on picket and
                        were cut off by the force which was sent to the assistance of Sheridan.</p>
                    <p>Hd. Qrs. Army of the Potomac, <lb/>April 1--Midnight.</p>
                    <p>A courier from Sheridan has just arrived with the most cheering news. The
                        combined forces of cavalry and Warren's infantry advanced against the enemy
                        this afternoon, driving them several miles and capturing about four thousand
                        prisoners, and a number of guns. They retreated to the Five Forks where they
                        were flanked by a part of the 5th corps which had moved down the White Oak
                        road. It was here the large number of prisoners were taken. The rebels then
                        retreated south, along the White Oak road and were vigorously pursued by
                        General Sheridan while McKenzie's cavalry, from the Army of the James,
                        advanced west on the Fork road towards the South Side road and when the
                        messenger left was only about three miles from it and would undoubtedly
                        reach it before morning. Thus the last great line of railroad the rebels
                        have to supply their capital and Lee's army is about to be severed and it is
                        firmly believed that they will immediately leave their present positions at
                        Petersburg and Richmond. Sharp cannonading is now going on near the centre
                        of the line held by the left of the 6th corps.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints official government dispatches reporting on the occupation and
                    evacuation of Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Additional dispatches reporting on the success of the Army of the Potomac,
                column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.04.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Spring Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the results from the recent election of election judges. Those
                    townships that elected an "abolitionist" judge are: Antrim, Greenvillage,
                    Fayetteville, Hamilton, Dry Run, Metal, Mercersburg, Peters, Loudon, Warren,
                    North Ward, and South Ward. Those that elected a Democratic judge are: Guilford,
                    Letterkenny, Concord, Sulphur Spring, Lurgan, Welsh Run, Quincy, St. Thomas,
                    Orrstown, Mt. Rock, and Washington. Also takes issue with the Repository's
                    classification of Mr. Coon as "Union." Says it is true that Coon is for the
                    Union, but "not in the Repository's meaning of the term."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Citizen Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eiker</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. Porter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>George R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinsler</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that D. M. Eiker, J. Porter Brown, and George R. Kaufman, who
                    escaped from a rebel prison in Salisbury, have arrived safely in Nashville,
                    Tennessee. Also notes that Charles H. Kinsler, also formerly a prisoner in the
                    South, died from typhoid fever in Philadelphia last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thanks Captain Thomas Myers of the 107th Regiment, Pennsylvania Volunteers,
                    for sending the Valley Spirit copies of Raleigh, North Carolina newspapers.
                    Points out to readers who "grumble at paying $2.50 per year for our paper" that
                    the subscription costs of those papers are much higher than the Valley Spirit's.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>77th Regt. P. V.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Sergeant R and the rest of the 77th Pennsylvania Volunteers
                    only learned that their regiment had been mounted from reading the Valley
                    Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rev. S. H. C. Smith</head>
                <origin>Mifflintown True Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The people of Chambersburg will receive emphatically a gospel messenger,
                    and we ask them to give him their kindest treatment, warmest affections, and
                    tender regards, assuring them that it will not be unworthily bestowed."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Newspaper from the previous place of employment for Rev. S. H. C. Smith
                    offers a tribute to the minister, who is the new pastor of the M. E. Church in
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin>Star of the Valley</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rea</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rea</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that on last Tuesday, while hauling cornfodder with James D. Rea,
                    William Gilbert was thrown from a wagon when his horses took fright. After
                    hitting a stone wall, Gilbert was left with a bruised side and a badly cut head.
                    He was treated by Dr. John D. Rea.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Summary taken from the Repository of recent state legislation of interest to
                Franklin County, column 1, classified ads, columns 2-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.04.05.04">
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
