<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.12.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/16</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-12-18">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="00">18</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.12.18.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.12.18.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Legislation For The Negro</head>
                <origin>Repository</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When Democratic orators and journals charged upon the Republican party that
                        it intended to invest the negro with the right of suffrage, the charge was
                        repelled with indignation. The people trusted to the honesty of the denial,
                        and elected Republicans to office. The sequel has shown the truth of the
                        charge and the duplicity of the denial.--The negro votes, <emph
                            rend="italic">by the authority of the Federal Government</emph>, in the
                        District of Columbia and in the States of the South that attempted to
                        secede. This is an exercise of the power on the part of Congress which is
                        not granted to it by the Constitution, and we maintain therefore that it is
                        not binding upon the nation. We assert this, not alone as our own firm
                        conviction but on the authority of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph>, whose utterances will surely be accepted by the Radicals
                        of this County as truth. In its issue of June 28th 1865, in an article
                        entitled "Negro suffrage," it says: </p>
                    <p>Looking practically at the proposed enfranchisement of the freedmen, we see
                        no hope for it at an early day. It cannot be brought about, as things now
                        are, except as time may prove their fitness for citizenship and [UNCLEAR]
                        the useless prejudices which are [UNCLEAR] against them. <emph rend="italic"
                            >The General Government cannot, by any possible means, [UNCLEAR] to them
                            the right of suffrage. To [UNCLEAR] the States alone belong that power
                            and duty' and thus far not one of the regenerated States has proposed
                            it.</emph></p>
                    <p>This, it will be remembered, was after the surrender of the armies of Lee and
                        Johnston. It was after Mr. Lincoln had been assassinated. The rebellion was
                        crushed. "Military necessity" was a thing of the past. The supremacy of the
                        Federal constitution was acknowledged. At such a time, with a full knowledge
                        of the situation--our neighbor uttered <emph rend="italic">his deliberate
                            judgement</emph> upon the subject when he said "the general government
                        cannot, by any possible means, <emph rend="italic">lawfully</emph> secure to
                        them (the negroes) the right of suffrage." His deliberate judgement we say,
                        because he closes the article with this sentence, "we have thus presented
                        the question <emph rend="italic">rather as it is than as we would have
                        it</emph>." If the general government could not then, by any possible means
                        lawfully give the negro a vote, the question presents itself, how has the
                        general government lawfully invested him with that right since that period?
                        Will the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> be kind enough to enlighten
                        us? If there has been no grant of power to the general government since to
                        do this, and we know not where to look for such a grant, then Congress has
                        clearly usurped the power which does not belong to it, and its action is
                        void. It does not belong to it, and its action is void. It has attempted to
                        do unlawfully, what the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> said, and what
                        everybody then admitted it could not lawfully do. If its action in this
                        respect is unconstitutional and shall be so declared by the proper tribunal,
                        then all its legislation upon this subject will be a dead letter, and the
                        governments established in the South under the superintendence of the
                        negroes must give way to the governments which will hereafter be established
                        in conformity to the Federal Constitution. </p>
                    <p>And when Democratic orators and journals went further and charged upon the
                        Radical party that the next step it would take would be <emph rend="italic"
                            >to put the negro in the jury-box</emph>, that charge was also repelled
                        with indignation. They were accused of lying for electioneering purposes.
                        The sequel has shown the truth of the charge and the falsity of the denial.
                        Look at the South under the military reconstruction bill. The negroes are
                        found in every jury-box.--The Grand Jury which found the bill of indictment
                        against Jefferson Davis on which he will likely be tried, if tried at all,
                        was partly composed of negroes. And now, last of all, Congress, as the
                        representatives of the Radical party, have passed a bill which will put the
                        negro in the jury-box in the District of Columbia. If the Radicals thus
                        legislate in the interest of the negro where they now have the power, is it
                        not reasonable to argue that they will enact similar laws wherever they can
                        gain power? The excuse for conferring upon the negroes of the South the
                        privileges heretofore exclusively enjoyed by the whites, has been that this
                        action was necessary in order to insure loyal State governments. How will
                        this apply to the legislation in regard to the District of Columbia? We
                        submit that every candid, honest man can not fail to see that it is the
                        purpose of the Radicals to force negro equal--upon the country in defiance
                        of the constitution and the expressed will of the people. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In an article that appeared in the June 28, 1865 issue of the Repository,
                    the editor of the Republican journal opined that Congress should not confer
                    blacks with suffrage rights; rather, he declared, that decision should be left
                    to the individual state governments. Now, two years later, the editors of the
                    Valley Spirit note, their rival has reversed himself. He, like the rest to the
                    Republican leadership, is not only willing to grant blacks the vote but is also
                    willing to admit them to juries. Where, they ask, will it end?</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Remember The Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With the onset of winter, the economic situation in the country has grown
                    worse. Throughout the North, unemployment is on the rise and, consequently, so
                    is the crime rate. After attributing the current predicament to corruption,
                    reckless government spending, and the introduction of a rotten financial system,
                    the editors advise readers to give generously in this time of need.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Repository</origin>
                <commentary>"THE <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> seems to have been thrown
                    into a terrible muddle by our simple request for light. We supposed that
                    inasmuch as it hoisted General Grant for President, it was well acquainted with
                    his political opinions, and would not hesitate to reveal them to us and to its
                    own party friends. But we were mistaken. It evidently does not know the
                    General's opinions, and consequently cannot disclose them. It asks its party to
                    "go it blind" as it is obliged to do. Its reason for supporting General Grant
                    for the Presidential nomination is that "it prefers to do so." It shuts itself
                    up in the solitude of its own heart chambers, and refused to announce the
                    grounds of its preference. It claims to be the exponent of Radical principles.
                    Week after week, its columns are filled with matter in support of the
                    reconstruction policy of Congress and in favor of political equality for the
                    negro. One would suppose that its candidate for President would be a man who is
                    unmistakably known to favor the same measure. And yet the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph> refuses to affirm this of General Grant. It says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                    <p>As to defining General Grant's position, we leave that entirely to him as
                        peculiarly his own business. We know what our position is, and the SPIRIT
                        professes to know it equally as well. <emph rend="italic">Of one thing it
                            can rest assured, we will support no man for the Presidential nomination
                            whose position is different from ours on the great questions now at
                            issue.</emph></p>
                    <p>Is it "peculiarly his own business" to define his own position when the <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository, as one of General Grant's organs</emph>, is
                        asking the Radicals of Franklin county to join in the cry for his
                        nomination? Is it not, rather, peculiarly <emph rend="italic">its</emph>
                        business to give to those whom it hopes to win over to the support of
                        General Grant, some good reasons for espousing his cause? It has distinctly
                        disclaimed supporting him on the ground of expediency. Then there is no
                        other ground but principle. So that we come back to the question, what are
                        the principles? Those the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> declines to
                        let us know "just now." Let it honestly acknowledge that it is trying an
                        experiment. Let it confess with candor that its party is reduced to this
                        unpleasant necessity by the sudden and unexpected change in its political
                        fortunes. Principle has often been slaughtered to make way for expediency,
                        and the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, in consenting to tomahawk its
                        Radicalism in order to increase the chances of whipping the Democrats, is
                        only adopting the well-established precedents of the organization of which
                        it is one of the mouth-pieces. </p>
                    <p>It, however, makes a faint show of resistance. It indulges a covert threat at
                        General Grant while it still keeps his flag flying. "We will support no man
                        for the Presidential nomination, whose position is different from ours on
                        the great questions at issue." What does this mean? Does it meant that the
                            <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> is <emph rend="italic">now</emph>
                        supporting General Grant because his position accords with its own on the
                        great questions at issue? No; if so, it would have no trouble in defining
                        General Grant's position, which it admits its inability to do. Then it must
                        mean that <emph rend="italic">unless General Grant soon opens his mouth and
                            declares hist hatposition is not different from the Repository's on the
                            great questions at issue, it will withdraw its support from him.</emph>
                        The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> is evidently growing impatient at
                        the General's continued reticence and is devising ways and means to get out
                        of its dilemma. Oh that my candidate would make a speech, is the of its
                        [unclear] though for or against my principles, so that I could commend him
                        with boldness or drop him like a hot potato! The General, on the contrary,
                        undoubtedly thinks that his "strength is to sit still." The <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository</emph> is in the same fix as the boy who won
                        the elephant at a raffle. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors ridicule the Repository for endorsing Gen. Grant without having
                    a clear sense of where he stands on the issues that are most dear to its cause.
                    The Repository's advocacy of his candidacy, they avow, illustrates the lengths
                    Republicans will go "in order to increase their chances of whipping the
                    Democrats" in the next election: the Republicans have shown they are willing to
                    sacrifice "principle" for "expediency."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Stanton Still Out In The Cold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite Speaker Colfax's public assertions that Stanton would be
                    re-instated to his cabinet post within twenty days of the assembling of
                    Congress, the former Secretary of War "remains in the inglorious obscurity to
                    which Andrew Johnson consigned him." And, states the article, there is "no
                    anxiety" to have him "restored to office."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Union League Declining</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Over the course of the past year, the popularity of the Union League of
                    Philadelphia has plummeted and its membership has dropped off dramatically,
                    relates the article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.12.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Dedication</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the United Brethren in Christ's new church, near
                    Mowersville, will be dedicated on Dec. 29th. Bishop Glossbrenner will officiate
                    the proceedings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Examination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKeehan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The examination period for Miss McKeehan's school will be begin this week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Rev. Irving MacGee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Having recently been appointed Pastor of the Lutheran Church in
                    Chambersburg, Rev. Irving Magee preached there last Sunday. His "introductory
                    sermon" will be held on January 19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Meeting In The Court House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There will be a meeting at the Court House on Wednesday in support of the
                    movement to amend the Constitution so "that God and Jesus Christ may be
                    recognised" in the document.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Friday, Upton Washabaugh, "a well known and highly respected citizen,"
                    died after suffering the effects of a "lingering and painful illness." Like his
                    father, Washabaugh was a local brewer until his illness forced him to retire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--The Burning Of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the report of the proceedings of the House of Representatives of the
                        United States, on Wednesday last, we learn that "Several adverse reports
                        were presented from the Committee on Claims, including one on the petition
                        of inhabitants of Chambersburg, Pa., for damages done to McCaualand's raid."
                        It is, of course, competent for the House to make an appropriation in spite
                        of the adverse report of the Committee, but we doubt whether anything of the
                        kind will be done. The People of Chambersburg have the misfortune to be
                            <emph rend="italic">white</emph>. If they had been <emph rend="italic"
                            >black</emph>, they would have been indemnified in full for their losses
                        by the first Congress that met after the destruction of the town. We would
                        like some Radical member of Congress to give us a good reason why that body
                        should appropriate twelve or fifteen million dollars every year to feed and
                        clothe Southern negroes who lost nothing and are able to work, and not
                        appropriate even a few hundred thousand for the relief of the white
                        sufferers at Chambersburg. This goes a long step beyond negro equality. It
                        is discriminating in favor of the negro and against the white man.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the House of Representatives' Committee on Claims
                    decided against compensating the victims of McCausland's raid. Unfortunately for
                    the residents of Chambersburg, the editors sardonically declare, they "have the
                    misfortune to be white." Had they "been black," however, "they would been
                    indemnified in full for their losses."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Chambersburg Woolen Mill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Woolen Manufacturing Co. is proposing to increase its
                    capital stock to $200,000. Initial capitalization of the mill was $125,000,
                    two-fifths of which was preferred stock. The same proportion of the new stock
                    will be issued as preferred, which pays 8% per annum. The common stock has paid
                    10% and, the article reports, it might be raised to 15% or 20%. The mill
                    processes about 500 pounds of wool and manufactures 800 yards of goods every 24
                    hours. The range of products include "Blankets and common Flannels and
                    Cassimeres up to fine Doeskins and Beavers." The mill employs 80 hands and pays
                    out $40,000 a year in salary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--New Band</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>George R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>W. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>Geroge W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Sol. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehmaster</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that a group called the "Citizen's Band" was recently formed. The
                    officers of the organization are as follows: President, George R. Nixon;
                    Vice-President, J. R. Sellers; Treasurer, W. H. Sellers; Secretary, W. N.
                    Bishop. Others officials in the group are George L. Hoffman, Jr., George W.
                    Harmony, W. F. Snyder, John Snyder, James C. Chambers, Sol. A. Huber, James M.
                    Davison, and A. Lehmaster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--A Fraternal Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that 70 members of the George Washington Lodge, F. A. M. of
                    Chambersburg, visited the Friendship Lodge of Hagerstown. The group was
                    accompanied by the Chambersburg Band.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Galbraith</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodburn</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 3rd, Franklin H. Skinner and Sarah J. Galbraith, of Cumberland Co.,
                    were married by Rev. Woodburn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allter</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 12th, William Small and Mary Allter were married by Rev. J. Hunter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.12.18.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
