<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.04.24">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>01/12/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-04-24">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="04">April</month>
			<day norm="00">24</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.24.01">
			<div type="l">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Andersonville</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Letter from Lewis Schade, esq. Counsel of Captain Wirz.</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">To the American People</emph>: </p>
					<p>Intending to leave the United States for some time, I feel it my duty, before
						I start, to fulfill in part a promise which, a few hours before his death, I
						gave to my unfortunate client, Captain Wirz, who was executed at Washington
						on the 10th day of November, 1865. Protesting up to the last moment his
						innocence of those monstrous crimes with which he was charged, he received
						my word, that, having failed to save him from a felon's doom, I would, as
						long as I lived, do everything in my power to clear his memory. I did that
						the more readily, as I was then already perfectly convinced that he suffered
						wrongfully.-Since that time his unfortunate children, both here and in
						Europe, have constantly implored me to wipe out the terrible stains which
						now cover the name of their father. Though times do not seem propitious for
						obtaining full justice, yet, considering that man is mortal, I will before
						entering upon a perilous voyage, perform my duty to those innocent orphans
						and also to myself.</p>
					<p>I will now give a brief statement of the causes which led to the arrest and
						execution of Captain Wirz. In April, 1865, President Johnson issued a
						proclamation stating that, from evidence in the possession of the "Bureau of
						Military Justice," it appeared that Jefferson Davis was implicated in the
						assassination of Abraham Lincoln, and for that reason the President offered
						a reward of $100,000 on the capture of the then fugitive ex-President of the
						Southern Confederacy. That testimony has since been found to be entirely
						false and a mere fabrication, and the suborner Conover is now under sentence
						in the jail in this city, the two perjurers, whom he suborned, having turned
						State evidence against him, whilst the individual, by whom Conover was
						suborned has not yet been brought to justice.</p>
					<p>Certain high and influential enemies of Jefferson Davis, either then already
						aware of the character of the testimony of those witnesses, or not thinking
						their testimony quite sufficient to hang Jeff. Davis, expected to find the
						wanting material in the terrible mortality of Union prisoners at
						Andersonville. Orders were issued accordingly to arrest a subaltern officer,
						Capt. Wirz, a poor, friendless, and wounded prisoner of war, (he being
						included in the surrender of General Johnston), and besides a foreigner by
						birth. On the 7th of May he was placed in the Old Capitol Prison at
						Washington, and from that time the greater part of the Northern press was
						busily engaged in forming the unfortunate man in the eyes of the Northern
						people into such a monster that it became almost impossible for him to
						obtain counsel. Even his countryman, the Swiss Consul-General publicly
						refused to accept money to defray the expenses of the trial. He was doomed
						before he was heard--and even the permission to be heard according to law
						was denied him. To increase the excitement and give eclat to the proceeding,
						and to inflame still more the public mind, the trial took place under the
						very dome of the Capitol of the nation. A military commission, presided over
						by one of the most arbitrary and despotic generals in the country, was
						formed, and the paroled prisonerof war, his wounds still open, and so feeble
						that he had to recline during the trial on a sofa, carried before by the
						same. How that trial was conducted the whole world knows. The enemies of
						generosity and humanity believed it then to be a sure thing to get at Jeff.
						Davis.</p>
					<p>Therefore the first charge was that of conspiracy between Wirz, Jefferson
						Davis, Seddon, Howell Cobb, R. B. Winder and a number of others, to kill the
						Union prisoners. The trial lasted for three months, but unfortunately for
						the blood-thirsty instigators not a particle of evidence was produced
						showing the existence of such a conspiracy; yet Captain Wirz was found
						guilty of that charge! Having thus failed another effort was made. On the
						night before the execution of the prisoner a telegram was sent to the
						Northern press from this city, stating that Wirz had made important
						disclosures to General L. C. Baker, the well-known detective, implicating
						Jeff. Davis, and that the confession would probably be given to the public.
						On the same evening some parties came to the confessor of Wirz, Rev. Father
						Boyle, and also to me, one of them informing me that a high Cabinet officer
						wished to assure Wirz, that if he would implicate Jefferson Davis with the
						atrocities committed at Andersonville, his sentence would be commuted. He,
						the messenger, or whoever he was, requested me to inform Wirz of this. In
						the presence of Father Boyle I told Wirz next morning what had happened. The
						Captain simply and quietly replied: "Mr. Schade, you know that I have always
						told you that I do not know anything about Jefferson Davis. He had no
						connection with me as to what was done at Andersonville. If I knew anything
						of him I would not become a traitor against him or anybody else, even to
						save my life." He likewise denied that he had made any statement whatever to
						General Baker.-Thus ended the attempt to suborn Captain Wirz against Jeff
						Davis. That alone shows what a man he was. How many of his defamers would
						have done the same? With his wounded arm in a sling, the poor paroled
						prisoner mounted, two hours later, the scaffold. His last words were that he
						died innocent-and so he did. The 10th day of November, 1865, will indeed be
						a black stain on the pages of American history.</p>
					<p>To weaken the effect of his declaration of Innocence, and of the noble manner
						in which Wirz died, a telegram was manufactured here and sent North, stating
						that on the 27th day of October, Mrs. Wirz, (who actually was 900 miles on
						that day away from Washington,) had been prevented by that Stauntonian <emph
							rend="italic">deus ex machina</emph>, General L. C. Baker, <emph
							rend="italic">from poisoning her husband</emph>! Thus, on the same day,
						when the unfortunate family lost their husband and father, a cowardly and
						atrocious attempt was made to blacken their character also. On the next day
						I branded the whole as an infamous lie, and since then I never have heard of
						it again, though it emanated from a Brigadier General of the United States
						Army. </p>
					<p>All those who were charged with having conspired with Captain Wirz have since
						been released, except Jefferson Davis, the prisoner of the American "Castle
						Chillon." Captain Winder was let of without trial, and if any of the others
						had been tried, which I do not know, certainly none of them would have been
						hung. As Captain Wirz could not conspire alone, nobody will now, in view of
						that important fact, consider him guilty of that charge. So much then for
						charge No. 1.</p>
					<p>As to charge No. II., to wit: Murder, in violation of the laws and customs of
						war, I do not hesitate to declare what about 145 out of 160, witnesses on
						both sides declared during the trial-that Captain Wirz never murdered or
						killed any Union prisoners with his own hands or otherwise. All those
						witnesses (about twelve or fifteen) who testified that they saw Captain Wirz
						kill a prisoner, have sworn falsely, abundant proofs of that assertion being
						in existence. The hands of Captain Wirz are clear of the blood of prisoners
						of war. He would certainly have at least intimated to me a knowledge of the
						alleged murders with which he was charged. In most all cases no names of the
						alleged murdered men could be given, and where it was done, no such persons
						could be identified. The terrible scene in court, when he was confronted
						with one of the witnesses, and the latter insisting that Wirz was the man
						who killed a certain Union prisoner, which irritated the prisoner so much
						that he almost fainted will still be remembered. That man (Grey) swore
						falsely, and God alone knows what the poor innocent prisoner must have
						suffered at that moment! That scene was depicted and illustrated in the
						Northern newspapers as if Wirz had broken down on account of his guilt.
						Seldom has a mortal suffered more than that friendless and forsaken man.</p>
					<p>Fearing lest this communication will be too long, I will merely speak of the
						principal and most intelligent of those false witnesses, who testified to
						individual murder on the part of Captain Wirz. Upon his testimony the Judge
						Advocate, in his argument, laid particular stress on account of his
						intelligence. This witness prepared also pictures of the alleged cruelties
						of Wirz, which were handed to the Commission, and are now on record, copies
						of which appeared at the time in Northern illustrated newspapers. He swore
						that his name was Felix de la Baume, and represented himself as a Frenchman
						and a grand-nephew of Marquis de Lafayette. After having so well testified
						and shown so much zel, he received a recommendation signed by the members of
						the Commission. On the 11th day of October, before the taking of the
						testimony was concluded, he was appointed to a clerkship in the Department
						of the Interior. This occurred whilst one of the witnesses for the defense
						(Duncan) was arrested in open court, and placed in prison before he had
						testified. After the execution of Captain Wirz some of the Germans of
						Washington recognized in de la Baume a deserter from the Seventh New York,
						(Steuben) regiment, whose name was not de la Baume, but Felix Oeser, a
						native of Saxony. They went to Secretary Hara in, and he dismissed the
						imposter and important witness in the Wirz trial on the 21st of November,
						eleven days after the execution. Nobody who is acquainted with the Conover
						testimony, in consequence of which the President of the United States was
						falsely induced to place a reward of $100,000 upon the head of an innocent
						man, will be astonished at the above disclosures of the character of
						testimony before military commissions. So much for charge No. II.</p>
					<p>If from twelve to fifteen witnesses could be found who were willing to
						testify to so many acts of murder on the part of Wirz, there must certainly
						have been no lack of such who were willing to swear to minor offenses. Such
						was the unnatural state of the public mind against the prisoner at that
						time, and that such men regarded themselves, and were regarded, as heroes,
						after having testified in the manner above described; whilst, on the other
						hand, the witness for the defense were intimidated, particularly after one
						of them had been arrested.</p>
					<p>But who is responsible for the many lives that were lost at Andersonville,
						and in the Southern prisons? That question has not fully been settled, but
						history will tell, on whose heads the guilt for those sacrificed hecatombs
						of human beings is to be placed. It was certainly not the fault of poor
						Captain Wirz, when, in consequence of medicines having been declared
						contraband of war by the North, the Union prisoners died for want of the
						same. How often have we read during the war that ladies, going South, had
						been arrested and placed in the Old Capitol Prison by the Union authorities,
						because some quinine, or other medicines, had been found concealed in their
						petticoats! Our navy prevented the ingress of medical stores from the
						sea-side, and our troops repeatedly destroyed drugstores, and even the
						supplies of private physicians in the South. Thus, the scarcity of medicines
						became general all over the South. Surgeon J. C. Pilot writes, September 6,
						1864, from Andersonville, (this letter was procured by the Judge Advocate in
						the Wirz trial): "We have but little more than the indigenous barks and
						roots with which to treat the numerous forms of disease to which our
						attention is daily called. For the treatment of wounds, ulcers, etc., we
						have literally nothing, except water. Our wards, some of them, are wild with
						gangrene, and we are compelled to fold our arms and look quietly upon its
						ravages, not even having stimulants to support the system under its
						depressing influence; the article being so limited in supply that it can
						only be issued for cures [?] under the knife."</p>
					<p>That provisions in the South were scarce will astonish nobody, when it is
						remembered how the war was carried on. General Sheridan boasted in his
						official report, that, in the Shenandoah Valley alone, he burned two
						thousand barns filled with wheat and corn, and all the mills in the whole
						tract of country; that he destroyed all factories of cloth, and killed, or
						drove off every animal, even to the poultry, that could contribute to human
						sustenance. And these desolation's were repeated in different parts of the
						South, and that so thoroughly that last month, two years after the end of
						the war, Congress had to appropriate a million of dollars to save the people
						of those regions from actual starvation. The destruction of railroads and
						other means of transportation, by which food could be supplied by abundant
						districts to those without it, increased the difficulties in giving
						sufficient food to our prisoners.</p>
					<p>The Confederate authorities, aware of their inability to sustain their
						prisoners, informed the Northern agents of the great mortality, and urgently
						requested that the prisoners should be exchanged, even without regard to the
						surplus which the Confederates had on the exchange rolls from former
						exchanges, that is, man for man.-But our War Department did not consent to
						an exchange. The did not want to exchange "skeletons for healthy men."
						Finally, when all hopes of an exchange were gone, Colonel Ouid, the
						Confederate Commissioner, offered, early in August, 1864, to deliver up all
						the federal sick and wounded, without requiring an equivalent in return, and
						pledged that the number would amount to ten or fifteen thousand, and if it
						did not, he would make up that number with well men. Although this offer was
						made in August, the transportation was not sent for them (to Savannah) until
						December, although he urged and implored (to use his own words) that haste
						should be made. During that very period the most of deaths at Andersonville
						occurred.-Congressman Covode, who lost two sons in Southern prisons, will do
						well, if he inquired <emph rend="italic">who </emph> those "skeletons" were,
						which the Hon. Secretary of War did not want to exchange for healthy men. If
						he does, he will hereafter be perhaps less bitter against the people of the
						South. </p>
					<p>But has the North treated her Southern prisoners so well that she should lift
						up her bands and cry "anathesus" [UNCLEAR] over the South. Mr. Stanton
						reports to Congress, July 10, 1866, that of Southern prisoners there died in
						the North 26,436 and of Northern prisoners in the South 22, 576. What a
						fearful record! Over 26,000 of prisoners dying in the midst of plenty! Mr
						Stanton gives the total number of prisoners in the north at 220,000 and in
						the South at 126,940. Suppose this to be correct, though this statement
						comes certainly from no impartial source, there died of prisoners in the
						South without medicines and provision, the eighth part. But the number of
						Southern prisoners in the North are probably included the paroled prisoners
						of Lee's, Johnston's and Smith's armies, who never entered a Northern
						prison. If that be so the mortality of Southern prisoners in the North will
						be even greater than that of the Federal prisoners in the South!</p>
					<p>We used justly to proclaim in former times that ours was "the land of the
						free and the home of the brave." But, when one-half of the country is
						shrouded in a despotism, which now only finds a parallel in Russian Poland;
						and when our generals and soldiers quietly permit that their former
						adversaries in arms shall be treated worse than the Helots of old, brave
						soldiers though they may be, who, when the forces and resources of both
						sections were more equal, have not seldom seen the backs of our best
						generals, not to speak of such as Butler and consorts, then we may well
						question whether the "star-spangled banner still waves over the land of the
						free or the home of the brave." A noble and brave soldier never permits his
						antagonist to be calumniated and trampled upon after an honorable surrender.
						Besides, notwithstanding the decisions of the highest legal tribunal in the
						land that military commissions are unconstitutional; the earnest and able
						protestations of President Johnson, and the sad results of military
						commissions, yet such military commissions are again established by recent
						legislation of Congress all over the suffering and starving South.</p>
					<p>History is just, and, as Mr. Lincoln used to say, we cannot escape history.
						Puritanical hypocrisy, self-adulation, and self-glorification will not save
						those enemies of liberty from their just punishment.</p>
					<p>Not even a Christian burial of the remains of Captain Wirz has been allowed
						by Secretary Stanton. They still lie, side by side with those of another
						acknowledged victim of military commissions, the unfortunate Mrs. Surrait
						[UNCLEAR], in the yard of the former jail in this city.</p>
					<p>If anybody should desire to reply to this, I politely beg that it may be done
						before the 1st of May next, as then I shall leave the country to return in
						the fall. After that day letters will reach me in care of the American
						Legation, or Mr. Benedetto Bolzani, Leipzig street, No 38, Berlin, Prussia.</p>
					<p>LOUIS SCHADE, Attorney-at-Law</p>
					<p>Washington, April 4, 1867</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>Louis Schade</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>Contains a copy of a letter from Captain Wirz's lawyer, Lewis Schade, who
					asserts that his client was wrongly convicted for his role in the deaths of the
					prisoners at the infamous Andersonville prisoner-of-war camp.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.24.02">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Democratic Committee Meeting</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kimmell</ln>
						<fn>F. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sharpe</ln>
						<fn>J. McDowell</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Orr</ln>
						<fn>James B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Loose</ln>
						<fn>Joseph S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brewer</ln>
						<fn>George W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The brief piece notes that the Democratic County Committee met at the
					office of Judge Kimmell on April 19th and elected F. M. Kimmell, J. McDowell
					Sharpe, James B. Orr, Joseph S. Loose, and George W. Brewer to represent the
					county at the State Convention to nominate a candidate for the state supreme
					court .</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>How They Love Them</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editors claim the Radicals have "summarily and contemptuously" rejected
					scores of soldiers appointed by President Johnson to fill civil appointments, a
					development that illustrates how ruthlessly political the Republicans are.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Military Rule Against Civil Law</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The Stevens-Sherman bill, says the <emph rend="italic">Age </emph>, is
						beginning to bear fruit. The planting of the dragon's teeth has produced a
						host of armed men, who are stealing away all the civil rights of the people
						of the South. In Military Division No. 2, formerly known as North and South
						Carolina, General Sickles has issued a proclamation which covers much of the
						ground formerly occupied by Courts of civil jurisdiction. That proclamation
						provides that no person shall be imprisoned for debt except upon conviction
						of fraud; that judgement or decrees for the payment of money on causes of
						action arising between December 19, 1860 and May 15, 1865, shall not be
						enforced by execution against the property or the person of the defendant;
						that sheriffs, coroners, and constables shall suspend for twelve months
						sales of 1860; that all proceedings for the recovery of money for the
						purchase of negroes are suspended; that in sales of property by execution or
						order of Court there shall be reserved to defendants having families
						depending upon them, implements of husbandry, household goods, etc, to the
						value of $500, and that the property of absent debtors shall not be taken
						under the foreign attachment process. The order also prohibits the carrying
						of deadly weapons, except officers and soldiers, and makes an offender
						amendable to trial and punishment by military commission; the punishment of
						death in certain cases of burglary and larceny is abolished. </p>
					<p>If this is the initiative military authority in the South, what may not be
						expected in the future? Many of the matters decided by General Sickles have
						been debated for a long time in other portions of the Union and are not yet
						settled. The annulment of contracts, the placing of impediments in the way
						of executions for debt, and other radical changes in the laws of the States
						composing Military Division, No. 2, are serious attacks upon the rights of
						self-government guaranteed to the people by the Constitution. But whether
						the act in themselves are just or unjust, is not the pith and marrow of the
						point to be urged against the proclamation of General Sickles and the law of
						Congress under and by authority of which it was issued. The root of the
						mischief lies in the destruction of Sovereign States by legislative
						enactments and the subordination of the civil authority to the military
						power in a time of universal and profound peace in the country. Congress has
						just as much authority to appoint a military commander for this State, and
						he to change all its laws and ordinances, as they had to enact the
						Stevens-Sherman bill, and commission the officers under it to act as General
						Sickles has done. Such an assumption of power would have been scouted in the
						English Parliament of 1688, which led the advance of the battle for civil
						rights there, and was repudiated also in the American Congress of 1776,
						which gave a free government to a young Empire in the West. But the mischief
						has been consummated. The Radicals have openly disregarded the fundamental
						law of the land, reduced ten States to military provinces, and placed over
						them military rulers who are competent to alter, abolish or enact what laws
						they please without the "consent of the governed." This is a Radical change
						in our whole theory of Government. There can no longer be a question upon
						this point, and men interested in the political condition and material
						progress of the nation must ask themselves the question, how can the tide of
						innovation be stayed? It must be checked, or the Republic will be merged in
						a military despotism. A defeat of the Radical party at the polls is the
						surest road to relief, and such acts as those of General Sickles will aid
						materially in bringing about that result.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article asserts that the Stevens-Sherman bill denies "the people of the
					South" their "civil rights." The provisions contained within the legislation --
					the "annulment of contracts, the placing of impediments in the way of executions
					for debt, and other radical changes in the law" -- represent a serious threat to
					"the rights of self-government guaranteed to the people by the Constitution."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Liberty and Suffrage Not Enough For the Negroes</head>
				<origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The Southern negroes seem to be apt scholars in the Radical school of
						aggression and plunder. A year or two ago they were thankful for the boon of
						liberty. A little later, for the privilege of civil rights. But now, grown
						great in arrogance, they demand free gifts of the lands owned by their late
						masters. What their next demand would be, if granted their desire in this,
						it is impossible to say, but possibly nothing short of the exclusive control
						of both the State and Federal Governments as the superior race. The
						following extract from the report of a Radical negro meeting held in
						Richmond, Virginia, on the 18th, not only bears out the foregoing statement,
						but it furnishes an instructive warning to the country:</p>
					<p>"The convention re-assembled at 10 A. M., to-day. The prevailing feeling
						shown in the speeches of the colored members was confiscation. One or two
						who opposed it were saluted by cries of 'copperhead.' The announcement by
						one Freeland, of Petersburg, that if Congress did not give the negroes land,
						they would be taken by violence, was received with much applause."</p>
					<p>Here we have the opening of a question that will eventually lead to
						disastrous results. The insane, dishonest and revolutionary utterances of
						Radical demagogues have been eagerly caught up by the negroes, and, sooner
						or later, must bear horrible fruits. Will not the country hold the Radical
						leaders responsible for what is to come, whilst crushing with military power
						the barbarous black savages who may undertake to overthrow the laws in order
						to satisfy their lust for plunder? Most certainly it will. When it becomes
						necessary to crush out with the bayonet the nigger free-booters who now
						threaten-under the very nose of the satraps-to commence a plundering war,
						the white Radical instigators will also be brought to judgement.-<emph
							rend="italic">Patriot and Union</emph></p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Since gaining their freedom, the article contends, blacks have increasingly
					"grown great in arrogance," to the point that they now "demand free gifts of the
					lands owned by their late masters."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Colored Suffrage at the North</head>
				<origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
				<commentary>"The Richmond Enquirer hits the men in the North who would force negro
					suffrage upon the South, while they refuse to accept the same thing at home,
					some raps over the knuckles in the article printed below:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The question of colored suffrage at the North is purely one of <emph
							rend="italic">prejudice </emph>. There is no reason for denying suffrage
						to the blacks of the North except the prejudice against them; for their
						numbers are too few to give the question any consequence as to its ill
						effect on the constituent body. In New York State, for example, the papers
						estimate that the extension of unrestricted suffrage to the negroes would
						only add ten thousand to the number of voters. As the aggregate vote
						actually cast for President three years ago was 780,000, the total number of
						voters in the State may be set down at little if any short of a <emph
							rend="italic">million </emph>. Yet these ten hundred thousand white
						voters refuse to open the doors to ten thousand black voters. They would
						outnumber the admitted ones in the ratio of a <emph rend="italic">hundred to
							one</emph>. Why do they not admit them? Are they <emph rend="italic"
							>afraid </emph> of them? or do they <emph rend="italic">hate </emph>
						them? It is always a grave question how far ignorant and vagrant persons may
						safely be embraced among suffragans. It is generally conceded that it is a
						subject requiring much caution, and that there is bunt [UNCLEAR] somewhere.
						But no such prudential consideration controls the action in New York. The
						only test she makes against these excluded blacks is their <emph
							rend="italic">color </emph> and the smallness of their number shows
						their exclusion to be from caprice and prejudice, and not from any
						conviction of necessity. Even arsenic, though poisonous, may be safely taken
						in minute doses. </p>
					<p>With such an example at home, Northern Congressmen commend themselves neither
						to white or black by their different proceeding here; and this apart from
						the impropriety of their interference at all.</p>
					<p>The colored people plainly see from their <emph rend="italic">home </emph>
						policy that it is from no regard <emph rend="italic">to them or their
						race</emph> that negro suffrage is ordered here; while the whites are
						constrained to regard it as an inexcusable and tyrannical trifling with the
						interests of the Southern community, white and black, to try suddenly and on
						a giant scale, at our risk, an experiment which they shrink from testing
						among themselves in the most attenuated degree. They give us by the spoonful
						what <emph rend="italic">they </emph> refuse to take in homeopathic doses. A
						physician would pronounce such practice mere reckless and deliberate
						poisoning. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that blacks in the North are denied the vote primarily because of
					white prejudice.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Radical Proscription of Working Men</head>
				<origin>Hartford Times</origin>
				<commentary>"A thousand men are walking the streets of Portland, Connecticut, asking
					employment, who were discharged by Radical employers for daring to vote the
					Democratic ticket at the late election in that State.--The Hartford Times thus
					speaks of the effort made by the Radical party to control the working men and
					its effects:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The piece reports that 1,000 white men in Connecticut were discharged by
					their Radical employers "for daring to vote the Democratic ticket" in the last
					state election.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Petty Pilfering</head>
				<origin>Harrisburg Patriot and Union</origin>
				<commentary>"Almost every newspaper in the State without exception as to party has
					denounced the wholesale stealing done by the Radical majority of the recent
					Legislature. The Harrisburg Patriot and Union gives an account of the petty
					pilfering carried on under the auspices of that body. It shows a condition of
					affairs which is most disgraceful, but the account is unquestioningly true in
					all respects. The Patriot says:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that the Republicans who served in the last assembly stole "all the
					nice rugs, mats, and other portable necessaries in and around the legislative
					halls," and used the state coffers to pay for their "whiskey, brandy, and gin."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.24.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--A Postmaster At Last</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hamsher</ln>
						<fn>B. Y.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Walsh</ln>
						<fn>Matthew P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The Senate confirmed Matthew P. Walsh as the new Postmaster of
					Chambersburg, though the same body recently rejected his appointment. Evidently,
					the Senate determined Walsh to be better suited for the position than the
					alternative candidate, B. Y. Hamsher, "a straightout 'copperhead.'"</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--The Courts--2nd Week</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hess</ln>
						<fn>John F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Pfoutz</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Helser</ln>
						<fn>Solomon</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McGrath</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Tucker</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harbaugh</ln>
						<fn>George J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Everett</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Everett</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Corwell</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Valentine</ln>
						<fn>Gilbert</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gsell</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Summarizes the cases heard by the Court during the second week of its
					current session. "Common Pleas. John F. Hess use of Samuel Pfoutz vs. Andrew S.
					Monn. The plaintiff, several years since, sold a farm in Quincy township at
					Public Sale, which was purchased by the defendant, who claimed the growing crop.
					A large number of witnesses were called on both sides whose testimony conflicted
					as to whether the grain was reserved in the conditions of sales as read at the
					time. Verdict for plaintiff for $392.03--the value of the grain with interest.
					Solomon Helser vs. William McGrath, former Sheriff. Trespass de bonis asportus.
					The defendant, as Sheriff of the County, levied on and sold, as the property of
					Jacob Myers, certain rye which was claimed by Helser as his property. Verdict
					for defendant. George Tucker vs. George J. Harbaugh. Assumpsit. Verdict for
					plaintiff $974.00. Samuel Baker, use of John Miller vs. William Everett,
					Executor of David Everett, dec'd. Assumpsit. This was a suit brought by
					plaintiff to recover money lent to David Everett in his lifetime and as the
					plaintiff held no evidence of the debt in the shape of a note or due bill, the
					claim was resisted by the Executor. Owing to some defect in the pleadings the
					jury was discharged and the case continued. The School Directors of St. Thomas
					township vs. Henry Corwell. This was an action on the case to recover the sum of
					one hundred dollars bounty, paid to defendant as a volunteer in the army, for
					St. Thomas township. The defendant, after having received the money and had
					himself credited to Green township and received $500 bounty. He refused to pay
					back the money to St. Thomas township hence the suit. Verdict for the plaintiff,
					$119.00. Gilbert Valentine vs. Samuel Gsell. Appeal from the Justice's Docket.
					The sum involved in this case was inconsiderable. The object of the suit seemed
					to us to be to enable the parties to learn a little law at each others expense.
					Verdict for plaintiff, $17.50."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="l">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Sunday Loungers</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The habit of lounging seems to have grown quite popular now-a-days,
						particularly with the youthful inmates of our town; they seem to have to
						have become so enamored with the disgusting habit that I fear it would go
						hard with them if they were compelled to abandon their favorite mode of
						agreeably passing time away on the Sabbath, by "loafing" on the corners of
						our streets. Now why do our "Junior Sons of America" hold sociable Sunday
						meetings on the public streets of this town, and insult persons who
						necessarily pass them, by making presumptuous and silly remarks concerning
						those persons! Are those young gents very anxious to inform people
						universally that they are low and vulgar specimens of humanity?-If that is
						their desire they might appoint a new rendezvous, where they would not be
						interrupted by passers-by. What is more embarrassing to a lady than to hear
						the purposely loud-spoken opinion of some ungentlemanly young man concerning
						what he considers distasteful in her attire or appearance, as she passes by
						him on the street! I have seen the authors of such impoliteness completely
						canned, and I think the same treatment might be administered with good
						results, to some of impudent young men who have no other way of amusing
						themselves, than by standing upon the street corners of this town,
						expressing their crude and ill-founded opinions of their superiors. A reform
						in this respect is much needed in our town, and if all right-thinking
						persons would speak out against the disgraceful habit in fitting words of
						disapproval, we doubt not the young men who amuse themselves in this way
						would soon become ashamed of their conduct and amend their manners. H.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>H.</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>"H." reproaches local youth for their "disgusting habit" of "loafing" on
					the town's street corners while "expressing their crude and ill-founded opinions
					of their superiors."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Eberly</ln>
						<fn>H. N.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Chambers</ln>
						<fn>Adeline</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Creigh</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 17th, H. N. Eberly and Adeline Chambers were married by Rev.
					Thomas Creigh.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Gleason</ln>
						<fn>Harry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 19th, Harry Gleason, 25, died in Chambersburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Wingert</ln>
						<fn>Minnie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wingert</ln>
						<fn>E. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wingert</ln>
						<fn>Lizzie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 8th, Minnie, only daughter of Lizzie and E. R. Wingert, died at 6
					months old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Metcalf</ln>
						<fn>Washington C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 13th, Washington C. Metcalf, 6, died near Waynesboro.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stouffer</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stouffer</ln>
						<fn>Abraham K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 9th, Abraham K., eldest son of John Stouffer, of Jacob, died at
					age 22 in Willow Grove.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.24.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
