<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.07.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/24/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-07-10">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="00">10</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.07.10.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.07.10.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Cost of Radical Reconstruction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It seems that the appropriation made to carry out the military reconstruction
                        act in the South had already been all expended so that a new appropriation
                        is necessary. It is understood that Congress at its present session will
                        appropriate half a million dollars more for that purpose. How do the
                        over-burdened tax-payer of the county like the prospect? With a debt of
                        three thousand millions hanging over the country and an exhausted treasury
                        unable to pay the interest as it falls due, Congress continues to rob the
                        people of their hard earnings by recklessly appropriating large sums of
                        money to keep up an expensive military establishment in the South, in order
                        to perpetuate the Radical party in power. All this enormous drain upon the
                        treasury could be saved if the Southern people were permitted to govern
                        themselves and defray the expenses of their own government, as they are
                        willing and anxious to do. but this would not answer the selfish and
                        ambitious ends of these Radical traitors. How long, Oh! how long will the
                        people patiently submit to these things.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In addition to imposing an unreasonable burden on white southerners,
                    Reconstruction, note the editors, is exhausting the treasury. "With a debt of
                    three thousand millions hanging over the country," they argue, "Congress
                    continues to rob the people of their hard earnings by recklessly appropriating
                    large sums of money to keep up an expensive military establishment in the South,
                    in order to perpetuate the Radical party in power."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Rump Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Having spurned "the teachings of WASHINGTON, JEFFERSON, MADISON, and the
                    other great and good men who founded the Republic, and openly declared their
                    intention to 'reconstruct' the government on the principles of the Radical
                    party," Republicans in Congress, the editors claim, have reconvened with the
                    goal of forcing black suffrage upon "all the States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Political Situation in Tennessee</head>
                <origin>N. Y. World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article renders a scathing portrait of the situation in Tennessee under
                    Gov. Bronlow, whom it labels the "filthiest of the scum that rose to the surface
                    in the civil war." Supplied with money from Loyal Leagues in the North, Bronlow
                    has organized a "loyal" militia to "harry, oppress, and terrify" anyone who
                    resists his despotic rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Viva La Simon--Viva La Corruption!</head>
                <origin>Carlisle Volunteer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The nomination of Henry W. Williams, <emph rend="italic">of
                        Connecticut</emph>, for Judge of the Supreme court, by the "Blockhead"
                        Williamsport Convention was a great triumph for the old Winnebago chief,
                        Cameron, The Cameron wing in the Convention was led by Wayne McVeagh, Esq.,
                        of Chester, Winnebag's son-in-law, who was assisted by Ned McPherson, the
                        Clerk of Thad. Steven's Rump Congress. The opponents of Cameron had Wm. B.
                        Mann of Philadelphia, as their captain. Williams was the Cameron candidate
                        for Judge, and M. Russel Thayer of the city, was the anti-Cameron
                        candidate.-Simon, as usual, triumphed, whether by the same means that he
                        used last winter when he was elected U. S. Senator, we know not; but the
                        anti-Cameron men hint very broadly that Williams was <emph rend="italic"
                            >unfairly </emph> nominated. </p>
                    <p>When Cameron, last winter, secured his election to the Senate over Curtin and
                        others, he was spoken of by more than two-thirds of the Radical Jacobin
                        journals of the State as one of "the most corrupt men in the Commonwealth,
                        who disgraced and demoralized every party whose cause he pretended to
                        espouse;" and they asserted in plain words, that he bought his election with
                        green-backs. Now, as Williams is the fast friend, the <emph rend="italic"
                            >protege </emph> of Cameron, and owes his nomination to him, can the
                        friends of Curtin and others, who were candidates for U. S. Senator last
                        winter, and who owing to Cameron's great wealth and free use of green-backs,
                        were so unmercifully slaughtered-can they support the imported Yankee for
                        Judge of the Supreme Court? By doing so, they strengthen Cameron's hands and
                        augment his power, which power he will use against them with relentless
                        vigor. If they are wise and desire to stop this bold, bad man in this
                        infamous career, they will refuse to give their support to the Connecticut
                        schoolmaster, who has been selected by him for the highest judicial position
                        in the State. Let them act as Cameron acts when his enemies receive
                        nominations. He strikes them at the polls. Let us see now whether the
                        Radical editors who, but a few months since, declaimed so vehemently against
                        Cameron's corrupt practices, have the pluck and rebukes him, now that an
                        opportunity is presented. If they desire to be considered honest and
                        consistent, they cannot and will not support Williams. Let them, then, for
                        once, we repeat, show a little independence and refuse their sanction to the
                        old Winnebago's arrangements. Beyond all question or doubt, Judge Sherwood,
                        the candidate of the people, will be elected by a sweeping majority. This is
                        an admitted fact, a forgone conclusion, and this time for those independent
                        Republicans who despise the trickery, chicanery and corruption of Cameron,
                        to place their seal of condemnation upon him and his doings. Will they do
                        it? We will see.-<emph rend="italic">Carlisle Volunteer</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article suggests that Henry W. Williams's nomination as the Republican
                    candidate for the Supreme Court is yet another example of Simon Cameron's
                    "corrupt practices." It asserts that, just as he did to win his Senate seat,
                    Cameron engineered a scheme to secure the selection of Williams over his rival
                    M. Russell Thayer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The People Must Recover Their Lost Power</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the article, Congress is currently ruled by a cabal of
                    "demagogues" who have duped the masses into "blindly" following their program.
                    If the people could "see and comprehend the secret plans of the Radical
                    leaders," it explains, "Radicalism would not live a day longer."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Kentucky Congressmen</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the wake of Congress' decision to deny the elected representatives from
                    Kentucky their seats, the article warns readers that Congress could "refuse to
                    admit the members of any Northern State with equal propriety."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.07.10.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Resigned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John A. Kunkelman resigned the pastorate of the Lutheran Congregation
                    and accepted a position in Fort Wayne, Indiana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Untrue</head>
                <origin>Fulton Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that reports of Mrs. Baker's demise are false. Baker was injured
                    last fall in the same accident in which Miss Hassler lost her life.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Dr. J. K. Reid</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>J. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. J. K. Reid, formerly of Chambersburg, opened a dentist office in York.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Writing School</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the opening of P. Hamman's writing school in the Masonic Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Deceased</head>
                <origin>Village Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whetzel</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Whetzel, 55, died from the injuries he suffered when a tree fell on
                    him while he was cutting wood. Whetzel's health had declined precipitously
                    following the amputation of his leg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Klipp</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. Klipp, a local baker, suffered serious injuries when he fell while
                    watering his horse. Baker sustained a broken nose when his horse kicked him in
                    the face while he lay on the ground.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Mad Dogs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mad dogs have appeared in unusually large numbers in portions of the
                    county. In Greene and Letterkenny townships, for instance, several rabid canines
                    have bitten other dogs and livestock belonging to farmers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--The Fourth In Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a fight broke out between blacks and whites in front of
                    Repository Hall on the Fourth of July.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.07.10.04">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
