<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.06.12">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>05/22</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-06-12">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="06">June</month>
			<day norm="00">12</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.06.12.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>The New Liquor Law</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>HARRISBURG, May 28.</p>
					<p>Two laws passed by the last Legislature of Pennsylvania have excited much
						comment. These are the Sunday liquor law, known as "an act to enable police
						officers to enforce order in licensed houses, and to exterminate the
						unlicensed traffic," and "An act to incorporate the Gettysburg Asylum for
						invalid solders, and to raise funds therefor, and for the securing and
						preserving of the battleground at Gettysburg."</p>
					<p>A full explanation of the manner in which they passed the Legislature is
						hereto appended.</p>
					<p>An act was introduced into the Legislature in February 18, 1867 to "Regulate
						the granting of licenses to eating houses and taverns in the County of
						Allegheny, and to enforce order therein." This became a law. On March 1,
						some person took a printed copy of the Allegheny, County bill (as above),
						and with a pair of scissors cut out <emph rend="italic">eleven </emph>
						sections and pasted them on a sheet of paper. But the artist evidently
						became dissatisfied with his own work for he drew his pen through one of the
						sections and blotted it out thus leaving <emph rend="italic">ten </emph>,
						which constitute the present liquor law. The section which was blotted out
						was in these words: "Every person who shall be convicted of fraudulently
						adulterating, for the purpose of sale, any substance intended for food, or
						any wine, whiskey, or other spirituous liquors, ale or beer, with any
						substance injurious to health, or who shall sell or offer for sale any such
						adulterated or poisonous food or drink, knowing it to be such, and the same
						come to the knowledge of the Board of Excise (police), it shall be their
						duty to report such case to the proper magistrate, as directed in section-of
						this act." </p>
					<p>The ten printed sections having been pasted in order, Senator Bingham, of
						Pittsburgh, wrote over the top of them the title of the newly constructed
						bill, viz: "An act to enable police officers to enforce order in licensed
						houses and to exterminate the unlicensed traffic."</p>
					<p>This bill was then introduced into the Senate on March 1, by Mr. Bingham, and
						was referred to the Committee on Vice and Immorality.</p>
					<p>On the morning of March 14 Mr. Worthington, from the Committee, reported the
						bill back to the Senate without any amendment.</p>
					<p>The patched-up printed bill was then sent to the State Printing office,
						whence it emerged in good shape and was put upon the files in front of each
						member. On April 2 the consideration of public bills was made the order in
						the Senate, and the bill of Mr. Bigham came up. It is usual with public
						measure to go into committee of the whole for purposes of amendment.-This
						was dispensed with and the bill was passed, without discussion (not finally,
						to a third reading, merely by a <emph rend="italic">viva voce</emph> vote,
						without any call of the yeas and nays. </p>
					<p>On April 4, bills on the third readings were considered and that of Mr.
						Bigham was passed <emph rend="italic">finally </emph> by a vote of 18 yeas
						to 10 nays. </p>
					<p>The only Philadelphia Senator voting in favor of it was George Connell, of
						the Fourth District.</p>
					<p>The Philadelphia Senators voting against it were Ridgewood and Donovan.
						Absent, McCandless.</p>
					<p>The yeas and nays were required by Schall (of Allentown) and Bigham (of
						Pittsburgh), and were as follows:</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">In favor of the bill</emph>-Bigham, of Allegheny; Browne,
						of Lawrence; Brown of Mercer; Coleman, of Lebanon; Connell, of Philadelphia;
						Cowles of Potter; Fisher, of Lancaster; Laudon, of Bradford; McConaughy, of
						Adams; Royer of Somerset; Taylor,of Beaver; White, of Indiana; Worthington,
						of Chester; and Hall, of Blair.-18. Republicans 17; Democrat 1. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Against the bill</emph>-Burnett, of Monroe; Davis, of
						Berks; Donovan, of Philadelphia; Glatz of York; James, of Bucks; Randall, of
						Schuykill; Ridgway of Philadelphia; Schall, of Lehigh; Searight, of Fayette;
						and Wallace, of Clearfield.-Republicans 1; Democrats 9. </p>
					<p>On April 5 the bill was sent from the Senate into the House, and by the
						special motion of some one (the records give no clue to the person was laid
						on the table, instead of taking the usual course, and being sent to a
						committee.</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">On April 9 the House took up one hundred and
						fifth-six</emph> bills for consideration, and passed or otherwise disposed
						of them by their titles! They were all "private bills," of local or
						individual interest, except the liquor bill, which, under the rules, had no
						legal place among them, being a "public bill." The <emph rend="italic"
							>minute book</emph> of the House, however, records it as having passed
						along with the rest, and the minute book is evidence which cannot be
						gainsayed. It is apparent, from a close inspection of this minute book, that
						the bill when its title was reached in numerical order, was not at first
						considered, but that the Speaker or clerks, or House overlooked it
						(unintentionally or willfully), and after the lapses of some little time and
						the transaction of other business, returned to it, and passed it by its
						title. </p>
					<p>As an evidence that "Public Bills" had no right to be considered on that day
						is the fact that at the same session another bill (No. 29) was objected to
						by a member because it was of a public character. The Speaker recognized the
						force of the suggestion, but decided that the bill in question was a
						"private" one, and it was, therefore, considered. Had it been "public" it
						would have been the duty of the Speaker to have ruled it out of order. By
						what meanse a general liquor law, affecting the whole State, was inserted on
						Private Calendar day, between an act to regulate a street in the Borough of
						Minersville, and an act to authorize the Lehigh Navigation Company to issue
						bonds, is a mystery which the members of the House may explain if they can.
						The Clerk, whose handwriting on the original bill declares it to have
						passed, is dead.</p>
					<p>The <emph rend="italic">Legislative Record</emph> (the official newspaper of
						the Legislature) has not one word to show that the bill was ever considered
						on April 9. </p>
					<p>If the bill <emph rend="italic">did </emph> pass on the private calendar on
						Tuesday, it was passed in an improper manner-at an unusual time, (Thursday,
						and not Tuesday, was public bill day,) and in direct violation of Rule 36 of
						the House, which declares that bills "shall be read in Committee of the
						Whole," so as to allow necessary amendments. </p>
					<p>The bill was signed by the Governor on its merits alone, it being no part of
						his duty to inquire into the manner of its passage or to doubt the
						correctness of the certified copy furnished him by the clerks.</p>
					<p>In conclusion, it may be given as the opinion of the writer, that if the
						Legislature violates its own rules, there is no power vested in any other
						tribunal to inquire into the facts, the clerks' books of the two houses
						being the only legal evidence by which the passage of a bill can be
						determined; and the entry in such books being <emph rend="italic">prima
							facie</emph> evidence that every rule of the House was compiled with-in
						other words, the House must sustain the acts and entries of its official
						agents, the clerks, whether said acts were in conformity with the usual
						rules, or in violation of them. </p>
					<p>The following are the facts relative to the passage of the "Gettysburg
						Asylum" (lottery) bill. They are from the official records:</p>
					<p>February 27-(Morning Session).-Senator McConaughy, of Adams County,
						introduced "An act to incorporate the Gettysburg Asylum for Invalid
						Soldiers, and to raise funds therefor, and for the securing and preserving
						of the battle-ground at Gettysburg," It was referred to the Committee on
						Corporations. The majority of the members and the press reporters
						considering it to be a local bill for a patriotic object, and neglecting for
						that reason to examine it carefully.</p>
					<p>February 27-(Morning Session).-Senator McConaughy moved to discharge the
						Corporation Committee from the further consideration of the bill, (Note.-The
						corporation Committee had never considered it, nor had it in their actual
						possession), and moved to suspend the rules.</p>
					<p>Senator Randall objected, whereupon Mr. McConaughy said:</p>
					<p>Mr. Speaker, this bill is to establish an asylum for invalid soldiers.</p>
					<p>On suspending the rules to consider the bill the yeas were 21 and nays 8. The
						bill then passed.</p>
					<p>It is questionable whether the majority of the Senators knew that the bill
						was a <emph rend="italic">public </emph> one, for almost instantaneously
						after its passage, Mr. Wallace arose and said: </p>
					<p>Mr. Speaker, it seems to me that we should devote some <emph rend="italic"
							>little </emph> attention to <emph rend="italic">public </emph>
						business. </p>
					<p>February 28 the bill was messaged to the House.</p>
					<p>March 1 (next day) Mr. Stumbaugh of Franklin County moved to suspend the
						orders and consider the bill, and it passed the House finally without yeas
						or nays, or a word of inquiry, debate, or explanation.</p>
					<p>At least two Philadelphia members must have been present, and allowed the
						bill to have passed without calling the yeas and nays, for almost
						immediately afterwards a motion was made by Mr. Lee, of Frankford, to
						adjourn, and one by Mr. Davis, to postpone the consideration of another
						bill.</p>
					<p>February 28 the bill was sent back to the Senate.</p>
					<p>March 6, compared and sent to the Governor.</p>
					<p>March 8, approved by the Governor and became a law.</p>
					<p>The bill was never printed in its passage through either house, and could be
						seen by no one except by a personal appeal to the courtesy of the clerks,
						and it is not within the recollection of the majority of Representatives
						that it was ever read in the House except by its title.</p>
					<p>All the above facts are gathered from and based upon the official records at
						Harrisburg, after a thorough and searching examination.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports on the passage of the "Sunday Liquor Law" and the "Gettysburg
					Asylum Bill," both of which, the article claims, were approved through dubious
					means.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>Developments! The Last Pennsylvania Legislature</head>
				<origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>PHILADELPHIA, May 27.</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Eds. Philadelphia Inquirer</emph>: </p>
					<p>Since the adjournment of the session of the Pennsylvania Legislature of 1867,
						the public press has denounced it as venal and corrupt.</p>
					<p>To the astonishment of the people, it appears that laws were privately
						enacted, of which no notice was taken in the newspapers of the day at the
						time of their passage. To the equal astonishment of some members of the
						Legislature, laws were made of which, <emph rend="italic">they </emph> knew
						absolutely nothing until long after the adjournment. </p>
					<p>These things seem to require an explanation. As the agent of a newspaper at
						Harrisburg during the session, allow me to make that explanation in distinct
						and explicit terms. It has never been so opportune as at the present time
						when honorable men throughout the State are endeavering to find a remedy for
						legislative corruption.</p>
					<p>The session of 1867 opened without the discussion of any measure of
						particular importance, except the Free Railroad law.-No rival corporations
						were in the field to urge "special" legislation. Every appearance indicated
						a dull winter.</p>
					<p>If it be true that many members had spent large sums in securing their
						nomination and election, their prospects at the time obtaining a return must
						have looked gloomy. Yet one recourse appeared to be left. If the people
						would not seek the law makers, the law makers could seek the people.</p>
					<p>Forthwith ingenious men devised a plausible system of <emph rend="italic"
							>making </emph> business. They appointed committees with varied
						powers.-In jocular legislative circles they were called "smelling
						committees." The ostensible object of their appointment was always "to
						ascertain if such and such evil existed, with power to send for persons and
						papers, and to report &amp;c." Armed with this authority, they went out
						into the Sate from Erie to the Delaware. They investigated the greatest
						variety of subjects from the private books of a well known capitalist to the
						price of oil on Sugar Creek. To prominent railroad managers they came like
						hawks upon a brood of chickens. Each committee resolved itself into one
						great mark of interrogation, and placed its formidable "why, how, when and
						where" before the victim, who tremblingly obeyed his demands as the great
						seal of the Commonwealth, with "Virtue, Liberty and Independence." blazoned
						upon it, was thrust before his eyes. These peregrinating, investigating,
						fragmentary, legislative excursionists had all their expenses paid by the
						State. What good thing did they do? </p>
					<p>If they were really appointed for any legitimate purpose, <emph rend="italic"
							>they never once achieved it</emph>. If they found any evil it still
						exists for <emph rend="italic">in no single case did they ever remedy
						it</emph>. If they where designed to secure good legislation on any subject,
							<emph rend="italic">they never succeeded in the effort</emph>. They were
						of no possible use to the people, whatever benefit may have accrued to the
						committees. </p>
					<p>This was one form of legislation that was more than equivocal. There was
						another equally bad, if not worse. Many members became speculators. Although
						originally sent by the people, to enact equal laws for all, they no sooner
						took their seats than they devised special bills, with their own friends,
						relatives and acquaintances named therein as incorporators. These bills were
						for many purposes, from the establishments of gold and silver mining
						companies, without enough land to bury a gold dollar, to the construction of
						immense railroads, without enough capital to buy one rail. The legislators
						of a great Commonwealth thus became law jobbers, with a stock on hand of
						charters to accommodate the market. It can readily be perceived that an act
						in which perhaps a dozen members were interested, was almost certain to be
						successfully passed. Not unfrequently these speculative laws (whether
						intrinsically or not) interfered with the vested rights of other parties,
						and became injurios to enterprises in which honorable men had expended years
						of toil and large amounts of money.</p>
					<p>These two illustrations of the committee system are intended to give a
						correct idea of the general morality of the session of 1867, and these
						illustrations lead to a point about which the people know little or nothing,
						viz: The <emph rend="italic">manner </emph> in which laws were made. </p>
					<p>In mercantile business a man who signs a promissory note which binds his
						property without first reading it, is adjudged to be an idiot. In ordinary
						social life, a man who indorses an agreement without knowing its contents,
						is esteemed a knave or a madman. <emph rend="italic">Yet the legislators
						of</emph> 1867, <emph rend="italic">actually passed laws at the rate of
							thirty to the hour, without reading them except by their titles</emph>.
						To appreciate the enormity of this transaction it must be remembered that
						these laws were to govern the widow and the orphan, the beggar and the
						capitalist, men of all religious creeds, business, interests and
						connections. A solemn duty that of protecting the citizen in every right
						that humanity holds dear, thus degenerated into a farce.-Day after day,
						whole pages of printed titles were enacted into laws, without the contents
						of the bills being read. </p>
					<p>But this farce was rendered even more ridiculous. To give a color of
						deliberation to the transaction, it was required in some cases that the
						person representing the Legislative District to which the bill (by its
						title) was <emph rend="italic">supposed </emph> to refer should say, "All
						right!" Whereupon it passed. An immense majority thus delegated to some one
						man the exercise of their own duty, ability and judgement. Happy era of
						Arcadian simplicity, when such confidence exists among men in high position,
						and when the utterance of just two words, by just one man, will give to a
						half-dozen pages of unknown manuscript the majesty of a law, representing
						the will and controlling the actions of millions of people. Sarcastic,
						indeed, was the remark of a member of the House, that it would save time to
						pass the bills by their <emph rend="italic">numbers </emph>, without the
						trouble of reading the titles. </p>
					<p>This system produced its unavoidable results. Members, officers and
						reporters, became entangled in the maze. Nobody knew exactly what bills had
						passed, or what ones had fallen. The duty of the speakers and officers was
						merely executive, and they had neither the power or ability to resist the
						wishes of a majority which seemed determined to transform a deliberate body
						into a machine for turning out laws with lightning rapidity. To trace
						particular bills, and ascertain their exact condition was the labor of
						hours. They were numbered by the thousands, and it was not uncommon for more
						than one hundred new ones in rough manuscript, to be introduced at a single
						night session. At odd times, on the special request of some member, one or
						more of these would be considered and hurriedly passed, no particular
						interest being manifested by any one in the provisions of the new law.
						Amendments were piled upon amendments, and in one case, eight new sections
						were offered to a bill as a single amendment.</p>
					<p>Not unfrequently after some apparently trifling bill had been printed for
						weeks, it would be modified two or three minutes before its passage by the
						substitution of an entirely new bill, with new provisions. It was quite
						common for a measure which had passed one House in harmless shape, to have
						some objectionable amendment quietly attached to it in the other branch. The
						English language was tortured to supply apparently harmless phrases which
						could afterwards be construed so as to confer immense powers. In one case a
						local corporation, nominally to operate in a little township, came very near
						being transformed into a mammoth organization, by adding the words "and
						elsewhere." In another case, under cover of a city railroad in Western
						village, was concealed a project to build a steam railroad anywhere in the
						State. The members of the Legislature of 1867 unquestionably knew that such
						practices were common at the very time they allowed bills to be passed by
						their title, under the "<emph rend="italic">all right</emph>" system; yet
						they took no warning. </p>
					<p>This is the way that laws were made at Harrisburg and this is the reason why
						many bills escaped the attention, not only of interested parties, but of the
						newspaper press at the time of their passage. Does any man wonder at it?</p>
					<p>This communication leaves very much <emph rend="italic">unsaid </emph>.
						Personalities are not needed to prove the effects of a bad system; but if
						any member feels aggrieved, let him ask himself whether the statements
						herein made are not literally true. Unless there is a reform, he and his pet
						projects may next year fall victims to the evil that he now indorses.-The
						people have a right to the better administration of legislative power. To
						obtain this, it does not necessarily follow that they need cast away men of
						any particular party or class, but only select from the candidates those who
						have shown themselves worthy of the trust. A <emph rend="italic">few </emph>
						such men were at Harrisburg last winter, but they were not in the majority.
						Such men should be cherished as tender flowers, whose purity has enabled
						them to bloom in a garden where good things generally die young. </p>
					<p>REPORTER.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>Reporter</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article offers a scathing account of the machinations hatched during
					the last session of the legislature.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.06.12.02">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editors urge Democratic journals around the country to abandon the
					recent trend of labeling Republicans as "Blockheads." Instead, they should
					continue to call them by the name given by the New York Herald: "Black
					Republicans." This "designation," they insist, "is peculiarly appropriate and
					truthful."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Supreme Judgeship</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editors support the nomination of George Sharwood, of Philadelphia, as
					candidate for Judge of the Supreme Court.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Corruption of the Last Legislature</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We direct the attention of our readers to two communications to be found on
						the first page our paper to-day, giving a somewhat detailed account of the
						manner in which bills and "jobs" were put through the Legislature at
						Harrisburg last winter. The first appeared in the Philadelphia <emph
							rend="italic">Inquirer </emph>, and was written by one who occupied the
						position of reporter during the session and consequently was personally
						cognizant of the facts, thereof. The other was doubtless also written by a
						reporter, and appeared in all the Philadelphia papers through the regular
						channel of the Associated Press. </p>
					<p>These developments show a most extraordinary and alarming state of corruption
						among the members of the Legislature.-Hundreds of bills were rushed through
						without being read except by their titles, and these frequently giving no
						clue to their real contents, so that the members outside of the "ring" had
						no knowledge of the character of the Legislation that was being enacted.-All
						that was necessary was for one of the "ring" to say "all right," and the
						bill was passed under the whip and spur without a word of discussion. We
						call particular attention to the account given to the "Gettysburg Asylum"
						swindle, and the part played by a certain Senator and Representative from
						this District in that transaction. Citizens of Franklin County, read, ponder
						and reflect, and then go earnestly to work to apply the remedy at the polls
						next fall.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>In light of the recent revelations regarding the "extraordinary and
					alarming state of corruption among members of the Legislature," the editors
					advise citizens to "read, ponder, and reflect, and then go earnestly to work to
					apply the remedy at the polls next fall."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>How Do You Like It?</head>
				<origin>Philadelphia Sunday Mercury</origin>
				<commentary>"White men of Franklin county, of whatever party, we want you to
					carefully read the following and let us know how you like it. We clip it from
					the Washington correspondence of the Philadelphia Sunday Mercury. The City of
					Washington is now under the domination of black and white niggers, in pursuance
					of a law passed by the Thirty-Ninth Congress, allowing negroes to vote. Again we
					ask, how do you like it?"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Shortly after the hour of the opening of the polls, the real, <emph
							rend="italic">bona fide</emph> white citizens-men who own all the
						property of the city, and who have resided here their lifetime-began to make
						their various ways to the election ground; and you in Philadelphia can
						imagine their astonishment in seeing all the polls in the hands of the
						negroes.-In their attempts to get to the polls at the rear of the darkies,
						those ahead would allow other darkies to slip in ahead of them, and thus
						prevent the white men from voting. Other negroes would vote and then fall
						back to the rear, and when some negro would come along who had not voted,
						they would exchange places with them, and by this game the white voters
						would wait five or six hours without obtaining a chance to vote, and would
						finally be obliged to leave the line-they not being able to give all their
						time, like the worthless contrabands, who are supported by the Freedmen's
						Bureau, and many could not stand the heat and fatigue. </p>
					<p>Many of the negroes could not tell their last names, and when asked by those
						inside the polls, these illiterate nigs would give their cognomens the same
						as they had received in the corn-field or negro dens of the city. 'Pompey,'
						'Jim,' 'Jack,' 'Sayles,' 'Browney,' or something else would be given, and
						when sent away, they would return to the polls with a name written on paper
						by some scoundrel of a white Radical, who was in attendance, and the name on
						the paper would be sure to be found on the register.</p>
					<p>As the sun arose on Monday morning, the heat became intense, but had no
						effect whatever upon the thick craniums of the negroes, while the whites
						were almost prostrated. Wenches of every hue, and some white niggers, were
						in attendance of the line of voters, and dealt out to the negroes all sorts
						of refreshments for their comfort. Some of the negroes improvised seats, and
						made themselves as comfortable as the circumstances permitted; and their
						manners indicated that they had come to stay all day if it were necessary to
						cheat the white man of his rights. In the Seventh Ward, known as the Island,
						which adjoins the Potomac river, at one of the precincts, an arrangement was
						effected between the negroes and whites, by forming two lines, so that each
						color should be voted in turn. This arrangement was going along smoothly and
						quietly, until Major Richards, the Superintendent of our Metropolitan polls,
						came on the ground and broke it up, and compelled the white line to form
						behind the negroes, and thus the whites lost their votes, as the negroes
						held the line all day, up to the very hour of closing the polls. Mr.
						Richards had no right to act in this manner, and as there were no
						disturbance of the peace, he defiantly transcended his duties; and if this
						stretch of authority had occurred in your city, the officer would have been
						most summarily dealt with; but here the Mayor had "the Fifteenth Infantry
						and the whole United States army at his back."</p>
					<p>There were at least <emph rend="italic">eight thousand</emph> negro votes
						polled-they electing their ticket by about 2,000 majority. A number of
						Departmental clerks voted with the negroes, and about two hundred of our
						white citizens. These Departmental clerks perjured themselves to vote, and
						as they are all marked, at the next State elections they will be looked
						after with great interest. If General George Washington had arisen from his
						grave, and had consented to have become a candidate, he would have met with
						the same defeat as those on our conservative ticket, as all the negroes for
						miles around were in town, and voted, as the country of negroes were very
						easily told from the city buck, with his second-hand finery. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Discusses the recent election in Washington, where blacks were allowed to
					vote for the first time.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Affairs in Tennessee</head>
				<origin>Age</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"The condition of affairs in Tennessee enables the people to see the
					legitimate effect of Radical rule."</excerpt>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article assails Gov. Bronlow's administration and reports that several
					opponents of the governor's "unlimited authority" have suffered violent attacks.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Old Thad's Charity</head>
				<origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The Home for Friendless Children of this city is an institution entirely
						worthy of the support of every charitable person in the county. It has for
						its end a noble and praiseworthy purpose. Persons of all political parties
						have contributed liberally to its support, and among those who have been
						most generous in subscribing to the erection of a new and handsome building
						for its use, we noticed the leading Democrats of Lancaster. The Republicans
						as a rule, have been equally as liberal. But there is one prominent name not
						to be found on this "roll of honor."-It is that of Thaddeus Stevens. <emph
							rend="italic">He refused to give a cent unless the Managers agreed to
							admitt negro children on a perfect equality with those born of white
							parents</emph>. There is a boldness and consistency in this act of Old
						Thad. He believes fully in negro equality, illustrates it in his household,
						insists upon it everywhere, and makes it a rule of his private and public
						life. He does not believe in forcing negro suffrage and negro equality upon
						the people of the South, and refuse to act upon the same principle at home.
						He is honest. His followers in Lancaster county and elsewhere, who refuse to
						come up to his standard, are cowards and hypocrites.-<emph rend="italic"
							>Lancaster Intelligencer</emph>.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>According to article, the Home for Friendless Children in Lancaster has
					been the recipient of generous charitable support from "every person in the
					county," irrespective of their political affiliations. Everyone, that is, except
					for Thad Stevens who has "refused to give a cent to the institution unless the
					Managers agreed to admit negro children on a perfect equality with those born of
					white parents." Though the article rebukes his decision, it argues that he is
					"honest" since he desires not only to foist black equality and suffrage upon the
					people of the South, but acts "upon the same principles at home."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>"The Mountain Labored and Brought Forth a Mouse"</head>
				<origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>In the wake of the House Judiciary Committee's determination that there is
					insufficient evidence to warrant the articles of impeachment, the article
					castigates the Radicals for their "blind fanaticism and malignant fiendishness"
					in pursuing the president.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Who Is The State Pardon Broker?</head>
				<origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Some time ago-after Beiber had been pardoned-Governor Geary was compelled
						through the demands of the people, whose sense of propriety and respect for
						the law and their courts had been so grossly outraged by his conduct in that
						case, to promulgate certain rules which he said he would follow in all
						subsequent applications for pardon. The sum and substance of these rules was
						that no more advance-pardons would be granted, and that in every case the
						testimony both for and against the criminal should be placed before him, as
						well as the judge's charge, sentence, and all other matters relative to the
						case.</p>
					<p>It seems, however, that he is totally disregarding those rules. In
						Westmoreland county a violator of the law lately came into court, and,
						before sentence, produced a pardon from Geary which had been granted either
						previous to or during the trial-though nobody knows how or when. At the late
						criminal session of York, four criminals came into court, in the same
						manner, with pardons from Geary. Such conduct is shameful and calls for the
						most emphatic censure. The pardoning of criminals in advance of sentence can
						be intended for no other purpose than to bring the State judiciary into
						disrepute. If not so intended, why does he not wait until parties have been
						fully convicted and sentenced, and then require the production of the whole
						testimony bearing upon the case, pro and con? If then found worthy of
						clemency a pardon would not only be a shield from punishment as fully as
						though granted previously on one-sided testimony, but it would, in a
						measure, stand in extenuation of the culprit's conduct. Not so a pardon
						granted secretly, in advance, and poked into the Judge's face as he is about
						to pass sentence. A pardon always stands as an admission of the guilt of the
						person pardoned, and such pardons as Geary grants not only admit the guilt
						of the culprits, but also that the testimony has not been examined for
						extenuating circumstances.</p>
					<p>These persistent attempts of the present Governor to bring contumely upon the
						courts will surely recoil upon himself if not the office he so unworhtily
						occupies. He may suppose that by shielding the lawless among his party with
						pardons for punishable offfences he may escape condemnation, but he cannot.
						The question of sustaining the courts is not marked nor bounded by party
						lines; and he will find that the more intelligent and law abiding of his own
						party condemn him, and, sooner or later, will make him suffer the
							penalty.-<emph rend="italic">Patriot &amp; Union</emph></p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article criticizes Gov. Geary's practice of granting "advance pardons"
					for political purposes, which, it asserts, is "shameful."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.06.12.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Not True</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McClure</ln>
						<fn>A. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The brief piece repudiates a rumor in "circulation" that Col. A. K. McClure
					and his family "had been murdered, on the plains by Indians."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Southern Relief</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Austin</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fletcher</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Elder</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Announces that Chambersburg churches will collect donations on June 16th
					for "the relief of the destitute people of the South." Donations will also be
					accepted at the Banking House of Messrs. Austin, Elder, and Fletcher.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Court</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McGrath</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sterling</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rodes</ln>
						<fn>Benjamin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kyler</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Mickey</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gelwick</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Zook</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shireman</ln>
						<fn>Margaret</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wagner</ln>
						<fn>Conrad</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Relates that restaurant licenses were granted to McGrath and Sterling's
					Tavern, Benjamin Rodes Restaurant, Kyler and Mickey's Restaurant, and George
					Gelwicks's Restaurant during the last session of the court. Applications for
					licenses were denied to Joseph Zook, Margaret Shireman, and Conrad Wagner.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Up The Shenandoah</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kimmell</ln>
						<fn>F. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stenger</ln>
						<fn>W. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duncan</ln>
						<fn>C. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hamasher</ln>
						<fn>B. Y.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that a party of local men left Chambersburg on June 10th for a tour
					of the Shenandoah, a trip that will include a stop in Staunton. Members of the
					party include F. M. Kimmell, W. S. Stenger, C. M. Duncan, and B. Y. Hamasher.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Hope Fire Company Election</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Barnes</ln>
						<fn>S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Snyder</ln>
						<fn>J. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McGrath</ln>
						<fn>A. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gilmore</ln>
						<fn>Frank</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Householder</ln>
						<fn>Fred</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Flack</ln>
						<fn>A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Clipper</ln>
						<fn>H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stratton</ln>
						<fn>T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Elser</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Beach</ln>
						<fn>P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Long</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rousman</ln>
						<fn>P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stratton</ln>
						<fn>S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Greenawalt</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Goetman</ln>
						<fn>P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wright</ln>
						<fn>C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nitterhouse</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Elser</ln>
						<fn>J. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Halfrick</ln>
						<fn>P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The Hope Fire Company held an election at its meeting June 4th. The
					following officers were selected: James Aughinbaugh was elected President, S.
					Barnes and G. Smith as Vice Presidents, J. F. Snyder as Secretary, A. C. McGrath
					as Treasurer, Frank Gilmore as Chief Directors, Fred Householder as Chief
					Engineer, A. Flack and H. Clipper as Asst. Engineers, T. Stratton, J. Elser, P.
					Beach, J. Long, P. Rousman, and S. Stratton as Directors, G. Greenawalt, P.
					Goetman, C. Wright, G. Nitterhouse, and J. H. Elser as members of the Executive
					Committee, and P. Halfrick as Superintendent.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Found Drowned</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McGaffigan</ln>
						<fn>Peter</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Reed</ln>
						<fn>William G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McIllwain</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Justice</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Boyle</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that Peter McGaffigan, an aged and "physically feeble" citizen of
					Chambersburg, was found dead in the Falling Spring on June 7th after he
					apparently fell into the water and drowned.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Southern Relief</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McLanahan</ln>
						<fn>J. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duncan</ln>
						<fn>C. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Contains a copy of the resolution passed by the Southern Relief Committee
					on June 6th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Etter</ln>
						<fn>Daniel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brubaker</ln>
						<fn>Peter</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brubaker</ln>
						<fn>Rebecca</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Creigh</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 30th, Daniel Etter and Rebecca, daughter of Peter Brubaker, were
					married by Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Landis</ln>
						<fn>Gideon W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hollar</ln>
						<fn>Mary Emma</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Price</ln>
						<fn>C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Elder</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 6th, Gideon W. Landis and Mary Emma Hollar were married at the
					residence of the bride's father by Elder C. Price.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Deal</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 3rd, George Deal, 74, died near Mercersburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Graham</ln>
						<fn>Thomas P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 25th, Thomas P. Graham, 27, died at his father-in-law's residence in
					Berkeley Co., West Virginia.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.06.12.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
