<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.09.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/02</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-25">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="00">25</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.09.25.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.09.25.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Negro Suffrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Said a Republican to us the other day, "If I could persuade myself that the
                        Republican party means to give the negro the right to vote, I would vote the
                        Democratic ticket this fall."</p>
                    <p>It is astonishing that any man could doubt that this is the purpose of the
                        Radical party. Wherever it has had the power, it has done so already. Since
                        1860 the majority of Congress have been Republicans. Congress has exclusive
                        jurisdiction over the District of Columbia. <emph rend="italic">It has
                            clothed the negro with the right of suffrage there.</emph></p>
                    <p>In Ohio, the Republican party has been overwhelmingly triumphant for years.
                        It has had such uninterrupted and brilliant successes, that it imagines that
                        it can carry any of its Radical measures. It has therefore submitted to the
                        people of the State the direct issue as to whether the negro shall vote in
                        that State or not, and it is upholding the affirmative side of the question.
                            I<emph rend="italic">t is seeking to clothe the negro with the right of
                            suffrage there.</emph></p>
                    <p>Senator Sumner introduced a bill into the last Congress which denies the
                        authority of the State to exclude the negro from the ballot box, and asserts
                        the power of Congress to clothe the negro with the right of suffrage,
                        anything in the State Constitution to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
                    <p>Pennsylvanians! we are not afraid of the direct issue. Our people would spurn
                        negro suffrage at the polls, by an overwhelming majority. Give them the
                        opportunity and its doom is sealed.</p>
                    <p>But the eradicate leaders in this State are again trying to deceive you. They
                        wish to make you believe that negro suffrage is not an issue in the coming
                        election. If you are against negro suffrage, how can you reconcile it to
                        your consciences to vote for a man who is in favor of it, and who will use
                        his influence to override your State laws in order to force it upon you.
                        Conservative Republicans, examine this question well.-Your speakers are now
                        addressing the people. Ask them whether or not they are for negro suffrage.
                        Don't be satisfied with their answer that this is not an issue now. Insist
                        on a categorical answer. Put the simple question, are you in favor of, and
                        would you vote for negro suffrage? and never rest satisfied until they say
                        yes or no. They will try to dodge it, and yet there is not a prominent man
                        among them who does not favor it.</p>
                    <p>Conservative Republicans of Franklin county! <emph rend="italic">Your leaders
                            here are all in favor of negro suffrage</emph>. Adjust the screws, and
                        see if you can't force it out of them.-Probe this matter thoroughly before
                        it is too late. Vote the Democratic ticket and you will be certain to
                        prevent negro suffrage. No other course issafe. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite their repeated attempts to instruct voters on the true designs of
                    the Radicals -- that is, to enfranchise blacks -- the editors lament the fact
                    that white Republicans have yet to see the light. Everywhere Republicans have
                    been voted into office, they have "clothed the negro with the right of
                    suffrage."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Negro Judge</head>
                <origin>New Orleans</origin>
                <commentary>"The telegraph brings the following interesting news from the city which
                    was not long since afflicted with Sheridan and the yellow fever:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a black judge has been appointed in New Orleans, to
                    which the editors of the Valley Spirirt declare, "Any white man in Franklin
                    county who hankers after the privilege of being brought before a colored Justice
                    of the Peace in the salubrious atmosphere of 'Wolffstown,' ought to vote the
                    Republican ticket."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Radical Praise Of The Negro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In reaction to the Republicans' persistent efforts to compliment blacks on
                    the "superior soundness" of their "judgement in relation to public affairs," the
                    editors ridicule the decision recently made by black legislators in Richmond to
                    subscribe two million dollars to the stock of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad
                    Company as imprudent. The last thing the people of Virginia need, the editors
                    argue, is to incur further unnecessary debt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The "Unhappy Failure"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reprimands Gov. Geary for his behavior during the dedication
                    ceremony for the Antietam Cemetery. Having been shunted from the list of
                    speakers at the event, Geary apparently addressed a throng of his supporters at
                    its conclusion and denounced the decision to keep him off the program as an act
                    of censorship.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Change In The Mode Of Voting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that a new system will be implemented in the upcoming
                    election. Voters will have to cast two tickets, one for the "Judiciary" and one
                    for the "County," rather than the previous method of using a singular ballot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Political Preachers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Editors of the Valley Spirit</emph>: </p>
                    <p>There was a communication in the last issue of your paper, (signed "What Say
                        You?) suggesting that "the true friends of the Christian faith should at
                        once rise from their seats and leave the church" when the pastor indulged in
                        a political harangue. I think this would be found a very ineffectual cure
                        for the evil of political preaching. One of your political parsons would
                        laugh at it. His conscience would never trouble him, and as long as he got
                        his salary he would care nothing about your empty pew. The effective cure
                        for political preaching is to <emph rend="italic">stop paying for it</emph>.
                        Whenever your pastor dabbles in politics in the pulpit, <emph rend="italic"
                            >quit paying him</emph>. Throw up your pew, or take your name off the
                        subscription list, as the case may be. If you want to hear the Radical side
                        in politics, take a Radical newspaper and pay for it, but don't let your
                        pastor cram Radicalism down your throat. If he attempts it, give him a
                        little less fodder to cram down his own. When his empty stomach begins to
                        squeal, he will do less political squealing out of his mouth. </p>
                    <p>THAT'S WHAT I SAY.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>"That's What I Say"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responding to a letter that appeared in last week's edition of the Valley
                    Spirit, urging readers to leave their Church if their pastor "dabbles in
                    politics in the pulpit," the correspondent instructs readers to stop paying
                    their preacher's salary as a more effectual deterent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.09.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Get Assessed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advises all "who intend to vote the Democratic ticket" to get assessed
                    immediately since the cut-off date to be eligible to vote is ten days before the
                    election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The proprietor of the hotel at "west point" of Chambersburg, John Gordon,
                    died suddenly on Sept. 19th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Constable</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammond</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearse</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>P. Hammond was sworn in as the Constable of Chambersburg's North Ward last
                    week. Hammond replaces William Pearse, who resigned from the post.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Death Of John Nill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Nill, former owner of Secrist's Mill, died on Sept. 19th, after
                    suffering the effects of a long illness. In addition to his work at the mill,
                    Nill served in a number of official capacities: as the Collector of Tolls on the
                    Pennsylvania Canal at Harrisburg; as the Justice of the Peace for Washington
                    township; and as Treasurer of the Waynesboro Saving Fund.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Balloon Ascension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Light</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John Light travelled over nine miles during his balloon flight
                    last Thursday before landing on John Benedict's farm near Funkstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Our Streets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that new street signs have been posted throughout the town. In the
                    process of officially labeling the streets, however, some of the former names
                    have been changed, a development the editors have criticized as unnecessary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Great Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that only a dozen people showed up at the last Republican meeting
                    in St. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. James Brotherton, "an old and widely known citizen of Franklin county,"
                    died in Waynesboro on Thursday. Brotherton was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Important To Pensioners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Warns pensioners who hold certificates as invalids that they must procure
                    the surgeon's certificate of examination before they can receive the amounts
                    owed them for the last six months. The examining surgeon for this county is Dr.
                    J. L. Suesserott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Another Great Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the most recent Republican meeting in Orrstown attracted only
                    six attendees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Returned From Europe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the return of Nicholas Uglow, 80, from his sojourn in England.
                    While visiting his native land, Uglow was fortunate enough to find two of his
                    brothers -- one older and one younger -- still alive.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Attempt At Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Over</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An unknown assailant entered Mr. Over's residence with the intent of
                    burgalizing the dwelling while the owner was away on business. The intruders
                    were forced to abandon their mission, however, after one of Over's neighbors,
                    upon hearing a commotion, "made a timely appearance" and scared the would-be
                    perpetrators off.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harkins</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shilito</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 8th, William J. Harkins and Isabella Shilito were married by Rev.
                    J. C. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rager</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Godbart</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickinson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 12th, James H. Rager and Maria Godbart, of Hagerstown, Md., were
                    married by Rev. J. Dickson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cover</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 18th, John Logan and Ann Cover were married by Rev. J. M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 3rd, James Harmon, 61, died near Spring Run.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrhart</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrhart</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrhart</ln>
                        <fn>Adam Rush</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 13th, Adam Rush, son of William and Mary E. Ehrhart, died at age
                    2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.09.25.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
