<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.11.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/14/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-11-20">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="11"/>
            <day norm="00">20</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.20.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.20.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Negroes In The Cars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals seem to be exceedingly unfortunate in their selection of men for
                        official positions. Andrew Johnson is not the only man who has turned his
                        back upon the party which elevated him to power. When Judge Agnew was
                        elected to the Supreme Court, he was regarded as the strongest type of
                        Radical. Whilst his ability and integrity were conceded by all parties,
                        there was a general impression prevailing that, upon questions involving the
                        tenets of his party creed, he would be extremely ultra. No suspicion was
                        entertained by anybody that he would fail to take his position along with
                        the advance guard of "the party of great moral ideas." Everybody was
                        therefore astonished to learn that he has chimed in with the overwhelming
                        popular sentiment, and uttered his condemnation of the odious doctrine of
                        the social equality of the races.</p>
                    <p>In a case which came up to the Supreme court recently, from the Court of
                        Common Pleas of Philadelphia county, Judge Agnew delivered an opinion which
                        is a model for conscience and perspicuity, to say nothing of its sound
                        doctrine. The plaintiff was a colored woman, named Mary E. Miles, who
                        brought a suit against the Philadelphia and West Chester Railroad Company,
                        to recover damages for being ejected from a car in which white persons were
                        seated, and forced to take a seat in another car, to which she was directed
                        by the conductor of the train. Judgment was rendered in her favor in the
                        court below, whereupon a writ of error was sued out to the Supreme Court.
                        The question involved was, as stated by Judge Agnew, "whether a public
                        carrier may, in the exercise of his private right of property, and in the
                        due performances of his public duty, separate passengers by any other
                        well-defined characteristic than that of sex."--The court take the
                        affirmative side of the question, and base their opinion upon two grounds,
                        namely, the right of private property which the carrier has in the means of
                        conveyance, and the public interest. We quote from the opinion of Judge
                        Agnew on the second ground.</p>
                    <p>The public has an interest in the proper regulation of public conveyances for
                        the preservation of the public peace. A railroad company has the right and
                        is bound to make reasonable regulations to preserve order in their cars. It
                        is the duty of the conductor to repress tumults as far as he reasonably can,
                        and he may on extraordinary occasions stop his train and eject the unruly
                        and tumultuous. But he has not the authority of a peace officer to arrest
                        and detain offenders. He cannot interfere in the quarrels of others at will
                        merely. In order to preserve and enforce his authority as the servant of the
                        company it must have a power to establish proper regulations for the
                        carriage of passengers. It is much easier to prevent difficulties among
                        passengers by regulations for their proper separation than it is to quell
                        them. <emph rend="italic">The danger to the peace engendered by this feeling
                            of aversion between individuals of the different races cannot be denied.
                            It is the fact with which the company must deal. If a negro takes his
                            seat beside a white man, or his wife, or daughter, the law cannot
                            repress the anger or conquer the aversion which some will feel. However
                            unwise it may be to indulge the feeling, human infirmity is not always
                            proof against it. It is much wiser to avert the consequences of this
                            repulsion races by separation, than to punish afterwards the breach of
                            the peace it may have caused.</emph></p>
                    <p>The Supreme Court thus recognize the fact of an unconquerable aversion, on
                        the part of the whites, to the idea and practice of being placed in social
                        contact with the negro. They doubtless speak from experience as well as
                        observation. And if they had needed any additional evidence to convince them
                        the result of the late elections would furnish them with the judgement of
                        the white masses upon this question. But the opinion goes further. It
                        announces the fact, that a Higher Power than any human agency has fixed a
                        great gulf between the two races, across which it was never intended that
                        either should pass. It says:</p>
                    <p>Why the Creator made on black and the other white we know not; but the fact
                        is apparent, and the races distinct, each producing its own kind, and
                        following the peculiar law of its constitution. Conceding equality, with
                        nature as perfect and rights as [UNCLEAR] , yet God has made them
                        dissimilar, with those natural instincts and feelings which He always
                        imparts to His creatures when He intends that they shall not overstep the
                        natural boundaries He has assigned to them. The natural law which forbids
                        their intermarriage and that social amalgamation, which leads to corruption
                        of race, is as clearly divine as that which imparted to them different
                        natures. The tendency of intimate social intermixture is to amalgamation,
                        contrary to the law of races. The separation of the white and black races
                        upon the surface of the globe is a fact equally apparent. Why this is so, it
                        is not necessary to speculate, but the fact of a distribution of men by race
                        and color, is as visible in the providential arrangement of the earth as
                        that of heat and cold. The natural separation of the races is therefore an
                        undeniable fact, and social organizations which lead to their amalgamation
                        are repugnant to the law of nature. <emph rend="italic">From social
                            amalgamation, it is but a step to illicit intercourse, and but another
                            to intermarriage</emph>. </p>
                    <p>And, after showing conclusively, in addition, that the laws and customs of
                        the State have been uniformly against intermixture of the races, this
                        admirable opinion closes as follows:</p>
                    <p>Following these guides, we are compelled to declare that at the time of the
                        alleged injury, there was that natural, legal, and customary difference
                        between the black and white races in this State, which made their separation
                        as passengers in a public conveyance the subject of a sound regulation, to
                        secure order, promote comfort, preserve the peace, and maintain the rights
                        of both carriers and passengers.</p>
                    <p>What a terrible damper upon the progressive notions of the Radical party! How
                        it undermines and explodes the Radical legislation of the last session of
                        our General Assembly, which imposes a heavy penalty upon the conductors or
                        other employees of railroad companies, who refuse the negro the right to sit
                        in whatever car and upon whatever seat he pleases! Judge Agnew deserves the
                        thanks of every white man in the Commonwealth, not so much by entertaining
                        these views as for having the independence to give expression to them. But
                        we submit to our Radical friends that he is sadly in need of
                        "reconstruction," and that it might be well to have the perambulating
                        committee on "a republican form of government," to take him and his opinion
                        into special consideration.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports on a case in which a black woman was ejected from a
                    railroad car carrying white people and was forced to sit in another section of
                    the train. The women sued the company and won. On appeal, however,
                    Pennsylvania's Supreme Court ruled in the Railroad's favor, asserting that,
                    since there "is an aversion between individuals of the different races," it had
                    the right "to make reasonable regulations to preserve order in their cars."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Loyalty And Disloyalty Change Places</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Loyalty has taken its flight from the Northern soil, and made its home in
                    the South."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Time makes queer changes. It sometimes causes States as well as men to turn
                        complete somersaults. In 1861, eleven Southern States seceded. Treason was
                        rampant within their limits. Patriotism was entirely dead in the hearts of
                        their inhabitants. Armed rebellion planned and labored there to break up the
                        National Government. Loyalty was a stranger to Southern soil. Then, the
                        North was ablaze with the fires of patriotism. "The high-ways and the
                        by-ways" were crowded with armed men rushing forward to save the Republic
                        from destruction. Loyalty, pure, disinterested loyalty was displaced
                        everywhere throughout the Northern States. Loyal men occupied the high
                        places of public trust. Northern Legislatures were composed of men who were
                        anxious to have everybody else fight, bleed and die for their country.
                        Whenever copperheadism dared to raise its head, it was pelted most
                        unmercifully. The wretch who dared to be a Democrat in those days, was
                        hooted at, proscribed and threatened with the direst evils. Loyal men waited
                        upon him with intimations that he must change his evil way, or take the
                        consequences. The South was totally disloyal--the North was pre-eminently
                        loyal.</p>
                    <p>What a wonderful transformation has taken place! The tables have been turned.
                        Loyalty has taken its flight from Northern soil, and made its home in the
                        South. Disloyalty, driven from the South, has taken possession of the
                        Northern States and threatens to hold permanent sway. Yes! strange to say,
                        the South, lately so terribly rebellious, elects loyal men to its high
                        positions, whilst the North, lately the home of the highest type of loyalty,
                        honors those who trample loyalty beneath their feet. The South has become
                        Union--the North has become rebel. Was ever such a metamorphosis seen
                        before? The superlatively loyal men of the North ought certainly to
                        emigrate. Inasmuch as they have lost their hold on power here, they might go
                        to the South and assist the blacks in administering the State governments in
                        that section. Have our Radical friends never heard of the dog, which, in
                        crossing a stream with a piece of beef in his mouth, saw his shadow and
                        jumping in to catch it, lost the meat?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There has been radical transformation in the country since the end of the
                    war, assert the editors. No longer is the South the bastion of treasonous
                    senitment; rather, the region is home to the country's most patriotic citizens.
                    In contrast, the editors contend, the reverse is true in the North, where "those
                    who trample loyalty beneath their feet" are now honored.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Denouncing Their Leaders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the editors, white rank-and-file Republicans are, in fact,
                    satisfied with the results from the election because they hope it will send a
                    message to the party's leaders that they should abandon their efforts to
                    enfranchise blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Fort Delaware Fraud</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>As mandated by an 1864 legislative act, Gov. Geary apppointed a commission
                    to record the votes of soldiers stationed at Fort Delaware. The editors
                    challenge the commission's results and assert that the soldiers in question were
                    ineligible to vote anyway.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.20.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Religion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Menges</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. H. Menges, of York, Pa., will preach in the Lutheran Church next
                    Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Newspapers Change</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reymer</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. R. Gaff sold the Valley Echo, published in Greencastle, to Col. B. F.
                    Winger. Editorial control of the newspaper will be under M. D. Reymer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Burglarious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last Wednesday, a burglar broke into Peter Brough's mansion on West Market
                    St. and stole a wardrobe, which contained two suits, from the room occupied by
                    John Brough.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Branch Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the Cumberland Valley Railroad Co. is considering
                    constructing a branch from Hagerstown to Williamsport. The proposed line would
                    put the residents of Franklin county "in communication with Cumberland" and
                    would give them greater access to the "famous 'Cumberland coal.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Teachers' Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the meeting of the Teachers' Institute was a success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Properties Purchased</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karper</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Jason B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Orr purchased the Smith Farm owned by John Karper. Orr paid $100 per
                    acre for the 106 plot. Jacob Mohler, Sr., purchased Col. Jason B. Orr's farm for
                    $125 an acres.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Look Out</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article cautions readers to be on the lookout for a "thieving set of
                    stragglers" who have preyed upon unsuspecting local residents, going
                    door-to-door asking for charity. Reportedly, these "scoundrels" have committted
                    several robberies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bixler</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brackenridge</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 14th, Dr. J. P. Bixler and Emma Brackenridge were married by Rev.
                    Moore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cretin</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullin</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 18th, Henry Cretin and Mary Harbaugh were married by Rev. John A.
                    Mullin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyter</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hudley</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beckley</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 21st, Jacob Eyter and Mary S. Hudley were married by Rev. G. H.
                    Beckley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stokes</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammon</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, Charles Shaffer, of Adams Co., and Sarah A. Stokes were
                    married at the residence of P. Hammon by Rev. H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rots</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutter</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, James H. Conner and Fannie Rots were married at the residence
                    of J. Sutter by Rev. H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spielman</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Charles G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 12th, Jacob Keller and Sophia Spielman were married by Rev. Charles
                    G. Fisher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>George F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deardorff</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 7th, George F. Summers and Mary A. Deardorff were married by Rev.
                    Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammaker</ln>
                        <fn>Adam C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanley</ln>
                        <fn>Alice M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 13th, Adam C. Hammaker and Alice M. Stanley, of Maryland, were
                    married by Rev. S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.11.20.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
