<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.10.23">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>06/08</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-10-23">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="10"/>
			<day norm="00">23</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.10.23.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.10.23.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Suspension Of The President</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Outraged at Thad Stevens's current attempt to unseat the President and thus
					"subvert the Constitution," the editors admonish readers to prevent him from
					consummating his "villainous scheme."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>A Contemplated Outrage</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Several of the Democratic candidates for the Senate and House of
						Representatives of our State have been elected by comparatively small
						majorities. The wonder is, considering how infamously the State was
						gerrymanded by the Republicans, that they have been elected at all. But it
						is proposed now to cheat them out of the positions to which they have been
						honestly elected by the people of their respective districts. The Harrisburg
							<emph rend="italic">Telegraph </emph>, published by as unprincipled a
						wretch as lives, calls upon the Radical majority of the Legislature to oust
						these men and put the defeated candidates in their places. They have been in
						the habit of doing this for the last seven years. Acting upon the theory and
						that "might makes right," they have not hesitated to dispossess Democrats of
						their official places without any pretence that there was any law to justify
						their action. In our own Senatorial District, Mr. Duncan was elected in 1865
						as fairly as any man was ever chosen by the people. Everybody knew that
						there was no illegality in or about that election sufficient to warrant the
						Senate in setting it aside, and yet he was only allowed to occupy his seat
						for a week or ten days. Republicans here positively blushed with shame at
						this outrage upon Mr. Dunce's individual rights, and at such a wanton,
						deliberate disregard of the clear and unmistakable choice of the people. It
						was conceded all round that the investigation by the Senatorial committee
						was a mere sham, there being a fixed determination to give the seat to
						McConaughy regardless of law, justice, equity and the particular merits of
						the case. Last year this Senatorial District condemned McConaughy by a
						majority of 23. This year, it speaks trumpet-tongued against the party to
						which he belongs by a majority of 581. </p>
					<p>We might cite other instances, both in the State and National Legislatures,
						whose injustice is equally glaring and notorious, but this will suffice.
						What we have to say now is, that it is time for the Conservative press to
						speak out against this system of gross wrong and stupendous fraud. It is
						time for the people to say that they will not tolerate any longer this
						carrying out of a premeditated and pre-arranged plan to defeat the popular
						will. If constitutional forms are to be set at naught, or if followed, only
						used for the accomplishment of such nefarious purposes, the sooner the
						people take the remedy into their own hands the better. When we are beaten
						we are in favor of submission, and when we are victorious we insist on
						reaping the fruits of our victory. When we elect men to offices fairly, we
						submit that it is our bounden duty to see to it that these men are allowed
						to perform the duties of their offices, and that by no trick or chicanery
						shall the men whom the people have condemned through the ballot-box, be
						substituted for those whom they have chosen. Let the <emph rend="italic"
							>Telegraph </emph> and all kindred sheets--let its publisher and editor
						and all kindred spirits--understand that in times like this, when a great
						revolution is sweeping over the land, it is exceedingly perilous to attempt
						to thwart the distinctly uttered wishes of the masses. Forbearance may cease
						to be a virtue. As a minority, we always asserted our rights--<emph
							rend="italic">as a majority, we are determined to maintain them</emph>.
						The men who have been legally chosen to the Senate and House of
						Representatives must be allowed to take and remain in their seats. No
						trumped-up charges of illegal voting--No deserter-disfranchising laws passed
						in direct violation of our Constitution, and no strained construction of our
						election statutes, will be held sufficient to justify a general ouster of
						the conservatives who have received certificates of election. Honesty must
						supplant dishonesty in our legislative halls. This system of corruption,
						bribery and wholesale sacrifice of honor for partisan purposes must be
						broken up. </p>
					<p>All we ask is that the same rules that the Radicals apply to the members of
						their own party shall be applied to Democrats, and that no Democrat shall be
						thrown out of his place for any reason which would not be deemed sufficient
						to dispossess a Radical of his seat also. We do not wish to indulge in
						threats, we do not seek to intimidate anybody, but we simply desire to
						inform this Hessian that the Democracy intend to see to it that if the men
						whom they have elected shall fill the positions to which they have been
						chosen, and that they will not be particular about putting gloves on their
						hands to deal with scoundrels who are casting about for ways and means to
						frustrate the legally and honestly expressed choice of the people.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>There is a move underway in Harrisburg to disallow the results of several
					contests in which Democratic candidates obtained small margins of victory over
					their Republican rivals, say the editors. In reaction, the editors call on "the
					Conservative press to speak out this system of gross wrong and studendous
					fraud."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>A Few Words To Republicans</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>At the Republican County Convention, the editors remind readers, a
					resolution was passed proclaiming that "no party has a right to exist which is
					not in harmony with the will of the people and is not sustained by their
					approbation." In the wake of the election, the editors now wonder whether the
					Republican leaders intend on complying with this "monstrous" declaration, though
					they do not expect them to. The editors also urge Republican supporters to
					re-evaluate their commitment to a party whose leaders would endorse such a
					"ridiculous" doctrine.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Cabinet Changes</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Rumors again abound that important changes in President Johnson's Cabinet
						will soon take place. It is said that prominent Democratic politicians have
						called upon the President since the election and urged him to organize a
						Cabinet that would more correctly represent the expressed opinions of the
						people than the one he has around him now. We do not pretend to say how much
						of truth and how much of falsehood there may be in these rumors. But we
						desire to express the hope that all the prominent Democratic politicians in
						the country will let President Johnson alone. He does not belong to us, and
						no distinguished Democrat who does not desire to forfeit his standing in the
						Democratic party can safely enter his Cabinet.</p>
					<p>Nor would it do the President himself any good to break up his Cabinet and
						reconstruct it on a Democratic foundation. Such a change, at this late day,
						might do more harm than good. It might, perhaps, weaken him still more. It
						could not possibly strengthen him. It is not because anything he has done
						for them as a party, that the Democracy sustain the President. It is not
						because they believe it to be in his power to do anything for them as a
						party that they have resolved to stand by him to the bitter end of his fight
						with the revolutionary cabal in Congress. They will stand by him just as
						resolutely in that fight if he retains his present Republican Cabinet, or
						puts other Republicans in their places, as if he filled it with Democrats.
						Their support is given to him on principle, and not from a desire to
						participate in his administration of the government. When they win the
						government out of the hands of their opponents, then they will want it
						administered by their own statesmen. They will sustain the President with
						all their might so long as he defends the Constitution and shows no signs of
						flinching, even though all who surround him in office be Republicans; but no
						array of Democratic names in his Cabinet could bind them to him for a single
						day if he faltered in the performance of his sacred duty. If he contemplates
						a change in his Cabinet, let him make it solely with reference to the
						approaching contest between himself and the Radical destructive. If his
						present Cabinet are warmly with him, we can see no need of his changing
						them. Least of all is there need of change in order to conciliate the
						Democracy. When the President finds himself engaged in a death-struggle with
						the leading spirits of the party which elected him--and he will probably
						have such a struggle on his hands on after the meeting of Congress--let him
						raise the Constitution above his head and cry aloud to the Democracy to come
						forth and save it, and as one man they will rally at his call. But they want
						no Cabinet officers till they can claim them under a Democratic
					President</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>President Johnson is planning to make further changes to his cabinet;
					"prominent" Democrats have urged him to consider members of their party as
					possible replacements. The editors counsel against such a move because, in
					addition to undermining the credibility of any Democrat who joined Johnson's
					cabinet, it would do the President "more harm than good."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="l">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Letter From Dixie</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>DARK CORNER, MADISON CO. MISS.,</p>
					<p>October 9, 1867</p>
					<p>To the Valley Spirit, <emph rend="italic">"Greeting"</emph>: </p>
					<p>I know your John M., knew him when he was a boy, away back in the times of
						the <emph rend="italic">Franklin Telegraph</emph>, and am truly glad to see
						that he has not bartered his hopes of heaven by joining the accursed party
						who are holding the poisoned chalice to the lips of all free white men,
						south of the Mason and Dixon, with one hand and a dagger in the other, as an
						inducement for us to drink of the cup. My recollection of the people of the
						county of my childhood and early manhood are such that I can scarcely
						believe that a majority of them can be acting with a party that is taxing
						its ingenuity to devise means to oppress and humble their fellow-men, after
						they have been stripped of everything, because forsooth they may have
						sinned. I am not one of those who believed in the right or policy of
						secession, but when the country of my adoption decided otherwise, I
						shouldered my musket and fought to the bitter end. However, I am no
						reconstructed--"all but one plank"--"I can't vote," but there is a colored
						gentleman helping me to raise corn for <emph rend="italic">bread </emph> who
						votes for us both, only he don't know how to vote until his brother Rad
						comes along from Connecticut or Massachusetts to tell him how. </p>
					<p>Mississippi will make bread enough and to spare, but the cotton crop will
						fall short fully one-half, caused by the depredation of the boil-worm just
						before the time of picking, and what is left will be eaten up by the <emph
							rend="italic">tax </emph> worm, before it reaches market, and as this is
						the only crop from which we can realize any money, you may form some faint
						idea of our future prospects. No man can imagine the desolation of the land,
						save one who was here before and since the little <emph rend="italic">riot
						</emph> we had down here a few years ago.--Previous to that time, it was
						literally a land flowing with milk and honey; and now, in places that
						formerly bloomed and blossomed as the rose, are fenceless farms and weeds by
						the briars, and the tenantless houses, save by the owl and the bat, and the
						mocea son and adder, and last year the cry wend up to God from many a
						hearthstone for bread. In the name of humanity is this not enough? What more
						do the extremists of the North want? They are pursuing a policy towards his
						down-trodden land that can only result in one thing--a war of races. Should
						it ever come, wo! wo! to the poor negro. But there is a single ray of hope
						lighting up the deep darkness of our future, and that is, that the present
						dominant party may be swept from power before they fully consummate their
						purposes. I will look anxiously for the result of the election in the
						Keystone State yesterday, and earnestly hope the people have set their seal
						of condemnation on the foul party. </p>
					<p>In times past I never had much love for the Democratic party--Henry Clay was
						the Apostle of my political creed--and I can't say that I love it any too
						much yet, but I am satisfied that it is the only human agency that can save
						this country.</p>
					<p>I receive the SPIRIT regularly, and its appearance is to me "like a shadow of
						a rock in a weary land." But how you ever get pay for it, is more than I can
						cypher at this present writing unless you take gubers in payment at a dime
						per quart.</p>
					<p>I notice that M'Clure has sent on some "bricks" made out of some new kind of
						dirt, picked up in Montana. I think I heard many years ago, something about
						the material from which they are made, and may have, in early boyhood, seen
						some specimens. If they are at all plenty, and are the kind your people
							<emph rend="italic">carry </emph> in their <emph rend="italic">hats
						</emph>, please send me one for mine. But, by the way, the crown is out of
						mine; couldn't you go to Deehert's cheap hat store and buy me a new one, sew
						it neatly in the crown and ship by express, prepaying the charges, otherwise
						I will not get it, as gubers are not a legal tender with our express agents.
						Don't let Butler know when you send it. </p>
					<p>What has become of everybody that lived in the old town eighteen years ago?
						We need enterprising citizens down here, with "money." Perhaps some of your
						population might be induced to immigrate. If "Jim Collins" is live and will
						come to Mississippi, I will guarantee him a seat in Congress at the first
						election. It does not require a residence of any stated time for gentlemen
						of his color, but he can vote immediately on landing.</p>
					<p>Two down East white men held a county meeting in the town of Canton a few
						weeks ago, to appoint delegates to a State Convention, to be held at
						Jackson, Miss. Present at the aforesaid meeting, the aforesaid down Easters
						and sixteen niggers. One of the white men and two of the niggers appointed
						themselves delegates to the State Convention. One of the darkies told his
						old master that as soon as he got to <emph rend="italic">Kongrass </emph> he
						would give him a "pintment," as he had been a good master to him, giving him
						plenty to eat, plenty <emph rend="italic">klose </emph> and not much work,
						and now when had the power, he would <emph rend="italic">member him</emph>.
						There seems to be a strong disposition on the part of many of our citizens
						to push forward the freedman into positions where he would make himself
						ridiculous. Now I think this is very wrong; and, as the white voting
						population is greatly in the minority, I think they had better let the
						Yankee emissaries and the negro fix up things to suit themselves. </p>
					<p>We have had, thus far, a pleasant fall, and delightful weather to gather our
						crops. A late frost in the Spring destroyed all the fruit, but the corn and
						sweet potato crops are good, and I do think there will be much suffering for
						the want of necessaries of life. When speaking about the freedman, I
						neglected to bear my testimony to their good behavior generally, considering
						that they were suddenly cast loose to think and act for themselves without
						any previous training and if bad men did not come among them from the North
						and put false notions in their heads, they might, in time, perhaps, do
						something for themselves and employers as laborers.</p>
					<p>If I can raise money enough for stamps, you may hear occasionally from</p>
					<p>SHEP.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>Shep.</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>Contains a letter from a former resident of Franklin county, who now
					resides in Mississippi. Among the topics touched upon in the correspondence are
					the effects of white disfranshisement and the general state of disrepair among
					Mississippi's plantations.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.10.23.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Religious</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>S. H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Rev. S. H. C. Smith will give a sermon to young men next Sunday at the M.
					E. Church.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Property Sold</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Richards</ln>
						<fn>J. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Eyster</ln>
						<fn>James C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Notes that Dr. J. C. Richards purchased James C. Eyster's property near the
					turnpike leading to Shippensburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Antietam National Cemetary</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Due to a lack of funds, relates the article, the "thirty-odd hands"
					employed at Antietam Cemetary have been discharged and work there has stopped.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Fatal Accident</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Frick</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Price</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Geiser</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that George Frick's daughter died in a tragic accident that
					occurred while she was playing near the connecting shaft between her father's
					foundry and the machine shops belonging to Messrs. Geiser, Price, and Co.
					Apparently, the girl's clothing became entangled in the shaft and, before she
					could be rescued, she was mangled, causing an instantaneous death.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="l">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>County Institute</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer>P. M. Shoemaker</trailer>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shoemaker</ln>
						<fn>P. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stenger</ln>
						<fn>W. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Informs readers of the upcoming meeting of the Franklin County Teachers'
					Institute on November 11th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Wingert</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Dieter</ln>
						<fn>Maria</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Schneck</ln>
						<fn>B. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 15th, Henry Wingert and Maria Dieter were married by Rev. B. S.
					Schneck.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Meisner</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Boner</ln>
						<fn>Lizzie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Eyster</ln>
						<fn>W. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 17th, Samuel Meisner and Lizzei Boner were married by Rev. W. F.
					Eyster.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Carmac</ln>
						<fn>Calvin P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bender</ln>
						<fn>Mary</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Winbigler</ln>
						<fn>W. P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 10th, Calvin P. Carmac, of Fulton Co., Pa., and Mary Bender were
					married by Rev. W. P. Winbigler.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Brown</ln>
						<fn>George W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McDonnel</ln>
						<fn>Mary E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Beck</ln>
						<fn>B. T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 2nd, George W. Brown and Mary E. McDonnel were married by Rev. B.
					T. Beck.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Weigel</ln>
						<fn>Jonas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fulton</ln>
						<fn>Emma</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Price</ln>
						<fn>C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 10th, Jonas Weigel and Emma Fulton were married by Rev. C. Price.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stoke</ln>
						<fn>Leonard</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Maththews</ln>
						<fn>Anna A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Moore</ln>
						<fn>J. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 8th, Leonard Stoke, of Jacksonville, and Anna A. Maththews were
					married by Rev. J. G. Moore.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hamsher</ln>
						<fn>Mamie Josephene</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hamsher</ln>
						<fn>B. Y.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hamsher</ln>
						<fn>Mary A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 18th, Mamie Josephene, daughter of B. Y. and Mary A. Hamsher, died
					at age 2.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Cook</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 18th, Jacob Cook, 80, died at New Guilford.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shearer</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 5th, Jacob Shearer, 67, died near Spring Run.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Brown</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 11th, Joseph Brown, 77, died near Spring Run.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Upperman</ln>
						<fn>Mary Ann</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Holland</ln>
						<fn>Margaret</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Oct. 7th, Mary Ann Upperman, 77, died at the residence of her daughter,
					Margaret Holland, in Fayetteville.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.10.23.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
