<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.05.08">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>03/21/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-05-08">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="05">May</month>
			<day norm="00">08</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.05.08.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.05.08.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Despotism Advances</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>It seems the Radical revolutionists are not content with overturning the
						civil governments of the ten underrepresented States of the American union,
						and subjecting their people to the rigors of martial law.-Having
						accomplished that, in flagrant violation of the Constitution, they are now
						turning their attention to the other States, and threatening them with the
						same absolute despotism, unless they vote the Radical ticket. Maryland,
						Tennessee and Kentucky are the first to be menaced by the "iron heel"" of
						Congressional usurpation. Our readers are aware that shortly before the
						adjournment resolutions were introduced into the "Rump" and passed by that
						delectable body, instructing the Judiciary Committee to inquire into the
						expediency of putting Maryland under the provisions of the "Military
						Reconstruction" bill, and one of her Senators, elected by a Legislature
						chosen by a large majority of her citizens, and with the broad seal of the
						Commonwealth upon his credentials, was denied admission to his seat, and is
						still so denied, <emph rend="italic">because </emph> his political
						sentiments differed from those of the Radical majority. And at this very
						moment, under the auspices of this Radical "Rump Congress," its adherents
						and partisans in the State of Maryland are conspiring to set up a
						revolutionary government, in opposition to the regular and legal government
						of the State; which bogus government is to be recognized by the Radical
						majority in Congress as the lawful government of the State, provided its
						concoctors, aiders and abettors deem it <emph rend="italic">safe </emph> to
						consummate the outrage. </p>
					<p>In Tennessee, the notorious Parson Brownlow is a candidate for re-election to
						the Gubernatorial chair of that State. In a fair and free election the old
						reprobate would not have the ghost of a chance, the Radical party being in a
						hopeless minority in Tennessee; hence Congress comes to his aid by
						furnishing him with ten thousand of arms, to arm his militia, composed of
						negroes and the worst class of whites.-Thus armed, he has sent his militia
						into all parts of the State, to inaugurate a reign of terror, and, if need
						be, drive the conservative voters from the polls when the day of election
						arrives. For fear, however, that all this machinery of despotism, which has
						been placed in the hands of the Radical party to carry the election in
						Tennessee, might, after all, not prove successful, they declare in advance
						that if the verdict of the people should be against Brownlow and his
						faction, it will not be accepted. The <emph rend="italic">Press &amp;
							Times</emph>, a torch-and-turpentine organ, published at Nashville,
						threatens that if Mr. Etheridge, the Conservative candidate for Governor,
						should be elected, he shall not be permitted to exercise the functions of
						his office. Congress is to be called upon to keep Brownlow in authority by
						military power. Says the <emph rend="italic">Press &amp; Times:</emph>
						"He who supposes that Etheridge, even if elected would be suffered by
						Congress to rule Tennessee knows little of its iron will and determination."
						And this is called "universal liberty!" Oh, shame, on the miscreants and
						tyrants who are stabbing to its vitals the grand system of Constitutional
						Government, framed by the wisdom of our revolutionary ancestors. The mailed
						hand of despotism has been laid upon the freedom of the ballot in Tennessee,
						and, through the usurpation of a fragmentary Congress, orders have been
						issued <emph rend="italic">to crush it to death!</emph></p>
					<p>Kentucky is threatened with the same interferences. A special dispatch from
						Louisville to the Cincinnati <emph rend="italic">Gazette </emph>, says: "The
						withdrawal of Harding, Union Conservative candidate for Governor, renders
						the election of Helm pretty certain, as the Radicals here have little hopes
						for their candidate.-But the question is mooted whether Helm <emph
							rend="italic">will be allowed to take his seat</emph>." This is
						following closely in the track of the Tennessee Radicals, and shows that the
						movement is a predetermined one-a plot to enslave the people of the States
						named. Even the proud old Commonwealth of Pennsylvania has been threatened.
						Thad. Stevens in his place in Congress lately denied that Pennsylvania ever
						had a Republican form of government, and he expressed the hope that
						"Congress would take her hand and give her a Republican government." And
						unless the people speedily awake to the dangers before them, Congress will
						make the attempt to "re-construct: the government of every State in the
						Union by the exercise of despotic and usurped powers. </p>
					<p>On this subject the <emph rend="italic">Age </emph> pertinently remarks: "The
						action of the Radical party in the instances named, shows the point to which
						they are prepared to go in their mad desire to hold possession f power in
						the States and in the nation. While forcing the ballot in the hands of the
						negro, they would at the same time not only deprive white men of the
						elective franchise, but disregard State elections, if against their
						candidates and policy. If Mr. Helm is elected Governor of Kentucky, or Mr.
						Etheridge of Tennessee, the party now clamoring for "impartial suffrage" is
						prepared to trample all forms of suffrage into the dust, and to rule the
						people by military power under the assumed authority of a sectional
						Congress. This is Radical regard for the elective franchise." </p>
					<p>How long, oh! how long, will the people patiently submit to these things?</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>In the wake of Congress' decision to place the former Confederate states
					under military rule, the editors claim that the Radicals have now focused their
					attention on the border states -- Maryland, Tennessee, and Kentucky -- and "are
					threatening them with the same absolute despotism, unless they vote the Radical
					ticket."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Great Democratic Victory in Lancaster</head>
				<origin>Intelligencer</origin>
				<commentary>"The municipal election in Lancaster city, the home of Thad. Stevens, on
					last Friday, resulted in a glorious triumph for the Democracy. Mayor Sanderson
					was re-elected by 511 majority. His majority last year was 181; a gain of 330 in
					one year. The Democrats also elected 26 out of 36 members of the council. The
					Intelligencer thus speaks of the result:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Most heartily do we congratulate the conservative citizens of Lancaster city
						upon the decided and complete triumph which they have achieved. The radicals
						made a desperate effort to carry the home of Thaddeus Stevens. They felt
						perfectly certain that they would be enabled to do so under the provisions
						of the new Ward Bill, which they had forced through the Legislature.-They
						even went so far as to put up as a candidate for Mayor, a man who is
						regarded as the special friend of Mr. Stevens. They had not the slightest
						doubt that they would be able to secure control of both branches of the City
						Councils. For that they had provided with especial care. We do not know how
						they will undertake to account for the terrible defeat they received. It was
						most complete and crushing. Very many Conservative Republicans are joining
						hands with the Democracy. They can no longer follow the lead of such men as
						Thaddeus Stevens, and are deserting the organization to which they have been
						attached for years. In that single fact the Radical leaders of this city can
						find one great reason for the rebuke they have received at the hands of the
						people. A revolution is going on which will sweep from their places the
						corrupt men who are now in power. All the signs of the times show a great
						change in public sentiment. A brighter day is dawning.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article celebrates the Democrats' victory in Lancaster city's municipal
					elections.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>"Radical Veracity"</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>According to the editors, at the end of the last session of Congress,
					Radicals asserted that the "Pope had closed the Protestant Chapel at the
					American Embassy in Rome." The Radicals fabricated this "falsehood," the editors
					contend, in an attempt to discredit a "conservative Republican" and justify his
					removal from office. Such misinformation, they argue, is symptomatic of the
					"mountain of lies" that the Radicals have foisted upon the "Northern mind."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>A Good Joke</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editors lampoon members of the legislature who agreed to vote for Simon
					Cameron for Senate in exchange for a bribe. Unfortunately for them, the editors
					maintain, once in power, Simon substantially reduced the amount he had earlier
					promised the corrupt legislators for their vote.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Riding with Negroes</head>
				<origin>Philadelphia News</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The editor of the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">News </emph> has been
						written to by a lady who complains that she was obliged, some days ago, to
						occupy a seat in a street railroad car between two negroes. They were of the
						masculine gender, and by "no means tidy," and she requests the <emph
							rend="italic">News </emph> to be assured that she has not, not even when
						writing, got rid of the peculiar odor that attaches to a perspiring darkey.
						She says that she is frequently obliged to go some distance from her home to
						visit an invalid relative, and that she is not able to walk so far, and asks
						what she is to do. This question the <emph rend="italic">News </emph>
						rightly considers a little difficult to answer. It says: "The law makes a
						specialty of the negro, and, if we use the cars at all, we must necessarily
						submit to the disagreeable annoyance. Our correspondent will probably excuse
						us for saying that she belongs to a Radical family, and that her husband
						cast his vote at the last election for the men who have imposed this
						degradation upon her and her daughters. It will be remembered that, during
						the last canvass, we frequently warned our readers of what they must expect
						if they elected Radical members of Congress and of the Legislature. They did
						so, and the result is before us. The negroes ride in the cars by legislative
						enactment, and, in so far as the action of our Legislature goes, by its
						agreement to the proposed fourteenth article to the Constitution, they are
						entitled to vote if it is adopted. The next movement is to admit them into
						the public schools, when our children will be compelled to sit by them and
						inhale their hot and fetid breath or leave the schools." </p>
					<p>Let ladies who object to being riveted down to the negro use what influence
						they can with their male friends to induce them to break up the Radical
						party, and send decent men to the Legislature. That's the only remedy we
						know of.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Commenting on the recently enacted legislation outlawing discrimination on
					the railroads, the article notes that it is white women who suffer the most from
					the consequences of Radical rule since it is they who are forced to sit beside
					blacks while traveling.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>A Negro Opinion</head>
				<origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article recounts a speech recently made by Beverly Nash, a black man,
					in South Carolina. In his address, Nash asserted that the "intelligent Southern
					negro" recognizes "the Southern white man as the true friend of the black man."
					Moreover, Nash avowed that there is "less prejudice everywhere south of the
					Potomac against the colored man, than there is north of it."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Publication of the Laws</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editors criticize the state legislature's "present absurd mode" of
					publishing recently enacted laws on the grounds that "the public" does not find
					out what measures have been passed until "six or eight months after the
					adjournment" of that governing body.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>The Radical Traitors and Revolutionists at Work in Baltimore</head>
				<origin>Baltimore</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports on "fraternization" between blacks and "white Republican unionists"
					at ward meetings held in Baltimore on May 3rd. The "chief object" of these
					meetings, the article relates, was "to take into consideration the condition of
					political affairs in Maryland" and to select delegates for the State Union
					Convention, scheduled to take place on May 14th. Yet this development has not
					been welcomed by all Marylanders. Under the leadership of Governor Swann, the
					Democrats in the state have declared their intention to ignore any resolution
					passed by the "Republican" convention, an act that may likely lead to the
					imposition of "martial law and military rule."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>The New Jury Law</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The following is the text of the new jury law:</p>
					<p>SECTION 1. <emph rend="italic">Be it enacted by the Senate and House of
							Representatives of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania in General Assembly
							met, and is hereby enacted by the authority of the same.</emph> That on
						the general election to be held on the Second Tuesday of October, Anno
						Domini, one thousand eight hundred and sixty-seven, and tri-ennially
						thereafter, at such election, the qualified electors of the several counties
						of this Commonwealth shall elect, in the manner now provided by law for the
						election of other county officers, two sober, intelligent and judicious
						persons to serve as jury commissioners, in each of said counties, for the
						period of three years ensuing their election; but the same person or persons
						shall not be eligible for re-election more than once in any period of six
						years: <emph rend="italic">Provided</emph>: That each of said qualified
						electors shall vote for one person only as jury commissioner, and the two
						persons having the greatest number of votes for jury commissioners shall be
						duly elected jury commissioners for such county. </p>
					<p>SEC. 2. It shall be the duty of said jury commissioners to meet at the seat
						of justice of the respective counties, at least thirty days before the first
						term of the court of common pleas, in every year, and thereupon proceed,
						with due diligence, to select from the whole taxable citizens of the
						respective county at large, a number, such as at the term of the court of
						common pleas preceding shall by the said court, be designated, of sober,
						intelligent and judicious persons to serve as jurors in the several courts
						of such county, during that year; and if the said commissioners cannot agree
						upon the names of the persons to be selected by them as jurors, they shall
						proceed as follows:--Each of the commissioners shall make a list containing
						the names of one-half of the requisite number of persons and ten percentum
						in addition thereto, and the proper number shall be obtained by each of said
						commissioners striking form the list furnished by the other, a number equal
						to the said addition; and the names not stricken out shall be the selection
						of the names of the jurors, and the said jury commissioners shall, in the
						mode and manner now directed by law, place the names of persons so selected,
						in the proper jury wheel, and the said jury wheel locked, as now required by
						law, shall remain in the custody of said jury commissioners and the keys
						thereof in the custody of said county.</p>
					<p>SEC. 3. The said jury commissioners and the sheriff of the respective county,
						or any tow of them, shall draw from the proper jury wheel panels of jurors,
						as grand jurors of the proper county, and as petit and traverse jurors, for
						the trial of issues in fact which may be taken in any action in any of the
						courts, civil and criminal, in the several counties aforesaid, in the manner
						now practiced and allowed; but before the said jury commissioners and
						sheriff shall proceed to select or draw jurors in the manner aforesaid, they
						shall severally take the oath or affirmation now prescribed by law to be
						taken by the sheriff and county commissioners before selecting and drawing
						jurors.</p>
					<p>SEC. 4. That so much of any act or acts of Assembly of this Commonwealth, as
						makes it the duty of the sheriff and county commissioners of any of said
						counties to select and draw jurors, shall be repealed, and cease to have any
						force or effect from and after the first day of December next, Anno Domini
						one thousand eight hundred and sixty-seven: <emph rend="italic">Provided
						</emph>, That all acts, and parts of acts of Assembly, now in force, in
						relation to the custody, sealing and unsealing, locking and opening of the
						jury wheel of the respective county, and all acts, and parts of acts of
						Assembly now in force, imposing any penalty and punishment on the sheriff
						and county commissioners, or either of them, for anything done or omitted by
						them in relation to the keeping, locking, or sealing or breaking the seal of
						any jury wheel, or in relation to the selection or drawing of jurors, shall
						be taken, deemed and held to apply to the said jury commissioners and
						sheriff. </p>
					<p>SEC. 5. Each of the said jury commissioners shall be allowed and paid out of
						the respective county treasury two dollars and fifty cents per day, and four
						cents per mile, circular, from the residence of the commissioners to the
						court house.</p>
					<p>SEC. 6. It shall be the duty of each of said jury commissioners to take upon
						himself and discharge the duties of his said office, under a penalty of one
						hundred dollars for each and every neglect or refusal to attend the same,
						and to be sued for and recovered before any justice of the peace of the
						proper county, as debts of like amount are now by law recoverable, ten
						dollars of which shall go to the person suing and the residue to be paid by
						the said justice to the treasurer of the respective county for the use of
						the same.</p>
					<p>SEC. 7. In case of inability of either or both of the said jury
						commissioners, by sickness or death, or other unavoidable causes, to
						discharge the duties of said office, or in case of neglect or refusal to
						serve thereon, it shall be the duty of the president judge in such county,
						wherein said vacancy may have occurred, to appoint a suitable person or
						persons, as the case may be, possessing the qualifications aforesaid, to
						perform the duties of said office during such vacancy, and such person or
						persons, after having complied with the requirements in the third section of
						this act, shall proceed to discharge the duties of said office the same as
						if elected by the people, until the next general election, when the people
						shall elect a commissioner in lieu thereof.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Contains a copy of the jury law recently enacted by the Legislature.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.05.08.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Deceased</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hollenberger</ln>
						<fn>W. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>W. S. Hollenberger, "a well-known citizen of Waynesboro" and Civil War
					veteran, died on May 1st after developing gangrene of the lungs.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Corner Loungers</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Houser</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Officer</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Everett</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Burgess</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>After noting that Philadelphia police have begun arresting "persons who
					lounge about corners on the Sabbath," the article encourages Burgess Everett to
					empower local authorities to do the same.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Prof. McClure's Concert</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McClure</ln>
						<fn>R. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Prof.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that the Chambersburg Musical Union concert, held on May 2nd, was
					"slimly attended" and laments that the efforts made by Prof. McClure, the
					group's leader, "to cultivate and develop musical talent in the community, have
					not been properly appreciated by the public."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Iron-Clad</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Provides an account of a performance given by a Irish man who appeared in
					the Public Square with a pocket full of marbles and four or five pieces of metal
					in the shape of swords, all of which he swallowed for the "edification and
					amusement" of the crowd that gathered to see him.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Theatrical</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Announces that McKean Buchanan, his daughter Virginia, and "a full and
					efficient company of ladies and gentlemen selected from the principal theatres
					of New York, Boston, and Philadelphia" will give a performance on May 13th at
					Repository Hall.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Colby</ln>
						<fn>T. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hunsler</ln>
						<fn>M. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kunkelman</ln>
						<fn>J. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 4th, T. F. Colby and M. R. Hunsler were married by Rev. J. A.
					Kunkelman.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Gelwicks</ln>
						<fn>Jeremiah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Snyder</ln>
						<fn>Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. Keller</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 2nd, Jeremiah Gelwicks and Elizabeth Snyder were married by Rev. J.
					Keller Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stover</ln>
						<fn>John E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Winger</ln>
						<fn>Anna M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brown</ln>
						<fn>I. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 30th, John E. Stover, of St. Louis, Cal., and Anna M. Winger were
					married by Rev. I. G. Brown.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shookey</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 22nd, John Shookey, 36, died in Washington township.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Horner</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 20th, James Horner, 68, died after a brief illness in Gettsburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Buhrman</ln>
						<fn>Aquila Hedding</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Buhrman</ln>
						<fn>A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 25th, Aquila Hedding, eldest son of Rev. A. Buhrman, died at age
					14.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Winger</ln>
						<fn>Calvin W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 22nd, Calvin W. Winger, 17, died at Claylick.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Wertz</ln>
						<fn>Mary</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Coble</ln>
						<fn>John W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On April 20th, Mary Wertz, 92, died at the residence of her son-in-law,
					John W. Coble.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.05.08.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
