<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.02.20">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>10/21/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-02-20">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="02">February</month>
			<day norm="00">20</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.02.20.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.02.20.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Radical Humanity</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary>"We glean from the <emph rend="italic">Repository </emph> the following
					choice extracts, as samples of the intellectual feats furnished by that
					hebdomadal, to its subscribers, at little other expense than of truth and fair
					dealing. Alluding to the Southern States, it says:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>"Conquered on the battle-field, condemned by the arbiter they themselves had
						chosen, they again resort to political intrigue and chicanery, to accomplish
						by artifice the ends force failed them to attain."</p>
					<p>Again-"Our only hope is we may find in Congress an Octavius too wise to be
						enchanted by fair words of flattery, too brave to be intimidated, and too
						honest to bow to gold."</p>
					<p>Again-"We will be humane to the South, but come what will to them, we must
						protect ourselves."</p>
					<p>As to the first extract, it is true that the South has been conquered on the
						battlefield. But where, or when, the intrigue, the artifice referred to?
						They have yielded as quietly, as submissively and in as good faith, as ever
						did one set of men to another. No one but such as would deny that he was the
						son of his mother, would dare, in sober earnest, to utter such a monstrous
						lie, in the hope of being believed. Such utterances are the idle cast of the
						meanest and most profligate politicians the world ever produced. They know
						they lie foully, and they know too they are not believed. But they live in
						hope that falsehood, well stuck to, will at length either command credence,
						or band together, in one determined conspiracy, a party force, that will
						laugh at truth and honor, and inaugurate another field of blood and carnage.
						For this purpose pimps and spies are scattered over the country whose office
						is to invent and propagate the grossest tales of southern barbarity and
						impute intentions and schemes, that have no other origin than their own weak
						and wicked inventions. Such vileness ignores all intelligence and
						understanding in the masses, all patriotism, and love of peace and
						substantial justice, on the part of the real lovers of the country. And what
						is it in the conduct of those they hate so fiercely that they denominate
						"political intrigue, chicanery, artifice," treason, &amp;c.,
						&amp;c.-Would you believe it. It is simply that, having returned to
						their allegiance, they refuse by any voluntary act of theirs, to sign the
						bond presented to them, that deprives them of <emph rend="italic">all their
							civil liberties</emph>, except the liberty to pay taxes into a northern
						treasury! And this negative reserve, this unwillingness to cut off their own
						right hands, to place a pollard at their throats, and bend the knee in
						craven humility and shame-this, forsoeth, is stratagem, is treason! </p>
					<p>"God help the brainless wight</p>
					<p>Pruned in Cimmerian night</p>
					<p>Who could such rant indite."</p>
					<p>The second extract is of little moment.-Its reference to the Octavius
						(Thaddeus Stevens) means simply an encouraging voice to cheer on the old
						demagogue to persevere in his unchristian course to territorialize ten
						States of the Union, so that they shall not have votes. The allusion to the
						courage of the back-window-jumper, as well as to the gold of the ruined
						South is palpably an attempt at covert sarcasm. We should like to see some
						of that same gold. There was a large sprinkling of Northern gold, the <emph
							rend="italic">Repository </emph> says, among the republican members of
						the State Legislature. But Congress, especially a Rump Congress must be
						honest. No field there is for speculation. To be sure a Cameron and a Cake,
						may be willing to spend $200,000 for the privilege of sitting there; but
						then they are rich. Their history shows how innocent they are of contracts,
						greed and spoils. </p>
					<p>We come to the last of these extracts.-It breathes such a flame of patriotism
						that we again recite it.</p>
					<p>"We will be <emph rend="italic">humane </emph> to the South, but come what
						will to them, we must <emph rend="italic">protect </emph> ourselves." </p>
					<p>Esop tells of a jewel found in a dunghill. Experience shows that tinsel is
						more apt to be discovered there. Whether this excerpt be gem or sham,
						depends on circumstances. Does the <emph rend="italic">Repository </emph>
						mean to withdraw all its previous hostile and unmanly requirements, and now
						tender in good faith the hand of friendship to the stricken South on the
						terms of security to the North? This would be a gem of a price. Indorsed by
						its party, the era of peace and good will would be at once unfurled
						throughout the length and breadth of this once happy Union. </p>
					<p>But if the meaning is "we have offered the most humane terms through the rump
						committee, and will have them, or aterner;" if it was intended as a mere
						repetition of offensive, unusual, and insulting terms, superciliously styled
						humane-then indeed the proposition assumes a different character.</p>
					<p>The humanity you tender is their disfranchisement-your security, that negroes
						should rule them! What a blessed Christian you are. Your religion is that of
						the drunken maniac who strikes again and again his prostrate friend, and
						sums up the achievement by cutting off his arms-<emph rend="italic">for
							future safety</emph>! Your "<emph rend="italic">come what will to
						them</emph>" is very characteristic. It smacks very much of the
						"devil-me-care" anxiety. You ought to study the history of selfishness as
						exhibited in earlier ages. No doubt a scrap like this from Bavarian records
						would suit your taste, and with a slight alteration might serve as a bending
						for the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>: "O holy saint Florian, save
						my house-burn others down." </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Spirit editor denounces recent Repository articles warning Northerners
					to remain suspicious of Southerners.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Let Us Smite The Poisoner</head>
				<origin>Democratic Watchman</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We recollect having once read, in a wild Eastern romance, of a monster who
						fed upon human flesh, and who gave his victims a subtile poison to steal
						away their reason and leave their animal appetites uncontrolled.-By this
						means he fattened them for his horrible feasts; for their sole object was
						the gratification of their own appetites, the moans they employed were
						fitting them to gratify his. Wild and improbable as this tale has always
						been considered, the real condition of our country to-day will equal it,
						when portrayed by the impartial historian of the future.</p>
					<p>For thirty years the Northern people have been poisoned by the radicalism of
						New England. Our schools have been polluted by books containing moral poison
						as deadly as the physical poison of the Arabian tale. Nearly all of our
						literature has emanated from the same source. Our histories, our
						geographies, our spellers, our dictionaries, and even our poetry and
						fiction, have been obtained at the same fountain head, and into all has been
						instilled the same slow and deadly moral poison. We would shrink from a
						poisonous drug with horror: but have seized with avidity something which
						destroys not merely animal life, but its capable of essentially killing that
						which is far more valuable to society and the world.-The reason of our
						people tottered when they listened to the precepts of the "Higher law," it
						fell from its throne, and left them at the mercy of their own passions, when
						they allowed themselves to be deluded by the cry of "bleeding Kansas" to the
						tune of "John Brown's soul," The literature of New England, and the
						travelling sons of Satan who came from the same hot bed of all evil, had
						accomplished the poisoning process when the Middle and Western States went
						to war with those of the South, and then began the horrible feast of the
						poisoner. The reason of our people had been dethroned by fanaticism, and
						while they seemed to be gratifying only their own unfounded and insane
						hatred of the South, they were in reality preparing themselves to be
						devoured by the monster who possessed them. New England reaped the profits
						of the late war, the East and the West fought the battles. We suffer to-day
						equally with the South; New England controls our legislation, and our loss
						is her gain. She is using the resources of a people infinitely superior to
						herself in every element of greatness, to further her interests, and in
						direct hostility to their own. Our own great State is distracted and torn by
						a political strife engendered solely by the baneful influence of New England
						poisons. The mighty West is striking wild and giant blows at its own mother
						and best natural friend, at the dictation of New England, and under the
						influence of the poison which she has disseminated. We are madly devouring
						our friends, and being in turn devoured by the natural enemy of both.</p>
					<p>The natural bonds of Union between the Middle and Western States and the
						South are strong, while there is a direct antagonism between us and New
						England. Hence the necessity for a revolution in the government. A
						restoration of the Union upon the basis of the Constitution of our fathers,
						would take from New England the power which she now yields, and put here
						where she properly belongs. She will therefore always resist the Union. She
						is and always has been for disunion, and in the very nature of things can be
						for nothing else. We wonder not at the course of those who lead; but we
							<emph rend="italic">do </emph> wonder at those who follow. The poison
						has spread widely and taken hold deeply in the morals of the people and no
						wonder. It has been instilled into babes in their nursery rhymes: the dose
						has been repeated in their school primers, doubled in their readers, and
						trebled in all their subsequent reading, until it has become a chronic
						poison, and will be constitutional in their children for generations. </p>
					<p>The present condition of things in this country is altogether unnatural, and
						must have been produced by improper means.-We attribute it solely to the
						dissemination of the fanatical ideas of New England transcendentalists, and
						before applying an antidote, we propose as the chief remedy to eat off the
						stream of poison which is constantly flowing upon us. Let Democrats
						everywhere discountenance the use of Yankee school-books, and if others
						cannot be had, let our children read the scriptures of God, as our brave old
						fathers did in their youth. Avoid New England literature as you would the
						lair of Satan, and above all check the circulation of the romances which
						come from the home of the Puritans in endless succession. When the fountain
						is cut off, we can fairly apply an antidote to the poison. The father of
						Hannibal took him to the temple of the gods and bade him wear "eternal hate
						to Rome." When Rome trembled to her foundations as his army marched in after
						years, the world learned how well that oath was kept. Let Democratic fathers
						bid their children swear, before High Heaven, eternal hatred to New England
						and her institutions, and then rear them that the oaths will be certainly
						kept.-Let us bring desolation to the homes of the spoiler, and never cease
						the work until naught is left but the bleak rocks and barren hills as they
						were when first polluted by the tread of a Puritan. Let the few good men of
						New England flee to more congenial States, as Lot fled from Sodom, and leave
						the children of Satan alone with their father. This may we effectually check
						the evil which has grown upon us.-<emph rend="italic">Democratic
						Watchman</emph></p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Alleging that Northerners "have been poisoned by the radicalism of New
					England" for the past thirty years, the article asserts that this propaganda has
					severed the "natural bonds" that linked the Middle and Western states with the
					South.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Legislation For Louisiana</head>
				<origin>Age</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article savagely criticizes the bill abolishing the current state
					government of Louisiana. The legislation would create a provisional government
					in its place; the governor would be selected by the President and approved by
					the Senate.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.02.20.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--New Law Firm</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McCauley</ln>
						<fn>I. H.</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hays</ln>
						<fn>S. Wilson</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Announces that a new law firm, McCauley and Hays, has opened in
					Chambersburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--In Jail</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Andrew Clarke, who was arrested in Gettysburg and charged with robbing the
					Waynesboro Post Office, has been returned to Chambersburg to face additional
					charges.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Larceny</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Wilson</ln>
						<fn>Pope</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Book</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Two black men, George Book and Pope Wilson, were arrested in Carlisle and
					charged with stealing a coat from White's Clothing Store.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--The Spring Election</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Announces that the Spring Elections for borough, township, and election
					officers will be held on March 15th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Brutal Outrage</head>
				<origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
				<commentary>"We clip the following from the Lancaster <emph rend="italic">Inquirer
					</emph> of last week:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>On Tuesday last, Officer Baker arrested a man named Martin Snyder, who
						resides in West Walnut street, this city on a charge of committing a rape on
						a girl about ten years of age, named Mary Elizabeth Eberly. The prisoner was
						taken before Alderman Wilely, when the following facts were elicited: Snyder
						called at the Children's Home on Saturday last, and represented to the
						matron, Mrs. MConmsey, that he desired to secure the services of one of the
						girls in that Institution, as his wife was away on a visit to some of her
						friends in Mount Joy. The matron refused to allow the girl to be taken away,
						without an order from one of the managers. Snyder then left, but soon
						returned wit an order and took the girl away with him. On Monday, the girl
						returned to the Home, with a note from the defendant's wife, stating that
						she did not suit. Several persons who were present observed that the girl
						appeared to be suffering from some cause, when Dr. John L. Atlee, President
						of the Board of Trustees, was called in, and made an examination; when he
						discovered that the young girl had been brutally outraged. The girl, on
						being questioned in regard to the matter, stated that Snyder had committed a
						rape upon her person, while his wife was absent from the home.</p>
					<p>A similar charge to the above was brought against the same defendant, by Mr.
						John K. Read, one of the Directors of the Poor, in the case of Anna Yeager,
						a girl about 14 years of age. Snyder had taken this girl from the Poor
						House, and kept her for several days, during which time he had violated her
						person, and then sent her back to the Alms House. Snyder was committed to
						prison by Alderman Wiley, to answer both charges at the next term of the
						Court of Quarter Sessions.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Officer</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Snyder</ln>
						<fn>Martin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Eberly</ln>
						<fn>Mary Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McComsey</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mrs.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Atlee</ln>
						<fn>John L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Yeager</ln>
						<fn>Anna</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wiley</ln>
						<fn>Alderman</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Informs readers about the rape of a ten-year old who resides in the local
					Children's Home.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Sommers</ln>
						<fn>Jacob V.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Landis</ln>
						<fn>Christiana</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Schneck</ln>
						<fn>B. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 12th, Jacob V. Sommers, of Middletown Valley, Md., and Christiana
					Landis were married by Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Metz</ln>
						<fn>Benjamin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bitner</ln>
						<fn>Annie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Schneck</ln>
						<fn>B. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 14th, Benjamin Metz and Annie Bitner were married by Rev. B. S.
					Schneck.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Houser</ln>
						<fn>A. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Pisler</ln>
						<fn>Mary E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gelwix</ln>
						<fn>Charles</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 14th, A. B. Houser and Mary E. Pisler were married by Rev. Charles
					Gelwix.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hendricks</ln>
						<fn>John E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Lutz</ln>
						<fn>Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. Keller</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 31st, John E. Hendricks and Elizabeth Lutz were married by Rev. J.
					Keller Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Royer</ln>
						<fn>Jonas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bitner</ln>
						<fn>Mary</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bitner</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. Keller</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 5th, Jonas Royer, of Penn's Valley, Centre county, Pa., and Mary
					Bitner, daughter of Jacob Bitner, were married by Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Snyder</ln>
						<fn>Leander M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Unger</ln>
						<fn>Catherine</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. Keller</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 7th, Leander M. Snyder and Catherine Unger were married by Rev. J.
					Keller Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Coble</ln>
						<fn>Mary Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. Keller</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 10th, Joseph Miller and Mary Elizabeth Coble were married by Rev.
					J. Keller Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Bell</ln>
						<fn>Victor C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Leady</ln>
						<fn>Ann E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Krebs</ln>
						<fn>W. E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 12th, Victor C. Bell and Ann E. Leady were married by Rev. W. E.
					Krebs.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Groff</ln>
						<fn>Catherine</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Groff</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 11th, Catherine Groff, wife of Jacob Groff, died at age 73.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Row</ln>
						<fn>Michael</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 8th, Michael Row, 86, died.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Reid</ln>
						<fn>Samuel D. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 8th, Samuel D. C. Reid, 29, died.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Wingert</ln>
						<fn>Lydia Martha</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wingert</ln>
						<fn>Christian</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Feb. 10th, Lydia Martha, daughter of Christian Wingert, died at age 22.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.02.20.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
