<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.04.03">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>11/23/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-04-03">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="04">April</month>
			<day norm="00">03</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.03.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Veto Message of the President</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Provides a transcript of President Johnson's message to the House of
					Representatives, vetoing the supplemental military bill.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.03.02">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Meyers</ln>
						<fn>B. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bowles</ln>
						<fn>Jeremiah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wiemer</ln>
						<fn>Frederick</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Announces that B. F. Meyers's nomination for Collector of Internal Revenue
					has been rejected by the Senate. As a result, Jeremiah Bowles, of Bedford, and
					Frederick Weimer, of Somerset, will continue to perform their respective duties
					as Collector and Assessor of the district that includes Franklin county.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>It is reported that Governor Geary has signed a bill requiring railroad
					operators to permit black women to ride in the ladies' car and to share seats
					with white women.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Accuses Radicals in the legislature of proposing a raise that would place
					their salary at $1,500 per session.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Military Rule</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>General Sheridan, commanding in Louisiana, has, <emph rend="italic">by virtue
							of his military authority</emph>, appointed a new Attorney General for
						the State, and new municipal officers and a new Judge for the city of New
						Orleans!-If some military potentate will now "establish a religion" and
						"create an order of nobility," we believe there will then be left unviolated
						no single provision of the Constitution of the United States. </p>
					<p>The removal and appointment of Judges of courts of law by a military officer,
						is one of those significant strokes at the very foundation of social order,
						which mark the stage of revolution which we have already reached. It is a
						new conception; till now, it probably never entered the brain of any one
						living in a civilized country; its effect on the minds of the American
						people, will show how much they may retain of the love of civil liberty
						which burned in the breasts of their forefathers. The Radical leaders assume
						that the whole land is ripe for servitude; their hands are raised to snatch
						the judicial power from the judges and the executive power from the
						President; all is to be engrossed and wielded by the Radical clique, through
						bureau and military agents. But, in their intoxication, we think they
						misjudge the American people; each act that displays the Radicals in their
						true colors, encourages our hope that their rule built on impudence and
						deception, is destined to no long continuance.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article labels General Sheridan's decision to replace several
					high-ranking state officials in Louisiana as proof of the Radicals' disregard
					for the "social order."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>"A Timely Warning"</head>
				<origin>Age</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"The negro suffrage forced on the South yesterday is to be forced on the
					North tomorrow."</excerpt>
				<transcript>
					<p>Nobody has yet had time to forget, says the <emph rend="italic">Age </emph>,
						that nearly every Republican organ and representative pledged themselves in
						the political campaign of last year, that their party harbored no design to
						force negro suffrage, even on the Southern States. Every imputation of that
						design, they met with the most positive and solemn denial, and they pointed,
						a proof, to the express terms of the proposed constitutional amendment,
						which, they said, left the whole question to the people of each State. The
						Congress elected on these solemn pledges has not been yet in session a
						month. They have, however, already passed a "supplemental reconstruction
						bill" fastening negro suffrage upon every Southern state, pinning it down on
						them with the point of the bayonet. The second act of the performance opened
						on Saturday last in the Senate, when Wilson brought in a bill to force negro
						suffrage on all the Northern States; and to cap the climax of impudence,
						this is based on the very "amendment" which purported to leave the whole
						matter to the States,-- Here is his bill omitting only a long lying
						"whereas" which precedes it as a preamble. Its title is "a bill to regulate
						the elective franchise in the United States:" </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives
							of the United States of American in congress assembled</emph>. That
						there shall be no denial of the elective franchise to any male citizen of
						the United States by any State on account of color or race, or previous
						condition, anything in the constitution or laws of any State to the contrary
						notwithstanding. </p>
					<p>SEC 2. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That every
						person who shall violate the provisions of this act shall, on conviction in
						any court of the United States, be fined for each and every offense not less
						than one hundred dollars, or be imprisoned not less than six months, or
						both, at the discretion of the Court. </p>
					<p>Let it be remembered that Connecticut and Ohio have, by very recent acts,
						determined to uphold the governing prerogative of the white race, as it is
						established in Pennsylvania, and other States of the North. But the Radical
						leaders are now, they think, strong enough to trample down public opinion
						and to dispense with further disguises. The "negro suffrage: that was
						excused and palliated in the last Congress as a necessary "war measure"
						against States that were charged-though falsely-as being still in
						rebellion-this same "negro suffrage" that was excused and palliated in the
						last Congress as a necessary "war measure" against States that were
						charged-though-falsely-as still being in rebellion-this same "negro
						suffrage" is now to be thrust upon the people of Connecticut and
						Pennsylvania, who were never before supposed to have forfeited the right of
						self-government, in the matters that belong to the States.</p>
					<p>Now, this example may plainly show, even to the blindest, how great an
						interest the Northern people have in the struggle that is now going on in
						our country between the principles of free constitutional government and of
						despotism. It is common enough, to speak of the Southern people with some
						commiseration-to depreciate the infliction on them of the oppressions that
						shock humanity, in the case of Poland, Hungary and Ireland. But we have an
						interest deeper and nearer than this.-The freemen of the North have their
						stake, too, and a great one it is, in the reckless desperate game the
						Radicals are playing for despotic power. All our liberties are at stake. We
						see the denial of the rights of the Southern States followed up promptly and
						surely by the denial of the rights of the States of the North. The negro
						suffrage forced on the South yesterday, is to be forced on the North
						to-morrow. If Congress has power to establish negro suffrage, so has it the
						right to institute military tribunals to enforce it. They are what Wilson
						means, no doubt, by "any court of the United States." The late decision of
						the Supreme Court declaring them illegal is now openly treated with
						contempt. A military commission is still the favorite engine of Radical
						despotism; it appears in all recent plans of reconstruction, though even
						Benjamin F. Butler does not hesitate to charge it with the murder of a
						woman.-The case of Mrs. Surratt, who was dragged in chains before an illegal
						tribunal, tried in furious and unfair haste, and, according even to Butler,
						condemned "without any evidence of guilt," may serve as an instance and a
						warning of what follows when passion and party violence triumph over law. If
						we are ever again to have law and order among us, it is time their rule
						should begin. It is no longer "a time of war" in which there was a claim to
						universal license. The people of the South, with a sincerity of which now,
						at least, there can be no doubt, are earnestly seeking the restoration of
						free constitutional government. They have learned to know its value. And
						must the Northern people learn it from its loss; or shall we be wise in
						time? Let every freeman who has a vote to give in any approaching election
						ponder well this question.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Despite the Republicans' pledge last year to refrain from forcing black
					suffrage upon the South, Radicals' actions in Congress thus far appear to
					repudiate all such claims. As evidence, the article includes a copy of a bill
					introduced by Senator Wilson that would make it illegal to deny the vote to any
					male citizen of the country on the basis of his color or race.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.03.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--To Taxpayers</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Announces that, due to the inclement weather over the past few weeks, the
					deadline for receiving a 5% abatement on taxes has been extended from March 31st
					to April 25th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Licensing Hotels and Restaurants Penalties for Selling
					Liquor Without License</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The following supplement having passed both branches of the Legislature
						received the Governor's signature and is, therefore, now a law:</p>
					<p>Section 1. <emph rend="italic">Be it enacted, &amp;c.</emph>, That when
						an application is made to any Court of Quarter Sessions of this Commonwealth
						for license to sell intoxicating drinks, it shall be lawful for said courts
						to hear petitions, in addition to that of the applicant, in favor of, and
						remonstrances against the application for such license, and, in all cases,
						to refuse the same whenever, in the opinion of said court, having due regard
						to the number and character of the petitioners, for and against such
						application, such a license is not necessary for the accommodation of the
						public, and entertainment of strangers and travelers, and upon sufficient
						cause being shown, the said courts shall have power to revoke any license
						granted by them; and all laws inconsistent with this section are hereby
						repealed. <emph rend="italic">Provided</emph>, that the sureties in the bond
						required of the applicant for license shall be signers to his petition. </p>
					<p>Section 2. That applications for license to keep an eating house, beer house
						or restaurant, authorizing the sale of domestic wines malt and brewed
						liquors, shall hereafter be made in the same manner and to the same
						authority as application, for license to keep a hotel, <emph rend="italic"
							>Provided </emph>, that the regulation in relation to bed rooms and beds
						shall not apply to applicants for an eating house, beer house and restaurant
						license; and the tenth section of the act of 20th April, 1858, authorizing
						county treasurers to grant an eating house or retail brewery license, is
						hereby repealed. </p>
					<p>Section 3. No license to keep an eating house, beer house or restaurant,
						under the provisions of the second section of this act, shall be granted in
						any incorporated city, for less sum than fifty dollars, nor elsewhere for a
						less sum than twenty dollars.</p>
					<p>Section 4. If any person, after the passage of this act, shall sell
						spirituous and vinous liquors, domestic wines, malt or brewed liquors,
						without having obtained a license authorizing him to do so, such person
						shall on conviction in the Court of Quarter Sessions, be fined, for the
						first offense in any sum not less than fifty, nor more than two hundred
						dollars, and for the second, or any subsequent offense, such person shall be
						fined not less than one hundred dollars, and in the discretion of the said
						court, be imprisoned in the county jail not less than thirty days, nor more
						than ninety days.-<emph rend="italic">Provided </emph>, That nothing in this
						act shall be construed to repeal the provisions of the act of Assembly,
						passed March 31, 1858 relating to sales by druggists and apothecaries. </p>
					<p>Section 5. That the provisions of the first section of this act shall not
						apply to the city of Philadelphia or to the county of Allegheny. <emph
							rend="italic">Provided </emph>, That nothing in this act shall authorize
						the granting of licenses to hotel and inn-keepers to vend vinous, spirituous
						and malt liquors, and to license beer houses, eating houses and restaurants,
						in any locality where licensing of hotels, inns, beer houses, eating houses
						or restaurants is now prohibited by law. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Provides a copy of the supplementary bill authorizing penalties for hotels
					and restaurants that sell liquor without the proper licenses.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--The Damage Bill</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>It is reported that the legislature passed the Damage Bill, which
					appropriates $500,000 for the border communities -- Adams, Franklin, Fulton,
					Bedford, Perry, York, Cumberland, and Blair counties -- affected by the war. To
					secure a portion of that sum, the piece says individuals will have to take a
					"test oath" of loyalty.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Tribute of Respect</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McCurdy</ln>
						<fn>Harriet</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Contains a copy of the resolutions passed by the Loudon Lodge, No. 197,
					I.O. of G. T., on March 23rd, 1867, in memory of Harriet McCurdy, recently
					deceased.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Fleming</ln>
						<fn>Robert</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Campbell</ln>
						<fn>Rachel Annie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Campbell</ln>
						<fn>Andrew</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>West</ln>
						<fn>William A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 21st, Robert Fleming, of Shade Gap, Pa., and Rachel Annie,
					daughter of Andrew Campbell, were married by Rev. William A. West.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Sollenberger</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wolfkill</ln>
						<fn>Sarah J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. Keller</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 24th, Joseph Sollenberger and Sarah J. Wolfkill were married by
					Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Blood</ln>
						<fn>Jane</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 27th, Jane Blood, 73, died.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Parker</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 18th, Samuel Parker, 48, died at the residence of his brother in
					Orrstown.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Gamble</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gamble</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 22nd, James Gamble, 86, died at the residence of his son, David
					Gamble, in Spring Run.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Heintzelman</ln>
						<fn>John Geary</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Heintzelman</ln>
						<fn>Andrew</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Heintzelman</ln>
						<fn>Sarah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 28th, John Geary, son of Andrew and Sarah Heintzelman, died at age
					5 months.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stech</ln>
						<fn>Philip</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On March 17th, Philip Stech, 74, died at his residence in Welsh Run.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.03.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
