<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.04.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/30/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-04-10">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="00">10</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.10.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.10.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that William McSherry's appointment as Assessor of Internal
                    Revenue was confirmed by the Senate. In addition, Charles W. Ashcom was
                    confirmed as Collector.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Beginning of the End</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The glorious result of the Connecticut election has sent a thrill of joy into
                        every patriotic heart in the country. For six long years the people have
                        groaned under the burdens imposed on them through the abuses and usurpations
                        of the Republican party. The Radical leaders have kept steadily advancing
                        step by step, in their work of destruction and revolution, until the
                        constitutional government established by our ancestors exists only in name,
                        whilst its vital principles have been overthrown. So insidious and artful
                        has this work been carried on, that the people were systematically deceived
                        by false promises and pledges.-They seemed bound by a charm from which it
                        appeared impossible to arouse them. The good and patriotic of the land had
                        begun to despair of the Republic, and were preparing their minds to receive
                        in silent sadness the imperialism which succeeded the ancient Roman
                        Republic, or the anarchy of the so-called Republic of Mexico. But the
                        delusion which has held the people spell-bound hitherto, is at last broken.
                        Light breaks from the East. The result of the election in Connecticut shows
                        that the people are at last beginning to awake to the true condition of the
                        country. It is indicative of that reaction in the public sentiment of the
                        country, which is destined, ere long, to sweep the Radical party from power.
                        It is the "beginning of an end" of that political revolution which we
                        confidently believe will yet bring back the administration of the government
                        to the ancient landmarks of the Constitution.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial celebrates the Democrats' victory in the recent election in
                    Connecticut and asserts that it "shows that the people of the country are at
                    last beginning to awake to the true condition of the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Reasons of the Radicals for Their Defeat in Connecticut</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Employing extracts from leading Radical journals to substantiate their
                    claims, the editors mock Republicans' rationalizations for the party's
                    performance in the Connecticut election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Case of Mrs. Surratt</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"An aged women, now recognized as innocent, was daily dragged before them,
                    loaded with chains; manacles on her wrists, a revolting spectacle such as had
                    not been seen for centuries in a court of justice."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Noting that even General Butler believes Mrs. Surratt was "unfairly tried
                    and unjustly condemned to death," the article offers her case as a prime example
                    of the injustice that occurs when military authorities usurp the
                    responsibilities of civilian courts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Registry Law in Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The Radical majority in our State Legislature have got up a
                    registration law, which will in all probability be passed. It is true that the
                    Constitution of the State stands opposed to any change in the qualification of
                    electors, but that is no impediment to the legislative enactment in these days.
                    The registration law as reported is as follows:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It requires Assessors to keep a registry of voters with their private
                        residences, and produce the same at the place of election, fourteen days
                        previous to the election to the judges and inspectors, who with the
                        assessor, shall meet on the twelfth day preceding the second Tuesday in
                        October, and continue in session from nine to six o'clock to receive the
                        names of persons not before registered, and hear and decide upon claims to
                        vote; and no person shall be allowed to vote whose name does not appear upon
                        the registry but any registered name may be challenged, just as if no
                        registry of the name had been made, and the election board may pass upon
                        such challenge; penalty for receiving non-registered votes shall be fine and
                        imprisonment, at the discretion of the court. The same meeting of the Board
                        and registry shall be had twelve days preceding every Presidential election.
                        At every special, and at every city, borough and township election, the
                        registry may be used as proof of the right to vote, unless satisfactory
                        rebutting testimony shall be produced. On the petition of five citizens that
                        they believe that frauds are about to be perpetrated at the polls, the
                        courts of the county, or the judge in vacation thereof, may appoint two
                        judicious, sober and intelligent citizens to act as overseers of any poll or
                        polis, who shall be selected from different political parties, where both
                        inspectors are of one political party, both of the overseers shall be taken
                        from the opposite political party; the inspectors to furnish such overseers
                        with every facility for understanding and taking notes of all decided on by
                        the board, and to challenge votes. The bill also provides heavy fines for
                        any clerk or protonotary, who shall issue any fraudulent naturalization
                        paper or issue such paper or blank to be used by any person at the polls.
                        The bill is the special order for Thursday morning.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes a bill promulgated by Radicals in the state legislature that
                    would alter the existing rules related to voter registration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Woman Question</head>
                <origin>Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an account of a convention held in Kansas in support of female and
                    black suffrage. Among those in attendance were such notables as the governor,
                    lieutenant-governor, and all members of the Supreme Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.10.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Fatal Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Keefer's widow died on April 6th after falling from a balcony in
                    what was formerly the Tankersley Hotel in St. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--A Distressing Case</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article recounts the tragic death of Jacob Foreman's son, who drowned
                    while playing in the Conococheague River on April 2nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Attempted Burglary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The piece relates the circumstances surrounding a thwarted burglary of
                    George Etter's home in Mercersburg on March 31st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.04.10.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
