<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1867/pa.fr.vs.1867.01.30">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>10/30/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1867-01-30">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="01">January</month>
			<day norm="00">30</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.01.30.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.01.30.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Bribery &amp; c.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The election of the great wiggle-waggle-sometimes called Simon Cameron-to the
						United States Senate, has brought up our friend Aleck standing. He whoops
						like any Indian, and if that old sinner, the Winnebago Chief, was not
						accustomed to such angry cries, it is probable he would be awfully scared.
						We are a little afraid, however, that he counts the valor of his foe at an
						exceeding low figure, and regards his paper explosions as made up of
						nine-tenths wind and one-tenth valor. Indeed, we well remember Aleck to have
						been on the Chieftain's track at divers times before, but never heard of
						damage following. These numerous hunts and strange escapes front a foe whose
						wily, have given rise in many minds to the singular notion that our
						chivalrous friend did not wish to hurt a hair of his head, much less to take
						his gory scalp.</p>
					<p>The fact that he does not put in motion any <emph rend="italic"
						>feasible</emph> mode to reach the evil he complains of, as against, <emph
							rend="italic">the man</emph> in question but contents himself with
						suggesting certain constitutional amendments, that by a round-about way, at
						some distant period, might operate on some luckless wight of the next
						generation - might raise a doubt of sincerity, but we acquit him of this. So
						much depended on the election of the "soldiers' friend," that failure there
						might well raise bile. </p>
					<p>It does seem queer though, that while he threatens continued and never-ending
						efforts to expose and extinguish the whole batch of Black Republicans who
						took the bribe to vote for wiggle-waggle, he earnestly renounces all
						intention to move against the greater rogue, the briber, because he has no
						"personal feelings against him." Well, here is a quandary! He thunders
						anathemas and threats against the forty of fifty little villains who sold
						their votes, against whom, the inference is, he has personal hostile
						feelings, and therefore will pursue them to the death, and because he has no
						such feelings against the great offender, who got up that whole catalogue of
						crime, therefore, &amp;c, &amp;c.</p>
					<p>This looks much like a change of programme, and common men, not well versed
						in the premises, might be at fault to know what was really meant. But we
						profess to see as deep into what is not to be seen as the next one; and
						therefore conjecture, in spite of all protestations to the contrary that
						quite so much personal indignation does exist against the one, as against
						the others. True, the record is against us. But types will sometimes lie. An
						unusual amount of Christian forgiveness ,and desire of reconciliation,
						sometimes chequers the temper even of an editor; but think "ye, a
						philanthropist, a humanitarian, a man who avouches himself a member of the
						party of "great moral ideas;" will such a one sometimes forgive, or for a
						brief moment fancy he has forgiven?</p>
					<p>There, then, is our conjecture. Take it for what it is worth. When [UNCLEAR]
						there was no bitter feeling. The sense [UNCLEAR] of wrong and the desire to
						avenge men still survive when justice calls. We therefore do assume our
						injured friend is on the war path still.</p>
					<p>Oh, if Simon were only a good and honest lover-not of party-but of his
						country in one word a constitutional democrat-how easy were his demolition!
						His fame might then be that of Madison or Washington, he would be [UNCLEAR]
						on sight, if in the way of a single loyal rouge!</p>
					<p>Unfortunately for the friend of the "soldier's friend" Simon Cameron bears no
						such disparaging mark about him. A perfect trimmer, he'll pass [UNCLEAR]
						muster with the blackest black,; at least as long as black is trump. - If it
						were not so, how could the party of "great moral ideas" retains power?</p>
					<p>But still our friend need not despair. - Where there is a will there mostly
						is a way. It is a little remarkable that one so astute on most occasions,
						should on this be under a cloud. That he should burn with honest indignation
						against the towering briber who out-bribes, and drives to the wall, the
						smaller bribers, is to be expected. That he has so far failed to put him
						down, or even with all the help of the irate Forney and the virtuous
						Stevens, to make the attempt, must be because he don't know how to do it.</p>
					<p>Well, one man has sometimes more common sense in a given case than a score of
						lawyers. We'll tell you how to do it. It is the plain and obvious way, and
						simply this; Take Stanton in your counsels. He can point you to the sly
						detective that give them but a trial, will soon discover what you want to
						know. Point out to them such of your caucus gentry, and others in their
						secrets, whose testimony you desire.- Incite your man-and with him all the
						guilty who refuse to testify, for conspiracy and bribery. It cannot be in
						the nature of things that operations on so large a scale as charged,
						embracing scores of actors, agents, runners to and fro, have left no mark,
						no crack, no unclosed avenue which property invoked could not a tale unfold
						that would startle the simple and make rogues tremble.</p>
					<p>This work of justice accomplished, and villains in high places punished
						through your instrumentality - your name will go down to posterity as a
						patriot and public benefactor, (who "without feelings of personal
						hostility," rendered a great service to the public good,) with a lustre and
						a halo, which, without this crowning act, the versatile editor of the <emph
							rend="italic">Repository </emph> could not rationally expect. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editors criticize Simon Geary for failing to take a bold stand against
					the Radicals. According to the piece, Geary had campaigned on the platform that
					he would "expose and extinguish" the corrupt practices of the "Black
					Republicans," a task he has yet to accomplish.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Impending Coup D'Etat</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The evidence is accumulating that the radical majority in Congress intend to
						subvert our republican form of government.-The clerk of the United States
						Senate, the mouth-piece of Radicalism, declares that party measures are to
						be carried out at all hazards, and if the "law" stands in the way of their
						consummation "so much the worse for the law," and Wendell Phillips declares
						that the North "knows her omnipotence, knows that she can <emph
							rend="italic">crush all the mere forms of government</emph> when it is
						necessary to do so in order to see cure its great purposes," Thaddeus
						Stevens, with a boldness which his fellow conspirators have not yet had the
						courage to manifest, has declared that "he would not stultify himself by
						claiming any constitutional authority for his actions," and Mr. Boutwell
						does not hesitate to declare, "with strong emphasis," that the Supreme
						Court-one of the co-equal branches of the government-" <emph rend="italic"
							>exists </emph> but by the <emph rend="italic">breath of
						Congress</emph>." And this in face of the fact that the Supreme Court was
						established by the people, through the Constitution mainly to <emph
							rend="italic">define the powers of Congress and pass upon the
							constitutionality of its acts</emph>. </p>
					<p>Can there be a doubt that a party whose leaders avow such infamously
						treasonable sentiments contemplate a <emph rend="italic">coup d'etat</emph>
						to consolidate all the powers of the government in the hands of the dominant
						faction in Congress? On this subject the New Your <emph rend="italic">Times
						</emph> published, on last Thursday, a letter from Washington, doubtless
						written by the editor, Henry J. Raymond, a member of the present Congress,
						and thoroughly acquainted with the revolutionary designs of the Radicals,
						which is full of startling warning to the nation. "The purpose of the
						majority of the present imperfect Congress, as we all see," says Mr.
						Raymond, "<emph rend="italic">is to remove the President</emph>, and not
						only the President but the <emph rend="italic">Supreme Court out of its
						way</emph>. We see this, and we look on in apathy and go about our
						money-making, stupidly trusting that no harm will come of it, and yet what
						is doing is that <emph rend="italic">constitutional government is destroyed
							before our eyes</emph>." Speaking of the bill introduced in Congress by
						Mr. Williams, of Pennsylvania, "to define the powers of the Supreme Court,"
						Mr. Raymond says: </p>
					<p>Congress has no more right to define the powers of the Supreme Court than to
						define its own powers or those of the President. The people have already
						done all this through the Constitution; and the people may change their
						definition through the Constitution. When the powers either of Congress, the
						President, or the Supreme Court are abridged or enlarged in any other way,
						constitutional government is at an end, and constitutional liberty has for
						the time perhaps for ever been destroyed. Yet this proposition to define the
						powers of the Supreme Court, and to make a full bench and unanimity
						necessary to any decision upon the constitutionality of the proceedings of
						the majority in Congress, was not rebuked or laughed down, but actually
						referred to the Judiciary Committee by a vote of one hundred and seven to
						thirty-nine.</p>
					<p>Here we have a proposition to usurp the functions of the Supreme Court, not
						"rebuked or laughed down," as it deserved to be, but actually <emph
							rend="italic">endorsed </emph> by a vote of "<emph rend="italic">one
							hundred and seven to thirty-nine</emph>!" Mr. Raymond continues; </p>
					<p>These things are done before us; the doom of our government is on the brink
						of execution; and yet we are quiet! Will nothing rouse us? Are we as
						sluggish of apprehension now, on the one hand, as we were before the
						rebellion, on the other? Our government is in peril now, as it was then; not
						of disintegration but of <emph rend="italic">usurpation-the usurpation of
							absolute power by the temporary representatives of a majority of the
							people of a part of this country</emph>. </p>
					<p>This is the testimony, not of a Democrat or "copperhead" but of a man in full
						comunion in the Republican party, who used his whole influence last fall for
						the success of the radical ticket. The danger to our institutions is
						imminent. Will the people heed the warning and prepare to meet the danger?
						It is time that these conspirators against the life of the Republic are
						stopped on their onward march of destruction. This "Rump Congress" should be
						speedily dispersed as public enemies plotting the overthrow of the best
						government the world ever saw. It is the only remedy we can see of saving
						the noble heritage bequeathed to us by our revolutionary ancestors." <emph
							rend="italic">Will President Johnson do his duty</emph>? </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>In reaction to the steady stream of Republican attacks on the Supreme
					Court, the editors assert there is little doubt that party leaders are
					contemplating a "coup d'etat to consolidate all the powers of the government in
					the hands" of the Radicals.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>The Era of 1642 in England and 1866 in America</head>
				<origin>Constitutional Union</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Despite the Radical leaders' claim to the contrary, the article maintains
					that the conflict between the Republicans and President Johnson is in no way
					analogous to the situation in England, in 1642, when Parliament was forced to
					protect its rights from Charles I's tyrannical rule.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>The Supreme Court</head>
				<origin>Anti-Slavery Standard</origin>
				<commentary>"If any of our readers still doubt that the purposes of the Radical
					party are revolutionary, and that they intend to consolidate all power in the
					hands of the Legislative Department of the government, regardless of the
					Constitution and law, and establish a despotism on the ruins of our republican
					system, let them read the following treasonable article, by Wendell Phillips,
					published in the Anti-Slavery Standard, attacking the Supreme Court, one of the
					co-ordinate branches of the government:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The late decisions of the Supreme Court allow us that we must henceforth
						count two of the three great co-equal powers of the government against us.
						Henceforth Congress fights alone for the nation against the Supreme Court
						and the President, leagued in the service of rebeldom. Of course, therefore,
						the context grows keener, and more equal, and the south takes courage.-The
						North is not discouraged, because she knows her omnipotence, knows that she
						can crush all the mere forms of government when it is necessary so to do in
						order to see cure its great purpose-justice, and the preservation of
						national existence. This the people mean to do, and will do unless balked by
						timid, selfish, incompetent and corrupt leaders. The action of the Supreme
						Court-its disloyalty-will not surprise Abolitionists; we have tested that
						bench forever since Taney - the mere creature of a self-willed
						president-took his seat there, it has ceased to be an Independent branch of
						the government, and become the convenient and supple fool of the Executive.
						Abolitionists well know that, during the whole course of its existence, it
						has never squared its decisions on the slave question either with justice,
						the spirit of the Constitution, or even its letter when that favored
						liberty. While its course on many great issues has been open to grave
						objections, its record on the negro question is infamous. We use the word
						deliberately. The use of it in this connection twenty-five years ago, won us
						the unmitigated abuse of the whole American press. We have maturely
						considered their protest, and remaining of the same opinion still,
						deliberately repeat the statement. Without limiting the remark to the slave
						question, we affirm that, on several important subjects the instinct of
						freedom has never led that court to deviate by accident or for a moment into
						any decision becoming the American people, their history, Constitution, or
						Declaration of Independence. An effort would have been made early in the war
						to remodel the court, but for a very general distrust of Mr. Lincoln's
						policy of filling vacancies there. Thaddeus Stevens, when appealed to in
						1802 to neutralize the poison of that bench by adding two or three
						trustworthy judges, replied:--"Add judges for Abraham to nominate! I had
						rather risk the court as it is." Events have confirmed his sagacity, two of
						Lincoln's nominates have joined the enemy. If present appearances may be
						trusted, that court, like the President, is henceforth to stand an
						insurmountable obstacle, as at present constituted, to any efficient and
						safe reconstruction. Thanks to the Dred Scott and other decisions, the bench
						long ago lost the sympathy and respect of the masses. General Jackson could
						not lift Taney to the bench; he could drag the bench down to Taney.--There
						are men whom it is impossible to make respectable, since they have no
						element to win respect. There is no human institution so venerable that the
						touch of vile men will not defile and degrade it. Ten years ago, the final
						cause of such a creature as Taney was inexplicable. To-day, the mystery is
						solved. No element less repulsive and discreditable than his character would
						have sufficed to utterly bankrupt such a power as that court, which, in its
						pristine vigor-serving tyranny with decorum-might have overawed and misled
						the people in this crisis. It will need but little effort to show the people
						the true course to be taken in this emergency. The nation must be saved, no
						matter what or how venerable the foe whose existence goes down before that
						necessity. The ideal of such a court, aloof from all political ambition, far
						above all party spirit, unimpassioned as justice, was a grand conception.
						Such a court would have been an invaluable element in our system. Until
						within some twenty years, the masses have regarded it as a bench, basing its
						decisions on definite, unvarying, and easily understood principles. Of late
						it is seen to be what it is, a mere appendage to party. Appointed for life,
						its judges must, of course, often find themselves appurtenant, by their
						prejudices and associations, to defend a party. Such is their present
						position; and, like all fragments and elements of the old, disloyal
						Democratic party, its fate is certain. The moment there arises in the
						republican ranks a man bold enough to strike, the people will applaud the
						blow. There will be the same outcry and the same resistance, from the same
						quarters, as there was when anti-slavery first demanded that the nation
						should mould its form or its spirit. The outcry and resistance will be just
						as vain in this case as in that. The instincts of the masses, the
						consciences of just men, the spirit of the age, and God's law, all demand
						that the inspiration and corner-stone of this government shall be justice.
						The Constitution, with its time-honored compromises held up by the strongest
						of parties, was dust in the balance against such a current. This court will
						prove the same. The dry rot of its political subservience has made it an
						empty form. The wind of the blow that demolished slavery were enough to
						scatter this obstacle from our path.</p>
					<p>WENDELL PHILLIPS.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>Wendell Phillips</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>Provides a copy of a "treasonable" article written by Wendell Phillips, in
					which he criticizes the Supreme Court for overstepping its authority in the test
					oath case.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>The National Republican Executive Committee</head>
				<origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Relates that the Republican National Executive Committee met on Jan. 25th
					in Washington, where it adopted a series of resolutions, including a provision
					declaring that none of the "States recently in rebellion should be admitted to
					the Union until they accept negro suffrage and negro equality."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>The Impeachment Question</head>
				<origin>Constitutional Union</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article describes the impeachment crisis as an example of the partizan
					politics that has plagued the nation since the end of war. Impeachment would not
					punish Johnson for committing a crime; rather, it would "change the form of the
					government, converting it into an aristocracy, with some Yankee as dictator."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.01.30.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Dwelling House Burns</head>
				<origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Middour</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that Jacob Middour's residence was destroyed in a fire on Jan.
					17th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--The Game Laws</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article alerts readers that, as a result of the law passed last year,
					the hunting season for pheasant and quail has ended.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Sad Accident On The Valley Railroad</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A horrible crash occurred on the Cumberland Valley Railroad line, in which
					five people were injured--some of them severely. Evidently, the wreck was the
					result of a broken rail, which threw the front engine from the tracks. Three of
					the victims are not expected to survive.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Court Proceedings</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Best</ln>
						<fn>Nicholas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hammond</ln>
						<fn>Daniel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hess</ln>
						<fn>John F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Mower</ln>
						<fn>A. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Needy</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stine</ln>
						<fn>Charles A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brown</ln>
						<fn>William H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hughes</ln>
						<fn>H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brant</ln>
						<fn>David C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Staver</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Etter</ln>
						<fn>Lewis</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shelry</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McNulty</ln>
						<fn>William C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Martin</ln>
						<fn>Alex</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kitzmiller</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Guyer</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Feldman</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Newcomer</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hartie</ln>
						<fn>J. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hess</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Plowden</ln>
						<fn>Calvin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Burkholder</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ditch</ln>
						<fn>David L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Cook</ln>
						<fn>Thaddeus</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Funk</ln>
						<fn>David H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Funk</ln>
						<fn>Ann C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Taylor</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gelwicks</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wengert</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Mussulman</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Balsley</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Palmer</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Burkholder</ln>
						<fn>Jeremiah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wolf</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Adair</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Eckleberry</ln>
						<fn>Issac</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Middleton</ln>
						<fn>Mary Ann</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Weiser</ln>
						<fn>Reuben</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Dullenmaster</ln>
						<fn>Lewis</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rowe</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Goettman</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Cunningham</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Metcalfe</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Benedict</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Snyder</ln>
						<fn>J. M. P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Adams</ln>
						<fn>Titus</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fry</ln>
						<fn>Anna</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Darts</ln>
						<fn>Susan</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Johnston</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gates</ln>
						<fn>Louisa</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Mellinger</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fry</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nave</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Johnson</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wilson</ln>
						<fn>Agnes</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wise</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lists cases tried and disposed of during the first week of the January
					Court. "Common Pleas. Nicholas Best vs. Daniel Hammond, Ejectment for a tract of
					land, situated in Fannet township. Verdict for the defendant. John F. Hess vs.
					A. S. Mower. This was an issue to test the ownership of certain grain growing on
					a farm sold at Public Sale by plaintiff to defendant. The jury being unable to
					agree were discharged by the Court. Samuel Needy vs. Walter &amp; Eden. An
					action in the case. Judgement confessed for $300. Charles Stein vs. William
					Brown. Appeal by defendant from the judgement of H. Appenseller, Esq., for
					$62.75. Verdict for plaintiff $4.95. J. W. Miller vs. H. Hughes &amp; Co.
					Assumpeit on Book account. Verdict for plaintiff $130.00. Quarter Session.
					Licenses were granted to the following persons: David C. Brant, Tavern; Samuel
					Staver, Tavern; Lewis Etter, Tavern; Henry Shelry, Tavern; William C. McNulty,
					Tavern; Alex Martin, Tavern; David Kitzmiller, Tavern, David Guyer, Tavern; John
					Miller, Tavern; Henry Feldman, Tavern; J. Newcomer, Restaurant; John P. Miley,
					Restaurant; J. H. Hartie, Wholesale Liquor Store. Com. vs. Jacob Hess, Assault
					and Battery. Defendant pleaded guilty. Fined $-- and costs. Com. vs. Calvin
					Plowden. Disturbing a religious meeting. Verdict--Sentenced to one month in
					County Jail. Com. vs. David L. Ditch, Thaddeus Cook, David H. Funk, and Ann C.
					Funk. Larceny of four turkeys. Verdict--David L. Ditch and Thaddeus Cook,
					guilty; the others not guilty. Sentenced each to pay a fine of $1.00 and costs
					of prosecution, and undergo an imprisonment in County Jail for one month. Com.
					vs. Thomas Baker. Larceny. Verdict--Not guilty. Com. vs. David L. Taylor and
					David Gelwicks. Conspiracy defraud, and obtaining goods by false pretenses from
					Joseph Miller. Verdict--Guilty on second count for obtaining goods on false
					pretenses. A new trial granted. Com. vs. Jacob L. Wengert. Blasphemy.
					Verdict--Not Guilty and the prosecutor, C. C. Foltz, to pay one-half of the
					costs, and defendant other half. Cases in which nolle prosequi was entered with
					leave of Court: Com. vs. Jacob Mussulman. Fornication and Bastardy. Com. vs.
					John Balsley. Fornication and Bastardy. Com. vs. Samuel Palmer. Fornication and
					Bastardy. Com. vs. Jeremiah Burkholder. Fornication and Bastardy. Com. vs.
					William Wolf. Larceny. Com. vs. William Adair. Selling liquor without license.
					Com. vs. Isaac Eckleberry et al. Surety of the peace. Com. vs. Mary Ann
					Middleton. Surety of the peace. Com. vs. Reuben Weiser. Fornication and
					Bastardy. Com. vs. Lewis Dullenmaster. Fornication and Bastardy. Com. vs. Rowe,
					Mellinger, et al. Riot and Assault and Battery. Com. vs. George Goettman.
					Assault and Battery. Com. vs. George Goettman. Larceny. Com. vs. William
					Cunningham. Assault and Battery. Com. vs. William Metcalf. Huckstering without
					license. Bills Ignored. Com. vs. John Benedict and J. M. P. Snyder. Rejecting
					ballot of a deserter. Com. vs. Titus Adams. Assault and Battery. Com. vs. Anna
					Fry. Assault and Battery. Com. vs. Susan Darts. Assault and Battery. Com. vs.
					Henry Johnston. Assault and Battery. Com. vs. Louisa Gates and George Baker.
					Larceny. Com. vs. John Mellinger and George Fry. Larceny. Com. vs. George Nave.
					Larceny. Com. vs. Samuel Johnson. Larceny. Com. vs. Agnes Wilson. Adultery. Com.
					vs. Joseph Miller. Larceny. Com. vs. Joseph Wise. Larceny. About a dozen true
					bills were found, which were continued to April term. Among them, we are glad to
					state, is a bill against the scoundrel who stole the carpet out of the German
					Reformed Church of this place a short time ago. He is now confined in the
					Penitentiary at Baltimore, and we understand, will be delivered to the
					authorities here on the expiration of his term there."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Middlekauff</ln>
						<fn>Hiram D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wiles</ln>
						<fn>Lydia Ann</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Krebs</ln>
						<fn>W. E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 24th, Hiram D. Middlekauff, of Lettersburg, Md., and Lydia Ann
					Wiles were married by Rev. W. E. Krebs.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Gans</ln>
						<fn>George W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Pileington</ln>
						<fn>Jennie H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Thomas</ln>
						<fn>C. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 15th, George W. Gans, of Smithburg, Md., and Jennie H. Pileington
					were married by Rev. C. F. Thomas.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Agnew</ln>
						<fn>N. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ritchet</ln>
						<fn>Mary E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ferguson</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 15th, N. S. Agnew and Mary E. Ritchet were married by Rev.
					Ferguson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Eshleman</ln>
						<fn>Peter T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Royer</ln>
						<fn>Susan</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shank</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 3rd, Peter T. Eshleman and Susan Royer were married by Rev. John
					Shank.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Allen</ln>
						<fn>William A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Leisher</ln>
						<fn>Rebecca</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kunkleman</ln>
						<fn>J. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 22nd, William A. Allen and Rebecca Leisher were married by Rev. J.
					A. Kunkleman.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn>William H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Milet</ln>
						<fn>Susan</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kunkleman</ln>
						<fn>J. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 22nd, William H. Baker and Susan Milet were married by Rev. J. A.
					Kunkleman.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Detrich</ln>
						<fn>A. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sweigart</ln>
						<fn>Susanna</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bell</ln>
						<fn>P. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 8th, A. R. Detrich and Susanna Sweigart were married by Rev. P. G.
					Bell.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Horner</ln>
						<fn>John R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stenger</ln>
						<fn>Martha A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stenger</ln>
						<fn>P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hassler</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 22nd, John R. Horner, of Newville, Pa., and Martha A., daughter of
					P. Stenger, Esq., were married by Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shuman</ln>
						<fn>Phillip</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Speck</ln>
						<fn>Margaret Virginia</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duff</ln>
						<fn>E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 18th, Phillip Shuman and Margaret Virginia Speck were married by
					Rev. E. Duff.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Minehart</ln>
						<fn>Jacob S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wise</ln>
						<fn>Catherine</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duff</ln>
						<fn>E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Diefenhaugh</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 1st, Jacob S. Minehart and Catherine Wise were married by Rev. E.
					Duff. The ceremony took place at the residence of John Diefenhaugh.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Foust</ln>
						<fn>John A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Burkholder</ln>
						<fn>Carrie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duff</ln>
						<fn>E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 17th, John A. Foust and Carrie Burkholder were married by Rev. E.
					Duff.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Killinger</ln>
						<fn>Isaac</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bare</ln>
						<fn>Caroline</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duff</ln>
						<fn>E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 24th, Isaac Killinger and Caroline Bare were married by Rev. E.
					Duff.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Fole</ln>
						<fn>D. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Little</ln>
						<fn>Kate</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brown</ln>
						<fn>I. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 22nd, D. A. Fole and Kate Little were married by Rev. I. G. Brown.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Rhodes</ln>
						<fn>John M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kuhn</ln>
						<fn>Martha</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Davis</ln>
						<fn>P. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 24th, John M. Rhodes and Martha Kuhn were married by Rev. P. S.
					Davis.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Dufrield</ln>
						<fn>Mary</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 21st, Mary Dufrield, 57, died.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Zigler</ln>
						<fn>Martha</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Zigler</ln>
						<fn>Isaac</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Zigler</ln>
						<fn>Martha</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 6th, Sarah Martha, daughter of Isaac and Martha Zigler, died at age
					6 months.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Deifenbaugh</ln>
						<fn>Mary</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Deifenbaugh</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Deifenbaugh</ln>
						<fn>Jacob Brinton</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 7th, Jacob Brinton, son of John and Mary Deifenbaugh, died at age
					2.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Ditman</ln>
						<fn>Margaret</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 20th, Margaret Ditman, 71, died near Mercersburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Werner</ln>
						<fn>Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan. 24th, Elizabeth Werner, 50, died.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1867.01.30.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
