<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.06.03">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/08/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-06-03">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">3</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.06.03.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.06.03.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Only Issue Before the People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have waded through an ocean of stuff on this subject--we have tried to be
                        excited over the "Impeachment." We have exercised ourselves to get up a
                        "sensation" over the rumored "charges in the Cabinet" and the proposed lying
                        down of the "Lion and Lamb together"--the sweet bed of roses in which Andy
                        Johnson and Congress were to wallow in harmony and peace--"all for the good
                        of the country" &amp;c. in fact we have actually heard of the nomination
                        of Grant and Colfax for President and Vice President by the Radicals at
                        Chicago, upon a bitter radical platform, and still we are so apathetic as to
                        remain quiescent, and in this feeling we are so presumptuous as to believe a
                        majority of the people of the United States coincide with us.</p>
                    <p>What is the matter? Can't the people be roused? Are the freemen of America
                        lost to all feeling and is the Nation to rush madly to destruction and no
                        hand or voice be raised to check the rapidly speeding train of events? Thus
                        queries some imbecile, some poor weak creature who does not perceive, in the
                        present column, the gathering wrath of an outraged people.</p>
                    <p>The only issue now is:-- <emph rend="italic">Shall Constitutional
                            Government--shall the Government of Law and Right be perpetuated or
                            shall it go down!</emph></p>
                    <p>The Radical party say <emph rend="italic">that it shall</emph>--with their
                        platitudes about equal rights, "Union" &amp;c, they mean that it shall,
                        if they elect Grant and continue in power. Mr. Thad Stevens says boldly that
                        his party "is acting outside the Constitution"--outside and above the
                        written and unwritten law handed down to us by the proud and devoted fathers
                        and founders of this Republic. Stevens and his satraps are the soul and body
                        of that party and their word is law, or rather force to it, for law, nothing
                        they say can be called.--It is not the simple degradation or extermination
                        of the people of the conquered States--the equality--the citizenship--the
                        honored birthright of every American that is at stake. It is not the fate of
                        the 3,000,000 poor deluded negroes, less in number than the free Indians we
                        drove before us--it is the fate of 3,300,000 white Americans that hangs in
                        the balance. An All-wise and beneficent Creator--the Eternal and Everlasting
                        God, never gave a people such a heritage; nor did he ever place before them
                        such an issue--words fail in attempting to express it--only the heart of the
                        people, inspired by Him can.</p>
                    <p>But a solemn sense of duty, as public Journalists, a conscientious conviction
                        of what is right compels us to say what we think, and our judgment is based
                        upon a residence of years in both sections of our now distracted country.
                        The Democratic party--that is all the elements opposed to the rule and ruin
                        policy of the fanatical radical, meet in Convention in N.Y. July 4th, 1868.
                        That Convention will, if it does its duty, represent the mass of the law
                        abiding, God fearing people of this country, and a fearful responsibility
                        will rest upon its members. It is no holiday work; no old time party caucus;
                        no "cut and dried" political maneuvering that they will be called upon to
                        do. The fate of a people, for weal or woe,--the honor of the martyred dead,
                        on both sides hangs in the balance. It is, (words of solemn and awful
                        import).</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Shall Constitutional Government--shall the only
                            Government of Law and Right be perpetuated or shall it go down?</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>This is the only issue, and to accomplish the object of every honest man but
                        one thing is to be done. It is, <emph rend="italic">overthrow the party now
                            in power at the polls in November.</emph> Little side issues about
                        "Clemency," about "Impeachment," about "Reconstruction," about "Negroes,"
                            <emph rend="italic">it id omne genus,</emph> can be attended to
                        hereafter. The main question now--the only question--is to nominate the men
                        on the above ticket who can beat Grant and Colfax and who are for the
                        Constitution and the Law.--It matters not to the people whether they were
                        "war" or "peace" Democrats--whether "Whigs," "Rebels" or what not--all the
                        <del/> is the overthrow of that party of rule and ruin. The Southern people
                        care not--they will ever honor their dead and glory in their past--but they
                        want peace and their rights, <emph rend="italic">as free citizens of the
                            Republic.</emph> Free citizens of the North and West, will you drop your
                        prejudice and passion and do your duty or will you, like Sampson of old,
                        destroy yourselves and the Temple of our hopes?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article calls on all "free men of the Republic" to act against the
                    domination of the Radical party rather than be--unconstitutionally--acted upon.
                    The author demands unity of all sections against this one single issue:
                    Constitutional government of law and right. Issues regarding clemency,
                    Reconstruction and blacks should only be dealt with after the defeat of the
                    radical ticket in November. The most important thing is to first ensure the
                    defeat of Grant and Colfax in the presidential election. Only then, will
                    constitutional government survive throughout the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Conservative candidates Robert E. Withers, James A. Walker, John L. Marye,
                    Jr., Marmaduke Johnson, Coleman Yellott, and Shelton F. Leake will address a
                    mass meeting in Staunton on June 17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>To Work, Gentlemen, to Work!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The papers are working, calculating from Schofield's report and other
                        sources, which give the Conservatives 37,000 majority in the State. That
                        majority may be fooled away by "General Apathy" or Gen. Fool, as it was in
                        the election for delegates to the convention. Trust not to it, people of
                        Virginia, but recollect that "God helps those who help themselves." Work
                            <emph rend="italic">now</emph>--See every man in your neighborhood--make
                        him register and see that he votes <emph rend="italic">against</emph> the
                        Constitution and for our ticket the day of election.--You gentlemen of
                        property and influence in each and every neighborhood, you lawyers, doctors,
                        merchants, property-holders, in towns, and <sic>villiages</sic> must turn
                        out and work on election day. Your carriages, your horses, your wagons, your
                        presence and labor--everything must be used to bring honest, but poor white
                        men to the polls. If necessary you must pay for the support of their
                        families while they are absent from daily toil. It is work -- <emph
                            rend="italic">hard work and no striking at the price.</emph> Come down
                        to it now and save future <emph rend="italic">confiscation</emph> of all, by
                        a small sacrifice of time and money. If you leave the matter to the "boys"
                        as you did during the war and hug your "theories" to your beating hearts at
                        home, it may be that the "boys" may get up an "indifference" equal to your
                        own. Turn out, gentlemen, turn out! for God's sake and ours! This is a
                        "rough and tumble fight" and even a broad cloth coat and silk vest must be
                        soiled or we may all go down -- <emph rend="italic">property</emph> as well
                        as <emph rend="italic">life.</emph> "The devil is loose in this land." Help
                        us to catch him, is all the "boys" ask now. Is it too much?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author suggests all men of wealth lend their hands to defeating the
                    proposed constitution by enlisting the support of the poorer white citizens. To
                    do this, work must be done that will require the use of material items. The
                    principle concern is that if this work is not done, the poor white Virginians
                    will grow apathetic, not vote, and thus the radical constitution will be
                    ratified.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Difference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Southern people have great individuality of character. It is strongly
                        marked upon the constitution of the U.S., and of the States. Their education
                        and habits made them love the independence of the individual men and bend
                        their remarkable development of great master minds--rulers and leaders of
                        the people for years.--The yankees--we mean the Puritanic New Englanders
                        when we say yankee--are, and have always been, <emph rend="italic"
                        >machines</emph> --the concentrated embodiment of one idea, and <emph
                            rend="italic">that idea itself.</emph> They have worked together, and in
                        war the machine overcome the individual selfishness--force and concentration
                        upset the individual--the grand and generous but unsupported idea. Now that
                        slavery which gave power--gave strength to that individuality is gone
                        forever, it is not like the "play of Hamlet with Hamlet left out" for us to
                        longer contend single handed against this fearfully and wonderfully made
                        machine? Is it not sound sense to educate the enlarged, individual brain of
                        the Southern people, so as to adopt every good yankee idea and conquer them?
                        It strikes us that not only policy but sound sense, love of country,
                        pride--every feeling which should animate a patriot dictates this course.
                        When you engraft on Southern character, yankee energy, yankee idea of
                        detail, yankee devotion to material interest, still retaining the lovable
                        qualities of the Southerner, you have the people who are to rule this
                        continent.--Let us try it. The price is surely worth the sacrifice of
                        individual invalutism and prejudice.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The difference between the "Southern people" and "yankees" is noted here as
                    one of a machine like attention to energy, detail, and material advancement. The
                    author suggests that southern men of greater character and mind adopt the yankee
                    ideas and incorporate them. When this occurs, southern men will rule the
                    continent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Word to Union Men</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reaches out to Augusta's unionists and encourages them to join
                    ex-confederates in voting down the new state constitution. "If you vote with the
                    deluded negroes and white scalawags prepare to be classed with them and don't
                    complain."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.06.03.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Confederate Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains that some of the bones of Confederate dead removed from
                    Gordonsville have been lying exposed in Staunton's station since last September.
                    The paper urges the Ladies' Memorial Association, who had allegedly raised
                    enough money to bury the remains, to do something about the situation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harry</ln>
                        <fn>David G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David G. Harry died in Staunton of paralysis at age 61.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.06.03.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
