<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.04.01">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-04-01">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">1</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.01.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.01.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Position Then and Now</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A valued friend and subscriber, who agreed with <del/> opposition to the
                        Constitution to be submitted with our advocacy of the call for a Convention
                        which framed it."</p>
                    <p> The answer is simple. We advocated the acceptance of the Convention as a
                            <emph rend="italic">terrible fact,</emph> as we did submission to Andy
                        Johnson's plans, considering and knowing both to be unconstitutional and
                        unjust but feeling it was the best we could do, powerless as we were to
                        accept the first radical plan <emph rend="italic">as a finality</emph> as we
                        did Johnson's. We were for fighting the devil with his own firewood, i.e.,
                        taking hold of the Reconstruction measures, and using them against the
                        Radicals. We were for electing a Conservative Convention to meet in
                        Richmond, which we would have acted in concert with the Conservatives North,
                            <emph rend="italic">not</emph> the hybred [sic] concern, which acts in
                        concert with our enemies there; and we believe it could have been done, if
                        the people had thrown off their indifference and <emph rend="italic"
                        >worked.</emph> To admit any other proposition is an insult to the
                        intelligence of the white people of Virginia. Just before the election, we
                        saw there was no hope for such action, as the Radicals were fighting our
                        straggling bands with disciplined forces, and we did all we could to defeat
                        the Convention and elect Conservative candidates. We know that there was no
                        premise of the Radicals to be relied upon; that it was a hellish scheme to
                        negroize the South, and we have always opposed the whole work of the mean
                        whites and <emph rend="italic">deluded blacks,</emph> at Richmond, because
                        it is infamous; a violation of every pledge made by the North during and
                        since the war, and because we are white. This, we think, is the position of
                        every paper and of every gentleman in the State, who went for accepting the
                        Radical plan, <emph rend="italic">as a finality,</emph> until they saw there
                        was nothing <emph rend="italic">final</emph> in it, but our absolute
                        subjugation to negro and radical rule. Some imbecile, may whine, "I told you
                        so," about his "coassistency," and say we are changeable, but we are not,
                        for we had rather be <emph rend="italic">"right"</emph> than <emph
                            rend="italic"> "consistent,"</emph> and <emph rend="italic">
                        "right"</emph> we honestly believe we were and are.</p>
                    <p>We hope the explanation is satisfactory, and that our friends will join with
                        us, heart and hand, in defeating the Radical Constitution. It is no time for
                            <emph rend="italic">white men</emph> to wrangle over "consistency," or
                        who was right and who was wrong. Old John Randolph once said that the men
                        who bellowed most about "consistency" were either knaves or fools or a
                        combination of both, and we agree with him. Therefore, waste no time on
                        them, but go to work and vote down the Radical Convention; for to discern
                        between the evils that energy can remove and the evils that patience must
                        bear, makes the difference between manliness and childishness - between good
                        sense and folly.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article seeks to dismiss the arguments made between whites of the
                    South regarding "consistency." This argument, suggests the author, is
                    counterproductive. The important issue is to rid Richmond of "negro rule," and
                    defeat the Radical constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>How to Turn the Tables</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For sixty years, says the Whig, Southern influence dominated the government.
                        We worked in the field of politics while the Northern people devoted
                        themselves to their industries. They grew rich and strong; and so the power
                        passed from our hands; the scepter departed from Judah, and the law giver
                        from beneath his feet.</p>
                    <p>We want to see the tables turned. The Northern people seem now to be demented
                        on the subject of politics. They have tasted power, and are intoxicated by
                        the draught. Not only the men, but the women and children are politicians.
                        It is time for us to quit the political field and employ our energies
                        elsewhere. We are outnumbered and overmastered, and our only hope of
                        acquiring wealth, influence and power, and measuring strength with them
                        again, is in devoting ourselves to our material industries. This was the
                        source of Northern wealth and power. We died by politics, while they
                        flourished by industry. Let us be warned by our fate and encouraged by their
                        success.</p>
                    <p>We have at present but one great political duty to perform, and that is to do
                        all that we can to rescue ourselves and our posterity from negro rule. Doing
                        that, we should give our time and attention to our material interests, and
                        after a while we shall reassert our sway and hold it by force of numbers as
                        well as of intellect. The secret of empire in these days is force, not moral
                        power or mind. Let us while holding on to those endeavors to accrue
                    that.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article suggests that southerners "quit the political field and employ
                    energies elsewhere." The problem, says the author, is that while southerners
                    dominated the government for years, northerners focused on industry. From this
                    they gained wealth and power and came to dominate the country. The great
                    political duty for southerners now is to focus on material interests.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper endorses Henry Wise's railroad boosterism and praises A. H. H.
                    Stuart and Col. John B. Baldwin for taking the same position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>T. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain T. P. Jackson, agent of the Freedman's Bureau for Augusta and
                    Highland Counties, has been promoted and asked to report at Farmville. "We knew
                    Captain J. personally, and a more perfect gentleman we have never met. In the
                    discharge of his duties he always gave satisfaction, and we cordially recommend
                    him to the good people of Farmville."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.01.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Growing Wheat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The wheat crop is reportedly doing very well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>White Sulphur</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. George L. Peyton has leased the Greenbriar, White Sulphur Springs for
                    $10,000 a year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>More than 70 buildings are under contract in Staunton, and construction
                    waits only for good weather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Staunton boasts more than 150 businesses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the Episcopal Church will give a fair at the dining hall of
                    the Virginia Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Fire Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The members of the Augusta Fire Company have established their library and
                    ask for donations of books.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.01.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
