<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.03.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-03-04">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.04.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The excitement at Washington seems to be subsiding. Matters relative to
                        impeachment, stand pretty much in statuquo.</p>
                    <p>Some of the leading Radicals declare that in less than two months the
                        President will be impeached and removed; when Ben Wade of Ohio will be
                        President; a man whom the Conservatives of Ohio have consigned to oblivion,
                        in the late election, and whose place is to be filled in the U.S. Senate by
                        that sterling Democrat Judge Thurman.</p>
                    <p>The "office tenure bill," which has passed for the purpose of tying the hands
                        of President Johnson, and giving the Senate the control of all his
                        appointments fails to teach Stanton. The bill was intended to disarm the
                        President, but as applies only to appointments made by the President and as
                        such coming under the purview of the Senate and Stanton not being an
                        appointment of President Johnson, but of Lincoln, the office tenure bill
                        does not save Stanton and completely giving Mr. Johnson the <unclear>under
                            tract.</unclear> It is now doubtful whether the President will be
                        impeached at all. Stanton it is thought will resign by June and thus avoid
                        as he does his trial, involving a quo warrento. It is thought the President
                        will stand <emph rend="italic">firm.</emph> He is managing his card so as to
                        set his policy by the Supreme Court, and thus arm him for the great issue by
                        the people at the Ballot Box.</p>
                    <p>There is no prospect for a fight. Yankees fighting Yankees is one thing, and
                        their fighting poor Rebs is another. They will bluster a little, but there
                        will be no fight. Our duty is plain. It is an affair of their own, a fight
                        amongst the Republicans. Radicals on the one hand and Conservatives on the
                        other. The "Rule or ruin" policy of the Radicals we trust will "not
                        prevail." Our sympathies are with the President so far as he <del/> preserve
                        the Constitution, and thus save what is left of Constitutional Liberty.</p>
                    <p>We hope for the best and belong to the class of the hopeful - we don't
                        despair. The people of the North have too much at stake. It will cost them
                        millions and billions to maintain Radical ascendancy and Radical rule; and
                        also the loss of their Liberties and the downfall of a white man's
                        government. Every negro vote in the ten former Slave States of the South,
                        will be equal to the same number of white votes in the North. It is a
                        question for the North to decide - not for us - we are powerless now, and
                        will remain so until the Conservatives of the North shall break the shackles
                        which negroocracy has placed upon our limbs. We must in the meantime develop
                        our resources, and take care of out State and municipal governments as best
                        we can. Continue to labor - "we will hope for the best."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Focusing on the possibility of the impeachment of President Johnson, the
                    author suggests that it is now unlikely. The Radical wing of the party has
                    squared off against its more moderate members insisting that the "tenure of
                    office" bill restricts Johnson's actions. The author predicts that cooler heads
                    in the North will realize the loss of liberties that this battle between
                    Republican factions implies. If Radical rule prevails, it could mean the
                    downfall of a white man's government. Since the South is powerless, southerners
                    should concentrate on developing resources while northerners decide this
                    pressing question.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Southall</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James C. Southall, convention delegate for the district including Augusta,
                    delivered a speech in favor of the minority report of the convention on the
                    elective franchise, "which is worthy of the better days of this noble and
                    beloved ol State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Thespians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Thespians will perform the Dumas tragedy "Catherine Howard, or the
                    Bride of Death."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dramatic Reading</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Scharf, formerly of the University of Virginia, will give a dramatic
                    reading in the Town Hall of Sheridan's comedy entitled "The Rivals."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Wheat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Shenandoah Valley flour is ranked first in Baltimore markets. "Virginia
                    Valley Red" is selling at $2.85, above flour from Pennsylvania and Maryland.
                    Baltimore merchants have declared Valley Family and Extra Flour the best that
                    reaches the city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silling</ln>
                        <fn>Kenney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Three daring robbers stole $35 and as much as $100 in gold from Kenney
                    Silling at his home near Parnassus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lost Confederate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barrow</ln>
                        <fn>Johnny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper advertises for people seeking information on Johnny Barrow, a 10
                    year old boy picked up by a Confederate soldier in the lines near Richmond. He
                    served as an orderly for a General, and supposedly has a grandfather living in
                    Frederick COunty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Merged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Augenbright</ln>
                        <fn>T. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. N. Augenbright of the Spectator and Miss Virginia Hopkins, daughter of
                    Dr. S. D. Hopkins formerly of Albermarle, were married in the Staunton home of
                    the bride's father on February 26th by the Rev. John L. Clarke. The paper wishes
                    the couple well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel M. Woodward of Staunton and Miss Virginia Arnall ("not Miss Gussie
                    as appeared last week"), daughter of Mr. John T. Arnall, were married at the
                    Staunton residence of the bride's father on February 25th by the Rev. William E.
                    Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tutwiler</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Susan A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Tutwiler and Miss Susan A. Wright, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Naked Creek at the residence of the bride's father, Joseph W. Wright, on
                    February 20th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earhart</ln>
                        <fn>Clement H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>Minerva A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Clement H. Earhart and Miss Minerva A. Landes, daughter of David Landes,
                    were married on February 20th by the Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Livick</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Susan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Livick and Miss Susan M. Spitler, both of Augusta, were married
                    on February 27th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Hanger married Miss Mary H. Eidson, both of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
