<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.07.01">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/08/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-07-01">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">1</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.07.01.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Striking View of Reconstruction in Virginia</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>J. Randolph Tucker writes to argue that while he believes all the
                    reconstruction acts are unconstitutional, Congress's actions toward Virginia are
                    especially unlawful. Congress, the President, and the Supreme Court had all
                    recognized the legitimate state government of Virginia at the end of the war,
                    and by including that state in the reconstruction acts, Congress in effect
                    overthrew a sitting state government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.07.01.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Situation--Politically and Otherwise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The busy hum of the "Reapers," the glad shouts of the harvest bands, as they
                        reap the rewards of labor well performed--the hard earned wages that come
                        only "by the sweat of the brow"--precludes the necessity of long editorials.
                        "The laborer is worthy of his hire," and all classes, South and North are
                        now being paid off by a merciful Providence. Things look brighter than at
                        any time since the war, politically as well as pecuniarily--and the poor,
                        oppressed South begins to see the "silver lining" to the "cloud" of her
                        troubles.</p>
                    <p> There is every indication that no election will be held in Virginia, but we
                        must keep up the good work of Conservative organization. The "scallawags"
                        know they will be defeated at a fair election, as they were in glorious old
                        Mississippi--they know that any Legislature elected would continue the "stay
                        law," which expires in January, 1868, and they want <emph rend="italic"
                            >cheap lands in Virginia.</emph> Therefore, there will be no election,
                        and the "scallawags" might as well clear out. We will soon be "out of the
                        woods!" restored to the Union, with all our rights as <emph rend="italic"
                            >white</emph> men, Virginians and freemen!</p>
                    <p>The voice of an outraged and indignant people will be expressed next
                        Saturday, July 4th, by the National Democratic Convention. The old
                        Democratic party, united and all-powerful, aided by all the Conservative
                        elements of the country, can but nominate a candidate representing the great
                        re-action against tyranny and wrong inflicted on the country by the Radical
                        Revolutionists.--Who he may be the Omnipotent alone can know; but we may
                        have faith in the party and the people! Be of good cheer and work, for a
                        better day is coming, ye Southern people! There are voices in the air; there
                        are undefined feelings in our heart; there is a "heart-boat" in every
                        pulsation, which speaks to us sand says--"Victory is ours! the <emph
                            rend="italic">right</emph> must conquer!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "situation" in this article is one of hope. Although radicals have
                    caused numerous problems, hard work and organization on the part of the
                    conservative element--from all sections--is proving effective. Soon,
                    particularly after the upcoming Democratic Convention, conservatives will once
                    again be in power in Virginia, and any "scalawags" will have to make haste away
                    from the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>City Council--June Session</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echelberger</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herr</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The June session of the City Council met, Mayor Trout presiding. A. T.
                    Maupin, Schofield's appointee to replace James W. Crawford was sworn in. A tax
                    ordinance expected to raise $18,000 was passed. It was decided that anyone
                    swearing, getting drunk, or committing assault and battery in town will be fined
                    no less than one, nor more than ten, dollars. The Street Commissioners were
                    ordered to pave the sidewalk from Job Turner's house to the Deaf, Dumb and Blind
                    Institute, with property holders and the Institute paying to McAdamize the
                    street. Schofield appointees Henry S. Echelberger and W. L. Herr appeared as
                    Aldermen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Schools. Commencement Exercises</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints accounts of the commencement exercises of the Virginia
                    Female Institute, the Wesleyan Female Institute, the Augusta Female Seminary,
                    and the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.07.01.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Cowan has raised $300 for the Soldier's Cemetery and Orphan Fund. The
                    paper urges citizens to pledge and pay money. "These poor neglected boys died
                    for you!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Ho For the Mountains!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>3,434 travellers have arrived at Staunton hotels since May 1st, including
                    1,980 in June alone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Western Lunatic Asylum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Western Lunatic Asylum receives visitors from 9am to 12pm and 3 to 5pm.
                    The paper reminds readers that the asylum is "a charitable institution, not a
                    menagerie" and begs that everyone follow the rules of the house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that the final exercises of the many female schools of
                    Augusta are a good "index of the increasing prosperity of our people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Staunton and Danville</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sublett</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Staunton ships a large amount of grain to Danville,
                    and commission merchant P. B. Sublett has orders for several thousand bushels of
                    corn. The many mechanics who have moved to Staunton from Southside are a good
                    indication of the relative strength of local economies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Sue E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. F. Hite and Miss Sue E. Wilson, both of Augusta, were married on June
                    24th by the Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGinty</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>M. Jinnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert A. McGinty and Miss M. Jinnie Jones, both of Augusta, were married
                    on June 16th by the Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Myers, wife of Rev. Hiram Myers, died in Waynesboro of
                    asthma on June 17th. She had reached "an advanced age."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Posey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hancock</ln>
                        <fn>O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Posey drowned while bathing at the landing of O. Hancock on Stony
                    Creek. He was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Willie R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Martha A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie R. Myers, infant son of Franklin H. and Martha A. Myers, died last
                    June in Augusta County. He was 1 year old. A poem of grief accompanies the
                    obituary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.07.01.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
