<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.01.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/03/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-01-08">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.01.08.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Pen and Ink Sketches of the Living and the Dead--Exodus From Richmond--The
                    Capture of Mr. Davis--Dahlgren's Raid Upon Richmond--General R. E. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of the last days of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>A Negro Opinion of White Radicals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper jokes that African Americans are refusing to enthusiastically
                    join the radicals because they are hostile to the "white trash" element in the
                    party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.01.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. R. Crockwell announces that Maj. A. M. Garber, Jr., has taken entire
                    control of the Valley Virginian Editorial Department. He is responsible for
                    everything that appears on the editorial page.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Only a Word or So</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The present condition of the Southern people, the wonderful capacity for
                        governing shown by gentlemen who nobly stood by the country, while "foolish
                        boys," <emph rend="italic">deserted it</emph>, and got killed, wounded or
                        robbed in the Confederate States service forces us to think of <lb/>"The
                        perils which do environ,<lb/>The men who meddle with cold iron." And then of
                        the trials beset those left to struggle for existence, against the "life
                        tenure in office," the taxation, the power for wrong, the Military Bills
                        give such men as Pierpont and other "mean whites," to say nothing of
                        negroes, poor creatures, who these agents of Satan have been, and are still,
                        leading a "Devil's own dance" to death and destruction.</p>
                    <p>It was hard for 8,700 Southern soldiers to surrender to 150,000 brave
                        Yankees, at Appamattox [sic], but to daily see the terms of surrender
                        broken; to have all the filth of the North; all the camp followers,
                        "scavengers," "bounty jumpers," of the Army, together with the scum of
                        Southern loyalty so called, poured out upon an unfortunate but noble people,
                        by Radical venom and hatred, is almost too much.</p>
                    <p>"How long, oh! Lord, how long? Are this sorely tired people to be be-deviled,
                        persecuted and swindled by this infamous gang of scoundrels, who prey upon
                        us like the "locusts of Egypt," and disgrace even the negroes they associate
                        with. Decent white men North, brave soldiers who honestly fought against us,
                        answer, and give us the chance to live <emph rend="italic">your honor was
                            pledged for</emph>at Appomattox.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article describes the situation in Virginia under radical rule. The
                    radicals, referred to as "agents of Satan" impose unfair taxation and use blacks
                    against their former masters. This article is a call to the men of the North to
                    honor the terms of surrender and remove radicals and others vindictive whites
                    from office in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>In Memoriam</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper mourns the loss of Gen. Kenton Harper, who it declares one of
                    Augusta's "most honored, loved and respected citizens." "We would write more but
                    the sad memory of the 'loved and lost' who served with Gen. Harper; the
                    recollections of his many acts of kindness to us, causes feelings beyond our
                    powers of expression."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Richmond voted a $2,000,000 subscription to the
                    stock of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company. "Certainly Augusta, richer
                    than Richmond, can vote $300,000."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Chesapeake and Ohio Subscription in the Counties</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article stressing the importance of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad to the
                    future prosperity of Virginia. The author points out several prominent Augusta
                    citizens who support it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Death of Gen. Harper</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice mourning the death of General Kenton Harper as a loss to all
                    Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Death of a Well-known Virginian</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Obituary and short biography of the late General Kenton Harper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.01.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. J. C. Covell will lecture before the Staunton Lyceum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Aid for the Deserving</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper endorses plans to found a Mechanic's and Working-man's Loan
                    Association in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Christmas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the streets of Staunton were crowded with
                    pleasure-seekers on Christmas Day. No fights were reported, and only a few
                    quarrels and "accidently drunks."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>City Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Council met January 4th, 1868. N. K. Trout, Mayor, presided. All present
                        except Crawford, Hope, Points, and Bickle, (sick.) The Mayor presented the
                        bond of Dr. A. M. Atkinson for payment on Market House and lot, which was
                        approved. The interest on the public debt of the city, amounting to $29,860
                        was allowed and the Treasurer ordered to pay same. The usual accounts for
                        preceding month were allowed. The account of Major Jed Hotchkiss, for
                        services as city Engineer, was not allowed, because it was not certified to
                        by Commissioners of Streets. A proposition to open a subscription of $50,000
                        by the city of Staunton to the stock of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad
                        Company was laid over for consideration at next meeting. It was ordered that
                        all accounts allowed by the Council, for sums under five dollars, shall be
                        paid hereafter by the Chief of Police, on the certificate of the clerk of
                        Council. Mr. Evans submitted an ordinance requiring owners of property,
                        fronting improved streets, to clean the snow from their sidewalks. Rejected
                        by a vote of 5 to 3. The Overseer of the Poor was authorized to employ a
                        city Physician for the poor, at a compensation of $30 per annum. (As the
                        competition for this office and salary will be very great, we advise
                        aspirants to make early application to Mr. Bunch, O. P.) True Council,
                        painfully impressed with the magnitude and importance of the labor performed
                        and, no doubt, hearing the horrifying rumor concerning Brig. Gen-Governor
                        Schofield's intention to order an election for city officers shortly,
                        adjourned to meet, if allowed, the 1st Saturday in February.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The January session of the City Council met, N. K. Trout presiding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Report of a Meeting at Hall's School-house, the 28th of December, 1867.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Whereas, the Congress of the United States have required a Convention to be
                        called in the State of Virginia for the purpose of creating a Constitution
                        of the State,</p>
                    <p>And whereas, from the action which has been taken by similar Conventions
                        which have been held in other Southern States, there are good grounds to
                        apprehend that the Virginia Convention now in session, may recommend to the
                        people a Constitution which will bring the State under control of the negro
                        race;</p>
                    <p>And whereas, in the opinion of this association, such a result would be most
                        disastrous to the best interest of the State, by transferring the political
                        power of the State to the most portion of its population, and ultimately
                        burthening the land and property of the people with enormous taxation,
                        imposed by those who would own but a small portion of the property of the
                        State, therefore</p>
                    <p>1st Be it resolved that, in the event of the adoption of such a Constitution
                        by the Convention, we pledge ourselves to each other, and to our fellow
                        citizens generally, to make every fair and honorable effort to defeat the
                        ratification of such constitution by the people; and to that end we will not
                        only vote against its ratification ourselves, but we will diligently exert
                        ourselves to induce every voter in our respective neighborhoods to attend
                        the polls and record their votes against it.</p>
                    <p>2nd Resolved, that we will cherish the kindest feelings toward the freedmen,
                        taking care to explain to him how his best interest will be promoted by
                        cultivating friendly relationship with the people with whom they live.</p>
                    <p>3d. Resolved, that our great aim should be to escape negro supremacy in the
                        State, and that we will exert ourselves to the utmost extent of our power
                        and influence to save ourselves and our race from this calamity and
                        disgrace.</p>
                    <p>On motion, the Chairman appointed leaders of tens whose duty it shall be to
                        obtain signers to the above.</p>
                    <p>The following gentlemen were then appointed, to wit: J.S. Ellis, B.F.
                        Cochran, Alex Coiner, G. Herman, Capt. C. G. Miller, George Nihergall and
                        David Rankin, Jr.</p>
                    <p>M. B. Coalter, Secretary</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitch</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herman</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nihergall</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coalter</ln>
                        <fn>M. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At a schoolhouse meeting, the speaker warns of the dangers inherent in a
                    new Constitution. The principle fear is that Radicals will shift power into the
                    hands of the black citizens of Virginia, thereby creating an unfair
                    representation by those with the least property. This will in turn create
                    problems regarding race relations between property holders and their former
                    bondsmen. Overall, this speech warns that Conservative white citizens will go to
                    any measure to avoid the "disgrace" of "Negro rule."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Toole</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Fr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Patrick O'Toole and Miss Kate Collins, daughter of the late Richard Collins
                    of Staunton, were married in St. Francis Church, Staunton, by Father Weed on
                    December 31st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donovan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Fr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Donovan and Miss Mary Scherer, daughter of John B. Scherer of
                    Staunton, were married in St. Francis Church, Staunton, by Father Weed on
                    December 31st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>G. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Ida C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Noah B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. G. M. King of Waynesboro and Miss Ida C. Campbell, daughter of J. L.
                    Campbell of Charles City County, were married on December 18th by the Rev. Noah
                    B. Price.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryant</ln>
                        <fn>Charles P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Busey</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles P. Bryant and Miss Amanda C. Burkholder of Augusta were married on
                    December 31st by the Rev. E. F. Busey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiflet</ln>
                        <fn>S. M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. M. D. Shiflet of Augusta and Miss Sarah Armentrout of Rockingham were
                    married on December 26th by the Rev. Mr. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherman</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>L. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. F. Sherman and Miss L. M. Miller, both of Augusta, were married on
                    December 26th by the Rev. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Rhoda L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. D. Wood, of Albemarle and Miss Rhoda L. Brown of Augusta were married on
                    December 18th by the Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolen</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James F. Davis and Miss Rebecca J. Bolen were married on December 30th by
                    the Rev. W. F. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Martha R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Martha R. Bledsoe, wife of Thomas A. Bledsoe, died in Staunton on
                    January 3rd. She was 32 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.01.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
