<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.12.03">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/11/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-12-03">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="11">December</month>
            <day norm="">3</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.12.03.01" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad--A County Investment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> It is in the pecuniary interest of Augusta, <emph rend="italic">as a
                            [unclear] county bargain,</emph> to vote the subscription to the Valley
                        Railroad--for--</p>
                    <p> 1st. The Engineers estimate for the <emph rend="italic">cost of
                        construction</emph> of the road through the county is about $1,200,000. The
                        most of this large sum of money will be expended in, and will remain in the
                        county, for it will be paid out for the cost of materials bridging, cross
                        ties, &amp;c, and for subsistence to the many laborers engaged in the
                        work; thus furnishing a <emph rend="italic">home market</emph> (that best of
                        all markets because <emph rend="italic">costing less to the
                        producer</emph>,) for many productions of the county that cost little to
                        produce, and would otherwise perish on hand for want of any market--such as
                        fruits, vegetables and poultry. One million dollars added to our circulation
                        would vastly stimulate industry, pay off many debts, and awaken universal
                        enterprise.</p>
                    <p> 2. The building of this road to cross <emph rend="italic">in our
                        county,</emph> the great Chesapeake and Ohio road, would establish Augusta
                        as the centre--"the hub"--around which would revolve all the great
                        industrial, commercial, and social movement and excitement of the State.
                        Such a crossing within this county, as it must be, would be, necessarily,
                        the only point anywhere <emph rend="italic">at once on both</emph> of these
                        two greatest national thoroughfares from East to West, and from North to
                        South, and would give to the county the advantage of either for its uses,
                        and <emph rend="italic">the competition between both.</emph> Thus we would
                        command, always, the very best market, and at the same time, the cheapest
                        transportation to reach it.</p>
                    <p> 3rd. The foregoing facts would <emph rend="italic">induce immigration at
                            once,</emph> to purchase our surplus lands, and thus furnish that <emph
                            rend="italic">prompt relief</emph> we now so much need, in our present
                        impoverishment, to work to advantage the rich lands of our county. There are
                        thousands at the South--of its best people, longing to take refuge in just
                        such a land as this, and only awaiting this certain omen of our future
                        prosperity; there are thousands in the North already attracted by the
                        wonderful natural advantages of this Valley, and only awaiting this
                        artificial improvement to be added in thus furnishing <emph rend="italic"
                            >access to the best markets, at competition rates of
                        transportation.</emph> Our unrivaled climate, healthful homes, orderly
                        population, fertile fields, exhaustless iron ore, and unlimited water power,
                        will make our Valley the garden of the world.</p>
                    <p> 4th. With these foregoing advantages the county investments in the stock of
                        the Valley Railroad, would be a good <emph rend="italic">money
                        operation,</emph> and help to lighten our county taxation. The history of
                        similar roads shows that the stock would, in the first place pay all the
                        interest of its cost by dividends, and soon also command a premium on its
                        original cost; thus the Baltimore and Ohio road stock now sells for TWENTY
                        PER CENT ADVANCE ON ITS COST to the city--besides the incidental good it did
                        in building up a great city. It is thus a speculation for the tax payers.
                        Augusta, then, by voting this tax would gain all the advantages of this
                        great road, and besides that would in a few years repay its cost in
                        dividends on the stock, and sell the stock itself at a large advance on its
                        original cost. In other words--long before the principle of the County bonds
                        paid for the stock becomes due--the dividends will pay all the interest on
                        the bonds without necessity for taxation, and a sale of the stock will pay
                        all the cost of the subscription for it, and a large surplus besides.</p>
                    <p> The Engineer's report shows that this route of the Valley Railroad will be
                        absolutely so much better as a route to the West than the present route of
                        the Baltimore and Ohio road--considering its better grades, shorter
                        distance, and better climate--that it "must become the MAIN ITEM" of that
                        great road--and if that route pays a premium of 20 <emph rend="italic">per
                            cent.</emph> on its original stock, still more may we presume that this
                            <emph rend="italic">Valley route</emph> will surely and speedily do the
                        same. Let every true citizen of this grand old County see to it, that this
                        great and golden opportunity in her history is not neglected, and possibly
                        lost forever.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Author takes great care in promoting the subscription of a Valley
                    Railroad. His argument primarily centers on the financial rewards expected from
                    any investments. Also, a railroad would make Augusta County a "hub" of economic
                    traffic, would encourage further investment from outside the county, and
                    naturally increase the population of the area. All of these things would not
                    only boost Augusta's economy but also secure the national prominence of the
                    county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Freedmen's Bureau</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that General Howard has ordered the discontinuance of
                    the Freedmen's Bureau. Only the educational department and agents for the
                    collection and payment of money due those in US military service will remain in
                    operation. The state of Virginia will retain one assistant commissioner and
                    chief superintendent of schools, one disbursing officer for the educational
                    department and payment of bounties, one to four assistant superintendents of
                    schools, one to five agents for the payment of bounties, and one to three
                    clerks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Associated Capital and Energy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Individualism in our Southern people is a great bar to their progress in
                        material things. This feature was stamped upon our character by and under
                        the old plantation system, when every plantation was a small principality
                        within itself, with its lord and its hereditary serfs or slaves. But a
                        change of circumstances has been wrought by the results of the war, and new
                        ideas must supervene upon the old, else we shall stand still, or rather (as
                        under the laws of nature to stand still is impossible) go backward.</p>
                    <p>We must learn the old lesson that there is <emph rend="italic">strength in
                            unity</emph>; and not only learn it but <emph rend="italic"
                        >practice</emph> it, if we would get the full benefit of what we are doing.
                        By dividing up our capital and energy, instead of combining them, we become
                        a prey to larger capital, and to combinations which may be formed against
                        us. Take a bundle of rods, separate them, and a child may break them, but
                        put them together, and they may defy the strength of a giant.</p>
                    <p>There is economy, too, in unity, as well as in strength. Separate concerns
                        are each often run at nearly as great an expense as the whole would be if
                        combined. We can hardly better illustrate our idea than by the usual
                        combinations to be seen in it. There we see a variety of machinery and but
                        one engine and one engineer. Give an engine and engineer to each machine,
                        and we see at once the waste of power and extravagant cost of running. Just
                        so of many pursuits requiring capital as a motive power, and skill to apply
                        and control it. We must learn the value of association and combination in
                        our enterprises and pursuits, both small and great, or we shall "waste our
                        strength for that which is nought."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that southerners must overcome their individualism bred by
                    the plantation system and combine their energy and capital in unified industrial
                    pursuits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.12.03.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Times</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "times are hard and money tight--something unusual
                    for Staunton."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>V. R. R. Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. H. H. Stuart and others will speak in favor of the Valley Railroad
                    subscriptions at a mass meeting in Staunton tomorrow night. A meeting in
                    Waynesboro will be held at the same time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of Staunton have invited A. H. H. Stuart, Col. J. B. Baldwin,
                    and M. G. Harman to address them on the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Matrimonial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the "matrimonial market" is "dull" in Martinsburg
                    and Staunton, but going at a "rush" in Rockingham and Shenandoah.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Christmas Toys</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Mag</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mag Cease is carrying a large number of Christmas toys, including wagons,
                    dolls, cakes, and candies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Niggardly Theft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> On Saturday night last two "niggers,"--one of them with a <emph
                            rend="italic">white</emph> skin--broke a glass in the window of the
                        little shebang above our office on New street, extracted
                        <sic>therefrom</sic> a couple of jars containing candy, were caught in the
                        act, could not prove they broke the window, and were set at liberty. It came
                        very near being a bitter-sweet to them. They hailed from the rural
                        districts, in the mountains.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This notice reporting a break-in and theft assumes the guilt of a black man
                    and a white man. Although they were supposedly "caught in the act," they were
                    set free due to lack of proof. The author emphasizes that these men were not
                    local.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Christian Generosity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of gentlemen of Staunton established a fund to benefit those who
                    suffered losses in the recent fire. P. B. Hoge, although he lost heavily,
                    donated money in favor of Robert Johnson, who lost everything. "Mr. Hoge can but
                    receive the highest commendations of his fellow men, and the liberal donors the
                    consciousness of having done a humane act, in thus contributing their tithe to
                    the wants of the sufferer--an old and worthy citizen, who has seen the frosts of
                    seventy off winters."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Destructive Fire--Loss of About $10,000</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. Byron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The cabinet maker shop of E. F. Johnson on Gospel Hill caught fire from an
                    old sheet iron stove. The flames quickly spread, burning down another building
                    and the residence of P. Byron Hoge. The fire company was able to stop the spread
                    of the conflagration to the home of D. A. Kayser. Mr. Hoge's loss is estimated
                    at $6,000 and Mr. Johnson's $4,000. Neither had insurance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Webb</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McComb</ln>
                        <fn>Susan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob F. Webb and Miss Susan M. McComb, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Barterbrook on November 26th by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lipscomb</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Lipscomb and Miss Cornelia C. Hunter, both of Augusta, were married
                    at the residence of John N. Hunter on November 24th by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Emma V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Miller and Miss Emma V. Beard, both of Augusta, were married at New
                    Hope on November 22nd by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weade</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Ella F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Weade and Miss Ella F. Davis, both of Augusta, were married at the
                    residence of the bride's mother on November 19th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arey</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>Lou C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Arey and Miss Lou C. Wheeler, both of Augusta, were married at the
                    residence of the bride's father on November 18th by the Rev. Thomas E. Carson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shields</ln>
                        <fn>Abbie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grobarger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Abbie Shields died of paralysis at the residence of George Grobarger,
                    near Greenville, on November 7th. She was 83 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Caperton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Caperton Echols, infant daughter of Gen. John Echols, died in Staunton
                    on November 30th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.12.03.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
