<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.04.15">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-04-15">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">15</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.15.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Make Home Pleasant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Among all our acquaintances, scarcely a half dozen standing at the head of
                        families seem to appreciate the moral bearing of the right sort of home and
                        the high influences which come from them. Home to a good many men is the
                        place wherein to eat, and sleep, and loll, and snarl, and order children
                        about, and put into practice generally small views of the rights of a
                        husband and father. And then, something higher than these, stand a more
                        intelligent and genial class who have a warm, social side, and are void of
                        tyranny, and cherish every noble hope for their children, and yet do not
                        quite see that home and its influences should be the main thing in the
                        thoughts and plans of every father, instead of being held greatly
                        subordinate to business and politics, and outdoor pleasure. To provide
                        abundantly and keep the house warm in cold times, and send the young ones to
                        school punctually and have family prayers once or twice a day are not all
                        the things that need doing, but home should be made a really bright and
                        happy place in every way. It should meet the wants of the whole nature of
                        the young. Festivals should be instituted. Returning birthdays should be
                        emphasized and made memorable. Little expeditions of the household to this
                        place and that should be planned. The right kind of books should be sought
                        and read, and talked over together. Indeed, scarcely anything helps a home
                        so much as general and cheerful conversation. Music should be brought in.
                        The taste of the children should be cultivated. - Decorations are excellent
                        in a merely moral view. Flowers and greenery should be made to assist in the
                        general culture. And if time is consumed and some money spent on these
                        things, there is no folly in it, but the best wisdom. For boys and girls are
                        blessedly guarded when they find all their faculties well met and exercised
                        at home. they do not care to roam, and so they are detained from a thousand
                        outside dangers. Their passions are kept quiet. They lie open to celestial
                        influences. Tis easy, comparatively, for such to be christians. Indeed, we
                        expect them to be Solomon's "train up a child" &amp;c, is likely to be
                        fulfilled in their case. - Tippling houses do not draw their pay from youth
                        who have been made to love their homes heartily. Wayward girls are bred in
                        unhappy homes. The mixed Christians (neither saints nor sinners) by whom the
                        church is lumbered and made inefficient, that is, the Christians who have
                        such obstinate kinks on their constitutions, that the grace of God is able
                        to straighten them only by slow degrees and a weary drill, they are
                        generally victims of untamed early influences in poorly managed houses.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article's principle objective is to extol the virtues of a healthy and
                    productive home. A home such as this will, by definition, be free of the
                    troubles of business and politics. Similarly it will be free of tyrannical
                    domination by the father figure. Instead, with children as the main focus, a
                    happy home will forge character through music, books, beautiful objects, and
                    devotion to God. Once these things are in place, and despite the cost, the home
                    will naturally be a pleasant one.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.15.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Manganese Steel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This great discovery of our countyman Lorenzo Sibert, Esq., will now soon
                        attract the attention of the whole mechanical world. The Steel produced by
                        Mr. Sibert in his operations at California Furnace last fall was the product
                        of a charcoal blast, and it was undecided how far, if at all the operation
                        could be carried on by stone coal as a fuel. - A few weeks ago Mr. Sibert
                        went to Baltimore to test this matter fully. He expected to have the use of
                        one of the largest furnaces there long enough to have made a thorough trial
                        of his flax with stone coal. But he only succeeded in getting the furnace
                        for twenty-four hours. So confident was he of the success of his theory that
                        he risked a trial of only 24 hours, where a failure might damage him
                        seriously and <del/> on a first trial, with new fuel, was to say the least,
                        problematical. The test was made and we understand that 10 or 12 tons of
                        this new metal was produced, that, so far as <del/> judged, without actual
                        chemical analysis, possesses all the characteristics of the 30 or 40 tons
                        made at Rockbridge, at the <del/> Furnace in the fall, and which has been
                        worked, tested and analyzed, and found to be steel of the most excellent
                        quality. Mr. Sibert also prosecuted some interesting experiments in the
                        shops of the Baltimore and Ohio R.R. Co., at Mt. Clare with satisfactory
                        results. Officers in charge of the mechanical operations of that company
                        have manifested their appreciation of the importance of this product by
                        placing at Mr. Sibert's disposal all the vast resources and machinery in
                        their shops for the practical application of his great discovery, at their
                        expense in material and labor, a most liberal and advantageous offer, which
                        he accepted.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Sibert spent last week in Washington preparing the necessary papers to
                        secure the benefits of his discovery by patents in all the principle
                        countries of Europe. These documents go out this week to the proper agents
                        in Europe, where the patents will at once be issued to Mr. Sibert and his
                        appointee and joint owner Mr. Brady, of Rockbridge. - The scientific
                        journals of the day show that the subject of this discovery, a cheap process
                        of making steel directly from Iron Ore, is engaging more attention from Iron
                        men in this country and abroad than any other connected with the
                        manufactures of the world. This is one of those discoveries that marks an
                        era in the industrial arts throughout the world, and most immediate portion
                        of Virginia. - No part of the United States - perhaps no part of the world -
                        is so rich in the principle elements of this new manufacture. Iron Ore and
                        manganese, in close proximity. - Timber, too, for charcoal is still
                        abundant, and by the time it gives out, the Chesapeake and Ohio R.R., it is
                        to be hoped, will open up the coal fields of the Kanawha Valley for the full
                        development of the Iron interest between the Alleghenies and Blue Ridge.</p>
                    <p>The parties having control of this Patent are about to pursue the right
                        policy not to push it upon the world, but let the world come after it. They
                        will make arrangements to put in operation this Spring a single first class
                        charcoal furnace here in the Valley and make 5 or 10 tons a day of <emph
                            rend="italic">Manganese Steel</emph> for Railroad purposes, such as
                        wheels, axles and rails, and supply this material to one or two leading
                        Railroads, and let its use proclaim its value. Thus by refusing to sell
                        territorial rights, but offering the process to all who choose to adopt it
                        and pay a small royalty, it will, in <del/> supplant all other modes of
                        producing steel for general purposes and wants of the world.</p>
                    <p>The furnace first engaging in this <del/> feature will have a great start in
                        the business and we hope it will be one of those in this county or
                        Rockbridge, as it will lead speedily to the erection of others and thus
                        create a new source of wealth to our favored region.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article details the invention and initial testing of a new process for
                    making steel. The paper proudly boasts that the inventor is a local man, and
                    that he is offering this new technology to anyone, both in the United States and
                    Europe, willing to pay a small royalty. Virginia, particularly Augusta County,
                    is in a unique position to capitalize from this new process, as there are
                    abundant natural resources available in the vicinity. If, the author suggests, a
                    furnace can first be built locally, it will bring a great deal of wealth to the
                    area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Valley of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper quotes the Norfolk Journal in asserting that the Shenandoah
                    Valley's great natural resources have attracted a stream of immigrants to the
                    area in the past two years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Why Lags the Work?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes excerpts from the Richmond Whig chastising Augusta
                    County for lagging behind in economic support for construction of the Covington
                    and Ohio Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.15.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noon</ln>
                        <fn>Johnny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Johnny Noon at the post office can supply big-city papers much faster than
                    the mail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Staunton's depot agents report heavy volumes of freight and estimate that
                    there have been more purchases by town merchants than in any previous season
                    since the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. L. Opie has returned from Kentucky with his new wife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. A. Burke is adding to his foundry and machine shops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Virginia Springs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The mountain retreats near Staunton are in great condition and ready to
                    open for the season.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Shade Trees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>J. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. K. Woods is adding shade trees to his lot, enhancing his property value
                    and the beauty of the surroundings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hupman</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewis V. Hupman and Miss Mary E. Anderson were married on April 8th by the
                    Rev. R. C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Giles</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Giles of Staunton and Mary C. Dunlap, daughter of William Dunlap of
                    Augusta, were married at the residence of the bride's father on April 8th by the
                    Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simmons</ln>
                        <fn>Sue W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cosby</ln>
                        <fn>J. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. L. Opie of Staunton and Sue W. Simmons of Bardstown, KY, were married in
                    Kentucky on March 31st by the Rev. J. V. Cosby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcome</ln>
                        <fn>Mildred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mildred Newcome died in Staunton of paralysis on March 31st. She was
                    60 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.15.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
