<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.09.09">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-09">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">9</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.09.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Practical Reconstruction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Since Capt. John Smith landed in the virgin land--Virginia; since Spotswood
                        crossed Rockfish Gap with his Horse Shoe Knights, and discovered the Goshen
                        land of "West Augusta,"--Virginia's far seeing statesmen have earnestly
                        sought for an outlet to her Western children, the States given by her
                        generosity to the Union, <emph rend="italic">under the Constitution.</emph></p>
                    <p>Her Washington suggested the Great Water Line, the James River and Kanawha
                        Canal. It has dragged its slow length along for years and now sticks fast in
                        the mud of Rockbridge, and Botetourt. The ripple of the waters, of the North
                        and the James never ceased to echo the cry of the West: "Come on--connect us
                        with the Atlantic and all is well!" but, war and its desolation forced us to
                        be deaf to their cry.</p>
                    <p>The war, with all its horrors, has done good. It has turned our minds to the
                        "practical reconstruction" of our State, and now the great interior lines
                        are fairly under way--from Norfolk to Bristol and from Richmond, by C.
                        &amp; O. R.R., to the Ohio. We greet them with an honest "God speed Ye
                        well!" they will make us prosperous and great and show the world that "there
                        is life in the old land yet."</p>
                    <p> The able superintendence, of a Fountaine and a Whitcomb over the Chesapeake
                        and Ohio, their prompt arrangements with capitalists, for its completion in
                        three years, gives joy to the heart of old Virginia and assures us that the
                        race is not <emph rend="italic">effete,</emph> as the Radicals say.
                        Norfolk--the Harbor of the Atlantic Coast--will soon strike hands with the
                        great West, by two routes, and become, what nature intended her to be, the
                        Emporium of the World. The Valley R.R., comes in, extending from Harper's
                        Ferry to Salem, making a direct line, from New York to New Orleans, on the
                        Gulf of Mexico; and completes that natural combination of interests, which
                        is destined to concentrate the great Water and Railroad trade of this
                        Continent at Norfolk.</p>
                    <p> Look at the map--study the Virginia <emph rend="italic">idea</emph> of
                        "practical reconstruction," and you will see that every line converges,
                        naturally, to this point--the base of all we hope, live and breathe for--the
                        prosperity of Virginia!</p>
                    <p>Turning with disgust from politics we fell like the weary traveler, when
                        after days of toil, he reaches the summit of the Nevadas, and sees the
                        Golden Land beneath him. We have reached the "Elliot's Knob" of Virginia's
                        reconstruction. Looking at her as she was, as she is, and as she will be,
                        when her through lines are completed--her people rich, united and happy,
                        mere words cannot portray our feelings. The Virginia heart exults, rejoices!
                        "God bless her! God prosper her! God guide her, forever and forever!</p>
                    <p> In conclusion, could we but <sic>enspire</sic> our people with the feelings
                        which tell us there is a better day coming, that there is "a Divinity that
                        shapes our ends, rough-hew them as we will;" that our rights and interests
                        are in our hands; that material prosperity brings political strength, and
                        the through lines will bring <unclear>shat.</unclear> Could we remove the
                        selfish old fogyism that weighs us down; could we bring all our people <emph
                            rend="italic">down</emph> to the dull details of "practical
                        reconstruction" of our country roads, farms, and the mechanic arts, as well
                        as the great through lines; could we teach them to educate themselves
                        practically--to make use of their master minds; then, we would proudly hear
                        that the grand old motto: "Sic Semper Tyrannis!" ring out again--then we
                        would see the ideas of Virginia controlling a Union of States--see her, the
                        Mother, in the proud majesty of <emph rend="italic">right,</emph> gathering
                        her brood under the wings of the Constitution she formed--protecting all--a
                        terror to none, but tyrants!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this article looks to the virtues of progress and predicts a
                    great future for Virginia. Citing how Virginians of old had sought to connect
                    the state by waterway to the west, he now connects "practical reconstruction"
                    with the proliferation of rail lines. This will inevitably connect Norfolk, and
                    thus the rest of Virginia, with the west and lead to prosperity and prestige
                    that Virginia held before the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Money Plenty in Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Times are right, especially on printers, but we are reliably inform that
                        money is being loaned in the country at the old rate, 6 per cent, for a
                        series of years, by our farmers. A gentleman in this city recently borrowed
                        $7000 for a term of years, at 6 per cent. In the face of this "One"--(we
                        hope there is only one so ignorant in Augusta) in the Spectator of 25th ult,
                        dare assert that Augusta County Bonds would only bring 25 cents on the
                        dollar. We will take them at par, for about $5000 due us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Update on the economic situation in Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Don't Halloo Before You Are Out of the Woods</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We learn the Rockingham people are rejoicing over the defeat of the
                        Chesapeake and O. R.R. subscription by Augusta! They say it prevents the
                        Valley road ever coming further than Harrisonburg and that they are now
                        taking trade from us.--This must make our people, who rejoiced over the
                        defeat of the subscription, happy! but we advise Rockingham not to halloo
                        too soon.--All who voted for the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio subscription will
                        vote $500,000 to the Valley and so will those who voted against it. Let us
                        turn our whole attention to the matter and vote the $500,000.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper advises those who cheered over the defeat of the Augusta
                    subscription to the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad to remember that the question
                    is not yet finally settled.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Why!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Why is there no enthusiasm for Grant?" radicals dismally ask. Because the
                        American people North are sensational--fond of "big things," even big
                        butchers, but like children, they soon tire of their toys and seek new
                        sensations. Grant was a costly toy. It was all very well when the excitement
                        was up, but now that it is down, Grant is "played out," as they say; and
                        they only remember what fools he made of them. This characteristic of the
                        Northern people, with the monstrous outrages of the Radical party, answers
                        the question and settles the whys and wherefores. He is a dead cock in the
                        pit--Pitch him out!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper suggests that the lack of enthusiasm for Grant is due to the
                    fickle nature of the northern character.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Rosecrans--Lee Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>General Rosecrans commences his letter as follows; "Full of solicitude for
                        the future of our country, I come with my heart in my hand to learn the
                        condition, wishes, and intention of the people of the southern States and
                        especially to obtain the sentiments of that body of brave, energetic, and
                        self-sacrificing men who, after sustaining the Confederacy for four years,
                        laid down their arms, swore allegiance to the United States, whose trusted
                        and beloved leader you have been." General Rosecran's letter is quite long.
                        The following is General Lee's reply.</p>
                    <p> White Sulpher Springs, <lb/> West Virginia, Aug. 26 1868. </p>
                    <p>General,--I have had the honor to receive your letter if this date, and in
                        accordance with your suggestions I have conferred with a number of gentlemen
                        from the South, in whose judgment I have confided, and who are well
                        acquainted with the public sentiment of their respective States. They have
                        kindly consented to unite with me in replying to your communication, and
                        their names will be found with my own, appended to this answer. With this
                        explanation we proceed to give you a candid statement of what we believe to
                        be the sentiment of the southern people in regard to the subject which you
                        refer.</p>
                    <p>Whatever opinions may have prevailed in the past in regard to African slavery
                        or the right of a state to secede from the Union, we believe that they
                        consider that those questions were decided by the war, and that it is their
                        intention in good faith to abide by that decision.</p>
                    <p>At the close of the war the southern people laid down their arms and sought
                        to resume their former relations with the United States Government. Through
                        their State conventions they abolished slavery and annulled their ordinances
                        of secession, and they returned to their peaceful pursuits with a sincere
                        purpose to fulfill all their duties under the Constitution of the United
                        States which they had sworn to protect. If their action in these particulars
                        had been met in a spirit of frankness and cordiality, we believe that ere
                        this old irritation would have passed away, and the wounds inflicted by the
                        war would have been, in a great measure, healed. As far as we are now the
                        people of the South entertain no unfriendly feeling towards the Government
                        of the United States; but they complain that their rights under the
                        Constitution are withheld from them in the administration thereof.</p>
                    <p>The idea that the southern people are hostile to the negroes, and would
                        oppress them if it were in their power to do so, is entirely unfounded. They
                        have grown up in our midst, and we have been accustomed from childhood to
                        look upon them with kindness. The change in relations of the two races has
                        wrought no change in our feelings towards them. They will constitute that
                        important part or our laboring population. Without the employment which
                        southern agriculture affords they would be destitute of the means of
                        subsistence, and become paupers, dependent on public bounty. Self interest,
                        even if there were no higher motive, would therefore, prompt the whites of
                        the South to extend to the negroes care and protection. The important fact
                        that the two races are, under existing circumstances, necessary to each
                        other, is gradually becoming apparent to both, and we believe that but for
                        the influence exerted to stir up the passions of the negroes, the relations
                        of the two races would soon adjust themselves on a basis of mutual kindness
                        advantage.</p>
                    <p>It is true that the people of the South, together with the people of the
                        North and West, are for obvious reasons, opposed to any system of laws which
                        will place the political power of the country in the hands of the negro
                        race. But this opposition springs from no feeling of enmity, but from a deep
                        seated conviction that at present the negroes have neither the intelligence
                        or qualification which are necessary to make them safe depositories of
                        political power. They would inevitably become the victims of demagogues who
                        for selfish purposes, would mislead them, to the serious injury of the
                        public.</p>
                    <p>The great want of the South is peace. The people earnestly desire tranquility
                        and the restoration of the Union. They deprecate disorder and excitement as
                        the most serious obstacles to their prosperity. They ask a restoration of
                        their rights under the Constitution. They desire relief from oppressive
                        misrule.--Above all, they would appeal to their countrymen for the
                        reestablishment in the Southern States of that which has justly been
                        regarded as the birthright of every American--the right of self government.
                        Establish these on firm basis and we can safely promise on behalf of the
                        southern people that they will faithfully obey the Constitution and the laws
                        of the United States, treat the negro with kindness and humanity, fulfill
                        every duty incumbent on peaceful citizens, loyal to the Constitution of
                        their country.</p>
                    <p>We believe the above contains a succinct reply to the general topics embraced
                        in your letter, and we venture to say on behalf of the southern people and
                        of the officers and soldiers of the late Confederate army that they will
                        concur in all the sentiments which we have expressed.</p>
                    <p>Appreciating the patriotic motives which have prompted your letter, and
                        reciprocating your expressions of kind regard, we have the honor to be,</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully and truly,<lb/> R.E. Lee of Virginia; G.T. Beauregard,
                        Louisiana; Alex. H. Stephens, Georgia; C.M. Conrad, Louisiana; Linton
                        Stephens, Georgia; A.T. Caperton, West Virginia; John Echols, Virginia; F.S.
                        Stockdale, Texas; F.W. Pickens, South Carolina; Wm J Robertson, Virginia; Wm
                        T. Turner, West Virginia; C.H. Subec, South Carolina; E Fontaine, Virginia;
                        John Letcher, Virginia, B C Adams, Mississippi; W J Green, North Carolina;
                        Lewis E Harvie, Virginia; P V Daniel, Jr., Virginia; W T Sutherlie,
                        Virginia; A B James, Louisiana; Toutant Beauregard, Texas; M O H Norton,
                        Louisiana; T B Branch, Georgia; H T Russell, Georgia; Samuel J Douglas,
                        Florida; Jeremiah Morton, Virginia; John B Baldwin, Virginia; George W
                        Bolling, Virginia; Theodore Flournoy, Virginia; James Lyons, Virginia;</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">To General W.S. Rosecrans,</emph> Minister to Mexico,
                        White Sulpher Springs, Va.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter is a partial reproduction of the correspondence between R.E.
                    Lee and W.S. Rosecrans concerning reunion. According to Lee, the southern people
                    want nothing but peace and prosperity within the Union. They are patriotic
                    supporters of individual liberty under the laws of the Constitution. There are
                    however, significant terms to Lee's version of reunion: all factors of
                    oppression must be removed. The southern people want to abide by the laws but
                    insist that they not be dictated by the radical contingent. The well-being of
                    black southerners is addressed suggesting that white southerners are best
                    equipped to take care of former slaves. Self-government is the principle
                    condition in this letter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Bryan's Grand Caravan, Menagerie and Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This "celebrated combination," the first to need a "vast caravan of horses,
                    wagons, etc., to transport it," will visit Staunton. "As a well-endowed
                    Zoological establishment, it will attract large attendance."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Travel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>2,550 travellers have arrived at Staunton hotels in August. The paper
                    estimates that at $5.00 each, the town should have earned $12,750.00 in profits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The First Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>McGinley and Carroll's circus will be in town on the 15th. It comes highly
                    recommended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Black Rock</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A "lively crowd" is visiting the Black Rock Springs in the northeast corner
                    of Augusta, about 17 miles from Waynesboro. "About 80 gay visitors are camped
                    there and they say, the bachelors especially, enjoy it hugely."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Sibert Iron-Steel Process</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brady</ln>
                        <fn>D. C. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A company will be set up in Baltimore and Bath Furnace to manufacture
                    Sibert's steel. D. C. E. Brady travelled to Baltimore last week to help organize
                    the company to work the patent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Street Commissioners are busy laying pavement and stepping stones in
                    the city. "With the four story brick houses and magnificent pavements we are so
                    vain as to think we will compare favorably with almost any city in the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plant</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn>Johana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn>J. Ambler</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Fr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin Plant and Mrs. Mary Beck and John B. Scherer, Jr., and Miss Johana
                    Sullivan, all of Staunton, were both married in Staunton's St. Francis Church by
                    Father J. Ambler Weed on September 8th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
