<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.03.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-03-11">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.11.01" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Prophetic Language</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper quoted the New York Herald asserting that Grant's nomination
                    cannot bring victory to the Republicans who are "blackened with the negro
                    policy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond Whig says there will be a great tide of immigration to the
                        South, and especially to Virginia, and the importance of encouraging this
                        immigration cannot be overestimated, and should not be lost sight of for a
                        moment. The negroes, as a class, will never be tax payers, will for the most
                        part be paupers, and will shun productive labor so long as they can maintain
                        a precarious, even miserable existence without it. Such lands as we have,
                        such mines and mineral deposits, such extensive forests and such substantial
                        water power, cannot be neglected by the great immigration interest. The
                        presence of savages did not deter enterprising men from colonizing the New
                        World, and the presence of negro voters will not deter immigrants from the
                        Northern States and from Europe from purchasing and settling on our fertile
                        lands and developing and utilizing the varied resources for which there is a
                        growing demand in all the markets of the world. There will be a rush of
                        immigration hither, and it is for us to hasten it by extending to the
                        immigrant all the encouragement and facilities that we can, and by
                        supporting our immigration societies and agencies. We confidently expect to
                        see an influx of settlers not only from the North and from abroad, but from
                        the young West. If the farmers of the West can purchase our rich lands at
                        low rates and place themselves in proximity with the markets of the world
                        from which they are now so distant, what is there to hinder them from doing
                        so? Not the want of society, of churches, of schools, roads, dwelling, out
                        houses, or any such conveniences. They already exist.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This piece illustrates the importance of immigration to the future
                    prosperity of Virginia. Just as "savages" did not deter the original
                    colonization of the region, black voters, who will never be tax-payers, should
                    not deter immigration now. The potential wealth available through fertile lands,
                    mineral deposits, and forests leads the author to "confidently expect" an influx
                    of settlers from all across the nation and abroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Staunton and Harrisonburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Middle River" writes the Virginian and argues that Staunton stands in
                    danger of losing the trade of surrounding counties if Augusta County roads are
                    not put in better order.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Points is Augusta County agent and sole vendor of a book entitled
                    "Gray Jackets" containing "incidents of the war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that "Can she cook?" is the number one question young men
                    have of prospective brides, something they learned to ask while in the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Flour Inspected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Fifer, flour inspector for Augusta, has inspected 5,595 barrels
                    between December 1867 and March 1868.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Virginia Hotel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginia Hotel closed yesterday, and Mr. Peyton's lease expires on
                    April 1st. Hereafter he can be found at the Greenbriar, White Sulphur Springs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Elvira M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallhelm</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Cook and Miss Elvira M. Stover, both of Augusta, were married at
                    the residence of the bride's father on March 5th by the Rev. H. Tallhelm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
