<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.09.30">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-30">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">30</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.10.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.30.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"God Bless the Ladies!"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is something touchingly sweet in this expression; so fraught with
                        memories of a glorious past; so hallowed and sacred, for it was over on the
                        lips and in the hearts of our loved and lost, that one can hardly write it
                        without tears.</p>
                    <p> "The boys"--ah, "the boys!" <emph rend="italic">our boys</emph>--so proud,
                        so brave, so free! said it, as they left home, mother, sister,
                        sweetheart--all, to fight for liberty! They said it on the march, in the
                        camp, under the starry bivouac; on the lonely <sic>pickit;</sic> in rain, in
                        storm; in the dreary prison cell; on the perilous edge of battle! With their
                        last breath it was feebly uttered and, even now, the disembodied spirits of
                        the dead-Angel voices--re-echo the chorus of every true Southern
                        heart-beat--"God bless the Ladies!"</p>
                    <p> And we would be false to our nature did we not say "God bless the Ladies"
                        who have so perseveringly struggled, against every obstacle, to do fitting
                        honor to the memory of the dead <emph rend="italic">we always have with
                        us,</emph> and cry shame on the pledge of the county of Augusta, who do not
                        aid them more!</p>
                    <p> The dinner on Monday and supper at night, was "a success," but what "a
                        success!" A people <emph rend="italic">eating</emph> to honor their dead!
                        Let us have an end to such things and raise the money necessary by every man
                        paying his part. The Soldier's Cemetery stands a disgrace to Augusta county
                        until this is done--but <emph rend="italic"> "now and forever"</emph> there
                        should be a monument there--inscribed: <lb/> "God Bless the Ladies!" </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article utilizes typical lost cause imagery to praise the women of
                    Augusta County who tirelessly work to do "fitting honor to the memory of the
                    dead." Further, the author calls for the men of the county to go beyond their
                    commemorative efforts and contribute more money to honor the fallen Confederate
                    soldier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Shall We Vote?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This is a question to be decided by the Conservative Central Committee of
                        Virginia.</p>
                    <p> We have urged <emph rend="italic">action</emph> in the matter, but have
                        received no favorable response. Why is no action taken? Are we in the fight
                        or out? Is Virginia to take things as they come, or reassert her proud old
                            <emph rend="italic">Sic Semper Tyrannis?</emph> If we are "out" let our
                        Central Committee say so--If "in" let the people see where we are to go.</p>
                    <p>Gentlemen, we commend to you the following brave words from Geo. H.
                        Pendleton, of Ohio, to Somers Kinney, of Houston, Texas:</p>
                    <p> Bangor, Me., August 21, 1868. <lb/><emph rend="italic">Somers Kinney, Esq.;
                            Houston, Texas:</emph></p>
                    <p>"My Dear Sir,--Yours of the 2d instant, dated at Brownsville, was forwarded
                        me from Cincinnati.</p>
                    <p> "In reply, I have only time to say that you cannot urge too strongly our
                        brethren of Texas as to stand by the National Democracy and resist all
                        Radical attempts to abuse you. My heartfelt wish is that you may succeed in
                        your new undertaking. We are making a last fight for constitutional liberty,
                        and the signs of the times indicate a Democratic triumph hitherto unknown.
                        Yield not a scintilla of your honor. <emph rend="italic">There is no room
                            for compromise</emph></p>
                    <p> "About your being allowed to vote, be not alarmed; <emph rend="italic">we
                            shall see that Texas is represented. Vote, by all means</emph></p>
                    <p>"Send me your paper to Cincinnati. I will write more fully to morrow or the
                        day after. Yours, George H Pendleton."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article urges the Conservative Central Committee into action. The
                    author acknowledges that with this group rests the decision on the matter of
                    voting, and he suggests that the Committee favor the vote. Otherwise, Virginia
                    will have to "take things as they come" from the Radical party. The author
                    supports his claims by illustrating Texas's commitment to a Democratic victory
                    and their desire to see "constitutional liberty" through by voting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Push on the Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Valley of Virginia must be developed says the Winchester Times. To effect
                        a full realization of our hopes we must adopt a wise and liberal policy,
                        both with respect to immigration and with respect to those new and useful
                        enterprises by which our great natural advantages may be made available. It
                        is undoubtedly true that the busy and unceasing sound of the steam engine
                        will be objected to by some worthy old gentlemen of the Rip Van Winkle
                        school, as an impertinent interference with their morning nap or their
                        evening siesta, but we predict that our venerable friends will learn to
                        sleep all the better under the lullaby of development and progressive
                        improvement. Let us then hail the coming of an industrious immigration, and
                        give our aid to the promotion of useful enterprise.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article combines immigration with "new and useful enterprise." The
                    influx of new arrivals will further stimulate the advancing industries that will
                    in turn bring prosperity to the Valley. The author implies that "industrious
                    immigration" will counter the idleness of gentlemen of the "Rip Van Winkle
                    school."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Future of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The Norfolk <emph rend="italic">Journal</emph> says "the last three years
                        have fully justified our undoubted confidence in Virginians, and we can
                        proudly boast that the whole State, poor and desolate as it is, has sprung
                        forward with a power and energy that has astonished even ourselves. We have
                        no fears for the future--onwards! onwards! is the motto of Virginia. If she
                        has done so much when more than one-half of her territory has been swept
                        with the besom of destruction, what will, in coming years, be her wealth and
                        glory! There rises before our eyes of faith a boundless vista of her future
                        prosperity. We see before the close of this century Old Virginia covered
                        over with railroads and crowded with population, with noble cities at every
                        fall of her rivers, manufacturing for the Union; with her mills developing
                        the infinite wealth now hidden in the bowels of the earth. This picture of
                        the future is no opium dreaming, but it is what must come to pass."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this article predicts a great and prosperous future for
                    Virginia. Manufacturing will open the doors to "boundless vistas" of wealth that
                    the state has to offer. Although the state is at present poor and desolate,
                    industrial ventures have, in the last three years, begun to show positive signs
                    for future affluence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the citizens of Augusta County, held in the Court House in
                        Staunton on September Court day, for the purpose of appointing Delegates to
                        the Commercial Convention which will meet in Norfolk city on the 14th of
                        October next, upon motion, Hon. Alex. H.H. Stuart was appointed Chairman,
                        and Col. James H. Skinner, Secretary of the meeting.</p>
                    <p>Col. J. Marshall McCue explained the object and importance of the Convention.</p>
                    <p>Col. B. Christian moved that the Chairman appoint fifteen delegates, and the
                        same number of alternatives to represent this county in said Convention.</p>
                    <p>Col. John B. Baldwin briefly addressed the meeting, urging the importance of
                        this county and section being represented in the proposed Convention, saying
                        that if Norfolk had forgotten this part of the country, that we at least had
                        not forgotten Norfolk, and that we hoped to make such a city of her, that
                        shortly she would not know herself.</p>
                    <p> Gen. John Echols further zealously advocated the motion showing the interest
                        that this county has in building up Norfolk, and making her the "great
                        Southern sea-port." He jocularly intimated that it would be wise to appoint
                        none but old men as delegates, as he feared that the well known hospitality
                        of Norfolk, and the preparations of welcome which were making might result
                        in leading astray <emph rend="italic">young</emph> men from the true objects
                        of the Convention.</p>
                    <p> Col. Christian thought if "hospitality" was significant of the sort of
                        internal improvement to be promoted--the <emph rend="italic">old</emph>
                        gentlemen should not wish to monopolize.</p>
                    <p>The motion upon being put was unanimously adopted and the Chairman appointed
                        thereunder the following Delegates and Alternates:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Delegates--</emph> John B. Baldwin, John Echols, Bolivar
                        Christian, J.M. McCue, R.G. Bickle, M.G. Harman, Jacob Baylor, Ths. W.
                        Shelton, B.B. Donaghe, N.K. Trout, W.A. Burke, H.M. Bell, R. Maury, E.W.
                        Bayley, John J. Larew.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Alternates--</emph> Col. R. Turk, Geo. E. Price, B.
                        Crawford, Absalom Koiner, Adam McChesney, Dr. Wm. E. Walters, M. W. D.
                        Hogshead, Jos. A. Waddell, Logan J. Maupin, Wm. Withrow, James W. Patrick,
                        Wm. M. Tate, J. Marshall Hanger, Thos. P. Eskridge, Col. W.D. Anderson.</p>
                    <p>Upon motion, the Chairman and Secretary were added to the Delegates</p>
                    <p> Upon motion, the meeting was adjourned<lb/> Alex H.H. Stuart, <lb/> Chairman
                        <lb/> Jas. H. Skinner, Secretary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bayley</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>Logan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of Augusta met to appoint delegates to an upcoming commercial
                    convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.30.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There is a diphtheria outbreak among Staunton's children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britt</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. Britt has been appointed flour inspector for Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares Staunton "the most progressive, quiet and orderly city
                    in the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Arrivals at our Hotels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>2,200 visitors have arrived at Staunton hotels in September, and 9,418
                    since June.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The friends of temperance held a picnic in Mt. Crawford last week.
                    Pennybacker and Price of Harrisonburg delivered addresses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bryan's great caravan, circus and menagerie performed in Staunton last
                    Friday. "The canvas and the crowd was the largest that has ever been in
                    Staunton, and everything passed off to the satisfaction of the people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Porterfield Kenney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Porterfield Kenney Bell, infant son of Maj. H. M. Bell, died in Staunton on
                    September 18th. He was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>Louis B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>K. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Louis B. Kelley, son of John and K. M. Kelley, died in Staunton on
                    September 25th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.30.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
