<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.03.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-03-25">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.25.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Address of Gen. Henry A. Wise to the people of the County of Augusta, upon the
                    subject of completing the Covington and Ohio Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Full page transcription of a speech by Henry Wise pointing out the benefits
                    that the Covington and Ohio Railroad would bring to Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Good Drinks Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares that the "Valley Virginian Temperance Society expired by
                    limitation yesterday."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Sullivan at the New Book Store has established a circulating library.
                    For a monthly fee, people may take home as many books as they want, one at a
                    time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper puts in a plea for a reading room stocked with journals to
                    complement the new circulating library.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Some Things That are Disgusting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To hear small editors who are neither Solomons nor Heroes, boast that they
                        never hesitated nor wavered about this or that, and blowing the silly blast
                        of their own self-conceit - that for five months, the small editor conducted
                        the only journal in the State, which openly and boldly opposed the nefarious
                        device of the call of a Convention; that others were <emph rend="italic"
                            >advocating it,</emph> and there are in this place one of them, whom no
                        doubt the small editor considers in the way, <emph rend="italic">obstructing
                            his sunshine</emph> - did so own up to the election, that <emph
                            rend="italic">he</emph> was right all the time - that no voter would now
                        be without the Spectator." This last is the key to all the boasting. The
                        Spectator wants money so badly, that he is willing to make it in the worst
                        of all ways, (having gassed about his circulation until the whole thing has
                        become ridiculous), by villifying [sic] his neighbors. We should like to
                        know if the Spectator was <emph rend="italic">right</emph> when he domiciled
                        himself in the enemy's lines during the war. That was a very conservative
                        policy indeed, but did not help much to save Virginia from "Radical or negro
                        rule." Was he right when he was very erroneously calling on all
                        Conservatives to stay away from the polls. - Thus, with a majority of 13,000
                        registered voters in Virginia, leaving everything in the hands of radicals
                        and negroes. We think this unerring mortal repented of this policy before he
                        got through. Was this right, when he opposed the call of the Convention,
                        when that man whom gentlemen delight to honor, General Robert E. Lee, who
                        fought <emph rend="italic">in</emph> his own lines while the small Editor
                        was <emph rend="italic">out</emph> of them, thought the convention ought to
                        be held and so ventured to advise his countrymen. True the result showed
                        that the convention was inevitable. Now the white registered vote greatly
                        exceeded the blacks in number. And by proper organization and a full turn
                        out the conservative element had every reasonable hope of electing a
                        conservative convention, now that by the advice of the small editor and his
                        aid the election went by default and resulted in filling the capital with a
                        disgraceful set of <emph rend="italic">animals</emph> who never could have
                        gotten there if the conservatives had voted their strength. But "the
                        Spectator is <emph rend="italic">right all the time."</emph> - Conservatives
                        fork over your half dollars. His wise council may succeed in keeping you
                        away from the polls again when the tug comes. Such things were
                    disgusting.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article condemns the editor of the Spectator for suggesting the
                    conservative element stay away from the polls. This, says the author, did little
                    to prevent "Radical or negro rule." Because of his words, the Radicals won by
                    default; now the capital is dominated by a "disgraceful set of animals."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
