<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.01.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/03/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-01-22">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">22</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.01.22.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Sensible Advice of a Colored Preacher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the advice of Dr. C. Brown to the Freedmen that urges
                    them not to attempt to take the land of their former masters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.01.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Ariel"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The pamphlet entitled "Ariel" that argues that African Americans have no
                    soul is making a large stir in Staunton's black community. The paper urges all
                    to read it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that economically times are harder in the South than ever
                    before. Capital is tied up, merchandise is selling slowly, and African Americans
                    are starving.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>War Rumors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper comments on rumors of another war beginning over political
                    issues. "They should remember that the men who fought, on both sides, during the
                    last war have had enough of it, and that those who did not will never fight
                    anybody. Anyway, our policy is to be quiet, vote down the Constitution,--vote up
                    the Chesapeake and Ohio Rail Road, and wait for better times."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>From 'Our Own Correspondent'--What a Valley Virginian girl saw on her way to
                    'West Virginia'--Her opinion of Andrew Johnson, etc., etc.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Phillippi, West Virginia,<lb/>7th January, 1868.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Dear Valley Virginian:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>In all the mountains of West Virginia there is naught to substitute your
                        bright coming. Will you quite forget me because so far away? Lest this be my
                        sad fate, accept this gentle reminder. That is a noble, noble Valley, whose
                        name you bear - sorrow filled my heart and my eyes were dim with tears, as a
                        farewell was spoken to my native snow mantled mountains that sentinel it on
                        every side. The shadow was not lifted from my spirit, till such a welcome as
                        only sunny faces Virginia girls and a courtly gentleman of the "Old School"
                        can give greeted us at Alexandria: and tho' the snow storm still pelted
                        pitilessly sunshine seemed to have bursted out in all its warmth and
                        brilliancy on all sides.</p>
                    <p>With a spirit struggle to behold the invisible hands about to bear the Old
                        Year to eternity, we gathered around its death bed - in witnessing the last
                        agony our dead joys died again - buried sorrows once more grappled at the
                        heart strings. The "New Year" came in tears - for its dead companion. We
                        will hope they were not shed for the 'evil to come.' The disappointment it
                        brought for us, we also trust, is not ruinous; for the hearts were set on
                        attending the President's Levee, and with a great deep sigh, <emph
                            rend="italic">that</emph> must needs be resigned. A greater cross could
                        have been endured with our surrounding; but we were privileged to enjoy more
                        than grand and warm hospitality affords - our lovely hostess brought out a
                        war chair, unpretending and convenient after camp chair fashion, with a
                        heavy piece of carpeting serving as a seat and back, and with emotion she
                        said "this was Gen Lee's chair during all the war, and after the surrender
                        presented to my husband, who was one of his clerks. He prizes it above
                        everything he possesses." What a great history in that chair and how it
                        speaks to the heart! Among life's highest privileges I hold my communion
                        with the matchless Chieftain's "Old Army Chair." At noon the sunshine came
                        out gloriously, enabling us to visit Christ's Church, where General
                        Washington was wont to worship. - Words may not express our deep emotion as
                        we entered the sacred edifice, and sought the pew, bearing on it a neat
                        silver plate the inscription, "Washington's pew." On the South side is a
                        very antique urn shaped pulpit, no longer used, and only retained against
                        the wishes of modern, fashionable members, because the aged, who worshipped
                        there in days long gone, cannot witness the sundering of so many hallowed
                        associations. It is not difficult to imagine yourself among the spirits of
                        the past, as you sit in those ivy clad shades; and it was not strange that
                        every voice was hushed and the heart <emph rend="italic">would</emph>lift
                        itself in <emph rend="italic">prayer</emph></p>
                    <p>Thence, we wandered to the spot made memorable by Elsworth's exploits, and
                        the noble Jackson's fall - though it now bears no marks of the tragedy it
                        had voices for Virginia girls, not quite reconstructed.</p>
                    <p>Vespers at the Catholic Church were not without interest, with such music as
                        a grand organ and noble soprano could produce in "Come ye disconsolate."
                        From these sources, we went to a hearth stone, so brightly beautiful, that
                        the heart will keep going back to it, wherever the boot step roams.</p>
                    <p>A charming ride on the Potomac to Washington introduced the second day, and
                        we soon found ourselves in the Smithsonian Institute, wondering much over
                        the meteors. The most marvelous of all, the one found, I think, in South
                        America, weighing 1,400 lbs, presenting the appearance of quite a regularly
                        defined circle and composed of metallic substance. - Then the huge
                        sea-animals, wild beasts from Africa's jungles to America's blooming
                        prairies, with birds of every form and plumage that vocal their praise,
                        called for exclamations. - Among the various products of habitable climes,
                        and curiosities from almost uninhabitable regions, the dress, worn by Dr.
                        Kane in his Arctic Expedition, was curious and most interesting. It was
                        formed of skin, clothed in heavy white wool, the skin extending over the
                        face and hands. A view of the Egyptian Mummies strengthened my wish for a
                        Christian burial; and the Egyptian idols, so rudely fashioned and presenting
                        countenances so inhuman, and even hideous, caused one deep thanksgiving,
                        that the God we worship is without beginning of days and end of years.</p>
                    <p>The desire to tell you of the beautiful corals, snatched from old ocean's
                        secret mines, the curiously rich mosaic from Pompeii, the less ancient,
                        though not less eloquent battered sword presented by Lafayette to an officer
                        in the Revolution, must not be indulged, for you are weary of my long talk
                        and I am in haste to reach the President's mansion. Yes, a band of Virginia
                        girls, very much enraptured with the magnificence of that American Palace,
                        had the audacity to beg the privilege of seeing the President; but I must
                        confess, the thought that our request would be denied nerved me wonderfully,
                        and as much as I desired the honour, the Usher's "walk this way ladies," was
                        not altogether a pleasing summons; however, once in his Honour's presence,
                        greeted by a smile and a cordial grasp of the hand, it was possible in
                        homely country girl style to express our appreciation of the privilege. Was
                        it vanity that prompted me to believe his noble countenance brightened, when
                        told we were from the Valley of Virginia. Much as we admired the almost
                        sublime stand he has taken in this life struggle between a lacerated,
                        bleeding country and political aspirants, we were not prepared to find a
                        personage so affable and a reception so near akin to Old Virginia
                        hospitality. While showing us his Library, and calling our attention to the
                        beautiful view of the Potomac from that point, he spoke tenderly of the
                        Country's present and future, and expressed a determination to do his duty
                        and leave the result to an All Wise Ruler of Nations. When we took our
                        leave, he kindly presented us with photographs, which we hold in the most
                        profound reverence. While reflecting upon the sentiments he so nobly
                        uttered, and reviewing his Official conduct, we were constrained to believe
                        that, with such a President all the power of a <emph rend="italic"
                        >fiendish</emph>Congress cannot destroy the Country. Pardon me! - This
                        letter has grown fearfully. If you desire to hear from me again, cheer my
                        mountain retreat by <emph rend="italic">your</emph>coming.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article briefly describes a journey made by a Virginia girl through
                    parts of the state and finally to Washington D.C. for an audience with President
                    Johnson. She gives descriptions of a meeting with citizens of Alexandria who
                    proudly display a chair once used by R.E. Lee in the field and a trip to the
                    church where George Washington worshipped. Most interesting is her report on the
                    Smithsonian Institute, which details as well as judges non-Christian cultures.
                    Describing a visit to the Executive Mansion, her opinion of the President is
                    favorable, and she predicts that Johnson will not allow Congress to destroy the
                    country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>White Labor of All Kinds</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gen. J. D. Imboden has begun an agency for procuring white labor. "It takes
                    population, white people, to build up a country; that we have the best country
                    on God's earth and we only want labor. A thickly settled white country means
                    power."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Christmas in the Mountains</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Brown Hill, Augusta Co., VA,<lb/> 13th January, 1868.</p>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR:--I wish I could write you a good letter, one worthy a place in
                        the columns of the Virginian. There is enough to tell, but I can't think of
                        it. Our new home is surrounded by those great grey mountains that stand off
                        to the west of Staunton like sentinels. I remember, when I was a young girl
                        in the A. F. Seminary, if I felt weary after the recitations of the day, I
                        would turn my back on all indoors, and seating myself at one of the windows
                        that looked to the west, I would gaze upon the mountains bathed in the glory
                        of an autumn sunset, "solemn, yet beautiful to behold."</p>
                    <p>But it was not of the old home that I started to write, but of our new one
                        here in the mountains. "Cold, bleak region," you call it? Now let me tell
                        you, despite all privations, we do manage to enjoy ourselves sometimes. The
                        country is thinly settled, and facilities for "getting around" are scarce;
                        yet I dare say, your city belles can't boast of a gayer Christmas than we
                        had. The beauty and chivalry of the country spent one night in mirth and
                        dancing. As I looked around on the company there assembled, memory stole
                        back to the happy Christmas of '66; many of that company were then mere
                        children, and many more were dwellers in fair city homes. I wonder if two
                        years have changed my old home as much? On New Year's day we were honored
                        with an invitation to a Darkey wedding. After witnessing the very amusing
                        ceremony, the <emph rend="italic">white folks</emph> were invited into "Old
                        Massa's" kitchen, where an ample repast was spread. Now I would like to make
                        people believe this was a little paradise, might even convince myself of it,
                        did I not so long for my old home and friends.</p>
                    <p>More Anon.<lb/> Lina</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Lina" writes the Valley Virginian with a description of Christmas in the
                    mountains near Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.01.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Thomas P. Jackson remains Chief of the Freedmen's Bureau for Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. C. R. Harris will lecture at the Staunton Lyceum on Friday night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Fire Company met recently. The paper urges citizens to donate money to
                    the organization, since it is a great boon to property holders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayland</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>E. A. Wayland and Joseph N. Woodward of Augusta have declared themselves
                    bankrupt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Registration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Higgs</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain A. F. Higgs, Military Commissioner for the district including
                    Augusta, visited Staunton last week. The people of Albemarle recommend him
                    highly. He appointed W. McCutcheon President of the Augusta Board of
                    Registration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Revolution in the Iron Business of the World</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moorman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. Howe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lorenzo Sibert's "Sibert Process" will revolutionize the manufacture of
                    steel. The Staunton foundry of Nelson, Moorman and Company cast some farming
                    tools using the method that proved "far superior to anything now in use."
                    Locomotive tires will be tested next on the Virginia Central Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. John Richardson, Conductor on the Virginia Central Railroad, and Miss
                    Sallie Brown, daughter of Judge Samuel B. Brown, formerly of Staunton, were
                    married on January 21st by the Rev. Mr. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleveland</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trowers</ln>
                        <fn>Alice T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Broadus</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>R. W. Cleveland of Staunton and Miss Alice T. Trowers of Charlottesville
                    were married on January 22nd by the Rev. Dr. Broadus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry H. Taylor of Rockbridge and Miss Mary J. Price of Augusta were
                    married on January 2nd by the Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>Robert T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major Robert T. Poage died near Mt. Sidney on January 11th. "He leaves a
                    disconsolate widow and an infant daughter."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn>Eli H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eli H. Parrent died at the Staunton residence of his daughter, Mrs.
                    Gillock, on January 12th. He was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Forrer died near Mossy Creek on January 2nd after a short illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stubbs</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Ann Stubbs died in Staunton on January 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.01.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
