<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.11.21">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>09/02/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1866-11-21">
			<year>1866</year>
			<month norm="11"/>
			<day norm="00">21</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>4</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.11.21.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Homely Girls</head>
				<origin>Cleveland Herald</origin>
				<commentary>"The editor of the Cleveland Herald, having been tolerably profuse in
					his compliments ot the pretty girls of Cleveland, has been requested to say a
					good thing in behalf of the homely ones, and he does it thus:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The editor of the Cleveland <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph>, having been
						tolerably profuse in his compliments to the pretty girls of Cleveland, has
						been requested to say a good thing in behalf of the homely ones, and he does
						it this: </p>
					<p>First--The homely girls of Cleveland are in a hopeless minority, but they
						mean well.</p>
					<p>Second--They go to Church every Sunday, and are fond of their meals. They had
						rather have their meals regularly than new bonnets.</p>
					<p>Third--They understand their business and wear No. 5 gaiters.</p>
					<p>Fourth--They are bright, intelligent, devoid of low jealousy, fond of music,
						dance at parties as though it was the chief end of life, and always go in
						when it rains.</p>
					<p>Fifth--They always thank the gentlemen for giving them seats in street cars;
						never flirt with the boys, because it is out of their line, and keep out of
						the fire.</p>
					<p>Sixth--They never have half a dozen young sprigs keeping company with them.</p>
					<p>Seventh--They wash their own handkerchiefs, iron their own collars, and darn
						their own stockings.</p>
					<p>Eighth--They never wear waterfalls that weigh over one hundred and fifty
						pounds and have neither "rats" nor other animals in the hair.</p>
					<p>Ninth--They don't call the young trash "perfectly splendid."</p>
					<p>Tenth--They never eat between meals.</p>
					<p>Eleventh--They are all going to get married.</p>
					<p>Twelfth--They will all marry well.</p>
					<p>Thirteenth--Their children will be bright and shining lights in the world.</p>
					<p>Fourteenth--They won't keep hired girls till their husbands can afford them.</p>
					<p>Fifteenth--They sleep under the musquito bars when convenient.</p>
					<p>Sixteenth--They can make coffee and nut cakes, and can do chamberwork.</p>
					<p>Seventeenth--They are O. K.</p>
					<p>Hurrah for the fellow who wrote that.--His head is level. We like homely
						girls ourself, with their quiet, kind, and cheerful ways. We endorse
					them.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article lists the various attributes of "homely girls."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.11.21.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>What of the Future</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>In less than two weeks from now Congress or what purports to be a Congress
						will again assemble. What extravagant and revolutionary legislation may be
						enacted by this "rump" body during the coming session it is impossible to
						predict. But what it will be bad enough in all conscience we may rest
						assured. Whether they will undertake to impeach the President will depend
						very much on circumstances. If they can carry out their designs without
						impeachment they will forbear to resort to that extreme measure, but if
						their revolutionary purposes can be accomplished in no other way we have no
						doubt the counsels of Phillips, Butler &amp; Co. will prevail, and the
						country will be hurled anew into civil war; for it must not be supposed that
						the President would tamely submit to being tried by an illegal and
						unconstitutional tribunal, or that the conservative masses of the
						country--the real friends of the Union and the Constitution--would permit
						him to submit. If the radicals force this issue upon the country it will be
						the end of their ill--gotten power, for the honest people of the country
						will rally again in defence of the Union and crush out Northern disunionists
						as effectually as they did Southern disunionists, only it will be done in
						much less time. If a new war comes upon the country in this shape, it will
						be <emph rend="italic">in fact</emph> what the last was only <emph
							rend="italic">in name</emph>--a war for the Union. </p>
					<p>The late war was a war between the Radical leaders of the North and the
						Radical leaders of the South, for political power.--When the war was
						imminent in the spring or 1861, and the patriotic portion of the people of
						both sections were laboring to preserve the peace and unity of the country
						by compromise, the extremists North and South, interposed and prevented a
						settlement because it would have interfered with their schemes for power and
						plunder.</p>
					<p>The Radical leaders prevented a compromise at that time, because as they
						alleged, it would have disrupted the Republican party. They preferred the
						disruption of the Union to the disruption of their party, and through their
						criminal neglect to aid in averting the impending calamity, the country
						drifted into civil war. War with all its horrors having thus been brought
						upon the country, the patriotic masses of the North without stopping to
						inquire into the causes, flew to arms in defense of an imperiled government.
						The Radical leaders, to make their ulterior designs, bawled themselves
						hoarse with the cry of "Union."</p>
					<p>The war waged under false pretenses, so far as the political leaders who
						shaped the war policy of the government were concerned, but the patriotic
						masses who composed the rank and file of the Northern army, knowing only
						their duty to their country, fought the war through to a successful issue,
						fondly believing that a restored Union would be the reward of their perils
						and sacrifices. But in this they were mistaken. It is almost two years since
						the war closed, and yet we are to-day apparently further from the attainment
						of the <emph rend="italic">pretended</emph> object of the war than at the
						time of the surrender of the rebel armies. Why is this? It is because the
						same political leaders who, in 1861 prevented an amicable settlement to
						preserve the Union, for fear of disrupting the Republican party, are now
						arbitrarily and illegally preventing a restoration in order that they may
						retain their hold on political power. The arrant knavery and hypocrisy of
						these men, by which a too credulous people has been deceived during the past
						five years, is thus made manifest and exposed. </p>
					<p>The South went to war and were defeated. They acknowledge themselves whipt
						and accept the situation. They are anxious to return to the fold from which
						they vainly attempted to stray. They have given every evidence that could
						reasonably be asked of their present loyalty and good faith, and the
						conservative portion of the Northern people--the same who labored so
						devotedly in the winter and spring of 1861 to preserve the Union without
						bloodshed--are willing to receive them in order to restore perfect harmony
						again to the Union of our fathers, and that peace may once more smile upon
						the whole land, bringing prosperity and happiness to all its people.</p>
					<p>But this grand consummation, so devoutly wished for by all true patriots, is
						prevented by the infernal spirit of radicalism now dominant in the North.
						Its revolutionary leaders have usurped unlimited power in the Legislative
						branch of the government, and, in defiance of the plain mandates of the
						Constitution, stubbornly refuse to restore the Union themselves or permit
						its restoration by any other department of the government. Is the Union then
						to remain indefinitely divided because a conspiracy to that end exists among
						the Radical leaders of the North? This is the pregnant question which now
						presses itself upon the minds of the American people. This is the problem
						which must be solved in the near future.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>With Congress scheduled to convene in less than two weeks, the editor
					speculates on what lays in store for the country, and reaches the conclusion
					that, should the Radicals push through their agenda, another civil war may be
					imminent.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Senatorial Convention</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Our Republican friends held a Convention in the Court House of this place on
						Tuesday of last week to express the choice of Franklin county for United
						States Senator, and to instruct the Senator and Representatives from this
						district to vote accordingly. The Convention was tolerably full, and was
						managed in the interest of Curtis by our neighbor of the <emph rend="italic"
							>Repository</emph>, who was himself a delegate from Guilford township. </p>
					<p>The anti-Curtis forces were led by Col. Weistling, of Quincy, but it was
						evident from the start that the Curtin men had the concern too well "set up"
						to admit of any division that would be entitled to be designated as a
						contest. Col. Weistling played his part well. His tactics were good--we
						might say admirable--but unfortunately for his cause he had no votes to back
						them. On all test questions, on the call of the yeas and nays, there was an
						almost unanimous response as Col. McClure dictated. To be sure occasionally
						a weak brother would get a little mixed and seem not to know exactly how to
						vote, but a little prompting would invariably bring him all right. It was a
						dull and spiritless affair, being entirely too one-sided to be interesting.</p>
					<p>The <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> last week gave its readers a full
						report of the proceedings of this Convention, as understood by it and its
						friends. The Harrisburg <emph rend="italic">Telegraph</emph>, a few days
						ago, contained another and quite a different account, dated at Chambersburg
						and doubtless written by an ardent friend and admirer of the great
						"Winnebago Chief." As it is doubtful whether the <emph rend="italic"
							>Repository</emph>] will so far forget its prejudice as to publish the
							<emph rend="italic">Telegraph</emph> account, we have conceived it to be
						our duty, as lovers of fair dealing between belligerent neighbors, to
						transfer it entire to <emph rend="italic">our</emph> columns, so that the
						people of Franklin county may have an opportunity of seeing <emph
							rend="italic">both</emph> sides of this interesting controversy. Our
						love of justice, and respect for the defeated Winnebagoans of this vicinity
						would not permit us to stand idly by and see them driven to the wall by the
						merciless strategy of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>. We have
						therefore kindly and voluntarily opened our columns for their defence. We
						trust our conduct will be duly appreciated and that the friends of the
						tribal chief will ever hold us in grateful remembrance for interposing our
						kind offices in their behalf. We ask no higher reward. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Wiestling</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McClure</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Relates that local Republicans held a convention at the Court House last
					week where they selected Curtin as "the choice of Franklin county for United
					States Senator."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>The Impeachment of the President</head>
				<origin>Albany Journal</origin>
				<commentary>"The following very sensible article is from the Albany Journal, the
					central Radical organ of New York. We trust that its warning and its cautions
					will be heeded in the quarter in which they are addressed. If they are not, the
					darkest and worst chapter to the history of the country is about to open."</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Though taken from what is ostensibly a radical journal, the article argues
					that those in favor of President Johnson's impeachment represent the desires of
					an "exceedingly active minority" rather than the wishes of the American people.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="l">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>A Glimpse Behind the Mask</head>
				<origin>Charleston Recorder</origin>
				<commentary>"A colored Baptist minister at Beaufort, S. C., writes to the
					"Christrian Recorder."</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>"Some of our white ministerial friends do more in the way of procuring farms
						and keeping our poor race in ignorance than anything else. They pretend when
						they are North that they would come down here and do anything for our race
						in the way of enlightening them; but instead of this, when they see the
						cotton gag, they forget all about Christ and Him crucified, and the saving
						of souls," Of certain Northern Merchants, he says: "All they wish to do is,
						teach what President Lincoln has done, and pat the colored man on the
						shoulder with the left hand, while with the right hand they catch hold of
						his pocket book. And when they have got the last cent from him, their
						friendship suddenly ceases. Then, "he is only a nigger."</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Contains an extract of a letter reportedly written by a black Baptist
					minister from South Carolina that characterizes northerners who have come to the
					South to "enlighten" the freedmen as selfish individuals bent on exploiting
					blacks for personal gain.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="l">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>From Virginia</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer>Oglethorpe</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>In his letter, "Oglethorpe," a Virginian, laments the Democrats' defeat in
					the recent election in Pennsylvania.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head/>
				<origin>Griffin (Ga.) Star</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The brief piece notes, then denounces, the election of two black men to the
					Massachusetts Legislature.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>McClure--Curtin Convention</head>
				<origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>CHAMBERSBURG, NOV. 15, 1866.</p>
					<p>GEORGE BERGNER, <emph rend="italic">Editor, Harrisburg Telegraph</emph>: </p>
					<p>DEAR SIR:--I have been looking over your valuable paper for a full report of
						the so-called McClure-Curtin Convention, but failing to see any reference to
						it, I sit down to give <emph rend="italic">you</emph> a fair and truthful
						account of its proceedings. </p>
					<p>This Convention met on the 13th of Nov., for the avowed purpose of electing a
						United States Senator who could be handled like a puppet by our
						distinguished "Pete," alias "Horace." Curtin, being about to relinquish the
						Governor's chair, and the chances for our distinguished townsman to buy and
						sell the next Chief Magistrate of this State, of the next three years being
						rather small, he is now attempting to place his own man in the United States
						Senate for the purpose of speculating in national affairs. But, Mr. Editor,
						I am digressing from my first intentions, to sit down and give you a report
						of the proceedings of the McClure-Curtin Convention.</p>
					<p>Mr. McClure, the editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, labored
						assiduously, for the last several weeks to induce the Republicans of
						Franklin county to attend the delegate elections called at his instance, and
						express their sentiments for United States Senator. The elections were held
						throughout the county on Saturday last, Nov. 10, 1866, and the following is
						the actual result: </p>
					<table>
						<row>
							<cell/>
							<cell>Curtin</cell>
							<cell>Against</cell>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Chambersburg--N. W.</cell>
							<cell>117</cell>
							<cell>91</cell>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Whole Rep vote in ward</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
							<cell>395</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Chambersburg--S. W.</cell>
							<cell>113</cell>
							<cell>52</cell>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Whole Rep. vote in ward</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
							<cell>298</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Guilford township, the residence of "Pete"</cell>
							<cell>12</cell>
							<cell>8</cell>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Whole Republican vote</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
							<cell>230</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Antrim</cell>
							<cell>117</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Whole Republican vote</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
							<cell>550</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Washington</cell>
							<cell>14</cell>
							<cell>44</cell>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Whole Republican vote</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
							<cell>350</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Quincy</cell>
							<cell>12</cell>
							<cell>30</cell>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Whole Republican vote</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
							<cell>160</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Fayetteville</cell>
							<cell>17</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Whole Republican vote</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
							<cell>200</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Greene</cell>
							<cell>11</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Whole Republican vote</cell>
							<cell/>
							<cell/>
							<cell>150</cell>
						</row>
					</table>
					<p>These are all the townships that held a partial election, and it will be seen
						that scarcely one-twentieth of their regular Republican voters obeyed the
						mandate of McClure, to attend the delegate elections.</p>
					<p>In Orrstown ten persons attended <emph rend="italic">en mass</emph> meeting,
						and selected delegates. </p>
					<p>In Lurgan township, nine were present to go through the same operation.</p>
					<p>In Letterkenny, twelve noses were counted at the meeting.</p>
					<p>In Concord, four gentlemen presented themselves.</p>
					<p>At Sulphur Springs, five participated.</p>
					<p>In Metal township, twenty gentlemen were present.</p>
					<p>In Peters township ten voters participated.</p>
					<p>At St. Thomas thirteen were present.</p>
					<p>In Montgomery ten were in attendance.</p>
					<p>In Hamilton twelve were on hand.</p>
					<p>Warren township did not respond to "Pete's" call.</p>
					<p>Mount Rock did not hold a meeting.</p>
					<p>Welsh Run did not elect delegates.</p>
					<p>In Loudon eight gentlemen met and appointed delegates.</p>
					<p>Counting all the persons who participated in this movement we have the number
						of four hundred and seventy-three for Curtin. Against, two hundred and
						eighty-two. Fifty-three gentlemen voted for various delegates without giving
						any instructions to them.</p>
					<p>Thus you have a truthful statement of the interest manifested by four
						thousand two hundred and fifty Republicans of this county, who voted for the
						representatives to the next Legislature, at the last October election.</p>
					<p>When the delegates met, sixty-six gentlemen, self-constituted, met for the
						purpose of instructing the gentlemen elected by the Republican party from
						the counties of Franklin, Perry and Adams as to whom they should vote for
						United States Senator.</p>
					<p>The Convention was called to order, and Col. McGowan a law student of
						McClure's, was placed in the chair, to act as President. "Peter" rang his
						bell, and most of the delegates answered "yea" to all he said</p>
					<p>Wherever but one delegate appeared from a district, he was authorized to cast
						the full vote of the township or borough, and in this way McClure makes it
						appear that seventy-six delegates were present at the Convention.</p>
					<p>After this arduous duty performed by our friend, "Pete," the Convention
						agreed to dine.</p>
					<p>In the afternoon, "Pete" moved that the Convention proceed to nominate a
						candidate for United States Senator.</p>
					<p>Before this motion was seconded, Colonel Wiestling obtained the floor, and
						stated that he did not appear as the champion of any particular candidate
						for United States Senator, nor for the purpose of impugning the motives of
						any gentleman who had managed to call for the present Convention, nor to
						criticize the anticipated course of any one whom the action of this
						Convention was intended to effect, and spoke against the expediency of
						giving instructions to our Representatives, as to whom they should support
						for United States Senator. Col. W. closed by offering the following:</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That this convention recognize the right
						and legality of giving expression to the views of the people on the
						important political questions of the day; and also of the advising and
						instructing their servants, the public officers whom they place in power, as
						to their proper course of action with reference to such questions; but they
						also believe with St. Paul, that all things which are lawful may not be
						expedient. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That where important principles are at
						issue, or where local interest are at stake, it is right and expedient to
						give instructions to our Representatives as to their actions; but upon
						questions of personal preference such as the present one before this
						convention, we deem it unwise and inexpedient to give any instructions to
						our Representatives as to which of the Honorable gentlemen named for the
						position of U. S. Senator they shall give their votes. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That having confidence in the honesty
						and faithfulness of the officers we have elected, we place implicit trust in
						their discretion and judgement to do what is best for the best interests of
						our State. </p>
					<p>"Peter" did not relish those resolutions, and spoke briefly against them.</p>
					<p>On the call of the yeas and nays, Quincy township voted a solid <emph
							rend="italic">yea</emph>. Some two or three others voted the same, but
						"Peter" had the convention "set up" so completely that the resolutions were
						negatived. </p>
					<p>After this, the convention went through the formality of nominating and
						electing the next United States Senator, and, of course, "Peter's" friend
						Curtin, with whom as rumor has it, he divided a <emph rend="italic">big
							thing</emph> when the tonnage tax, Sumbury and Erie, and other big jobs
						were run through the Legislature, carried on the palm, and is now elected U.
						S. Senator by his distinguished servant, "Peter." </p>
					<p>The loyal citizens of Pennsylvania need not fear that the 473 Curtin men of
						Franklin county will frighten the Representatives from this district. They
						will discharge their duty faithfully, and select such a man for U. S.
						Senator, as will satisfy and represent the true sentiments and feelings of
						the Republicans of this State.</p>
					<p>I will merely mention one fact to show your readers who M'Clure managed the
						delegates. One delegate appeared from Washington township. He was instructed
						to cast the seven votes from that township for Mr. Stevens, and he obeyed,
						at first, his instructions. But "Peter" induced him (by what means your
						correspondent knoweth not) to vote for Curtin.</p>
					<p>I have one word in reply to the Harrisburg correspondent of the Chambersburg
							<emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, who signs himself "Horace," <emph
							rend="italic">alias</emph> "Pete." He says that the card published in
						your paper is a libel on Colonel Stumbaugh, and a fraud upon the people. If
						this is so, Colonel Stumbaugh ought certainly to prosecute you for libel,
						and then he might follow the example of "Peter"--threaten you for tow or
						three terms of court with a violent prosecution of his case, and then step
						up magnanimously, enter a <emph rend="italic">nolle prosequi</emph>, and
						give his counsel money to pay costs of all proceedings had. Such things have
						been done in Franklin county, and they might be repeated in yours. </p>
					<p>I have merely given you the above hasty sketch of the proceedings of the
						Convention held in this town so that the people may not be misled with
						representations that Franklin county has instructed her Representatives for
						any man. They have been elected by the Republicans of this district, who
						have the utmost confidence in them, and they will discharge their duties
						without listening to the mandates of a corrupt faction.</p>
					<p>ADAM</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>Adam</trailer>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McClure</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wiestling</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Provides a recap of the results from the Republican State, or so-called
					"McClure--Curtin," Convention.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.11.21.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--A Dangerous Counterfeit</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that a "new and dangerous" $50 counterfeit note is circulating.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a ">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Fatal Accident</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hassler</ln>
						<fn>Laura</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hassler</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Maj.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gordon</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn>Harriet</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 10th, a terrible accident occurred one mile west of McConnellsburg
					that left Laura Hassler dead and Harriet Baker seriously injured. The two women
					were riding in their buggy, accompanied by the son of John Gordon, when the
					horse dashed off unexpectedly throwing them both to the ground.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Soldier Monument in Path Valley</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Walker</ln>
						<fn>John H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Capt.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Campbell</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gaston</ln>
						<fn>T. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wolff</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>West</ln>
						<fn>William A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>J. Gordon</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ferguson</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gehr</ln>
						<fn>George W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports on the unveiling of the Soldiers' Monument in Path Valley, which
					was organized by Capt. John H. Walker, William Campbell, T. R. Gaston, and John
					Wolff. During the event, Rev. William West, Rev. J. Gordon Smith, Rev. G.
					Ferguson, and George W. Gehr delivered speeches.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Dedication Meeting</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Dickson</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Rev. J. Dickson announces that the new church in Marion will be dedicated
					on Dec. 2nd.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Fire and Arrests</head>
				<origin>Shippensburg News</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McClure</ln>
						<fn>R. P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Butts</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Justice</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Notes that two men were arrested in connection with the fire that destroyed
					R. P. McClure's barn on Nov. 14th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Richter</ln>
						<fn>J. D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Roth</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stoutagle</ln>
						<fn>Maggie S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 13th, J. D. Richter and Maggie S. Stoutagle were married by Rev. G.
					Roth.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Peiffer</ln>
						<fn>John A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Trautman</ln>
						<fn>Mary</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Roth</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 13th, John A. Peiffer and Mary Trautman were married by Rev. G.
					Roth.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Maymen</ln>
						<fn>George W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gossart</ln>
						<fn>Rebecca</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Dickson</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 13th, George W. Maymen, of Washington Co., Md., and Rebecca Gossart
					were married by Rev. J. Dickson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Heimel</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Darnfeld</ln>
						<fn>Kate</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Roth</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 13th, Henry Heimel and Kate Darnfeld were married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hassler</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hassler</ln>
						<fn>Laura Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 13th, Laura Elizabeth Hassler, daughter of John Hassler, died.
					Laura was 13 years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Spangler</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Spangler</ln>
						<fn>Charles</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Spangler</ln>
						<fn>Ann E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 18th, Charles, son of Jacob and Ann E. Spangler, died. Charles was
					3 years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Elliot</ln>
						<fn>Catherine</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 10th, Catherine Elliot, 80, died.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Campbell</ln>
						<fn>Rebecca</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Campbell</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 14th, Rebecca Campbell, relict of Thomas Campbell, Esq., died at
					age 83.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Brake</ln>
						<fn>Malinda</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brake</ln>
						<fn>John S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brake</ln>
						<fn>Franklin Kurtz</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 11th, Franklin Kurtz, son of John S. and Malinda Brake, died at 2
					years of age.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Campbell</ln>
						<fn>James Irwin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 7th, James Irwin Campbell, 32, died.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.11.21.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
