<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.12.26">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>09/17/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1866-12-26">
			<year>1866</year>
			<month norm="12">December</month>
			<day norm="00">26</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.12.26.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.12.26.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The Democratic Party Vindicated</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The great issue between the Democratic and Republican parties during the war,
						related to the power assumed by the general government to arrest civilians
						"without due process of law," and try them before illegal military
						commissions. The Democratic party, earnestly protested against this
						assumption on the part of a Republican administration, as a flagrant
						infraction of one of the plainest provisions of the Constitutions,
						destructive of the personal rights of the citizens as guaranteed by that
						sacred instrument, dangerous to public liberty and tending directly to over
						throw of our free institutions. This was the main issue between the two
						parties during the war. The Republican party threw aside the Constitution as
						a thing [UNCLEAR] for the emergencies of civil war, and proceeded to assume
						all sorts of unwarranted and extraordinary powers, being governed solely by
						what they chose to call "military necessity." Under the [UNCLEAR] of
						"necessity" persons were arrested all over the loyal States upon vague
						suspicion that they were in sympathy with the rebellion, or upon the false
						information of spies and pimps of the administration, without having
						afforded them an opportunity disproving the charges preferred against them,
						or even of knowing what the charges were; or else they were taken before an
						illegal Military Commission, "organized to convict," and either hung or sent
						to the Dry Tortugas to undergo an imprisonment at hard labor during the
						continuance of the war.--It is needless to cite instances of proof of what
						we allege. The facts are too well known to the country.</p>
					<p>Against these gross outrages and usurpations the Democratic party solemnly
						protested. They contended that the Constitution was the supreme law of the
						land; that it was intended by its authors to meet every emergency of war as
						well as peace, and that any departure from its teachings or violation of its
						requirements by those sworn to "protect and defend" it, was usurpation.--For
						its defence of the Constitution and the liberties of the people under it,
						the Democratic party was everywhere denounced as disloyal, and in sympathy
						with treason.--absurd and paradoxical as the proposition is, to defend the
						Constitution was to defend treason in the eyes of the party in power.--So
						far did the bold usurpers at Washington lead the people astray that the
						Democratic party really became odious on account of its heroic defence of
						the great chart of human freedom. It was worth a man's liberty, not to say
						his life, to speak out boldly in defence of the chartered rights of American
						citizens. The citizens of our own community have not yet forgotten the time
						when a certain "A. S. Ashmead, Lieutenant and Provost Marshal" ruled the
						town of Chambersburg and vicinity with despotic sway, enforcing his illegal
						orders with bayonets in the hands of a "Provost Guard" composed of Baltimore
						plug nglies. All must remember how he picked up peaceable and unoffending
						citizens on our streets, and sent them off under guard on the first train to
						his master at Baltimore, the redoubtable Gen. Schneck, to undergo a mock
						trial before a "Military Commission," and to be sent across the lines or
						suffer some other infamous and illegal punishment. And when we ventured in
						these columns to protest against those outrages on the personal rights and
						liberty of our citizens, we were waited upon by this military [UNCLEAR] ,
						with all the pomp of an eastern Bashaw, and notified that, unless we
						refrained from criticizing his conduct and actions in the future, we
						likewise would be arrested and have assigned to us a quarters in Fort
						McHnery. Thus were the personal rights of the citizen violated with impunity
						during the reign of "military necessity" and "military commissions." We have
						referred to transactions which took place in our midst because our people
						are familiar with the facts. Other and still greater outrages were committed
						in other sections of the country, in the name of "military necessity." The
						blood of hundreds of american citizens who were murdered by these illegal
						commissions cries aloud from the grave for vengeance against the usurpers at
						Washington under whose authority these things were done.</p>
					<p>But, notwithstanding the odium which attached to the Democratic party for its
						noble defence of the rights of the people, during the perilous times through
						which we have passed, the day of its vindication has at last come. the
						highest judicial tribunal of the country--the Supreme Court of the United
						States--has just rendered a decision affirming, in the most positive terms,
						the position of the Democratic party on the right of military commissions to
						try civilians. The Supreme Court declare all such trials to be illegal and
						unconstitutional. the case in which the decision is given, is known to the
						country as the "Indiana Conspiracy Case." Several citizens of the State of
						Indiana were arrested by the military authorities in 1864, for conspiracy,
						tried before a military commission and sentenced to be hung. Before the day
						fixed for their execution, their sentence was commuted by President Johnson
						to imprisonment for life. The case was then brought before the United States
						Circuit Court for Indiana, on a writ of <emph rend="italic">habeas
						corpus</emph>, for the discharge of the prisoners. The two Circuit Judges
						being divided in opinion, the case was certified to the Supreme Court, where
						the final decision was rendered as above referred to. </p>
					<p>The opinion of the Court refers to the importance of observing the
						constitutional guarantees for the protection of the citizen in his person
						and property, and declares that the "experience of our past history shows
						the wisdom of the framers of the Constitution, in constructing it to be
						alike efficient in war as in peace." The learned Judge who delivered the
						opinion then continues: "The powers of the Constitution should bot be
						strained to suit emergencies, for on its maintenance in all its integrity,
						depend our liberties and fee government, not only in the present, but for
						all time to come."</p>
					<p>What Democrat does not feel an honest pride in being a member of that
						glorious old time-honored party, whose position on a fundamental question of
						constitutional government is thus judicially endorsed by the highest Court
						in the land? What better vindication could it ask? and what higher monument
						to its patriotism and fidelity to law?</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>In the wake of the Supreme Court's decision in the "Indiana Conspiracy
					case," it has become clear, says the Spirit's editor, that the Democrats were
					justified in their opposition to the use of military commissions to try
					civilians.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Attacking The Supreme Court</head>
				<origin>Washington Chronicle</origin>
				<commentary>"Forney's Washington Chronicle has the following bold attack on the late
					decision of the Supreme Court in the "Indiana Conspiracy case:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>It can scarcely fail to shock the sensibilities and provoke the severe rebuke
						of loyal men everywhere. The exultation of <emph rend="italic"
						>Intelligencer</emph> over it will awaken a jubilance echo throughout
						rebeldom, and the hearts of traitors will be made glad by the announcement
						that treason, vanquished upon the battle-field, and hunted from every other
						retreat, has at last found a secure shelter in the bosom of the Supreme
						Court. </p>
					<p>The military commission thus denounced as usurpation has existed as a
						legitimate instrumentality, in the hands of the war-making power, from the
						foundation of the government: It has again and again been recognized by
						Congress composed of the greatest statesmen, jurists and patriots of the
						nation, and has been constantly employed by all our most illustrious
						generals as a potent agency for the suppression of the rebellion. President
						Lincoln, himself an able lawyer, and, as a Chief Magistrate, most careful of
						human life, confirmed and executed the death sentences of this tribunal in
						numberless cases. Yet we are now told that all this array of learning and
						patriotism, and experience and loyalty, which has given unhesitating support
						to the military commission is to be held for naught in the presence of a
						single voice of the Supreme Court. The bravest, truest and wisest men of the
						land, who have used this tribunal in defense of the national life, are thus
						branded as felons and we are now told that the real criminals of the war
						were not the traitors, spies, guerillas, and assassins tried, but the
						patriots who tried them. This extraordinary decision will doubtless receive
						the attention of Congress at an early day.</p>
					<p>"<emph rend="italic">This extraordinary decision will doubtless receive the
							attention of Congress at an early day</emph>!" Was such a sentiment ever
						uttered before in this land of constitutional government? Just think of
						Congress sitting in judgement on the decisions of the Supreme Court! Is
						there any further evidence needed to prove that the radicals intend to
						revolutionize this government? We think not. If it were not for the serious
						dangers threatening the permanency of our foe from government through these
						revolutionary doctrines now being pressed upon the country by the radicals,
						the absurdity of the above propositions would be really amusing. </p>
					<p>The <emph rend="italic">Age</emph>, in commenting on the above extract from
						the <emph rend="italic">Chronicle</emph> says: "This attack upon the Supreme
						Court for acting strictly within its line of sworn duty shows what the
						anti-constitutional party are prepared to do in order to carry out their
						plans. All the judges of the court agreed that in the particular case before
						them the "military commission" was a "usurpation." Chief Justice Chase said
						that Congress gave no power to try the accused by a 'military commission;"
						but, on the contrary, he had made express provisions for the adudication of
						such cases before the civil courts." In this state of facts, a military
						commission, in open defiance alike of the Constitution and an express
						statute of Congress, proceeded to try, condemn and order for execution a
						citizen of Indiana. That was an illegal act, an usurpation of power, and it
						could not be made either legal or constitutional by the acts of General
						Hovey, General Hooker, or the late President of the United States, Mr.
						Lincoln. The Supreme Court of the nation is the final arbiter, and in this
						case they have rested their decision upon such facts and principles as must
						command the respect and support of every man in the nation who is not
						blinded by passion and willing to overthrow all law and order, and leave the
						dearest rights of American citizens, those affecting their lives and
						liberties, at the mercy of any political faction that may happen to be in
						the ascendancy at any particular period in the history of the nation. </p>
					<p>The last sentence of the article copied from the <emph rend="italic"
							>Chronicle </emph>, which is promulgated in advance in order to give the
						cue to the Radical press, contains a threat that is full of meaning. "This
						extraordinary decision will doubtless receive the attention of Congress at
						an early day," means that congressional action will be evoked to prevent the
						Supreme Court form championing the Constitution and the rights of citizens
						under that instrument. If the President defends the States or the people
						against the usurpations of Congress, he is threatened with impeachment, the
						"block and the axe," and when the Supreme Court assumes a position on the
						same broad line of sworn duty, Congress is called upon to review its
						decisions at an early day. This part of the Radical plot against the union
						and the rights of citizens under the Constitution, and hence the eagerness
						and ferocity with which it is defended by the <emph rend="italic"
						>Chronicle</emph>, hence the indecent attack made upon the Supreme Court by
						the allegation that treason has "at last found a secure shelter" in that
						august tribunal. </p>
					<p>The line that separates Radicals from the friends and defenders of a
						constitutional form of government in this nation is daily becoming more
						distinctly marked. The Supreme Court, in this case of Milligan, has but
						affirmed principles recognized as sound, legal and constitutional by lawyers
						and statement of all parties, and yet for so doing they are denounced and
						their motives are assailed in a most indefensible manner. This shows the
						drift of Radical opposition to the continuance of a form of government where
						life, liberty and property are protected by sure constitutional provisions,
						and should arouse the attention of freemen to the real designs of this
						dangerous faction."</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Denounces the Washington Chronicle, a Republican journal, for running an
					article that rebukes the Supreme Court for its judgement in the Indiana
					Conspiracy case.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Gen. Grant Taught A Lesson In Loyalty</head>
				<origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
				<commentary>"The ex-mule contractors, ex-office holders and ex-speculators in the
					necessities of the government, who write the editorials of the Harrisburg
					Telegraph, (Geary's home organ--owned by Cameron) have been giving General
					Ulysses S. Grant a lecture on loyalty and honor. The following appeared as
					editorial in that sheet on the 9th:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article criticizes the Harrisburg Telegraph for asserting that Gen.
					Grant is disloyal because he endorsed Gen. Pickett's application for pardon.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Trial by Military Commission--Decision by the U. S. Supreme Court</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Provides a synopsis of the Supreme Court's decision in the Indiana case,
					which also includes the dissenting opinions of Justices Chase, Wayne, Swayne,
					and Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>A Petition of White Men Presented to Congress</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Senator Saulsbury, of Delaware, introduced a petition challenging the
					constitutionality of the Congressional Act that grants black men the vote in the
					District of Columbia, but denies that same privilege to white immigrants who
					have not resided in the country for five years.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.12.26.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Give Us Railroad Time</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>To make things easier for railroad passengers, the brief piece suggests
					that the clock in the Court House should be set so that it is in sync with the
					clock at the depot.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Deardorf</ln>
						<fn>Daniel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hess</ln>
						<fn>Lizzie J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Schneck</ln>
						<fn>B. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 18th, Daniel Deardorf and Lizzie J. Hess were married by Rev. B. S.
					Schneck.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>John Y.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hess</ln>
						<fn>Sue E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Schneck</ln>
						<fn>B. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 20th, John Y. Miller and Sue E. Hess were married by Rev. B. S.
					Schneck.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Lane</ln>
						<fn>Joshua</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Neal</ln>
						<fn>Joshua</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>S. H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 18th, Joshua Lane and Mary Neal were married by Rev. S. H. C.
					Smith.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Rhinehart</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Greenawalt</ln>
						<fn>Godfrey</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Zettle</ln>
						<fn>Carrie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>S. H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 30th, at the residence of Mr. Rhinehart, Godfrey Greenawalt and
					Carrie Zettle were married by Rev. S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shields</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. Keller</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sackman</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rames</ln>
						<fn>Charlotte</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 19th, at the residence of Mr. Shields, Joseph Sackman and Charlotte
					M. Rames were married by Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Yankey</ln>
						<fn>Leander</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. Keller</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Yankey</ln>
						<fn>Leander</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Slaughentraup</ln>
						<fn>Amanda</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 20th, Leander Yankey and Amanda Slaughentraup were married by Rev.
					J. Keller Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Blankey</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 18th, William Blankey, 75, died in Greenvillage.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Sheffler</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sheffler</ln>
						<fn>Catherine Ann</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Thompson</ln>
						<fn>William J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Thompson</ln>
						<fn>R. T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 13th, Catherine Ann, daughter of Dr. William J. and R. T. Thompson
					and wife of James Sheffler, died in Rossville, Indiana at age 37.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Thompson</ln>
						<fn>W. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sheffler</ln>
						<fn>Catherine</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 15th, Dr. W. G. Thompson, 37, died in Rossville, Indiana, having
					moved from Franklin county 2 months to attend his sister. Dr. Thompson passed
					away 2 days after the death of Catherine, the result of hemmorage.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.12.26.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
