<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.12.12">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>09/08/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1866-12-12">
			<year>1866</year>
			<month norm="12">December</month>
			<day norm="00">12</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.12.12.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>The President's Message</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Fellow-citizens of the Senate and House of
							Representatives"</emph>: </p>
					<p>After a brief interval the Congress of the United States resumes its annual
						legislative labors. An all-wise and merciful Providence has abated the
						pestilence which visited our shores, leaving its calamitous traces upon some
						portions of our country. Peace, order, tranquility, and civil authority have
						been formally declared to exist throughout the whole of the United States.
						In all of the States civil authority has superseded the coercion of arms,
						and the people, by their voluntary action, are maintaining their Governments
						in full activity and complete operation. The enforcement of the laws is no
						longer "obstructed in any State by combinations too powerful to be
						suppressed by the ordinary course of judicial proceedings;" and the
						animosities engendered by the war are rapidly yielding to the beneficent
						influences of our free institutions, and to the kindly effects of
						unrestricted social and commercial intercourse. An entire restoration of
						fraternal feeling must be the earnest wish of every patriotic heart; and we
						will have accomplished our grandest national achievement when, forgetting
						the sad events of the past, and remembering only their instructive lessons,
						we resume our onward career as a free, prosperous, and united people.</p>
					<p>In my message of the 4th of December, 1865, Congress was informed of the
						measures which had been instituted by the Executive with a view to the
						gradual restoration of the States in which the insurrection occurred to
						their relations with the General Government. Provisional Governors had been
						appointed, Conventions called, Governors elected, Legislatures assembled,
						and Senators and Representatives chosen to the Congress of the United
						States. Courts had been opened for the enforcement of laws long in abeyance.
						The blockade had been removed, custom houses re-established, and the
						internal revenue laws put in force, in order that the people might
						contribute to the national income. Postal operations had been renewed, and
						efforts were being made to restore them to their former condition of
						efficiency. The States themselves had been asked to take part in the high
						functions of amending the Constitution, and of thus sanctioning the
						extinction of African slavery as one of the legitimate results of our
						internecine struggle.</p>
					<p>Having progressed thus far, the Executive Department found that it had
						accomplished nearly all that was within the scope of its constitutional
						authority. One thing, however, yet remained to be done before the work of
						restoration could be completed, and that was the admission to Congress of
						loyal Senators and Representatives from the States whose people had rebelled
						against the lawful authority of the General Government. This question
						devolved upon the respective Houses, which by the Constitution, are made the
						judges of the elections, returns, and qualifications of their own members;
						and its consideration at once engaged the attention of Congress.</p>
					<p>In the meantime, the Executive Department--no other plan having been proposed
						by Congress--continued its efforts to perfect, as far as was practicable,
						the restoration of the proper relations between the citizens of the
						respective States, and the States, and the Federal Government, extending
						from time to time, as the public interests seemed to require, the judicial,
						revenue, and postal systems of the country. With the advice and consent of
						the Senate, the necessary officers were appointed, and appropriations made
						by Congress for the payment of their salaries. The proposition to amend the
						Federal Constitution, so as to prevent the existence of slavery within the
						United States or any place subject to their jurisdiction, was ratified by
						the requisite number of States; and on the 18th of December, 1865, it was
						officially declared to have become valid as a part of the Constitution of
						the United States. All of the States in which the insurrection had existed
						promptly amended their Constitutions, so as to make them conform to the
						great change thus effected in the organic law of the land; declared null and
						void all ordinances and laws of secession; repudiated all pretended debts
						and obligations created for the revolutionary purposes of the insurrection;
						and proceeded in good faith, to the enactment of measures for the protection
						and amelioration of the condition of the colored race. Congress, however,
						yet hesitated to admit any of these States to representation; and it was not
						until towards the close of the eighth month of the session that an exception
						was made in favor of Tennessee, by the admission of her Senators and
						Representatives.</p>
					<p>I deem it a subject of profound regret that Congress has thus far failed to
						admit to seats loyal Senators and Representatives from the other States,
						whose inhabitants, with those of Tennessee, had engaged in the rebellion.
						Ten States--more than one-fourth of the whole number--remain without
						representation; the seats of fifty members in the House of Representatives
						and of twenty members in the Senate are yet vacant--not by their own
						consent, not by a failure of election, but by the refusal of Congress to
						accept their credentials. Their admission, it is believed, would have
						accomplished much towards the renewal and strengthening of our relations as
						one people, and removed serious cause for discontent on the part of the
						inhabitants of those States. It would have accorded with the great principle
						enunciated in the Declaration of American Independence, that no people ought
						to bear the burden of taxation, and yet denied the right of representation.
						It would have been in consonance with the express provisions of the
						Constitution, that "each State shall have at least one Representative," and
						"that no State without its consent, shall be deprived of its equal suffrage
						in the Senate." These provisions were intended to secure to every State, and
						to the people of every State the right of representation in each House of
						Congress; and so important was it deemed by the framers of the Constitution
						that the equality of the States in the Senate should be preserved, that not
						even by an amendment to the Constitution can any State, without its consent,
						be denied a voice in that branch of the National Legislature.</p>
					<p>It is true, it has been assumed that the existence of the States was
						terminated by the rebellious acts of their inhabitants, and that the
						insurrection having been suppressed, they were thenceforward to be
						considered merely as conquered territories. The Legislative, Executive, the
						Judicial Departments of the Government have, however, with great
						distinctness and uniform consistency, refused to sanction an assumption so
						incompatible with the nature of our republican system, and with the
						professed objects of the war. Throughout the recent legislation of Congress,
						the undeniable fact makes itself apparent, that these ten political
						communities are nothing less than States of this Union. At the very
						commencement of the rebellion, each House declared, with a unanimity as
						remarkable as it was significant, that the war was not "waged, upon our
						part, in any spirit of oppression, nor for any purpose of conquest or
						subjugation, nor purpose of overthrowing or interfering with the rights or
						established institution of those States, but to defend and maintain the
						supremacy of the Constitution and all laws made in pursuance thereof, and to
						preserve the Union with all dignity, equality, and rights of the several
						states unimpaired; and that as soon as these objects "were" accomplished the
						war to cease." In some instances, Senators were permitted to continue their
						legislative functions, while in other instances Representatives were elected
						and admitted to seats after their States had formally declared their right
						to withdraw from the Union, and were endeavoring to maintain that right by
						force of arms. All of the States whose people were in insurrection, as
						States, were included in the apportionment of the direct tax of twenty
						millions of dollars annually laid upon the united States by the act approved
						5th August, 1861. Congress, by the act of March 4, 1862, and by the
						apportionment of representation thereunder, also recognized their presence
						as States in the Union: and they have, for judicial purposes, been divided
						into districts as States alone can be divided. The same recognition appears
						in the recent legislation in reference to Tennessee, which evidently rests
						upon the fact that the functions of the State were not destroyed by the
						rebellion, but merely suspended; and that principle is of course applicable
						to those States which, like Tennessee, attempted to renounce their places in
						the Union.</p>
					<p>The action of the Executive Department of the Government upon this subject
						has been equally definite and uniform, and the purpose of the war was
						specifically stated in the proclamation issued by my predecessor on the 22d
						day of September 1862. It was then solemnly proclaimed and declared that
						hereafter, as heretofore, the war will be prosecuted for the object of
						practically restoring the constitutional relations between the United States
						and each of the States and the people thereof, in which States that relation
						is or may be suspended or disturbed."</p>
					<p>The recognition of the States by the Judicial Department of the Government
						has also been clear and conclusive in all proceedings affecting them as
						States, had in the Supreme, Circuit and District Courts.</p>
					<p>In the admission of Senators and Representatives from any and all of the
						States, there can be no just ground of apprehension that persons who are
						disloyal will be clothed with the powers of legislation; for this could not
						happen when the Constitution and laws are enforced by a vigilant and
						faithful Congress. Each House is made the "judge of the elections, returns,
						and qualifications of its own members:" and may, "with the concurrence of
						two-thirds, expel a member." When a Senator or Representative presents his
						certificate of election, he may at once be admitted or rejected; or, should
						there be any question as to his eligibility, his credentials may be referred
						for investigation to the appropriate committee. If admitted to a seat, it
						must be upon evidence satisfactory to the House of which he thus becomes a
						member, that he possesses the requisite constitutional and legal
						qualifications. If refused admission as a member for want of due allegiance
						to the Government, and returned to his constituents, they are admonished
						that none but loyal to the Untied States will be allowed a voice in the
						Legislative Councils of the Nation, and the political power and moral
						influence of Congress are thus effectively exerted in the interests of
						loyalty to the Government and fidelity to the Union. Upon this question, so
						vitally affecting the restoration of the Union and the permanency of our
						present form of Government, my convictions heretofore expressed, have
						undergone no change; but on the contrary their correctness have been
						confirmed by reflection and time. If the admission of loyal members to seats
						in the respective Houses of Congress was wise and expedient a year ago, it
						is no less wise and expedient now. If this anomalous condition is right
						now--if, in the exact condition of these States at the present time, it is
						lawful to exclude them from representation, I do not see that the question
						will be charged by the efflux of time. Ten years hence, if these States
						remain as they are, the right of representation will be no stronger--the
						right of exclusion will be no weaker.</p>
					<p>The Constitution of the United States makes it the duty of the President to
						recommend to the consideration of Congress "such measures as he shall judge
						necessary or expedient." I know of no measure more imperatively demanded by
						every consideration of national interest, sound policy and equal justice,
						than the admission of loyal members from the now unrepresented States. This
						would consummate the work of restoration, and exert a most salutary
						influence in the re-establishment of peace, harmony, and fraternal feeling.
						It would tend greatly to renew the confidence of the American people in the
						vigor and stability of their institutions. It would bind us more closely
						together as a nation, and enable us to show to the world the inherent and
						recuperative power of a Government founded upon the will of the people, and
						established upon the principles of liberty, justice, and intelligence. Our
						increased strength and enhanced prosperity would irrefragably demonstrate
						the fallacy of the arguments against free institutions drawn from our recent
						national disorders by the enemies of republican government. The admission of
						loyal members from the States now excluded from Congress, by allaying doubt
						and apprehension, would turn capital, now awaiting an opportunity for
						investment, into the channels of trade and industry. It would alleviate the
						present troubled condition of those States, and, by inducing emigration, aid
						in the settlement of fertile regions now uncultivated, and lead to an
						increased production of those staples which have added so greatly to the
						wealth of the nation and the commerce of the world. New fields of enterprise
						would be opened to our progressive people, and soon the devastations of war
						would be repaired, and all traces of our domestic differences effaced from
						the minds of our countrymen.</p>
					<p>In our efforts to preserve "the unity of government which constitutes us one
						people," by restoring the States to the condition which they held prior to
						the rebellion we should be cautious, lest, having rescued our nation from
						the perils of threatened disintegration, we resort to consolidation, and in
						the end absolute despotism, as a remedy for the recurrence of similar
						troubles. The war having terminated, and with it all occasion for the
						exercise of powers of doubtful constitutionality, we should hasten to bring
						legislation within the boundaries prescribed by the Constitution, and to
						return to the ancient landmarks established by our fathers for the guidance
						of succeeding generations. "The Constitution, and to return to the ancient
						landmarks established by our fathers for the guidance of succeeding
						generations. "The Constitution which at any time exists, until changed by an
						explicit and authentic act of the whole people, is sacredly obligatory upon
						all." "If, in the opinion of the people, the distributions or modification
						of the constitutional powers be, in any particular, wrong, let it be
						corrected by an amendment in the way in which the Constitution designates.
						But let there be no change by usurpation; for it is the customary weapon by
						which free Governments are destroyed." Washington spoke these words to his
						countrymen, when followed by their love and gratitude, he voluntarily
						retired from the cares of public life. "To keep in all things within the
						pale of our constitutional powers, and cherish the Federal Union as the only
						rock of safety," were prescribed by Jefferson as rules of action to endear
						to his "countrymen the true principles of their Constitution, and promote a
						union of sentiment and action equally auspicious to their happiness and
						safety." Jackson held that the action of the General Government should
						always be strictly confined to the sphere of its appropriate duties, and
						justly and forcibly urged that our Government is not to be maintained nor
						our Union preserved "by invasions of the rights and powers of the several
						States. In thus attempting to make our General Government strong, we make it
						weak. Its true strength consists in leaving individuals and States as much
						as possible to themselves; in making itself felt, not in its power, but in
						its beneficence; not in its control but in its protection; not in binding
						the States more closely to the centre, but in leaving each to more
						unobstructed in proper constitutional orbit." These are the teachings of men
						whose deeds and services have made the illustrious, and who, long since
						withdrawn from the scenes of life, have left to their country the rich
						legacy of their example, their wisdom and their patriotism. Drawing fresh
						inspiration from their lessons, let us emulate them in love of country and
						respect for the Constitution and the laws.</p>
					<p>The report of the Secretary of the Treasury affords much information
						respecting the revenues and commerce of the country. His views upon the
						currency, and with reference to a proper adjustment of our revenue system,
						internal as well as impost, are commended to the careful consideration of
						Congress. In my last annual message I expressed my general views upon these
						subjects. I need now only call attention to the necessity of carrying into
						every department of the Government a system of rigid accountability,
						thorough retrenchment, and wise economy. With no exceptional nor unusual
						expenditures, the oppressive burdens of taxation can be lessened by such a
						modification of our revenue laws as will be consistent with the public
						faith, and the legitimate and necessary wants of the Government.</p>
					<p>The report presents a much more satisfactory condition of our finances than
						one year ago the most sanguine could have anticipated. During the fiscal
						year ending the 30th of June, 1865, the last year of the war, the public
						debt was increased $941,902,537, and on the 31st of October, 1865, it
						amounted to $2,740,854,750. On the 31st day of October, 1866, it has been
						reduced to $2,551,310,006, the diminution, during a period of fourteen
						months, commencing September 1, 1866, and ending October 31, 1866, having
						been $206,379,565. In the last annual report on the state of the finances,
						it was estimated that during the three-quarters of the fiscal year ending
						the 30th of June last, the debt would be increased $112,194,947. During that
						period however, it was reduced $31,196,487. the receipts for the year having
						been $89,905,905 more, and the expenditures $200,529,235 less than the
						estimates. Nothing could more clearly indicate than these statements the
						extent and availability of the national resources, and the rapidity and
						safety with which, under our form of Government, great military and naval
						establishments can be disbanded, and expenses reduced from a war to a peace
						footing.</p>
					<p>During the fiscal year ending the 30th of June, 1866, the receipts were
						$558,032,620, and the expenditures $520,750,940, leaving an available
						surplus of $37,281,680. It is estimated that the receipts for the fiscal
						year ending the 30th of June, 1867, will be $475,061,386. For the fiscal
						year ending June 30, 1868, it is estimated that the receipts will amount to
						$436,000,000, and that the expenditures will be $359,247,641--showing an
						excess of $85,732,359 in favor of the Government. These estimated receipts
						may be diminished by a reduction of excise and import duties; but after all
						necessary reductionsshall have been made, the revenue of the present and of
						following years will doubtless be sufficient to cover all legitimate charges
						upon the Treasury, and leave a large annual surplus to be supplied to the
						payment of the principal of the debt. There seems now to be no good reason
						why taxes may not be reduced as the country advances in population and
						wealth, and yet the debt be extinguished within the next quarter of a
						century.</p>
					<p>The report of the Secretary of War furnishes valuable and important
						information in reference to the operations of his department during the past
						year. Few volunteers now remain in the service, and they are being
						discharged as rapidly as they can be replaced by regular troops. The army
						has been promptly paid, carefully provided with medical treatment, well
						sheltered and subsisted, and is to be furnished with breech loading small
						arms. The military strength of the nation ahs been unimpaired by the
						discharge of volunteers, and the disposition of unserviceable or perishable
						stores, and the retrenchment of expenditure, Sufficient war material to meet
						any emergency has been retained, and, from the disbanded volunteers standing
						ready to respond to the national call, large armies can be rapidly
						organized, equipped, and concentrated. Fortifications on the coast and
						frontier have received, or are being prepared for more powerful armaments;
						lake surveys and harbor and river improvements are in course of energetic
						prosecution. Preparations have been made for the payment of the additional
						bounties authorized during the recent session of Congress, under such
						regulations as will protect the Government from fraud, and secure the
						honorably-discharged soldier the well-earned reward of his faithfulness and
						gallantry. More than six thousand maimed soldiers have received artificial
						limbs or other surgical apparatus; and forty-one national cemeteries,
						containing the remains of 104,526 Union soldiers, have already been
						established. The total estimate of military appropriations is $25,205,669.</p>
					<p>It is stated in the report of the Secretary of the Navy that the naval force
						at this time consists of two hundred and seventy-eight vessels, armed with
						two thousand three hundred and fifty=one guns. Of these, one hundred and
						fifteen vessels carrying one thousand and twenty-nine guns, are in
						commission, distributed chiefly among seven squadrons. The number of men in
						the service is thirteen thousand six hundred.--Great activity and vigilance
						have been displayed by all the squadrons, and their movements have been
						judiciously and efficiently arranged in such a manner as would best promote
						American commerce, and protest the rights and interests of our countrymen
						abroad. The vessels unemployed are undergoing repairs, or are laid up until
						their services may be required. Most of the iron-clad fleet is at League
						Island in the vicinity of Philadelphia, a place which, until decisive action
						should be taken by Congress was selected by the Secretary of the Navy as the
						most eligible location for that class of vessels. It is important that a
						suitable public siation should be provided for the iron-clad fleet. It is
						intended that these vessels shall be in a proper condition for any
						emergency, and it is desirable that the bill accepting League Island for
						naval purposes, which passed the House of Representatives at its last
						session, should receive final action at an early period, in order that there
						may be a suitable public station for this class of vessels as well as a
						navy-yard of area sufficient for the wants of the service on the Delaware
						river. The Naval Pension fund amounts to $11,750,000, having been increased
						$2,760,000 during the year.--The expenditures of the Department for the
						fiscal year ending 30th June last, were $43,324,526, and the estimates for
						the coming year amount to $23,598,436. Attention is invited to the condition
						of our seamen, and the importance of legislative measures for their relief
						and improvement. The suggestions in behalf of this deserving class of our
						fellow-citizens are earnestly recommended to the favorable attention of
						Congress.</p>
					<p>The report of the Postmaster General presents a most satisfactory condition
						of the postal service and submits recommendations which deserve the
						consideration of Congress. The revenues of the Department for the year
						ending June 30, 1866 were $14,386,986, and the expenditures $15,352,079,
						showing an excess of the latter of $965,093. In anticipation of this
						deficiency, however, a special appropriation was made by Congress in the act
						approved July 28, 1866. Including the standing appropriation of $700,000 for
						free mail matter, as a legitimate portion of the revenue yet remaining
						unexpended, the actual deficiency of the past year is only $265,093--a sum
						within $51,141 of the amount estimated in the annual report of 1864. The
						decrease of revenue compared with the previous year was one and one-fifth
						per cent., and the increase of expenditures, owing principally to the
						enlargement of the mail service in the South, was twelve per cent. On the
						30th of June last there was in operation six thousand nine hundred and
						twenty-one miles, as aggregate annual transportation of seventy-one million
						eight hundred and thirty seven thousand nine hundred and fourteen miles, and
						an aggregate annual cost, including all expenditures, of $8,417,184. The
						length of railroad routes is thirty-two thousand and ninety-two miles, and
						the annual transportation thirty-two thousand and ninety-two miles, and the
						annual transportation thirty million six hundred and nine thousand four
						hundred and sixty-seven miles. The length of a steamboat route is fourteen
						thousand three hundred and forty-six miles; the annual transportation three
						million four hundred adn eleven thousand nine hundred and sixty-two miles.
						The mail service is rapidly increasing throughout the whole country, and its
						steady extension in the Southern states indicates their constantly improving
						condition. The growing importance of the foreign service also merits
						attention. The Post Office Department of Great Britain and our own have
						agreed upon a preliminary basis for a new Postal Convention, which it is
						believed will prove eminently beneficial to the commercial interests of the
						United States, inasmuch as it contemplates a reduction of the international
						letter postage to one-half the existing rates; a reduction of postage with
						all other countries to and from which correspondence is transmitted in the
						British mail, or in closed mail through the United Kingdom; the
						establishment of uniform and reasonable charges for the sea and territorial
						transmit of correspondence in closed mails; and an allowance to each Post
						Office Department of the right to use all mail communications established
						under the authority of the other for dispatch of correspondence, either in
						open or closed mails, on the same terms as those applicable to the
						inhabitants of the country providing the means of transmission.</p>
					<p>The report of the Secretary of the Interior exhibits the condition of those
						branches of the public service which are committed to his supervision.
						During the last fiscal year, four million six hundred and twenty-nine
						thousand three hundred and twelve acres of public land were disposed of, one
						million eight hundred and ninety-two thousand five hundred and sixteen acres
						of which were entered under the homestead act. The policy originally adopted
						relative to the public land has undergone essential modifications. Immediate
						revenue, and not their rapid settlement, was the cardinal feature of our
						land system. Long experience and earnest discussion have resulted in the
						conviction that the early development of our agricultural resources, and the
						diffusion of an energetic population over our vast territory, are objects of
						far greater importance to the national growth and prosperity than the
						proceeds of the sale of the land to the highest bidder in an open market.
						The pre-emption laws confer upon the pioneer who complies with the terms
						they impose the privilege of purchasing a limited portion of "unoffered
						lands" at the minimum price. The homestead enactments relieve the settler
						from the payment of purchase money, and secure him a permanent home, upon
						the condition of residence for a term of years. This liberal policy invites
						emigration from the old, and from the more crowded portions of the new
						world. Its propitious results are undoubted, and will be more signally
						manifested when time shall have given it a wider development.</p>
					<p>Congress has made liberal grants of public land to corporations, in aid of
						the construction of railroads and other internal improvements. Should this
						policy hereafter prevail, more stringent provisions will be required to
						secure a faithful application of the fund. The title of the lands should not
						pass, and by patient or otherwise, but remain in the Government and subject
						to its control until some portion of the road has been actually built.
						Portions of them might then, from time to time, be conveyed to the
						corporation, but never in a greater ratio to the whole quantity embraced by
						the grant than the completed parts to bear to the entire length of the
						projected improvements.--This restriction would not operate to the prejudice
						of any undertaking conceived in good faith and executed with reasonable
						energy, as it is the settled practice to withdraw from market the lands
						falling within the operation of such grants and thus to exclude the
						inception of a subsequent adverse right. A breach of the conditions which
						Congress may deem proper to impose should work a forfeiture of claim to the
						lands so withdrawn but unconveyed, and of title to the lands conveyed which
						remain unsold.</p>
					<p>Operations on the several lines of the Pacific Railroad have been prosecuted
						with unexampled vigor and success. Should no unforeseen cause of delay
						occur, it is confidently anticipated that this great thoroughfare will be
						completed before the expiration of the period designated by Congress.</p>
					<p>During the last fiscal year the amount paid to pensioners, including the
						expenses of disbursement, was thirteen million four hundred and fifty-nine
						dollars; and fifty thousand one hundred and seventy-seven names were added
						to the thousand nine hundred and ninety-six pension rolls. The entire number
						of pensioners, June 30, 1866, was one hundred and twenty-six thousand seven
						hundred and twenty-two. This fact furnishes melancholy and striking proof of
						the sacrifices made to vindicate the constitutional authority of the Federal
						Government, and to maintain inviolate the integrity of the Union. They
						impose upon us corresponding obligations. It is estimated that thirty-three
						million dollars will be required to meet the exigence of this branch of the
						service during the next fiscal year.</p>
					<p>Treaties have been concluded with the Indians who, enticed into armed
						opposition to our Government at the outbreak of the rebellion, have
						unconditionally submitted to our authority, and manifested an earnest desire
						for a renewal of friendly relations.</p>
					<p>During the year ending September 30, 1866, 8,716 patents for useful
						inventions and designs were issued, and at that date the balance in the
						Treasury to the credit of the Patent fund was two hundred and twenty-eight
						thousand two hundred and ninety-seven dollars.</p>
					<p>As a subject upon which depends an immense amount of the production and
						commerce of the country, I recommend to Congress such legislation as may be
						necessary for the preservation of the levees of the Mississippi river. It is
						a matter of national importance that early steps should be taken not only to
						add to the efficiency of these barriers against destructive mundations, but
						for the removal of all obstructions to the free and safe navigation of the
						great channel of trade and commerce.</p>
					<p>The District of Columbia, under existing laws, is not entlitld to that
						representation in the National Councils which, from our earliest history,
						has been uniformly accorded to each Territory established from time to time
						within our limits. It maintains peculiar relations to Congress, to whom the
						Constitution has granted the power of exercising exclusive legislation over
						the seat of government. Our fellow-citizens residing in the District, whose
						interests are thus confided to the special guardianship of Congress, exceed
						in number the population of several of our Territories, and no just reason
						is perceived why a delegate of their choice should not be admitted to a seat
						in the House of Representatives. No mode seems so appropriate and effectual
						of enabling them to make known their peculiar condition and wants, and of
						securing the local legislation adapted to them. I therefore recommend the
						passage of a law authorizing the electors of the District of Columbia to
						choose a delegate, to be allowed the same rights and privileges as a
						delegate representing a Territory. The increasing enterprise and rapid
						progress of improvement in the District are highly gratifying, and I trust
						that the forts of the municipal authorities to promote the prosperity of the
						national metropolis will receive the efficient and generous co-operation of
						Congress.</p>
					<p>The report of the Commissioner of Agriculture reviews the operations of his
						Department during the past year, and asks the aid of Congress in its efforts
						to encourage those States which, scourged by war, are now earnestly engaged
						in the resurrection of domestic industry.</p>
					<p>It is a subject of congratulation that no foreign combinations against our
						domestic peace and safety, or our legitimate influence among the nations
						have been formed or attempted. While sentiments of reconciliation, loyalty
						and patriotism have increased at home, a more just consideration of our
						national character and rights has been manifested by foreign nations.</p>
					<p>The entire success of the Atlantic Telegraph between the coast of Ireland and
						the Providence of Newfoundland, is an achievement which has been justly
						celebrated in both hemispheres as the opening of an era in the progress of
						civilization. There is a reason to expect that equal successes will attend,
						and even greater results follow, the enterprise for connecting the two
						Continents through the Pacific Ocean by the projected line of telegraph
						between Kamschatka and the Russian possessions in America.</p>
					<p>The resolution of Congress protesting against pardons by foreign Governments
						of persons convicted of infamous offences, on condition of emigration to our
						country, has been communicated to the States with which we maintain
						intercourse, and the practice, so justly the subject of complaint on our
						part, has not been renewed.</p>
					<p>The congratulations of Congress to the Emperor of Russia, upon his escape
						from attempted assassination, have been presented to that humane and
						enlightened ruler, and received by him with expressions of grateful
						appreciation.</p>
					<p>The Executive, warned of an attempt by Spanish-American adventurers to induce
						the emigration of freedmen of the United States to a foreign country,
						protested against the project as one which, if consummated, would reduce
						them to a bondage even more oppressive than that from which they have just
						been relieved. Assurance has been received from the Government of the State
						in which the plan was matured, that the proceeding will meet neither its
						encouragement nor approval. It is a question worthy of your consideration,
						whether our laws upon this subject are adequate to the prevention or
						punishment of the crime thus meditated.</p>
					<p>In the month of April last, as Congress is aware, a friendly arrangement was
						made between the Emperor of France and the President of the United States,
						for the withdrawal from Mexico of the French expeditionary military forces.
						This withdrawal was to be effected in three detachments, the first of which,
						it was understood, would leave Mexico in Novemver, now past, the second in
						March next, and the third and last in November, 1867. Immediately upon the
						completion of the evacuation, the French Government was to assume the same
						attitude of non-intervention, in regard to Mexico, as is held by the
						Government of the United States. Repeated assurances have been given by the
						Emperor, since that agreement, that he would complete the promised
						evacuation within the period mentioned, or sooner.</p>
					<p>It was reasonably expected that the proceedings thus contemplated would
						produce a crisis of great political interest in the Republic of Mexico. The
						newly appointed minister of the United States, Mr. Campbell, was therefore
						sent forward, on the 9th day of November last, to assume his proper
						functions as Minister Plenipotentiary of the United States to that Republic.
						It was also thought expedient that he should be attended in the vicinity of
						Mexico by the Lieutenant General of the Army of the United States, with the
						view of obtaining such information as might be important to determine the
						course to be pursued by the United States in re-establishing and maintaining
						necessary and proper intercourse with the Republic of Mexico. Deeply
						interested in the cause of liberty and humanity, it seemed an obvious duty
						on our part to exercise whatever influence we possessed for the restoration
						and permanent establishment in that country of a do-domestic and republican
						form of government.</p>
					<p>Such was the condition of affairs in regard to Mexico, when, on the 22d of
						November last, official information was received from Paris that the Emperor
						of France had some time before decided not to withdraw a detachment of his
						forces in the moth of November past, according to engagement, but that this
						decision was made with the purpose of withdrawing the whole of the forces in
						the ensuing spring. Of this determination, however, the United States had
						not received any notice or intimation; and , so, soon as the information was
						received by the Government, care was taken to make known its dissent to the
						Emperor of France.</p>
					<p>I cannot forego the hope that France will reconsider the subject, and adopt
						some resolution in regard to the evacuation of Mexico which will conform as
						nearly as practicable with the existing engagement, and thus meet the just
						expectations of the United States. The papers relating to the subject will
						be laid before you. It is believed that, with the evacuation of Mexico by
						the expeditionary forces, no subject for serious differences between France
						and the United States would remain. The expression of the Emperor and people
						of France warrant a hope that the traditionary friendship between the two
						countries might in that case be renewed and permanently restored.</p>
					<p>A claim of a citizen of the United States for indemnity for spoilations
						committed on the high seas by the French authorities, in the exercise of a
						belligerent power against Mexico, has been met by the Government of France
						with a proposition to defer settlement until a mutual convention for the
						adjustment of all claims of citizens and subjects of both countries, arising
						out of the recent wars on this Continent, shall be agreed upon by the two
						countries. The suggestion is not deemed unreasonable, but it belongs to
						Congress to direct the manner in which claims for indemnity by foreigners,
						as well as by citizens of the United States, arising out of the late civil
						war, shall be adjudicated and determined. I have no doubt that the subject
						of all such claims will engage your attention at a convenient and proper
						time.</p>
					<p>It is a matter of regret that no considerable advance has been made towards
						an adjustment of the differences between the United States and Great
						Britain, arising out of the depredations upon our national commerce and
						other trespasses committed during our civil war by British subjects, in
						violation of international law and treaty obligations. The delay, however,
						may be believed to have resulted in no small degree from the domestic
						situation of Great Britain. An entire change of ministry occurred in that
						country during the last session of Parliament. The attention of the new
						ministry was called to the subject at an early day, and there is some reason
						to expect that it will now be considered in a becoming and friendly spirit.
						The importance of an early disposition of the question cannot be
						exaggerated. Whatever might be the wishes of the two Governments, it is
						manifest that good-will and friendship between the two countries cannot be
						established until a reciprocity, in the practice of good faith and
						neutrality, shall be restored between the respective nations.</p>
					<p>On the 6th of June last, in violation of our neutrality laws, a military
						expedition and enterprise against the British North American Colonies was
						projected and attempted to be carried on within the territory and
						jurisdiction of the United States. In obedience to the obligation imposed
						upon the Executive by the Constitution, to see that the laws are faithfully
						executed, all citizens were warned, by proclamation, against taking part in
						or aiding such unlawful proceedings, and the proper civil, military and
						naval officers were directed to take all necessary measures for the
						enforcement of the laws. The expedition failed, but it has not been without
						its painful consequences. Some of our citizens, who it was alleged were
						engaged in the expedition, were captured, and have been brought to trial, as
						for a capital offence, in the Providence of Canada. Judgement and sentence
						of death have been pronounced against some, while others have been
						acquitted. Fully believing in the maxim of government, that severity of
						civil punishment for misguided persons who have engaged in revolutionary
						attempts which have disastrously failed, is unsound and unwise, such
						representation has been made to the British Government, in behalf of the
						convicted persons, as being sustained by an enlighten and humane judgment,
						will, it is hoped, induce their cases an exercise of clemency, and a
						judicious amnesty to all who were engaged in the movement. Council has been
						employed by the Government to defend citizens of the United States on trial
						for capital offences in Canada, and a discontinuance of prosecutions which
						were instituted in the courts of the United States against those who took
						part in the expedition has been directed. I have regarded the expedition as
						not only political in its nature, but as also in a great measure foreign
						from the Untied States in its causes, character, and objects. The attempt
						was understood to be made in sympathy with an insurgent party in Ireland,
						and, by striking at a British Province on this Continent, was designed to
						aid in obtaining redress for political grievances which, it was assumed, the
						people of Ireland had suffered at the hands of the British Government during
						a period of several centuries. The persons engaged in it were chiefly
						natives of that country, some of whom had, while others had not, become
						citizens of the Untied States under our general laws of naturalization.
						Complaints of misgovernment in Ireland continually engage the attention of
						the British nation, and no great an agitation is now prevailing in Ireland
						that the British Government have deemed it necessary to suspend the writ of
							<emph rend="italic">habeas corpus</emph> in that country. These
						circumstances must necessarily modify the opinion which we might otherwise
						have entertained in regard to an expedition expressly prohibited by our
						neutrality laws. So long as those laws remain upon our statue books, they
						should be faithfully executed, and if they operate harshly, unjustly, or
						oppressively, Congress alone can apply the remedy, by their modification or
						repeal. </p>
					<p>Political and commercial interests of the United States are not unlikely to
						be affected in some degree by events which are transpiring in the eastern
						regions of Europe, and the time seems to have come when our Government ought
						to have a proper diplomatic representation in Greece.</p>
					<p>This Government has claimed for all persons not convicted, or accused, or
						suspected of crime, an absolute political right of self-expatriation, and a
						choice of new national allegiance. Most of the European States have
						dissented from this principle, and have claimed a right to hold such of
						their subjects as have immigrated to and been naturalized in the United
						States, and afterwards returned on transient visits to their native
						countries, to the performance of military service in like manner as resident
						subjects. Complaints arising from the claim in this respect made by foreign
						States, have heretofore been matters of controversy between the United
						States and some of the European Powers, and the irritation consequent upon
						the failure to settle this question increased during the war in which
						Prussia, Italy, and Austria were recently engaged. Great Britain has never
						acknowledged the right of expatriation. She has not for some years
						practically insisted upon the opposite doctrine. France has been equally
						forbearing and Prussia has proposed a compromise, which, although evincing
						increased liberality, has not been accepted by the United States. Peace is
						now prevailing everywhere in Europe, and the present seems to be a favorable
						time for an assertion by Congress of the principle, so long as maintained by
						the Executive Department, that naturalization by one State fully exempts the
						native-born subject of any other State from the performance of military
						service under any foreign Government, so long as he does not voluntarily
						renounce its rights and benefits.</p>
					<p>n the performance of a duty imposed upon me by the Constitution, I have thus
						submitted to the Representatives of the States and the People such
						information of our domestic and foreign affairs as the public interests seem
						to require. Our Government is now undergoing its most trying ordeal, and my
						earnest prayer is, that the peril may be successfully and finally passed,
						without impairing its original strength and symmetry. The interest of the
						nation are best to be promoted by the revival of fraternal relations, the
						complete obliteration of our past differences, and the inauguration of all
						the pursuits of peace. Directing our efforts to the early accomplishment of
						these great ends, let us endeavor to preserve harmony between the
						co-ordinate Departments of the Government, that each in its proper sphere
						may cordially co-operate with the other in securing the maintenance of the
						Constitution, the preservation of the Union, and the perpetuity of our free
						institutions.</p>
					<p>ANDREW JOHNSON.</p>
					<p>WASHINGTON, December 3, 1866.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>Andrew Johnson</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>Contains a transcript of President Johnson's address before the Senate and
					House of Representatives.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.12.12.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>The President's Message</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editorial lauds the President's speech, and offers him high praise for
					sticking to the Reconstruction policies he laid down last year.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>"Corrupt Appointments"</head>
				<origin>Repository</origin>
				<commentary>"In a very extraordinary article in last week's Repository, under the
					above caption, the following very extraordinary paragraph occurs in relation to
					the appointments in the district:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The appointment of such men to office has naturally resulted in a system of
						wholesale political profligacy and debauchery, going down to the meanest
						creatures who have purchased the crimes of the high contracting parties. In
						this district, with two characteri [UNCLEAR] chief revenue officers, the
						little streams are of course as corrupt as the fountains. The chiefs being
						the offspring of purchase, the subordinates could not be other than the
						spawns of corruption. Their places were hawked about from door to door
						before the election to purchase votes, and since the election, regardless of
						promises made by the leaders, the same places have been auctioned to the
						highest bidders. While perhaps few districts have sounded the same depths of
						political debauchery attained by our new officials and those who created
						them, we doubt not that in every district of the State, and generally
						throughout the Union, the same policy has prevailed and the same venality,
						in a greater or less degree, has humiliated the people.</p>
					<p>These are grave charges. No one but a shameless knave, it is reasonable to
						suppose, would be reckless enough to publicly prefer charges reflecting so
						seriously upon the character of his neighbors, unless he was in possession
						of the necessary proof to substantiate them. Can the <emph rend="italic"
							>Repository</emph> furnish the proof? Will it be kind enough to inform
						us what offices were "hawked about from door to door to purchase votes," and
						by whom? And will it also tell us by whom "the same places have been
						auctioned to the highest bidders," and at what price?--Let the <emph
							rend="italic">Repository</emph> produce the proof of its infamous
						allegations, or stand convicted of willful and malicious falsehood. </p>
					<p>But apart from the truth or falsity of the charges, they come with a bad
						grace from the chief editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>,
						whose business in life has been trading in politics, and judging from
						appearances, he has been eminently successful in the business. He should be
						the last man to charge corruption upon others; and if it be true that a man
						should always 'practice what he preaches," he, of all men, is the least
						qualified to write essays upon political morality. </p>
					<p>The new appointees in this district who are denounced as "characterless," and
						"spawns of corruption," we hazard nothing in saying, will compare favorably,
						in regard to honesty and general fitness for their positions, with their
						immediate predecessors, or even with the editor of the <emph rend="italic"
							>Repository</emph>. The appointees in our own town and country are all
						gentlemen of unblemished character whose uprightness and honesty have never
						before been called into question. It is true that they don't live in as
						large houses, or own as many broad acres, as some other people, but this may
						be accounted for in the fact that that they never dabbled in government
						contracts, never speculated in oil stocks, and never were members of the
						State Legislature. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article attacks the Repository for denouncing the district's most
					recent appointees, and challenges the journal to "produce the proof of its
					infamous allegation, or stand convicted of wilful and malicious falsehood."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Congress of Madmen</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt>"They seem to be raging like tigers or hyenas, and are ready to devour at
					once all the people of the Southern States."</excerpt>
				<transcript>
					<p>Our readers will see how furiously the Mongrels begin their work at
						Washington. They seem to be raging like tigers or hyenas, and are ready to
						devour at once all the people of the Southern States. They are going to have
						Congress remain in permanent session, take all appointing power virtually
						from the President, repeal the amnesty law, vote negro suffrage everywhere,
						even in Africa doubtless, reduce all the Southern States to Territories,
						&amp;c., &amp;c., &amp;c. Well, let these knaves, fools and
						madmen go ahead. It is, perhaps, best they should.--The fiercer the storm
						the sooner it is over. In the meantime, Democrats can only watch and pray.
						We are powerless to stay the torrent of their wild determination to carry
						out their impracticable and Heaven-defying theories. Let them rush on,
						strike the rock and meet the thunderbolt! Our country is in the very vortex
						of a tremendous revolution. The Mongrels fancied, when Lee surrendered, that
						their long antipated revolution was successful, but at the very moment they
						were drinking their success, God dashed the cup from their hands. Lincoln
						fell! The course of his successor balked their purposes for a time, but now,
						encouraged by the result of the recent elections, they will stick at
						nothing. Their bitterness against Johnson has become rage, their enmity is
						developed into fiendishness. But the violence of their passions will consume
						them. At the moment they think they will stand, they will fall. Courage
						then, North and South! Let no act that true men and patriots may do, in this
						crisis, ever rise in future judgement to condemn them. Now is the time for
						real bravery. That courage that might face a storm of shot and shell, might
						falter where the blandishments of office are profferred in one hand and the
						severities of tyrannical government offered in the other. Moral courage is
						the highest type of manhood. Let us stand by truth though the heavens
					fall.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Since the Republicans' triumph in the last election, notes the editorial,
					the country "is in the vortex of a tremendous revolution." But with little power
					to stop the Radicals' assault on the Constitution, the Democrats can only "watch
					and pray."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Renewal of Congressional Agitation</head>
				<origin>Age</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Congress has recommended agitation.--The fact that the President in his
						message avoided all sensational features, all expressions or allusions
						calculated to re-open the differences between the executive and legislative
						branches of the government, has no effect in restraining the latter. The
						tone and temper of the Radical leaders showed the spirit by which they were
						animated, and the lash of party discipline was applied in such a manner as
						to make the vote a unit, save the matter of postponing the reading oft he
						President's message. Even in that measure the radicals were actuated more by
						a desire to have the message in the possession of the House in order to make
						use of it for partisan purposes, than to listen respectfully to the views of
						the Chief Magistrate of the nation upon subjects touching our national honor
						and standing abroad and the prosperity of the people at home. Stevens and
						Boutwell and Kelly and Sumner talked treason to the Constitution within the
						national Capitol, and a crowed of excited negroes shouted the praises of
						Congress and denounced the President without, and thus the Second Session of
						the Thirty-ninth Congress was inaugurated.</p>
					<p>The measures proposed with such incident hast are all of an ultra partisan
						and sectional character, and are calculated to widen the breeches between
						the sections.--The door of conciliation is shut, and force pushed into the
						foreground as the only remedy that will be applied for settling the
						difficulties between the North and South.--The repeal by the House of the
						thirteenth section of the act of July 17, 1862, authorizing the President to
						extend amnesty and pardon to the persons engaged in the late rebellion, was
						a step indicating the determination of Congress to strip the President of
						all power to heal the wounds inflicted by civil strife, and to make even the
						pardoning power an agency for perpetuating their political influence. This
						was followed by other measures intended to reduce the patronage of the
						President and increase that of the legislative branch of the government. Mr.
						Sherman offered a bill "to prevent the illegal appointment of officers of
						the United States," and Mr. Williams one "to regulate the tenure of such
						officers." These bills provide that no salary shall be paid to officers
						rejected by the Senate and afterwards appointed by the President; and that
						officers appointed with the consent of the Senate shall hold their offices
						until successors are similarly appointed, until othwise provided by law.
						Both these bills are intended to accumulate power in the Senate, and enable
						that body to interfere with the appointing power which the Constitution
						vests in the President. In the House, Mr. Schenck introduced a bill fixing
						the time for the meeting of the Fortieth Congress, and each succeeding one,
						on the 4th day of March, the day on which the term begins for which the
						Congress is elected. This is putting in a practical form Mr. Stevens' idea
						that Congress should be continued <emph rend="italic">en permanence</emph>
						as a means of overriding the executive branch of the government and usurping
						power which is not confided to the Legislature by the Constitution. The bill
						introduced by Mr. Kelly for reorganizing the Internal Revenue Department,
						and vesting the appointment of the Chief Commissioner in the Supreme court
						of the United States, is also dangerous and revolutionary in a double
						aspect. First, as a continuation of the plot to render the President
						powerless to thwart the schemes of a political factor; and, second, as a
						deliberate plan to make the Supreme Coart a partisan body and thus infuse
						into its decisions the same spirit of narrow and selfish bigotry and
						intolerance which distinguishes the acts, measures, and policy of the
						Radical party of the country. </p>
					<p>These are samples of legislation proposed by the dominant party of the
						Country at this eventful period in its history. They are full of mischief,
						and if consummated will produce most lamentable results. The entire
						subjugation of the Southern States seem to be resolved upon by the Radical
						leaders. They will listen to no compromise. The history of the past is
						unheeded, and the signs which tell of a future full of disaster to the
						nation, if their plan be put into execution are disregarded. The
						Constitution is no longer venerated or regarded by this band of fanatical
						agitators. They mean to strip one co-ordinate branch of the government of
						all power, and infuse the poison of sectional and partisan feeling into
						another, by loading it with party influence and patronage. In this way power
						will be steadily gathered into the keeping of Congress, and that body will
						rule the land without check or hindrance. The adoption of the Constitutional
						amendments by the Southern States is no longer regarded by the Radicals as a
						sufficient atonement for the past. The wild wave of political ambition has
						swept the leaders past that point, and they are drawing the masses in their
						wake. The action of Congress points to subjugation in the South, and a
						radical change in our form of government in all parts of the country, unless
						some remedy can be applied calculated to arouse the people and make them see
						and appreciate the danger by which they are surrounded.</p>
					<p>This inauguration by Congress of a new era of political agitation, the
						projection of measures out measuring in bitterness of hatred to the South
						and the Southern people those which characterized the last session, and the
						intensity of feeling which entered into the discussion of those measures on
						the part of the leading men of the Radical organization in the National
						Legislature bodes no good. The honor and welfare of our country demand
						peace. But the Radicals are determined that peace shall not come.--They mean
						to agitate, to inflame the passions of the people, and at the same time to
						adopt such measures as will fasten the chains of Radical rule upon the
						masses, North and South. That this is their purpose is evident from the
						measures proposed at the opening of the present session of Congress, and the
						people should watch the acts and votes of their representatives. The
						material interests of the country, united with the patriotic impulses of the
						masses, may impede the march of the radical column until the "sober second
						thought" of the nation can have time to operate, and in the meantime the
						Democratic party, in and out of Congress, will continue to uphold the
						Constitution, the rights of the states, the principle of fair representation
						and the perpetuity of a republican form of government, against all
						opposition. <emph rend="italic">Age</emph>. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Despite the President's decision to avoid any mention of controversial
					issues, his attempts to diffuse the tension in Washington have had virtually no
					effect on the Radicals, who, asserts the article, are forging ahead with their
					plans "to widen the breaches between the sections."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>The Violence of Congress</head>
				<origin>New York World</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Questioning the constitutionality of the Radicals' recent legislative
					actions, the article condemns their behavior, particularly their attempt to curb
					the president's power to appoint officials. In fact, it suggests that Congress
					has "acted more in the spirit of a weak, scolding woman ... than like a body of
					self-poised legislators."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>A Villainous Proposition</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary>"A Radical paper says Thad Stevens read in caucus the other day, a bill
					to prevent removals from office, and adds:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>It is reported that Thad Stevens introduced a bill to the Republican Caucus
					which, in addition to preventing presidential removals from office, would
					require the Chief Executive to have all of his appointments confirmed by the
					Senate. In addition, the legislation would prevent any nominee who is rejected
					by that body from holding any office of honor or profit for three years.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.12.12.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--The New Town Clock</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Announces that the town's new clock has arrived. It will be placed in the
					dome of the Court House in the next few days.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Humbug</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>During three nights last week a French Jew, calling himself Signor Blitz,
						gave a series of exhibitions in Repository Hall, in this place. His coming
						had been heralded for a week previous by large posters on dead walls and old
						stables in which he promised a rare exhibition of his powers as a magician,
						ventriloquist and bird trainer; as well as the distribution among his
						[UNCLEAR] of farms, watches, sewing machines, and other "portable property."
						The hall was packed mightily by an eager crowd impatiently sitting through
						the poor performances of the "signor' and his miserable attempts at
						ventriloquism, buoyed up by the expectation of getting a rich present at the
						close. For two nights the presents were distributed with seeming fairness,
						and the "signor" won golden opinions from his audiences. On the third and
						last evening, the price of admission was raised to fifty cents and every
						ticket holder was presented a valuable present. The [UNCLEAR] was densely
						crowded, every one expecting to get a gold watch or sewing machine, but
						alas! [UNCLEAR] to content themselves with a black ring worth three cents, a
						shiny tin goblet or cheap butter knife. The sewing machine wasn't
						"distributed" and the gold (?) watch was disposed of according to previous
						arrangement. Thus closed another miserable humbug, by which our people were
						swindled out of nearly, if not quite, one thousand dollars by a very shabby
						imitator of the famous [UNCLEAR]. How much better would it have been had our
						citizens appropriated the money, thus thrown away upon a charlatan, to the
						relief of the suffering poor in our midst, who, during the coming winter,
						will be left to shiver by their cold hearthstones for want of it.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Provides an account of a con man who, according to the article, managed to
					swindle approximately $1000 from the residents of Chambersburg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Education of the South</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>A very large congregation assembled in the Lutheran Church of this place on
						Sunday evening last, to hear an address by "Capt. Geo. W. Curry, agent of
						the American Freedman's Union Commission," on the importance of establishing
						schools in the South for the education of the freedmen. The Captain gave a
						succinct history of the origin and operations, since its organization, of
						the society of which he is an agent. The educational labors of the
						commission are intended to embrace the destitute white population of the
						South as well as the freedmen. The speaker gave a very gratifying account of
						the success of the institution in having already established a large number
						of schools in various parts of the Southern States, all of which, he says,
						are in a flourishing condition. The Rev. Mr. Kunkleman followed the agent in
						a brief address, giving his experience in connection with the operations of
						the commission in the West. Our neighbor, Col. McClure, likewise made a few
						remarks in response to an invitation, stating that he knew nothing of the
						enterprise except what he had learned from the speakers preceding him, but
						from what he had heard he had no hesitation in giving it his hearty
						approval. The main object of the meeting, of course, was to raise funds for
						the society, and subscriptions for that purpose were taken, the amount of
						which we did not learn.</p>
					<p>Now, the ostensible object of the enterprise is certainly praiseworthy. There
						can be no rational objection to the elevation and education of the freedmen
						and other destitute classes of the South. As a naked proposition, free from
						all connection with partisan politics, it certainly would be commendable and
						deserving of the liberal support of all whose means would enable them to do
						so. But just here is where the trouble begins. Doubtless many who are
						connected with this enterprise are actuated by the purest motives, but we
						have reason to believe that in many instances it is used by designing
						political demagogues more for the purpose of inculcating among the freedmen
						a feeling of hatred and revenge towards their late masters than for the
						purpose of enlightening their minds and christianizing their hearts. It is
						certainly right that these ignorant and destitute people should be properly
						educated and enlightened. They should be taught to read and write and have
						afforded them an opportunity of acquiring a knowledge of such other branches
						of an education as their minds are capable of; but we were not aware that
						teachiing little niggers to sing "John Brown's soul is marching on" was any
						part of a proper education. If that is the method of teaching their
						"manhood," we dissent. We are decidedly opposed to canonizing the soul of
						Old John Brown.--Thieves and murderers, in our judgement, are not the proper
						material out of which to make a patron saint.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>On Dec. 9th, Capt. George W. Curry, a representative of the Freedmen's
					Bureau, delivered an address in Chambersburg in which he spoke on the importance
					of establishing schools in the South. According to the article, Curry sought to
					garner the crowd's support for this endeavor by stressing the fact that the
					Bureau's plans are "intended to embrace the destitute white population of the
					South as well as the freedmen."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Greencastle Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>On Dec. 22nd, the women of the M. E. Church, of Greencastle, will hold a
					fair to help raise money for the construction of a new church edifice.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Mercersburg Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Women in Mercersburg will hold a festival and fair to benefit the town's
					Presbyterian Sabbath School.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Mercersburg Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that a revival is in progress at the M. E. Church in Loudon.
					Between 30 and 40 individuals have professed conversion.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Waynesboro Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Bender</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Justice</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Diltch</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Cook</ln>
						<fn>Thaddeus</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Last week, David Diltch and Thaddeus Cook were arrested for stealing
					turkeys from George Hoover. The men were committed to jail by Justice Bender.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Waynesboro Items</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Welsh</ln>
						<fn>Jacob R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nevin</ln>
						<fn>A. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>It is reported that Jacob R. Welsh was appointed Postmaster in Waynesboro.
					Welsh will replace A. G. Nevin.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--State Appropriations to Students and Graduates</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Relates the contents of an act recently passed by the Legislature that
					offers 50 cents per week to students attending Normal School so long as they
					agree to teach in one of the state's common schools for two years after
					graduation. Students whose fathers lost their lives while serving the Union, or
					were disabled while in the service, are entitled to a stipend of $1 per week.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--A Suggestion</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The article advocates the enactment of an ordinance requiring property
					owners to number their houses.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Glass</ln>
						<fn>Lydia</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn>Isaac G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Schneck</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf>S.</sf>
						<pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 27th, Isaac G. Baker and Lydia Glass were married by Rev. Dr. S.
					Schneck.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Senneny</ln>
						<fn>Abraham S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Lawson</ln>
						<fn>A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
						<fn>H. Y.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 21st, Abraham S. Senneny and A. Lawson were married by Rev. H. Y.
					Hummelbaugh.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Detrich</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nava</ln>
						<fn>Anna M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kunkelman</ln>
						<fn>J. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 6th, William Detrich and Anna M. Nava were married by Rev. J. A.
					Kunkelman.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Knepper</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Knepper</ln>
						<fn>Malida</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Buhrman</ln>
						<fn>A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 29th, Henry Knepper and Malida Knepper were married by Rev. A.
					Buhrman.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Burns</ln>
						<fn>William H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Amsley</ln>
						<fn>Rachel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Buhrman</ln>
						<fn>A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 4th, William H. Burns and Rachel Amsley were married by Rev. A.
					Buhrman.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McClay</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hullup</ln>
						<fn>Ann Rebecca</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Oiler</ln>
						<fn>J. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 28th, James McClay, of Fairfield, Adams county, and Ann Rebecca
					Hullup were married by Rev. J. F. Oiler.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Snively</ln>
						<fn>J. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hade</ln>
						<fn>Mary J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Callendar</ln>
						<fn>N. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 2nd, J. R. Snively and Mary J., daughter of William Hale, were
					married by Rev. N. S. Callendar.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Rotz</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Criseman</ln>
						<fn>Ann E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gast</ln>
						<fn>F. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 20th, Samuel Rotz and Ann E. Criseman were married by Rev. F. A.
					Gast.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Robinson</ln>
						<fn>John R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Milet</ln>
						<fn>Mary T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gast</ln>
						<fn>F. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 4th, John R. Robinson and Mary T. Milet were married by Rev. F. A.
					Gast.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hess</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 9th, John Hess, 78, died near Waynesboro.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hollinger</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Dec. 5th, John Hollinger died at an advanced age.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Eby</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Eby</ln>
						<fn>Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Nov. 29th, Elizabeth, wife of George Eby, died at 42.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.12.12.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
