<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.05.30">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>07/23/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1866-05-30">
			<year>1866</year>
			<month norm="05">May</month>
			<day norm="00">30</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.05.30.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Freedmen's Bureau</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Contains a copy of the scathing report issued by Generals Steedman and
					Fullerton, who were given the task of assessing the impact and effectiveness of
					the Freedmen's Bureau. The pair toured Virginia and North Carolina before making
					their recommendations.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.05.30.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>President Johnson's Cabinet</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Since taking Lincoln's place, the relationship between Johnson and his
					Cabinet has been rather tumultuous, explains the editorial, even though there
					are several members who "heartily approve of the President's policy of
					restoration." With the exception of Secretary McCollough, however, their "love
					of party is stronger than their love of country." If Johnson hopes to succeed in
					his plans, it insists, he must purge "all the traitors and spies at once from
					his council board."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>2</column>
				<head>The Deserter's Law</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Among the many important cases claim the attention of the Supreme Court, now
						in session at Harrisburg, is one from this county involving the
						constitutionality of the law of Congress disfranchising delinquent drafted
						men and deserters.</p>
					<p>Henry Reilly, a citizen of Hamilton township, was drafted into the military
						service of the United states on the 10th of July, 1864, and having been
						regularly served with a notice of his conscription, he refused, and never
						did report to the Provost Marshal of the 16th district for service in the
						army of the United States, nor did he furnish a substitute, or pay the
						required sum of money therefor. When Reilly offered his ballot at the
						Hamilton poll on the 19th day of October last, the judge of the election
						refused to receive his vote on the ground that he was a deserter from the
						military service of the United States, and in consequence thereof, was
						disfranchised by the act of Congress providing for the enrolling and calling
						out of the national forces, approved the 3d day of March, 1865.</p>
					<p>Immediately after the election Mr. Reilly bought suit against the judge who
						rejected his vote, and at the January term following the case was submitted
						to the decision of the court without the intervention of a jury and promptly
						decided by Judge King, in an able opinion published in our columns at the
						time, in favor of the plaintiff. In pursuance of that decision judgement was
						entered against the defendant, Benjamin Huber, for the sum of one dollar and
						costs. Thus so far as our court had the power the act of Congress attempting
						the disfranchisement of the citizens of a sovereign State was declared
						unconstitutional and void. A writ of error to the Supreme Court was then
						sued out by the defendant and the case is now before that tribunal for final
						decision.</p>
					<p>The Legislature of the State at the recent session passed a law, similar in
						its provisions to the act of Congress, which Gov. Curtin holds over for his
						action, until the Supreme Court has passed upon the constitutionality of the
						former act. On the opening of the case the Attorney General, Hon. Wm. M.
						Meredith, sent in and had read before the court the following paper:</p>
					<p>ATTORNEY GENERAL'S OFFICE,</p>
					<p>Harrisburg, May 23, 1866.</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">My Dear Sir</emph>:--I understand that a case involving
						the question of the constitutionality of the act of Congress which provides
						for the disfranchisement of deserters will be heard before you to-day. It
						was my purpose, on the hearing of the same case, as <emph rend="italic"
							>unicus curia</emph>, to make or ally the statement which I now beg
						leave to present to the court in writing. The physical disability under
						which I am temporarily laboring will, I hope, afford a ground for your kind
						indulgence in the adoption of this mode of communicating with the Court. </p>
					<p>Shortly before the termination of the last session, a bill was sent to the
						Governor for his approval, providing for carrying into effect, so far as
						relates to the exercise of suffrage in the commonwealth, the enactments of
						the act of Congress referred to. Understanding that one or more cases,
						involving the question of the constitutionality of that act of Congress,
						would be presented for your decision at the present term he thought that a
						due observance of that respect for and obedience to the law, as adjucated by
						the highest juridical tribunal of the commonwealth, which have always been
						prominent characteristics of our people, required that he should wait, if
						possible, the result of your decision. As the provisions of that bill are
						probably not otherwise known to the Court, I beg to suggest that if, it
						should become a law, a very considerable time will be required to make the
						necessary thorough examinations of the military records of the United
						States, and to prepare the detailed lists, which it directs to be
						transmitted to the officers of the respective courts of quarter session, and
						to afford sufficient time between such transmission and the general
						election, to persons whose names may be upon those lists, to obtain the
						evidence of any mistakes which may have occurred to themselves individually.
						I conceive it to be my duty to bring these circumstances to the attention of
						the Court, that they may be apprized of the great public interests that seem
						to invite an early announcement of their judgement on the question.</p>
					<p>I am, with great esteem,</p>
					<p>Very truly yours, &amp;c.,</p>
					<p>WM. W. MEREDITH</p>
					<p>Attorney General, Pa.</p>
					<p>The case was very ably argued before a full bench of Judges, by J. McDowell
						Sharpe, Esq., for defendant in error. We presume a decision will soon be
						announced by the court, and we feel assured that such a decision will be a
						correct and proper one. The Judges hold a high position for integrity and
						legal ability, and it is scarcly possible that they will sustain a law in
						plain and direct conflict with the fundamental law of the State. If the
						Congress of the United States can disfranchise a citizen of Pennsylvania for
						one cause, they may for another, and in a very brief period we may find the
						great State of Pennsylvania occupying the position of a <emph rend="italic"
							>department</emph> of the central government, shorn of every vestige of
						sovereignty, and ruled in everything, by the powers at Washington, now so
						completely under the domination yankee fanatics.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McClure</ln>
						<fn>A. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Chronicles the case of Henry Reilly, a citizen of Hamilton township who was
					disfranchised on the grounds that he was a deserter. Reilly challenged the
					decision in court and won. The judgement in the case has been appealed, and is
					currently before the Supreme Court.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Mr. Stanton "Speaks A Piece"</head>
				<origin>Age</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>After the apparent reversal of his position regarding the President's
					Reconstruction policy, the editorial questions the veracity of Gen. Stanton's
					conversion. Rather than being done out of conviction, the article contends,
					Stanton's move illustrates the lengths that the general will go to avoid
					"imperil[ing] his tenure of office."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>The Vote As They Fought</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The soldiers of the borough of York, and vicinity, recently organized a club,
						the call for which was signed by <emph rend="italic">two hundred and
							thirty-five</emph> veterans of the late war. The following are the
						resolutions passed by the club after its organization, which we commend to
						the politicians of the disunion-negro-suffrage party of Franklin
						County.--Where are Geary's mythical "three hundred thousand?" The soldiers
						of Pennsylvania, in the coming contest, are going to "vote as they
						fought"--for the Constitution and the Union. Here are the
						resolutions--soldiers read: </p>
					<p>WHEREAS, We, soldiers of the War for the Union, from the borough and vicinity
						of York, have formed ourselves into an organization, social and political,
						and for the purpose of defending at home as well as in the field the great
						principles of the Constitution of the United States, AND WHEREAS, we are on
						the eve of a great political contest in this State, and are desirous of
						declaring to our fellow citizens our sentiments, be it therefore unanimously</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That having fought for the Union and
						assisted to restoring the national authority throughout the land, we are
						unalterably opposed to the Radicals of Congress who are attempting to do
						what the rebels failed to do--subvert our free institutions and destroy the
						Union. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the rebellion having been crushed
						and its armies dispersed, the people of the Southern States should be
						immediately restored to their rights in the Union and that loyal
						representatives should be admitted to Congress, and we declare the late
						action of Congress excluding those States for four years from
						representation, at the same time, making them subject to taxation, to be
						unjust and tyrannical. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the government of our Fathers is a
						White Man's Government made by White men, for White men, and therefore, we
						are opposed to Negro Suffrage: and since the abolition of slavery was
						accomplished through the war, and the South have accepted the result in good
						faith, it is unjust as well as unconstitutional for Congress to force upon
						them Negro Suffrage and Negro Equality. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we will stand by President Johnson
						in his noble efforts to defeat the bold, bad men who stand in the way of the
						restoration of the States to their full constitutional rights, and that, we
						believe that in his magnamonious policy is only to be found a sure road to
						restoration of a Union of hearts, and Union of States, and peace and
						prosperity to the land. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we are opposed to the party which
						detracts from the honor which belongs to the White Soldier, of conquering
						the rebellion and saving the Union, by declaring that without the assistance
						of the negro the cause would have been lost and that "the negro bears the
						palm." </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That it comes with a bad grace from a
						party whose Rump Congress has been so busy attempting to defeat President
						Johnson's policy and legislating for the negro that it has not found time to
						equalize the bounties of soldier's or grant them bounty land, to claim to
						the "Soldiers friend" and ask them for their votes. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we believe that Hon. Hiester
						Clymer, the Democratic candidate for Governor of Pennsylvania, holds upon
						all the great principles of public policy views similar to our own. and is a
						firm supporter of President Johnson, and that therefore we will support him
						with our voices and votes. </p>
					<p>The resolutions were then, on motion, unanimously adopted.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>In the borough of York recently, reports the piece, a group of more then
					200 former soldiers organized a political club and passed a series of
					resolutions endorsing the Democratic platform. This development is a reflection
					of the attitude prevalent among the Keystone State's Civil War veterans who, it
					asserts, will "vote as they fought" in the upcoming election--"for the
					Constitution and the Union."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>How The Soldiers Are Going</head>
				<origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We have never believed that the soldiers could be induced to support Geary.
						They know that he is indebted to the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic"
							>Inquirer</emph>, for his Military reputation such as it is. They know
						that he professed to be "a life-long Democrat," until he was offered the
						nomination of the Republican party by Simon Cameron and John W. Forney. They
						know that when he became the tool of these corrupt and intriguing
						politicians, he was ready to do their bidding. They know that he has openly
						declared that he endorses the acts and the speeches of Thad Stevens. Knowing
						these things, no right thinking man among the retured soldiers will vote for
						Geary. All over the State they are arraying themselves with the Democratic
						party in support of President Johnson's policy, and in open opposition to
						the radical disunionists and their bogus Military candidate for Governor. </p>
					<p>Wherever the attempt has been made to get up clubs among the soldiers pledged
						to the support of Hiester Clymer and President Johnson's policy, the
						returned veterans have responded most heartily and enthusiastically. In York
						several hundred rallied at once to a call of that kind. In Mifflin county a
						Clymer Club has been organized among the soldiers, which already numbers a
						large proportion of that class among its members. The Perry county <emph
							rend="italic">Democrat</emph> comes to us this week with a call for a
						Soldiers' Democratic County Convention, signed by some hundreds of <emph
							rend="italic">bona fide</emph> veterans. On the other hand the soldiers
						fail to respond to calls from the supporters of Geary. We had an instance of
						their aversion to him and his party in the recent convention held in this
						county.--The meeting was ridiculously small. In Mifflin county a similar
						meeting was an absolute failure, so much that they had to choose a civilian
						to preside. In Perry county less than a dozen responded to the loudest kind
						of a call from the leaders of the Radical Disunion party. </p>
					<p>So it will be throughout the entire State of Pennsylvania. The soldiers do
						not believe that they fought through the war in vain. They not battle for
						the sacred cause of the Union, and justly regard it as an insult to be asked
						to support a political party which boldly avows its intention of preventing
						a restoration of the Union until the negroes are allowed to vote and made in
						all respects the equal of the white race. The soldiers will stand by
						President Johnson and will support his wise and statesmanlike policy. They
						cannot be gulled into endorsing the infamous schemes of such avowed
						disunionists and negro worshippers as Thad. Stevens and Charles
						Sumner.--They know that Geary is only a miserable tool in the hands of the
						Stevens faction in this State, and knowing this they will repudiate him with
						scorn and contempt. The soldiers, in the language of a brave private, <emph
							rend="italic">"will vote as they shot, of the Union and not for the
							negro."--Lancaster Intelligencer.</emph></p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Throughout the state, according to the editorial, soldiers are aligning
					themselves with the Democratic Party "in support of the President Johnson's
					policy, and in opposition to the radical disunionists and their bogus Military
					candidate for Governor."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>7</column>
				<head>Consolidation of Telegraph Companies</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>There are indications, the article reports, that the leading stockholders
					and a majority of directors of the Western Union and the American Telegraph
					companies have agreed to merge.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.05.30.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Fire</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Badebaugh</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mrs.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kyle</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>It is reported that two fires were set on May 21st, one at the stable of
					George Kyle and the other at Wolff's barn. Both of the blazes are believed to be
					the work of arsonists.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Barn Burnt</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Loose</ln>
						<fn>Joseph</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 20th, Rev. Joseph Loose's barn was destroyed by fire. It is not
					known whether the fire was intentionally set.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Davis</ln>
						<fn>P. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nace</ln>
						<fn>David B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wampler</ln>
						<fn>Julia D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wampler</ln>
						<fn>Lewis</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 22nd, David B. Nace, of McConnellsburg, and Julia D., daughter of
					Lewis Wampler, were married by Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Davis</ln>
						<fn>P. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Umberbower</ln>
						<fn>Peter</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Beyers</ln>
						<fn>Susan</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 24th, Peter Umberbower and Susan Beyers were married by Rev. P. S.
					Davis.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McElroy</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McNue</ln>
						<fn>Charles</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Carbough</ln>
						<fn>Agnes</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 24th, Charles McNue and Agnes Carbough were married by Rev. William
					McElroy.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Atherton</ln>
						<fn>Laura Bell</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Atherton</ln>
						<fn>James B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On May 22nd, Laura Bell, wife of James B. Atherton, died at age 17.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.05.30.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
