<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.02.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/14/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-02-14">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="00">14</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.02.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Governor Curtin's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a transcript of Governor Curtin's speech before the legislature on
                    Jan. 30, 1866. The address makes specific references to Chambersburg and the
                    damages suffered by town residents as a result of the various border skirmishes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.02.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Address of the Democratic State Central Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>DEMOCRATIC STATE COMMITTEE ROOM</p>
                    <p>HARRISBURG, Feb. 9, 1866</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Democracy of Pennsylvania:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The events of the last political canvas are yet fresh in your minds.</p>
                    <p>You announced your unequivocal endorsement of the restoration policy of
                        President Johnson, and denounced the doctrine of negro suffrage.</p>
                    <p>Your opponents affirmed their support of the President, and evaded the issue
                        upon the question of suffrage.</p>
                    <p>A powerful organization, large official patronage and an unscrupulous use of
                        money, secured to them the victory.</p>
                    <p>The record of the past month stripe the weak from the face of the victors.</p>
                    <p>They treat with derision the declared policy of the president. They have
                        placed the Government of the Constitution in abeyance, and its legislative
                        and executive functions are usurped by a cabal of men, who in obedience to
                        caucus, govern the nation through the forms of a directory.</p>
                    <p>The right of each State to regulate the qualifications of the electors is
                        denied; the will of the people of the District of Columbia to overridden,
                        and by an almost unanimous vote. The Republican party in Congress and the
                        State Legislature accord to the negro equal political rights with the white
                        man.</p>
                    <p>The initial step toward a war of races has been taken, and a consolidated
                        government looms up in the distance.</p>
                    <p>The tents of the President upon these points are our cardinal doctrines. In
                        sustaining him we vindicate them.</p>
                    <p>Organize in every nook and corner of the Commonwealth.</p>
                    <p>Organize to maintain the President, to maintain your principles, to restore
                        the Union, to vindicate the supremacy of your race, and to bring in
                        political oblivion the men who have been false to the Union, false to their
                        pledges, false to the instincts of their blood, and true alone to the
                        madness that rules the hour.</p>
                    <p>By the order of the Democratic State Central Committee.</p>
                    <p>WILLIAM A. WALLACE Chairman.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>William A. Wallace</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of the speech given by W. W. Wallace, the Chairman of the
                    State Democratic Party, on Feb. 9, 1866. In his address Wallace called on the
                    party faithful to "sustain the President" and "vindicate the supremacy" of their
                    "race."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Basis of Representation</head>
                <origin>Washington</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Quite a number of Constitutional amendments to regulate the basis of
                        representation in Congress, has been proposed in that body. All of them are
                        crude and not likely to obtain the end aimed at. The most stupid is that of
                        Hon. John M. Broomall of this State which is as follows:</p>
                    <p>"That representation and direct taxation shall be apportioned among the
                        States which shall be in the Union according to their numbers, counting the
                        whole number of persons in each State, excluding Indians not taxed;
                        Provided, whenever the elective franchise shall be denied by the
                        Constitution or laws of any State to any portion of their male citizens
                        above the age of twenty-one years, the same proportion shall be excluded
                        from the basis of representation."</p>
                    <p>The effect of this amendment would be directly the reverse of the object
                        which these men seek--to compel the Southern States to give the right to
                        vote to the freedmen, or else lose members of Congress in proportion to the
                        whole colored population. Mr. Broomall's amendment will not effect this
                        object, but will give the Southern States an <emph rend="italic"
                        >increased</emph> number of representatives. Thus in South Carolina the late
                        slave population numbered in 1860 over 400,000, which, at the present ratio,
                        of representation, would give three members of Congress for that portion of
                        her population. Now if South Carolina will not confer the right of suffrage
                        on about eighty thousand males old enough to vote, that number under Mr.
                        Broomall's proportion, will be excluded from the basis of representation.
                        Under the present representation of <emph rend="italic">three-fifths</emph>
                        this 400,000 is counted only as 240,000, and if the 80,000 males were
                        excluded, it would leave 320,000 who would all be counted and the
                        represented portion would be increased to <emph rend="italic"
                        >four-fifths</emph>. </p>
                    <p>The mode of <emph rend="italic">compelling</emph> the Southern States to give
                        the right to vote to the negroes, would seem to us not to be very
                        objectionable, and we think those States should not be very much averse to
                        it, as instead of losing members, they will gain, and their representation
                        in Congress be increased thereby. Let these Constitution tinkers go on; give
                        them plenty of rope and they will undoubtedly hang themselves.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacking what it deems to be a dangerous trend, the editorial criticizes
                    Radicals' various attempts to alter the Constitution since the end of the war.
                    Using a bill recently introduced by Congressman John Broomhall, a representative
                    from the Keystone state, the piece illustrates how the unintended consequences
                    of these measures may actually do more harm than good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Congratulates George Sanderson, a "sterling and uncompromising old
                    Democrat," who was re-elected mayor of Lancaster on Feb. 6th. According to the
                    article, Sanderson managed to prevail in the contest in spite of the "most
                    strenuous exertions [that] were made by the negroites" who sought to defeat him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Coffroth and Koontz Muddle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of the report issued by the Congressional Committee, which
                    awarded Gen. Coffroth the Sixteenth District's seat in the disputed election
                    with Koontz, his Republican challenger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>"That Man at the Other end of the Avenue"</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Making reference to a quote by Thad Stevens that castigated the President
                    for his Reconstruction policies, the article mocks the Radicals' support of
                    black suffrage, as contrary to the country's democratic principles. The piece
                    also includes extracts from a conversation between Frederick Douglas and Andrew
                    Johnson that took place during the president's meeting with a delegation of
                    leading black men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Freedmen's Bureau</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Senate has passed the "bill to enlarge the powers of the Freedmen's
                        Bureau."</p>
                    <p>Its provisions cover all the lately seceded States. All this vast area it
                        divides into "districts," these districts, again, are divided into
                        sub-districts, containing a county each, and furnished each with a local
                        agent. This local agent is to receive a yearly salary of $1,500. And, as
                        there are to be nearly a thousand of these new office-holders, the cost of
                        keeping them would considerably exceed a million dollars a year; which in
                        addition to the people's already enormous taxes is, however, by no means the
                        worst feature of this Freedmen's Bureau bill. It aims to throw the whole
                        burden of the support and care of an immense mass of the Southern negroes
                        upon the government.</p>
                    <p>The plan, stated in plain, truthful terms is exactly this: A plan to
                        establish <emph rend="italic">a vast Government Almshouse for
                        negroes;</emph> and to provide a thousand more office-seekers with fat and
                        lazy offices. </p>
                    <p>By the provisions of the bill, the Secretary of War is authorized to "issue
                        provisions, clothing, fuel, and other supplies, including medical stores and
                        transportation, as may be deemed needful."</p>
                    <p>That this would practically establish a gigantic Government Poor-house for
                        the negroes, is beyond dispute or denial. Naturally lazy, the Southern negro
                        would at once avail himself of this offer of Government care and support. He
                        has been told by the Abolition emissaries connected with the present
                        establishment that he need have no care for the future; and he believes it.
                        He has been taught to believe that "the Government" would soon seize and
                        parcel out to the negroes the farms and plantations of the South, stock
                        them, and furnish them with all the necessary appliances for easy and
                        comfortable living. General Grant discovered the influence of these
                        mischievous tales among the negroes of every portion of the south; the
                        negroes believe they are to be supported by the government, the fact is
                        abundantly confirmed from all quarters. This measure which has passed the
                        Senate carries out their idea in practice. It would cost the people not less
                        than Fifteen Millions a year, in addition to their present taxes; and its
                        only effect would be to maintain an army of greedy office-holders, and a
                        million or more of lazy negroes in idleness, while its tendency would be
                        directly to override the inhabitants and paralyze the industry of the South,
                        and to retard the sorely needed development of its resources.</p>
                    <p>It is amazing that a measure to force upon the Government the care and
                        support of a million lazy negroes could have passed the Senate even in these
                        crazy times. It can hardly be supposed that such a measure meets any favor
                        from the President. Indeed it seems calculated directly to interfere with
                        and embarrass his policy of Restoration. But it has passed the Senate, and
                        what hope is there that it will be defeated in the House?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After detailing the particulars of a proposed bill to enlarge the
                    Freedmen's Bureau, the article criticizes the plan because "it's only effect
                    would be to maintain an army of greedy office-holders, and a million or more ...
                    lazy negroes in idleness." Additionally, charges the author of the piece, the
                    legislation would "paralyze the industry of the South" and "retard the sorely
                    needed development of its resources."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Hit--A Palpable Hit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the House of Representatives recently, Mr. Ross, of Illinois, moved an
                        amendment of the rules so that one day in six of the time spent by Congress
                        might be devoted to the public business, to be called the "<emph
                            rend="italic">White Man's Day</emph>." </p>
                    <p>Of course the resolution was tabled instantly. The Rump Congress finds it
                        better worth while to try to save the Republican party than to restore the
                        Union; and so, instead of taking care of the national affairs of thirty
                        millions of people, it spends all its time upon the local affairs of six or
                        eight millions, who are quite capable of managing them for themselves. One
                        of these days the thirty millions will wake up and drive out these wretched
                        fanatics, who are practicing strangulation upon the political and commercial
                        life of the Republic. That will be the "white man's day."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article applauds a recent measure sardonically put forth by a
                    Congressman from Illinois calling for the establishment of "White Man's Day," to
                    be held one out of every six days that Congress devotes to public business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Brutus</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brutus, the Spirit's correspondent in Harrisburg, reports that, after a
                    lengthy debate, legislators approved the bill to provide relief for the
                    residents of Chambersburg. The measure passed by a vote of 73 to 23, with the
                    most vocal opposition coming from McKinlay, of Lawrence, McAffee, of
                    Westmoreland, and Mann, of Potter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.02.14.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The Fannettsburg Lyceum" which, for years before, and until the war, was
                        conducted with such zeal, calling in all the talent of the valley, as well
                        as talented lecturers from abroad, in which Chambersburg in no small degree
                        contributed, has again been revived with Col. R. W. McAllen, as President;
                        D. F. Noble, as Vice President; John T. Moore, as Secretary; B. C. Dawney,
                        as editor; and W. S. McAllen, as Assistant Editor. The writer hereof can
                        refer to the association with no more force than in the following clipping:
                        "It has always been our opinion that no place of any considerable size
                        should be without such an institution; and we regard it as a favorable
                        citizen that Lectures and Literary Associations seem to be among the
                        dominant ideas of the times. As a source of recreation and relief from the
                        monotony of the wintry season they are of great service and besides their
                        healthy excitement they are, or ought to be a source of substantial mental
                        benefit. That both these ends have been gained by the Society both for the
                        persons who have participated in the exercises, and for those who have been
                        auditors, we think is generally acknowledged. The eminent success of the
                        association has been as gratifying as it was desirable. The debates have
                        varied very much both in merit and interest; as all public efforts will
                        which are for the most part extemporaneous in their character,--at one time
                        full of spirit and enthusiasm, and at another dragging heavily their slow
                        length along. But undoubtedly the main feature of the Association has been
                        its series of Lectures. Here the sustained interest marked the high measure
                        of success. All the lecturers were taken from our own county, and the supply
                        has not been exhausted. As a whole, we have no hesitation in saying, the
                        lectures were of a very high order. To this we can scarcely think of a
                        single exception. Nothing was more evident than the intellectual stimulus
                        which the occasion afforded to many comparatively unaccustomed to such
                        exercise. And such stimulus will not unfrequently bring out a man more than
                        a casual observer would ever suppose to be in him, and more than he ever
                        reckoned on himself. Here is then one of the more decided advantages of such
                        an institution, the opportunity it affords for self improvement, and the
                        salutary necessity of intellectual effort it lays upon some who are gifted
                        for it, and who yet would not put it forth without such a stimulus. Many a
                        man who has figured largely on the broadest arena of the world has been
                        roused to the conciousness of his powers, by some such apparently
                        insignificant occasion. And as a general rule the audience will be
                        interested and profited in proportion to the advantage which accrues to the
                        lecturer himself. The habitually large audiences which have assembled attest
                        that there is really a disposition among us to appreciate intellectual
                        effort. We hope that such an association will be one of the standing facts
                        at least of our winter months."</p>
                    <p>"DELT."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>"Delt"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dawney</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The letter offers high praise for the Fannettsburg Lyceum, which "Delt"
                    contends is an excellent institution because it provides members of the
                    community with an "intellectual stimulus" and an opportunity "for
                    self-improvement."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The letter endorses the proposal to build the Normal School in
                    Chambersburg, employing several rationales to justify the move.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Largenreine</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linbeat</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 26th, Dr. Henry Largenreine and Elizabeth Linbeat, of Carlisle,
                    were married by Rev. R. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monart</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bauer</ln>
                        <fn>Amelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Monart and Amelia Bauer were married on Feb. 6th, by Rev. R. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 8th, Daniel Bear and Rebecca Arnold were wed in a ceremony
                    performed by Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>North</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 6th, Peter North and Mary E. Miller were married by Rev. Joseph
                    King.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Selrich</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Selrich</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 5th, George Selrich, son of Phillip Selrich, died. George was 10
                    months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.02.14.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
