<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.07.04">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>08/09/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1866-07-04">
			<year>1866</year>
			<month norm="07">July</month>
			<day norm="00">04</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.07.04.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>The "Deserter" Case</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Argument of J. McD. Sharpe, Esq., before the Supreme Court of Pennsylvania,
						in the case of Huber vs. Reilly, generally known as the "Deserter" Case.</p>
					<p>May it please the Court, I trust your honors will believe me when I say that
						I rise to discuss the question, under feeling of the most painful
						embarrassment. I am overcome by the consciousness that nothing I can say
						will either instruct, or edify the mind of the Court. I am overpowered by
						the reflection that upon a proper presentation of the question, now at the
						bar of the Court, may depend to some extent, at least, its right and proper
						decision, and that most certainly upon its correct determination, hang
						suspended the liberties of near thirty thousand freemen of Pennsylvania.
						Indeed this is all odds the most important case ever argued before this
						tribunal. Other cases have been discussed here, involving millions of money.
						A few involving the life of the citizen. But this case involves that,
						without which property would be valueless, and life itself a curse--the
						possession of the privileges of a freeman and his right to call himself a
						citizen of Pennsylvania. With such fearful responsibilities weighing upon
						the speaker, it is no wonder that his tongue should hesitate, his cheek pale
						and his heart faint. One thought alone nerves him to proceed, it is the
						consciousness of the justice of his cause; the faith that truth in the end
						always must triumph, and the firm conviction that the learning of this court
						can master the gravest subjects and solve the most intricate questions, even
						when aided by feeble insturmentalities. Thus stimulated and encouraged I
						shall endeavor to present this case to the court, with as much brevity and
						as little trespass upon your patience as its importance will permit.</p>
					<p>After four years of the most fearful internecine strife known to modern
						history, it hath pleased God to bring this nation back into the paths of
						peace. The temple of Janus is closed and the sounds of war are hushed
						throughout all our borders.--The thirsty earth hath drunk her fill of blood
						spilled in fratricidal strife. The moloch of war hath been so gorged with
						the victims that even his hunger is appeased. The pangs and throes of a
						gigantic revolution have passed off and the Republic lives.--Time and again,
						our liberties were well nigh wrecked upon the treacherous rock of military
						despotism. Though we held fast to the Constitution, and as the mariner
						clings to the plank when night and the tempest are around him, it was not
						without much reproach through bitter tribulation. During those four bloody
						years it was not always safe to say, we love the government which are
						fathers gave us, and we mean to stand by its organic laws as the only
						palladium of our liberties Many edicts were issued and laws passed both by
						the national and State legislatures which did not pretend to have a
						Constitutional warrant, but boasted themselves to be the offspring of
						military necessity. The war powers of the government expanded to such
						colossal proportions that the Constitution was wholly overshadowed and its
						sanctity mocked and profaned. Indeed there was quite a large school of
						politicians, who boldly proclaimed that the Constitution was not intended
						for times of war. Bold blasphemy; unblushing effrontery, thus to stigmatize
						the wisdom of its framers; men who having broken the chains of tyranny,
						after a struggle of eight weary years, it is now pretended, so loved
						bondage, that when they came to form a government they pined an unbridled
						sceptre in the hands of their own servants more potent to smile down their
						liberties, than that of the monarch against whom they had rebelled.--What is
						to be said of the folly and the mariner, who when his vessel is out upon an
						unknown and tempestuous sea, with a starless night above him, and the raging
						waves around him, would throw his chart and compass overboard? What is to be
						said of the folly, aye worse than folly, the wickedness of those, who, when
						the ship of state freighted with the hopes of human liberty, is tossed about
						upon an angry ocean, its crew in mutiny, its sails gone, and itself a
						helpless wreck rushing upon the breakers, would cast the helmsman into the
						deep and throw the chart of the Constitution after him. Surely madness must
						rule the hour, which gives birth to such follies. We submit that there is a
						time when the Constitution is of more value than at other times, it is
						during the exigencies of war. Because it is just in such times that there is
						the strongest temptation to usurp unwarranted powers. It is then, the
						strongest tendency to centralization manifests itself. It is then, that the
						voice of reason and the pleadings of outraged justice are too often stifled
						by the gust of passion or remain unheeded amid the dreams of ambition. If
						there is a time when we can do better without a Constitution that other
						times, it is when we are in a state of profound peace. Then there is no
						opportunity for, and therefore little danger of usurpation being successful.
						The machinery of government runs smoothly and without a single jar in its
						accustomed grooves. He who would attempt to play the usurper then, would
						swiftly rush upon his own destruction. It is only in times of civil
						commotion, that some desiring Caesar can seize and bind the liberties of the
						people.</p>
					<p>These strange doctrines and new theories about war powers and military
						necessity sound better everywhere else, than in this august presence. The
						plea of tyrants must surely be unwelcome in a court which is sworn to uphold
						the Constitution. I fondly hoped that the learned counsel (Mr. Ceasna) who
						opened this discussion would have led his train of though along by the old
						constitutional landmarks. Instead of this he mounted his war steed and
						galloped in gallant style along the highway of military necessity. No
						warning finger board admonishing him, as he rushed on, that he was on the
						wrong road, availed to turn him back. He had started for a goal and he must
						reach it. At length it is won and he exclaims, "when the Constitution gives
						Congress a power, it also confers all powers that are either convenient or
						necessary to carry the delegated power into successful execution." In other
						words unconstitutional means may be employed to execute a constitutional
						power. Congress has "the power to raise and support armies," thereofre it
						may quarter them upon the citizens. Congress has the power to "make the
						rules for the government and regulation of the land and naval forces,"
						therefore it may punish the deserter by robbing him of his citizenship,
						without a trial and conviction by <emph rend="italic">due process of
						law</emph>. The Constitution prohibits the quartering of troops upon the
						citizen. It is equally emphatic in its denunciation of all attempts to rob
						him of his life, liberty and property, except by the judgement of his peers
						or the law of the land. Yet because these are convenient and may at times be
						necessary means to execute the delegated powers above quoted, the learned
						counsel argues that such means may be properly and constitutionally used.
						This argument makes the Constitution <emph rend="italic">a felo de
						se</emph>. What can be more illogical and absurd than to make the incidental
						power stronger, and give it a wider sweep, than the substantive power? Yet
						to such desperate straits is the counsel driven, in order to justify the
						construction which he claims for the act of Congress. We will not attempt to
						follow the gentleman further in his latitudinariansim, but will content
						ourselves with a brief elaboration of the following propositions: </p>
					<p>1st. The right to regulate suffrage, and to prescribe the qualifications of
						electors, is a State right, and Congress has no power either directly or
						indirectly, to interfere with or impair that right.</p>
					<p>2d. The act of Congress of the 3d of March, 1865, is an <emph rend="italic"
							>ex post facto</emph> law, and, therefore, violates the Federal
						Constitution. </p>
					<p>3d. The act proposes to inflict and impose pains and penalties upon supposed
						offenders, before and without a trial and conviction by due process of law,
						and therefore is in direct antagonism to the bill of rights.</p>
					<p>4th. The act is in conflict with the Constitution of the united States,
						because in disfranchising the citizen without making any provision for the
						trial and conviction of the offender, Congress has usurped the exercise of
						judicial authority.</p>
					<p>No one, we presume, will doubt that before the Federal Constitution was
						adopted and the Union was formed, all governmental power was in the States.
						By adoption of the Constitution a division was made of this power, and
						certain portions of it were delegated to the United States the <emph
							rend="italic">residuum</emph> remaining in the States except so far as
						it was extinguished by express prohibitions upon the States. Thus, the
						Constitution of the United States declares, "the powers not delegated to the
						United States by the Constitution, nor prohibited by it to the States, are
						reserved to the States respectively or to the people."--We have thus the
						Constitutional fact, that the States are to exist concurrently with the
						Federal Government having certain powers beyond the control of the United
						States, for they or the people are expressly declared to be possessed of all
						powers not delegated to the Federal Government, or expressly prohibited to
						them. It will also be admitted that whilst the United States are absolutely
						sovereign over all subjects delegated to them, yet, their jurisdiction being
						derivative, is necessarily limited. We have then these two Constitutional
						facts:-- 1st. States are to exist concurrently with the United States,
						having a class of subjects exclusively within their dominion, and beyond the
						reach of Federal power. 2d. The Federal Government is to exist concurrently
						with the States, having an absolute and sovereign control over all maters
						delegated to it. Let us assure ourselves of the correctness of these
						propositions, by a few quotations from the judgments of the learned court:
						In Sharpless vs. the mayor of Philadelphia 9 Harris 160, J. Black said, "In
						the beginning the people held in their own hands all the power of an
						absolute government, the transcendent powers of parliament devolved on them
						by the revolution (1 Bald 220; 8 Wheaton 584; 2 Peters 656). Antecedent to
						the adoption of the Federal Constitution the power of the States was supreme
						and unlimited, (3 Serg. de Rawle, 68). If the people of Pennsylvania had
						given all the authority which they themselves possessed, to a single person,
						they would have created a despotism as absolute in its control over life,
						liberty, and property, as that of the Russian autocrat.--But they delegated
						a portion of it to the United States, specifying what they gave and
						withholding the rest. The powers not given to the government of the State
						with certain limitations and exceptions expressly set down in the State
						Constitution. The Federal Constitution confess powers particularly
						enumerated; that of the State containing a general grant of all powers not
						excepted. The construction of the former instrument is strict against those
						who claim under it; the interpretation of the latter is strict against those
						who stand upon the exceptions, and liberal in favor of the government
						itself.--The Federal Government can do nothing, but what is authorized
						expressly or by clear implication; the State may do whatever is not
						prohibited." In the same case, on page 179, the present Chief Justice said,
						"The Federal Constitution sprung from the experienced necessities of the
						States of the confederacy, and was formed out of powers specifically granted
						and enumerated by the people. To the extent of the powers granted, this
						instrument restrains the sovereignty of the States, but the powers not
						delegated to the United States by the Constitution nor prohibited by it to
						the States, are reserved to the States respectively or to the people.
						Because the people are more largely represented in the State government,
						than in the national; and because the powers granted to the Federal
						Government are in derogation of State rights, the rule of strict
						construction as applied to these grants is obviously conservative and just,
						though no universally admitted. The people are the source of all political
						powers.--They enumerate those they grant to the Federal government, and
						those they reserve from State government. The Legislative power of the
						States extends to all subjects properly legislative, not found in or the
						other of these enumeration's, and the only question additional to those
						already stated, that can arise on the constitutionality of a State law is,
						does it contravene the grants in the Federal Constitution?" </p>
					<p>In Kneedier <emph rend="italic">et al</emph> vs. Lane <emph rend="italic">et
							al</emph> 9 Wright 258, Chief Justice Woodward said, "It is impossible
						to study our State and Federal Constitutions, without seeing how manifestly
						the one was designed to guard and maintain the personal and social rights of
						the citizen; the other to take care of his external relations. Nurture,
						education, property, home, wife and children, servants, administration of
						goods and chattels after death, and a grave yard in which to sleep the sleep
						of death, these are among the objects of State solicitude, in the protection
						of which the State provides civil authorities and back of them as the <emph
							rend="italic">posse comitatus</emph> and the militia to make the civil
						administration effectual." In the same case, on page 264, Mr. Justice
						Thompson said, "The Constitution of the United States defines and enumerates
						the powers of the general government, and limits them by the solemn
						declaration that the powers not delegated to the United States by the
						Constitution, nor prohibited by it to the States, are reserved to the States
						respectively, or to the people; the government established by the
						Constitution is, therefore, a limited government, beyond the limitations of
						which including necessary incidents of expressly granted powers, all
						exercise of authority by Congress is mere usurpation. We should remember
						this in construing the Constitution; and we should remember also, that the
						entire machinery of government provided by it, was poised between checks and
						balances, designed not only to prevent it from transcending its orbital
						limits, but to guard against oppression from other sources. The objects to
						be attained, as declared in the preamble, must be kept in view, when we are
						called to expound its provisions; and we are bound to construe it, so as to
						preserve and advance them all. The purpose as declared in the preamble was
						"to form a more perfect Union, establish justice [,] insure domestic
						tranquility, provide for the common defense, promote the general welfare,
						and secure the blessings of liberty to ourselves and our posterity. Each of
						these objects are supposed to be secured by the Constitution, and no one of
						them must be overlooked in a too eager desire to lend a supposed efficiency
						to some other. To do so would endanger the whole. To provide for the common
						defense is one purpose avowed for establishing the Constitution, and the
						duty devolves on Congress to execute it; but it must not be executed in such
						a manner as to encroach on the paramount purpose of securing the blessings
						of liberty to ourselves and our posterity also declared. That its one
						instance to show that no legislation, nor no construction, can be valid or
						sound which is not in harmony with the Constitution." </p>
					<p>In the same case, page 277, Mr. Justice Strong said: "It is said, and truly
						said, that the federal government is one of limited powers. It has no other
						than such as are expressly given to it, and such as (in the language of the
						Constitution itself) 'are necessary and proper for carrying into execution
						the powers expressly given.' By the tenth article of the amendments, it is
						ordained that the powers not delegated to the United States by the
						Constitution, nor prohibited by it to the states, are reserved to the states
						respectively, or to the people. Of course there can be no presumption in
						favor of the existence of a power sought to be exercised by Congress. It
						must be found in the Constitution."</p>
					<p>Keeping firmly fixed in our memories these emphatic enunciations of the true
						principles of construction of the federal and state Constitutions, let us
						look into the Constitution of the United States and learn what powers the
						states have delegated to the national government. We read therein, that
						Congress shall have power,</p>
					<p>"To lay and collect taxes, duties, imports and excises. To pay the debts and
						provide for the common defence and general welfare of the United States."</p>
					<p>"To borrow money on the credit of the United States."</p>
					<p>"To regulate commerce with foreign nations and among the several states and
						with the Indian tribes."</p>
					<p>"To establish an uniform rule of naturalization and uniform laws on the
						subject of bankruptcy throughout the United States."</p>
					<p>"To coin money, regulate the value thereof and of foreign coin, and fix the
						standard of weights and measures."</p>
					<p>"To provide for the punishment of conterfeiting the securities and current
						coin of the United States."</p>
					<p>"To establish post offices and post roads."</p>
					<p>"To promote the progress of science and useful arts by securing for limited
						terms authors and inventors the exclusive rights to their respective
						writings and discoveries."</p>
					<p>"To Constitute tribunals inferior to the Supreme Court."</p>
					<p>"To define and punish piracies and felonies committed on the high seas and
						offences against the laws of nations."</p>
					<p>"To declare war, grant letters of marque and reprisal, and make rules
						concerning captures on land and water."</p>
					<p>"To raise and support armies."</p>
					<p>"To provide and maintain a navy."</p>
					<p>"To make rules for the government and regulation of the land and naval
						forces."</p>
					<p>"To provide for the organizing, arming and disciplining the militia, and for
						governing such part of them as may be employed in the service of the United
						States."</p>
					<p>"To exercise exclusive legislation in all cases whatsoever over such
						districts (not exceeding ten miles square) as may by cession of particular
						states and the acceptance of Congress, become the seat of government of the
						United States."</p>
					<p>"To make all laws which shall be necessary and proper for carrying into
						execution the foregoing powers, and all other powers vested by the
						Constitution in the government of the United States, or in any department or
						office thereof."</p>
					<p>This is the chart of powers granted by the states to the federal government,
						and besides those therein enumerated, the counsel now addressing the court
						knows of no others.</p>
					<p>The prohibitions upon the states are as follows:</p>
					<p>SECTION 10. (1) "No state shall enter into any treaty, alliance or
						confederation; grant letters of marque and reprisal, coin money, emit bills
						of credit, make anything but gold and silver coin a tender of payment of
						debts; pass any bill of attainder <emph rend="italic">ex post fact</emph>
						law, or law impairing the obligation of contracts or grant any title of
						nobility." </p>
					<p>(2) "No state shall without the consent of Congress lay any imposts or duties
						on imports and exports, except what may be absolutely necessary for
						executing its inspection laws; and the net produce of all duties and imposts
						laid by any state on imports or exports shall be for the use of the treasury
						of the United States, and all such laws shall be subject to the revision and
						control of Congress. No state shall without the consent of Congress, lay any
						duty of tonnage, keep troops or ships of war in time of peace, enter into
						any agreement or contact with another state or with a foreign power, or
						engage in war unless actually invaded, [UNCLEAR] such imminent danger as
						will not admit of delay."</p>
					<p>It will thus be observed that outside, and beyond the powers delegated to the
						federal government and prohibited to the states, there is a large and
						undefined class of subjects, which relate to the domestic economy and
						individual rights of the people, over which the states are expressly
						declared by the Constitution of the United States to have absolute
						jurisdiction and complete control. In searching for the domain of a federal
						and State jurisdiction respectively, we must not forget the rules of
						interpretation, to which we have already called the attention of the court.
						To which may be added the canon laid down by Chief Justice Black in
						Commonwealth vs. Hartman, 5 Harris 119--in the following emphatic language:
						"It is to be remembered that the rule of interpretation for the state
						constitution differs totally from that which is applicable to the
						Constitution of the united States. The latter instrument must have a strict
						construction, the former a liberal one. Congress can pass no laws but those
						which the Constitution authorizes either expressly or by clear implication;
						whilst the Assembly has jurisdiction of all subjects in which its
						legislation is not prohibited. The powers not granted to the government of
						the Union are withheld; but the State retains every attribute of sovereignty
						not taken away."</p>
					<p>Now, we look in vain among the powers delegated to Congress for one which
						gives the Federal Government authority to regulate the right of suffrage, or
						to prescribe the qualifications of electors in the States,--Among the
						prohibitions none are to be found which take away from the states the
						jurisdiction over this subject.</p>
					<p>The only power given to Congress over the question of citizenship, is that
						which confers the right "to establish an uniform rule of naturalization
						throughout the United States." The fact that this power, and this alone, was
						conferred upon Congress, is pregnant with the strongest negation of any
						other power to regulate the status of citizenship or the right of suffrage,
						either directly or indirectly in the States. <emph rend="italic">Expressio
							unius est exclusio alterius</emph><emph rend="italic">expressum facit
							[UNCLEAR] tacitum</emph>. The question is not, (for that is admitted)
						has Congress the right to legislate an alien into a citizen? But the
						question is, can Congress by a legislative act, transform a citizen into an
						alien? Can Congress by the word of its power, strip a citizen of
						Pennsylvania of the high prerogatives of a freeman, and sentence him unheard
						and without a trial, to a vassalage more ignominious than that of a Russian
						serf? The statement of this monstrous proposition furnishes its own
						sufficient answer. The argument of the learned counsel on the other side
						assumes that there is such a thing as citizenship of the United States,
						wholly separate and independent of a state citizenship; that Congress has
						such control over United States citizenship, as to be able, at will, to
						deprive its possessor of the immunities and privileges that appertain to it;
						that the Act of Congress, of the 3d of March, 1865, "stripped deserters of
						the franchises of the United States citizenship, and made them aliens; and
						that inasmuch as the Constitution of Pennsylvania declares that only
						citizens of the United States shall enjoy the right of suffrage within her
						limits this man, (Mr. Reilly) by virtue of this act of Congress, ceased to
						be a qualified elector of Pennsylvania. Such (if we understand the
						gentleman,) is the process of reasoning, on the part of the counsel for the
						plaintiff in error. This argument seems at first blush, to be plausible, but
						a little consideration will disclose its heresy. By what process does a
						native Pennsylvanian become a citizen of the United States? No
						naturalization is necessary in such a case, and no Congressional action is
						required.--Birth in Pennsylvania makes him a citizen there, and through his
						State citizenship and in consequence of it, he becomes a citizen of the
						United States. The one citizenship is inseparable from and dependent upon
						the other. The same blow that strikes the one down destroys the other also.
						It is impossible for Congress to deprive deserters of the capacity to hold
						any office of trust or profit under the United States, or of the privilege
						of exercising any rights of citizens thereof, without at the same time
						robbing them of the prerogatives of State citizenship. Now, the able counsel
						on the other side, seem to appreciate the difficulty of maintaining the
						doctrine that Congress, by a direct exercise of power, can enter the domains
						of the State and regulate questions of State citizenship. They appear to
						shrink back from the bold assertion of the dogma that Congress can directly
						interfere with the right of Pennsylvania to regulate the qualifications of
						her own electors. But they seek to screen themselves from the odium
						attaching to such a heresy, by erecting a thin breastwork out of a United
						States citizenship, distinct and distinguishable from a State citizenship,
						and from behind this barrier they cast their missiles at the rights of the
						States. They say, we will not attempt to interfere with your State
						citizenship <emph rend="italic">eo nomine</emph>, but we will take from you
						your immunities as a citizen of the United States, and our State
						Constitution then comes to our rescue and declares that you thereby cease to
						be qualified as an elector. If it be true, as we believe, and we have tried
						to show that a native born citizen becomes a citizen of the United States
						only through his state citizenship, then this act of Congress, by depriving
						deserters of the prerogatives of citizens of the United States, makes a
						direct assault upon the qualifications of electors in the States. We submit
						that it is unconstitutional and void, because no power to do this thing was
						ever delegated by the State to the federal government. But it is argued that
						Congress may "make rules for the regulation of the land and naval forces."
						That discipline is necessary for the preservation of armies; that desertion
						is ruinous to their efficiency and existence; that therefore, Congress may
						define what shall constitute desertion, may prescribe its punishment, and as
						a part of the pains and penalties, may inflict disfranchisement and loss of
						citizenship. It is said that this reasoning makes the act constitutional; we
						submit that it does not. We affirm that Congress cannot, even by way of
						punishment for crime, attach such disqualifications to the elective
						franchise in the States, as to entirely deprive any class of citizens the
						right to vote. If Congress can inflict this punishment for desertion, it may
						go on and define new offenses <emph rend="italic">ad infinitum</emph>, each
						of which shall be punished in the same way. Thus it may declare, that to
						speak disrespectfully of the President of the United States, or to call in
						question its own infallible wisdom, shall be sedition. It may declare, that
						to deny the equality of the negro or to deprive him of any of the rights
						enjoyed by the white man, shall be a crime against "the higher law," and all
						these offenders shall become aliens and cease to be voters. It was one of
						the vices of the conscription law that, whilst the Constitution recognized
						the substantive and independent existence of the militia of the States, it
						allowed draft after draft to be made from this State force until the whole
						came to be swallowed up in what was called "the national forces." So, by
						allowing Congress to punish desertion by loss of citizenship, you invite a
						similar punishment for other offenses, until one class after another is
						deprived of the elective franchise and the State lies prostrate at the feet
						of Congress, without voters and without citizens, having only a name to
						live, whilst in truth it is dead. It may be said that this is putting an
						extreme case and pushing the consequences of such legislation to the verge
						of absurdity. But when a power not expressly conferred upon Congress is
						sought to be inferred from some general power of the Constitution, and an
						examination discloses the fact that the power is capable of such abuse as to
						enable those who exercise it to subvert the government itself, we are
						furnished the strongest argument against the existence of such inferential
						power. To say that a power has recently been discovered which is potent
						enough to strike down State rights, and wipe out State lines when exercised
						to its fullest capacity, is simply to assert that the Constitution our
						forefathers framed has been changed by some remarkable revolution. Who would
						deny that our whole system has been changed, if Congress can stretch forth
						its sceptre over the States and issue its edict that no man shall vote until
						he attained the age of thirty, or the black man shall vote and the white man
						shall not vote in Pennsylvania. No less is the usurpation which unasks its
						designs under the specious covering of a punishment for crime. </p>
					<p>AGNEW, Judge--You have been arguing a question of power. We may agree that
						the law, with regard to desertion, was impolitic, but that is not the
						question of power. Congress has the power to establish post offices and post
						roads. Robbing the mail is an offence, and punished even to the extent of
						death. Do you think that Congress has the power to disfranchise the mail
						robber? Rather, when Congress is in the exercise of its undoubted power, may
						it not extinguish the right of franchise as well as any other, when in such
						exercise of power, as a consequence entailed. They may extinguish private
						rights, including the right of life."</p>
					<p>Mr. SHARPE--"Certainly Congress may for some offences prescribe the
						punishment of death. But Congress cannot change or increase the punishment
						of crime, after it has been committed. Congress cannot make an act which was
						innocent, at the time it was done, a crime, and punish it as such."</p>
					<p>AGNEW, Judge--"It may be <emph rend="italic">ex post facto</emph>, but I am
						asking you only a question of law." </p>
					<p>Mr. SHARPE--"I think Congress cannot take away the right of suffrage as a
						punishment for crime. In doing so, it is interfering with those matters,
						over which the Constitution gives the States exclusive and absolute
						dominion. Congress cannot do indirectly what it cannot do directly. Your
						Honor would not pretend that Congress can directly by legislation, prescribe
						the qualifications of electors in the States. Whilst your Honor will no
						doubt concede this much, I go a step further and submit that Congress cannot
						add even as a punishment for crime, disqualifications to the elective
						franchise, strange and unknown to the Constitution and laws of Pennsylvania.
						["]</p>
					<p>AGNEW, Judge--"I understand that."</p>
					<p>WOODWARD, C. J.--"I believe that Congress has never punished the mail robber
						until convicted, or indeed no other criminal. Therefore it does not follow,
						that if Congress has the constitutional power to deprive a citizen of his
						citizenship, that they may do so without conviction. Rather Congress has not
						the power to take away the right of suffrage without trial."</p>
					<p>STRONG, Judge--"Conceding that Congress has the power to inflict punishment,
						is it not true that the right of suffrage is inseparable from the State
						government itself. Is not therefore any action of Congress which takes away
						the right of suffrage a direct blow at States rights."</p>
					<p>Mr. SHARPE--["]Exactly. As I said before, Congress may go on and disfranchise
						class after class of voters, until the State has no electors left."</p>
					<p>AGNEW, Judge--"Well, if we all commit crime, I suppose we will."</p>
					<p>Mr. SHARPE--["] One word more upon this general head and we shall leave it.
						Some information may be obtained from the political history of the times, in
						regard to the views which the moral latitudinarian constructionists
						entertain upon this right of Congress to interfere with the elective
						franchise in the States. There is by no means a small school of our
						statesmen who insist that Congress has the power and ought to exercise it of
						declaring who shall vote in the States that seceded from the Union. But the
						chief corner stone of this asserted power, is the dogma, that these States
						have forfeited their rights, and are now to be treated as conquered
						provinces. The very basis of the doctrine is pregnant with the affirmation
						that it has not and can not have any application to a State that never
						seceded. Pennsylvania has never attempted to secede, she never lost her
						status in the Union, and therefore upon the theory of this class of
						statesmen, Congress cannot usurp such a right in this Commonwealth. Again,
						the specious pretext which is set up in favor of this act of Congress, that
						disfranchisement is entailed upon the offender as a punishment for his
						crime, is triumphantly swept away by the recent congressional action of many
						of the same congressmen who passed the act in controversy.--This ultra
						school of politicians, we presume will not insist that northern deserters
						are worse that southern traitors. If deserters could be constitutionally
						disfranchised by an act of Congress, it is certainly fair to suppose that
						traitors might be disposed of in the same way, by the same summary process.
						Yet it has been discovered since the passage of the act of Congress of the
						3d March, 1865, that rebels cannot be robbed of their citizenship without an
						amendment to the Constitution of the United States. Two thirds of the
						Congress and three fourths of the State legislatures must all concur before
						rebels can be made aliens. Yet the counsel for the plaintiff in error insist
						that a simple utterance by a bare majority of Congress can strip northern
						deserters of the immunities of citizenship, consign them to slavery, doom
						them to infamy, and set them up as a mark for the finger of scorn to point
						at. If this be true, I had rather be a southern traitor than a northern
						deserter.</p>
					<p>2nd. Our second proposition is: That this act of Congress is an <emph
							rend="italic">ex post facto</emph> law, and, therefore, violates the
						Federal Constitution. It is apparent from the case stated that the person
						whom it sought to disfranchise as drafted into the military service of the
						United States on the 19th of July, A. D. 1864, and failed to report to the
						Provost Marshal of the 16th district of Pennsylvania, in obedience to the
						draft notice. The act of Congress in dispute was approved on the 3d of March
						1865. It is clear from this statement of facts, that if Henry Reilly was
						guilty of any offence at all, he committed it some months prior to the
						passage of the act of Congress. If therefore the law is <emph rend="italic"
							>ex post facto</emph>, within the meaning of that phrase in the
						Constitution, it is wholly void and inoperative; because the Constitution
						declares in unmistakable language, "<emph rend="italic">that no bill of
							attainder or ex post facto law shall be passed</emph>." </p>
					<p>We have an authoritative exposition of what constitutes an <emph
							rend="italic">ex post facto</emph> law from the Supreme Court of the
						United States made at an early day. In Caleden and wife vs. Bulland and
						wife, 3 Dallas, 300 Judge Chase defined an <emph rend="italic">ex post
						facto</emph> law to be one which, 1st, Aggravates a crime, or makes it
						greater that it was when committed. 2d, Every law that changes the
						punishment, and inflicts a greater punishment, than the law annexed to the
						crime when committed. 3d, Every law that alters the legal rules of evidence,
						and receives less, or different testimony, than the law required at the time
						of the commission of the offence to convict the offender. If this act of
						Congress is open to all or any of these faults, it is <emph rend="italic">ex
							post facto</emph>, and therefore void and of no binding force. Does it
						aggravate the crime, and change the punishment making it greater than
						before. We submit that it does. The crime we are considering is not that of
						desertion, but simply a neglect to report in answer to a draft notice.
						Although a majority of this court held in Kneedler <emph rend="italic">et
						al</emph> vs. Lane <emph rend="italic">et al</emph> 9 Wright, 238, that a
						defaulting drafted man is a deserter, and may be punished as such, we cannot
						rid ourselves of the idea that there is a wide distinction between the two
						classes of offenders. whilst the deserter was usually tried and sentenced by
						a court martial, the defaulting drafted man was simply arrested and put into
						the military service.--The military authorities made this distinction, and
						comported with the common sense view of the matter. But the counsel argue
						that defaulting drafted men having <emph rend="italic">been</emph> declared
						deserters, and amenable to the penalties of desertion, might have been shot
						to death by musketry under the law, as it existed prior to the 3d of March,
						1865, and that therefore an act which punishes simply with forfeiture of
						citizenship, neither aggravates the crime, nor enhances its punishment. But
						we appeal to the gentlemen to answer whether a non-reporting drafted man was
						ever shot to death, or punished in the same manner as deserters from actual
						service. If such cases have ever occurred they have never come to our
						knowledge. But supposing for the sake of the argument, that defaulting
						drafted men stand in the same guilt with deserters from actual service, and
						may pass under the same condemnation, yet the punishment is not necessarily
						death; it may be death, or such other punishment as a court martial may
						choose to inflict. The punishment is, therefore, discretionary. and the
						exercise of that discretion would ordinarily be controlled by the peculiar
						circumstances of each individual case. A careful reading of the act of
						Congress will show, however, that this option is to a great extent destroyed
						and taken away. A deserter from actual service and a non-reporting drafted
						man are declared to be equally criminal, and must be punished <emph
							rend="italic">at least with loss of citizenship</emph>. A less penalty
						than disfranchisement, can no longer be pronounced. Can it, therefore, be
						argued with any degree of candor that this act does not aggravate the crime,
						and increase its punishment. I oppose to the <emph rend="italic"
						>dictum</emph> of the gentlemen, the language of the law itself, which
						declares, "that in addition to the other lawful penalties of the crimes of
						desertion from the military or naval service, all persons who have deserted
						the military or naval service of the United State, who shall not return to
						the said service, or report themselves to a Provost Marshal within sixty
						days after the proclamation hereinafter mentioned, shall be deemed and taken
						to have voluntarily relinquished and forfeited their rights of citizenship,
						and their rights to become citizens. </p>
					<p>STRONG, Judge--"What is the offense provided for in the act of 1865. Is it or
						is it not an offense to be committed after a certain time shall have
						elapsed, that is sixty days after the proclamation should be issued?"</p>
					<p>Mr. SHARPE--"I think not, sir, it is true that the man who does report
						himself as commanded by the proclamation, shall be relieved from punishment.
						But suppose he does not report and the sixty days have expired, what shall
						he be punished for? Not for failing to report, and to take advantage of the
						proclamation, but for his prior desertion. This sixty days proclamation was
						meant to furnish an amnesty to those who should avail themselves of it. A
						proclamation of amnesty presupposes that somebody has committed crime, and
						is liable to punishment. The President's amnesty proclamation, issued to
						those engaged in the rebellion, extended pardon to such as could and did
						avail themselves of it. Those who refused to partake of its grace and were
						and still are liable to pains and penalties, not because they rejected the
						amnesty, but because they are supposed to have committed treason. So with
						the proclamation provided for in the act of Congress, those who are obedient
						unto it shall save themselves, those who stand out against it are still
						liable to condemnation and punishment for their old offenses."</p>
					<p>READ, Judge--"The amnesty proclamation leaves the party, if he does take
						advantage of it, just where he was. But if he does not take advantage of
						this proclamation, then it prescribes an additional punishment for not
						taking advantage of it."</p>
					<p>Mr. SHARPE--"But may it please your Honor, suppose that he never saw or heard
						of the proclamation?["]</p>
					<p>READ, Judge--"That don't make any difference; it cannot make any difference."</p>
					<p>WOODWARD, C. J.--"There was no conviction in this case."</p>
					<p>Mr. SHARPE--"No sir; no man can be punished for desertion unless
						convicted.--This proclamation says that if the man does not return within
						sixty days, he shall be deemed to have forfeited his citizenship."</p>
					<p>WOODWARD, C. J.--"Then you say that this act of Congress itself is a
						conviction of the offender.["]</p>
					<p>Mr. SHARPE--"Yes sir; Congress pronounces the sentence without affording an
						opportunity to the condemned to be heard. It judges, it convicts, and it
						punishes, thereby arrogating itself judicial authority, in violation of the
						Constitution."</p>
					<p>But if possible the act is still more obnoxious to the objection of being
							<emph rend="italic">ex post facto</emph>, from the further fact that it
						alters the legal rules of evidence, and receives less or different testimony
						than the law required at the time of the commission of the offense, in order
						to convict the offender. Prior to the passage of the act no one could be
						convicted of desertion without a trial, and no evidence was sufficient to
						convict except the voluntary confession of the party, or such other
						testimony was needed as to convince the court beyond all reasonable doubt of
						his guilt. Now it is pretended that the mere failure of a drafted man to
						report at the headquarters of the Provost Marshall, and an <emph
							rend="italic">ex parte</emph> record of that fact, made out there in his
						absence, furnishes ample proof of guilt. It is upon such evidence freemen
						are to be punished with the loss of a boon of more value to the honorable
						mind than life itself. Who will doubt for a moment that the rules of
						evidence have thus been changed, and that <emph rend="italic">ex
						parte</emph> statements and hearsay testimony have been substituted for that
						full and ample proof which is attained by the party when he is confronted
						with the witnesses and has had an opportunity to sift the few grains of
						truth from the chaff of falsehood, by cross examination. </p>
					<p>3d. This brings us to our third proposition, which is that the act of
						Congress proposes to inflict and impose pains and penalties upon offenders,
						before and without a trial and conviction, and therefore is in direct
						antagonism to the bill of rights. Article 5th of the amendments to the
						Constitution declares, "that no person shall be held to answer for a capital
						or otherwise infamous crime unless a presentment or indictment of a grand
						jury, except in cases arising in the land or naval forces or in the militia,
						when in actual service, in time of war or public danger, nor shall any
						person be subject for the same offence to be twice put in jeopardy of life
						or limb; nor shall be compelled, in any criminal case, to be a witness
						against himself, <emph rend="italic">nor to be deprived of life, limb or
							property without due process of law</emph>." </p>
					<p>Article 6th declares, "In all criminal prosecutions the accused shall enjoy
						the right to a speedy and public trial by an impartial jury of the State and
						district wherein the crime shall have been committed, which district shall
						have been ascertained by law, and to be informed of the nature and cause of
						the accusation; to be confronted with the witnesses against him; to have
						compulsory process for obtaining witnesses in his favor, and to have the
						assistance of counsel for his defence.</p>
					<p>Our forefathers had drunk deep of the bitter waters of tyranny. They had
						staked life, liberty and property upon the issue with despotism. The
						struggle was fierce and bloody and its result often doubtful. At the last
						cloud of war rolled away and the sunlight of victory illuminated their
						banners. When they came to establish a government, that would secure the
						blessings of a liberty to themselves and their posterity, they were not
						unmindful of the lessons of their own experience, and regarding these
						provisions as necessary and essential bulwarks against the aggressions of
						power they incorporated them into the organic law.</p>
					<p>It is the peculiar infamy of this act of Congress that it seeks to tear down
						and scatter to the winds all these safeguards of life, liberty and property.
						It is contended in this case, that Congress meant that the failure of a
						drafted man to obey a draft notice, and report in obedience thereto, to a
						Provost Marshal[l] as and shall be conclusive evidence against him of the
						crime of desertion, and that he shall be disfranchised in consequence
						thereof, before without the ascertainment of his guilt by any court civil or
						military . This is shocking to every instinct of humanity, a [UNCLEAR] upon
						the jurisprudence of our age, a libel upon that innate sense of justice
						which has always been supposed to be a peculiar possession of the American
						people. If such be the true construction of the act of Congress, then the
						stamp act, and the duty upon tea, which brought on the American revolution
						are in great danger of being made respectable enactments. Is a citizen to be
						condemned unheard? Is he not to have a hearing? Shall he not be confronted
						with the witnesses against him? Shall he not enjoy the rights of a public
						and speedy trial?--Shall he not have compulsory process to compel the
						attendance of his witness, and have the assistance of Counsel? Can he be
						deprived of his life, liberty or property without due process of law? Are
						these rights mere myths--the fancies of a disordered brain? Or do they have
						a real and substantial existence. I beseech my brethren on the other side to
						look into the Constitution of their country. I implore them to take it down
						from the shelf, where they have hid it for the last four years, and after
						brushing the dust from it, to unroll it, and study it. What say you, my
						brethren, do you find these rights in the sacred parchment? If so, does not
						this act of Congress stand already condemned in your eyes, as well as before
						the whole world. What provision does it make for a trial? Who is to bear, to
						judge, to condemn and to pass sentence of disfranchisement? The law is as
						silent as the grave, upon all these important and vital questions. You might
						as well expect a dead man to answer you, as to hope for a reply from this
						law, thus "dead in trespasses and sins." But say, our friends on the other
						side, the act contemplates a hearing, and fixes a competent tribunal. This
						is a trial about the right of suffrage. Therefore, boards of election
						officers shall examine into and decide these questions. But it is to be
						remembered that whilst the right to vote is incidentally involved in the
						investigation, there is still a graver question at issue, is the man guilty
						of desertion? This primary question must first be met and decided before you
						reach the question of the right to vote at all. Who made boards of election
						officers judges in the questions of guilt or innocence? To decide that a man
						has not a right to vote, under this act of Congress, is first to decide that
						is a criminal, a deserter, and therefore liable to punishment. But it is
						argued that the boards of election officers do decide upon the
						qualifications of electors. In some cases they do. But in no case have they
						a right to do so, and where their decision also involves a judgement upon
						the guilt or innocence of crime, of the voter. And where the loss of
						suffrage is simply a result following a previous conviction of the offender.
						There are two grave and conclusive reasons why boards of election officers
						cannot try these questions [UNCLEAR] 1st. It is impracticable for them to do
						so. 2nd. They have no recognition in the Constitution as juridical
						tribunals, and their judgements would simply be tyrannical edicts, and not
						the deprivation of the of the citizen of his life[,] liberty and property by
							<emph rend="italic">due process of law</emph>. The impracticability of
						boards of election officers entering into the examination of such cases must
						strike every one at first blush. If there is to be a hearing at all, both
						sides must be heard. The defendant has the constitutional right to have
						compulsory process to compel the attendance of his witnesses. Suppose they
						refuse to attend.--Can election officers issue the subpoena and attachments
						to compel them to appear and testify? We know of no such authority. The case
						is urgent, it must be decided at once. If the defendant's witnesses are
						absent, will the election officers proceed to trial, and condemn upon the
						suborned testimony of government detectives and informers? If so, the
						hearing is a farce, and the trial is a mockery of justice. But suppose the
						witnesses on both sides are present, and the parties are ready for trial.
						The Constitution gives the accused "the right to have comment for his
						defense." The Government will also have the right to be heard by her
						prosecuting officer. Suppose not a single case only, but ten, twenty or a
						hundred such cases arise before the same election board, how are they all to
						be disposed of in one day. And what in the meantime becomes of the other
						hundreds of voters who are waiting at the polls for an opportunity to cast
						their ballots. It seems to me that no sensible man ought to argue that it is
						practicable for election officers to perform such duties. But this objection
						goes simply to the expediency of establishing such a tribunal. Above and
						beyond this is the fundamental objection, that election boards have no
						standing in the Constitution for the trial and conviction of offenders. A
						man shall not only, not be condemned unheard, but he shall not be condemned
						at all, <emph rend="italic">unless by due process of law</emph>. This
						doctrine is as old as <emph rend="italic">magna charta</emph> itself.--The
						hearing and trial are worth nothing unless before a constitutional tribunal.
						It is the deprivation of life, liberty and property, without a trial by some
						of the tribunals recognized by the Federal Constitution that is so
						emphatically condemned. Will my learned friends allege that boards of
						election officers can try men for their lives, deprive them of their
						property, or rob them of their liberties? Is the judgment of such a
						tribunal, upon such questions, of any more vitality in this free land, then
						the edict of the Doge of Venice? </p>
					<p>Due process of law here means the judgement of a competent and constitutional
						court. "Except in cases arising in the land or naval forces, or in the
						militia, when in actual service in times of war or public danger," the <emph
							rend="italic">trial must be by jury</emph>. In the cases within the
						exception the trial may be by court martial. We cannot without difficulty
						reconcile ourselves to the idea that a man who refuses to go late to the
						army, is, in spite of his refusal, to be considered in the army, for
						purposes of a trial and punishment by court martial. Respect for the
						doctrine of <emph rend="italic">stare decisis</emph> [UNCLEAR] us not to
						repeat our objections in this presence. Admitting then that the
						non-reporting drafted man, is to be treated as though he were in actual
						service, he can neither be tried nor punished except by the judgment of a
						court martial. Until thus tried and convicted, he is presumed to be, and in
						the eye of the law is an innocent man. No arbitrary or <emph rend="italic"
							>ex parte</emph> hearing and judgement of an election board can change
						this legal and constitutional fact. When the record of the trial and
						conviction of a defaulting drafted man, either by a jury or his countrymen,
						or by a court martial, shall be produced before an election board, it will
						be time enough for it to decide upon the right of the condemned to have his
						vote.--Until then, their decision of the question is an officious and
						unconstitutional interference with the constitutional rights of the citizen
						and of no more weight than the judgement of the King of Dehorney [UNCLEAR]. </p>
					<p>I will read, not for the edification of the court, but for the instruction of
						my friends on the other side, the fierce denunciation of Judge Coulter,
						hurled at similar legislation in Brown vs. Hummell, 6 Barr, 61. "What then
						is the law of the land, as it relates to the protection of private rights?
						Does it mean bills of attainder in the shape of an act of Assembly, whereby
						a man's property is swept away from him without hearing trial or judgement,
						or the opportunity of making known his rights or producing his evidence? It
						certainly does not. It was to guard against such things which had been
						common in the reign of the Stuarts and their predecessors, and with which
						our forefathers of the Anglo-Saxon race were familiar, that these
						irrevocable and unassailable provisions were introduced into the
						Constitution. The law of the land does not mean acts of Assembly in regard
						to private rights, franchises and interests, which are the subjects of
						property and individual dominion. But it means what is clearly indicated by
						the other provisions of the bill of rights, to wit: the law of the
						individual case, as established in a fair and open trial, or any opportunity
						given for one in court and by due course and process of law. <emph
							rend="italic">I am a Roman Citizen</emph>, were once words of power
						which brought the proudest pro-consul to a pause, when he was about to
						commit oppression; and the talismanic words I am a citizen of Pennsylvania,
						secures to the individual his private rights, unless they are taken from him
						by a trial, where he has a chance of being heard by himself, his counsel and
						his testimony, <emph rend="italic">more majorum</emph>, according to the
						laws and customs of our fathers, and the securities and safeguards of the
						Constitution.--Sir Edward Coke defines the meaning of the words by law of
						the land, for they were used in <emph rend="italic">magna charta</emph>, and
						have been sprinkled with the tears and blood of many patriots, to be a trial
						by due course and process of law. I do not therefore regard an act of
						Assembly by which a citizen of Pennsylvania is deprived of his lawful right
						as the law of the land. The first judgment upon earth was upon summons and
						hearing. Where art thou Adam? And hast thou eaten," &amp;c., preceded
						the ejectment of Adam and Eve from their beautiful inheritance, the garden
						of Eden, and the proudest legislator may learn wisdom from such an example.
						It is against principle of liberty and common right to deprive a man of his
						property or franchise while he is within the pole of the Constitution, and
						with his hand on the altar, and give it to another without hearing and trial
						by due course and process of law. I oppose against it the majestic authority
						of this great people as reflected from the Constitution. But the most
						important of all our franchises, the fight of an elector and citizen cannot
						in a confused sense be called property. It is not assets to pay debts, nor
						does it descend to the heir or administrator. But who does not feel its
						value? and who, but would turn pale if he thought he could be deprived of it
						without hearing or trial, by act of assembly." If this eminent judge were to
						rise from his honored grave, and one were to tell him, that this very thing
						so bravely denounced by him, had been attempted by the American Congress,
						how his great heart would swell with indignation, and his eloquent tongue
						flash forth its fierce invective. Glancing around upon this bench, which he
						had once occupied, along with his illustrious compeers, now so worthily
						adorned by their and his successors, in pleading accents he would beseech my
						erring brethren on the other side, not to profane this sacred temple, by the
						presence of such strange Gods, and not to corrupt the true faith by such
						false doctrines. </p>
					<p>4th. Time will not permit us to elaborate our fourth, and last proposition.
						We will content ourselves with simply stating it.--We allege that this act
						of Congress, is in conflict with the Constitution of the United States,
						because in disfranchising the citizen without making any provision for the
						trial and conviction of the offender, Congress has assumed the exercise of
						judicial power. The language of the section is, "in addition to the other
						lawful penalties of the crime of desertion from the military or naval
						service, all persons who have deserted the military or naval service of the
						United States, who shall not return to said service, or report themselves to
						a provost marshal within sixty days after the proclamation hereinafter
						mentioned, shall be deemed and taken to have forfeited their citizenship,
						and their rights to become citizens; and such deserters shall forever be
						incapable of holding any office of trust or profit under the United States,
						or of exercising any rights of citizens thereof."</p>
					<p>No provision is made in the law for a trial and hearing. No tribunal is
						established for the decision of such cases. The punishment is not to follow
						conviction by any court or tribunal known to the federal Constitution. It is
						simply the announcing and pronouncing of a sentence by Congress. If so, then
						it becomes a palpable violation of the federal Constitution, because the 1st
						section of the 3d article requires the judicial power of the United States
						to be vested in one Supreme Court and in such inferior courts as Congress
						may from time to time ordain and establish. The judges whereof shall hold
						their offices during good behavior and shall at stated times receive for
						their services a compensation which shall not be diminished during their
						continuance in office. For Congress to usurp the powers of the federal
						Courts and pronounce sentences without conviction, would then be as
						revolutionary as it would be for the federal courts to arrogate to
						themselves the powers of Congress. Such discord introduced into the
						governmental system would soon drive the spheres from their appropriate
						orbits. We submit therefore that the judgement of the court below was right
						and ought to be affirmed.</p>
					<p>We have now discharged our duty in this great case; feebly and imperfectly it
						is true, but with the honest conviction that we are right. We are convinced
						that the measure of our weakness is most completely filled up by the ability
						of this Court. It is an honor sufficient to satisfy any reasonable ambition,
						no tow occupy a seat upon that bench. The five Judges who now compose this
						Court are now making precedents which will stand as juridical landmarks in
						all time to come. You have the high privilege of teaching our children how
						an upright judiciary, amid all the temptations of arbitrary power, could
						stand unmoved by the arts of flattery, or the cajolery of those in power,
						fast by the Constitution as our fathers left it. The eyes of the whole
						people of this great Commonwealth are fixed upon this Court. They have
						nailed their faith to you and believe that you will be now, as in times
						past, the guardian of their liberties. The pen that writes the judgement of
						this Court enfranchising and disenthralling thirty thousand citizens of
						Pennsylvania will shed an additional lustre upon our jurisprudence, and will
						write an epitaph of true renown for its author more enduring than monuments
						of brass and marble.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Sharpe</ln>
						<fn>J. McDowall</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Contains a transcript of the argument presented before the State Supreme
					Court by J. McDowall Sharpe, attorney for the defense in the Huber vs. Reilly
					case.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.07.04.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>The Issue Made Up Between the President and Congress</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>After praising the President for the message he delivered to Congress
					following the passage of the Constitutional Amendment, the editorial discusses
					the motives behind the Radicals' efforts to ratify the measure as quickly as
					possible, a move it says "reveals the weakness of the Radical faction."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Slow Justice</head>
				<origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Another effort was made in the Senate by Mr. Poland to have a small measure
						of simple justice meted out to loyal men in the South, who, upon the faith
						of the Government for which they suffered, and to which they remained loyal
						under the most trying circumstances, furnished supplies to the Union armies
						in the South during the war. The measure was bitterly opposed, with
						characteristic illiberality, by Messers. Howard and Wilson. The former was
						posseses with the fanatical idea that everybody in the South must even yet
						necessarily be treated as "an alien enemy." He never heard of a belligerent
						paying for stores taken from an enemy. The Senator could not have been
						familiar with the manner in which our war with Mexico was conducted. Then,
						his private property of every description was respected and protected; even
						the smallest act of pillage received exemplary punishment in our army, all
						supplies taken for the use of the army, except the property of the Mexican
						Government, were pain for in cash. This was the principle upon which the
						recent war was to have been conducted. The only departure from it was the
						distinction made between the property of loyalists and rebels. The idea of
						repudiating the debts due to the loyal men of the South, for supplies
						furnished by them to the Union army, was never entertained until after the
						conclusion of the war. Mr. Trumbull has a correct idea upon this subject. It
						cost something to be a loyal man in the South during the rebellion; and to
						furnish supplies to the Union army was treated by the rebel authorities as
						an act of treason, and invariably subjected the loyal men who did so to
						imminent danger, not only to their property, but to their lives. In
						furnishing these supplies the loyal men of the South exhibited an
						hundredfold more patriotism than the Northern contractors, who grew fat upon
						their contracts without exposure to any danger or privation whatever. There
						are no creditors of the Government who so justly merit full and speedy
						payment of their claims as these Southern loyalists, who literally risked
						their lives, their fortunes, and their sacred honor to serve the Government
						in the hour of need. The settlement of these claims has been already too
						long deferred by the arbitrary and iniquitous ruling of the War Department.
						Th opposition offered in Congress to the speedy adjustment of such claims is
						a convincing proof of the insincerity of the profession of the Radicals of
						friendship to the Southern loyalists.--<emph rend="italic">National
							Intelligencer</emph>.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports on the failed efforts of Senator Poland to indemnify loyal
					residents of the South who furnished supplies to the Union armies during the
					war.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>A Pitiful Whine</head>
				<origin>Repository</origin>
				<commentary>"The article in last week's Repository on the decision of the Supreme
					Court in the "Deserter Case," is neither honest nor manly. We did not expect so
					much backing and filling in a journal boasting the independence of the
					Repository. It admits that this decision is a "universal amnesty to all" alleged
					deserters, and adds: "Viewed in any aspect the case can be presented, we must
					accept the conclusion that the practical decision is that the deserters cannot
					be disfranchised or punished." And yet after this apparently frank admission, it
					goes on to say:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We presume that the effect of the decision in our political struggles will
						not be material. On the one side there is an act of Congress and an act of
						the legislature, and on the other side a decision of a divided State Court,
						and it is probable that deserters will be disfranchised in some districts
						and vote in others, as heretofore. While there is a palpable conflict of
						authority upon a question so vital, and justice pleads on the one side
						against perfidy shielded by legal technicalities on the other side,
						uniformity of practice under the law cannot be attained. The people of
						Pennsylvania, as a rule, are proverbially law-abiding, and they will
						cheerfully yield their convictions and their sense of justice to the final
						adjucation of any question.</p>
					<p>Just what this muddled paragraph means we confess ourselves unable to
						determine.--Does it mean that the Republican election officers, under the
						teachings of their party leaders, will disfranchise alleged deserters in
						defiance of the decision of the Supreme Court, and thereby become exceptions
						to the "rule" that the "people of Pennsylvania are proverbially law-abiding;
						and that they will cheerfully yield their convictions and their sense of
						justice in the <emph rend="italic">final adjucation of any question</emph>."
						Let us have an explanation, Colonel. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The editorial criticizes the Repository for its equivocal reaction to the
					judgement issued in the Deserter Case.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.07.04.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Supreme Court--Franklin County</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hartie</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Heiser</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McGrath</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Noel</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Karper</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Clark</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Trindell</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wister</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>King</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Judge</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The Supreme Court sitting at Wilkesboro has announced decisions in the
					following cases from Franklin county--Miller vs. Hartie, judgement affirmed.
					Heiser vs.McGrath, judgement reversed. Noel vs. Karper, Clark vs. Trindell,
					judgement reversed. Wister vs. School Directors of Antrim township, judgement
					affirmed.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Orr</ln>
						<fn>Thomas X.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Orr</ln>
						<fn>John R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McKee</ln>
						<fn>Maggie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McKee</ln>
						<fn>Matthew</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 24th, John R. Orr and Maggie, daughter of Matthew McKee, were
					married by Rev. Thomas Orr.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Smith</ln>
						<fn>S. H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Durbarow</ln>
						<fn>Thomas R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Guthrie</ln>
						<fn>Anna M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 28th, Thomas R. Durbarow and Anna M. Guthrie were married by Rev.
					S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hamman</ln>
						<fn>P. S.</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Jones</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Davies</ln>
						<fn>Sarah J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On Jan.6th, Jacob Jones and Sarah Davies were married by P. S. Hamman, Esq.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hamman</ln>
						<fn>P. S.</fn>
						<sf>Esq.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Camp</ln>
						<fn>Christian B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Kriger</ln>
						<fn>Elizabeth D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 21st, Christian B. Camp and Elizabeth D. Kriger were married by P.
					S. Hamman, Esq.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>Died</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Bitner</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bitner</ln>
						<fn>Abraham</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On June 28th, Abraham Bitner, son of Jacob Bitner, died. Abraham was 13
					years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.07.04.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
