The outlook of soldiers in 1861 differed greatly from the opinion of the hardened veteran of 1865.  In 1861,  soldiers reflected upon the excitement of receiving their uniforms, news of friends from home in nearby regiments, and the possibility of seeing action in their first engagement.  Later in the war, men spoke of death in a matter of fact tone, asked if their discharged friends had made it home, or concerned themselves with the remaining days of their own enlistment. 
	The historian Bell Wiley hypothesized that if the Civil War writings of both North and South were tossed into the air, it would be impossible to separate them again by original region.  Indeed, it seems that the central issues the Franklin County soldier concerned himself with were the same as his Augusta counterpart.  Regardless of ideological affiliation, soldier's thoughts surrounded the common themes of military life, spirituality, and life at home.
	The boredom and terror of military life affected all soldiers.  Camp life formed the greatest subject of writings, often describing monotonous duties such as picket or guarding prisoners.  Soldiers to the best of their logistical abilities also cataloged troop movements.  Battle scenes were often dramatic but closed quickly with deferral of details to the newspapers.  It seemed the soldiers were more concerned with family and friends.
	The soldiers longed for details about life at home.  They often requested "the particulars" of life at home, a description of the ladies, recent marriages, or details of business arrangements.  Life at home went on during the war, and the writings of soldiers seemed to serve as a connection with the world they had left behind.
	Religion and spirituality emerged in unison with the previous themes of military service and life at home.  Away from home, and surrounded by the death and carnage of battle, men exercised their strong beliefs, and questioned the value of human life.  Testimonials to fallen friends characterized letters of both Augusta and Franklin.   
	Although they approached the war with great fervor in 1861, the reality of total warfare had set in by the end of the war.  Throughout the war years, the issues of military service, home front, and spirituality maintained their utmost importance to the Civil War writers of Augusta and Franklin County.       		
