<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.03.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/02/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-03-11">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.03.11.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.03.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>After the passage of the bills removing the political disabilities of two or
                        three thousand who had applied, or whose names were placed among the
                        applicants by their friends, we had expected to see the general bill, for
                        the removal of all disabilities imposed by the Amendments and Reconstruction
                        acts, taken up and hurried through both Houses of Congress. Yet we find the
                        names of individuals daily presented and the general bill still sleeping on
                        the table. The restoration of nearly all the <sic>seceeding</sic> States to
                        the Union was a recognition by Congress of their "loyalty" and yet it has
                        failed to restore many of their best citizens to their rights as citizens of
                        the United States or even of their own States. This is a severe comment on
                        the good sense of Congress, and is a stigma upon those therein who have
                        failed to rise equal to the occasion and to set at naught that partisan
                        prejudice which has so marred its legislation and the interests of the
                        country for several years past.</p>
                    <p>There has, however, been a step taken in the right direction. The select
                        committee on the removal of disabilities to whom the matter was referred,
                        reported back to the Senate, on Friday last, the following bill with the
                        recommendation that it be passed:</p>
                    <p>Be it enacted, That an act entitled "An act to prescribe an oath of office,
                        and for other purposes, approved July 2, 1862, and all parts of other acts
                        requiring the taking or administration of the oath in said first mentioned
                        act prescribed be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
                    <p>This oath has been, in the main, but a stepping stone to the unprincipled.
                        Some good men have taken it and that conscientiously, but thousands have
                        merely used it for the positions and opportunity for plunder it afforded,
                        some striking examples of which have been exhibited in the Congressional
                        Halls. Would that we could add, "and only exhibited there." It has proven,
                        as a general thing, a net to catch the competent and qualified and fill the
                        majority of officers in the South with the incompetent, or unprincipled. It
                        is therefore high time it no longer disgraced the congressional statutes.</p>
                    <p>It is said, with some degree of authority, that the above bill will pass both
                        Houses. We trust it may, and we would regard its passage also as the
                        precursor to the passage of the general amnesty bill, and the entering wedge
                        to more magnanimous legislation on the part of Congress, and with the best
                        effects on the interests and prosperity of the country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Awaits anxiously for Congress to pass a bill removing restrictions on
                    former Confederates and taking loyalty oaths to hold office. Insists
                    unscrupulous people only take such oaths to gain office and power with no regard
                    for the people. Hopes Congress will act fast to correct this situation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.03.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sixteen persons joined the Presbyterian Church last Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Post-Office Operations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During the half-year ending December 31, the Staunton Post-Office received
                    $7,844.79 in money orders and paid out $7,270.30. The office canceled 97,726
                    stamps worth $2,931.78.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpers</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forsyth</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The conference of the M. E. Church appointed H. G. Simpers to a position in
                    Augusta and W. H. Forsyth in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Follansbee</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah W. Hall and Miss Elizabeth H. Blakemore, both of Augusta, were
                    married in Mt. Solon on February 24th by the Rev. James M. Follansbee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Row</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Row, postmistress at Moffet's Creek, died at her residence on
                    March 2nd. She was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Jane S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hattie Jane Harlan, daughter of George and Jane S. Harlan, died in Staunton
                    on March 2nd after a protracted illness of three years. She was 15 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.03.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
