<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.07.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/14/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-07-29">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The all absorbing topic with our people now is the subject of the county
                        subscription to the stock of the Valley Railroad. This subject has been
                        written about and discussed in the papers, <emph rend="italic">pro</emph>
                        and <emph rend="italic">con</emph>, for a number of weeks past, and many
                        points have been brought out tending to show the greatest advantages to our
                        people from the early completion of this <emph rend="italic"
                        >necessary</emph> public improvement, and as a consequence the reasons why
                        our people, should, as one man, vote for the subscription. These reasons
                        have doubtlessly been considered by many, and we know some former opponents
                        who now propose to vote for and are working to carry the county
                        subscription. We do not propose to recapitulate the arguments already
                        adduced, but to look at the subject from another stand point.</p>
                    <p>In the first place we are positively and emphatically a railroad man. We
                        believe they have advantaged every community to which they were of easy
                        access. We are in favor of all the railroads which are projected and can
                        possibly be projected through our county. We would rejoice to see the Page
                        Valley Railroad constructed and we are equally anxious to see the Valley
                        Railroad a reality. But there are some roads more advantageous to a
                        community than others. This is the case as between the above named roads.
                        Let us look at the two.</p>
                    <p>Suppose the Page Valley Railroad built to Fisherville, without a cent's cost
                        to our people, and how would it advantage them? It will open up the section
                        through which it passes. Will it do anything further? One of the great
                        advantages of Railroads is the cheap and rapid transportation of productions
                        from the producing sections to the places of demand. Will this be afforded
                        by the Page Valley Road? We think not, and we give you our reasons. It runs,
                        in connection with other roads, to Philadelphia and New York, and for every
                        transshipment, or every road over which produce passes, an additional amount
                        is added to the cost of transportation, and by the time produce from this
                        section reaches either Philadelphia or New York, the costs reduce the net
                        receipts below what would be realized in Richmond or Baltimore and that is
                        surely no advantage. But our people do not, nor are they likely to send
                        their produce to either Philadelphia or New York, and our merchants are not
                        likely to buy there and ship over this road for the same reason.</p>
                    <p>Then as to Baltimore, which is a better market for our produce than either of
                        the above. Whether the produce shipped on this road reaches Baltimore by the
                        Manassas road and its connections, or by the Baltimore &amp; Ohio Road
                        from its point of connection with the Page Valley Railroad, it will be
                        subjected to local rates, at least after it leaves the Page Valley Road,
                        which will continue the present high rates of transportation, so much
                        complained of in this locality now. Look at it then calmly and judge for
                        yourselves if it can possibly be a competition likely to reduce the rates of
                        transportation and render it cheap.</p>
                    <p>Let us then view the Valley Railroad in this light. Will it be likely to
                        render transportation cheap? It will be a continuous line of railway to
                        Baltimore, and run, in all probability, by one company. The Baltimore
                        &amp; Ohio Railroad Company are anxious to run it when completed and
                        have made a proposition to do so. Produce will then be transported, without
                        breaking bulk, directly from any point in Augusta, or along the line of this
                        road, to Baltimore, thereby saving the additional costs of transshipments
                        and of extra tariffs where freight passes over several roads. Breaking bulk
                        and shipping over several roads, is very like a farmer starting a load of
                        hay to town and upsetting the wagon once or twice. By the time he has
                        re-loaded it his profits are considerably reduced, if any profits are left
                        after the operation.</p>
                    <p>But the prime question is, "will the stockholders favor low tariffs," and
                        thereby reduce the rates of transportation? This is the most important
                        aspect and from whence arises the greatest advantages to communities. The
                        stockholders are the City of Baltimore, $1,000,000, Baltimore &amp; Ohio
                        Railroad, $1,000,000, and the counties and towns along the line, $1,200,000.
                        What are their interests? Clearly Baltimore has not invested in this road as
                        a matter of speculation. She cares nothing for the dividends arising from
                        it. Her object is to help to open up another direct line of communication
                        from a rich and productive section, and to secure the transportation of its
                        productions to her limits. From the increase of her business thereby she
                        will derive ten-fold more advantage than if the road declared a dividend of
                        20 <emph rend="italic">per cent, per annum.</emph> This she clearly
                        understands. It is surely not her interest to drive off trade by high rates
                        of transportation, but, on the contrary, she is directly interested to have
                        the very lowest possible rates of transportation. The people of the Counties
                        and Towns along the line are also directly interested in having low rates.
                        The <emph rend="italic">People</emph> of Baltimore and the <emph
                            rend="italic">People</emph> of the Valley will own eleven-sixteenths of
                        the whole stock, and both are directly interested in low rates and they will
                        have them. It is this very thing that will secure low rates for the future
                        on this road, and force low rates on every road running through this
                        section. Stock Companies, composed of individuals, are always interested to
                        secure the greatest possible dividends, and, as owners of Railroads, are
                        continually making the effort to raise their rates and where there is no
                        competition always succeed. Where there is competition the rates are reduced
                        to the lowest possible figures. The Valley Railroad will be a competing line
                        with the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Railroad and the only competing line it
                        will have in this section. The large majority of its stockholders are, as we
                        have shown, forever committed to low rates of transportation. This will
                        secure a lasting saving to all along its route. Then people of Augusta can
                        you afford to let this advantageous offer slip? Will you not vote the
                        subscription, or do you prefer to continue to pay in the shape of freight
                        tariffs, for the future without deriving any benefit <sic>therefor</sic>, as
                        much yearly as would pay your railroad tax for three or four years?</p>
                    <p>The farmer and merchant are directly affected by and are interested in
                        lowering freight rates. The mechanic, laborer and other consumers are,
                        though seemingly indirectly, as directly interested in the same thing. They
                        pay the original cost of articles consumed with the profit and freight
                        added. If the latter be low it is directly a saving to them. Then we are
                        all, farmer, merchant, mechanic and day-laborer, interested in this matter.
                        The Valley Railroad secures the end desired. Then let us turn out, on the
                        6th of August and accomplish the greatest good to old Augusta by voting,
                        with an unanimity unsurpassed, for the County subscription.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives one of its many arguments for the benefits of subscribing to the
                    Valley Railroad. Lists the advantages Augusta residents would have, including
                    lower tariffs and direct access to prime markets in Baltimore. Tries to get
                    people to withdraw support for a rival railroad that would not pass through
                    Staunton directly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Election Day. Saturday, August 6th, 1870. Subscription to Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints an address arguing that passing the county subscription to
                    the Valley Railroad will ensure construction of the line to the economic benefit
                    of Augusta. It dismisses concerns that the subscription will result in high
                    taxes. The paper also includes a list of men appointed to canvass the various
                    voting districts on election day. City of Staunton: Chairman Capt. J.
                    Bumgardner, Jr., William Frazier, Benjamin Crawford, Col. R. H. Catlett, R. W.
                    Burke, W. H. H. Lynn, A. N. Breckinridge, S. A. Hoshour, P. H. Trout, W. H.
                    Tams, W. J. Nelson, George E. Price, John B. Scherer, Jr., D. A. Kayser, W. L.
                    Lushbaugh, Capt. W. L. Balthis, R. M. Guy, Dr. J. W. Harris, C. W. Stafford, H.
                    B. Michie, B. T. Bagby, J. Fred Effinger, W. H. Watts, George A. Smith, Dr. W.
                    S. McChesney, J. C. Gayer, A. H. Fultz, N. B. Hendry, John S. Lipscomb, John B.
                    Hoge, M. H. Effinger, Capt. T. D. Ranson, John Donovan, S. H. Hilb, R. H.
                    Fisher, Heber Ker, James W. Crawford, Charles Trayer, J. A. Moore, J. L.
                    Timberlake, W. L. Herr, Capt. W. H. Sale, J. E. Hanger, W. J. Keller. Beverly
                    Manor Township: Chairman William J. D. Bell, Col. J. Baylor, Capt. E. W. Bayly,
                    A. Anderson, Col. William A. Bell, H. L. Opie, D. R. Williams, W. W. Donaghe,
                    Jr., Fred L. Fultz, John Trimble, Dr. Walters, Capt. P. O. Palmer, St. F. C.
                    Roberts, William Taylor, R. B. Swoope, Henry Eidson, Jr., John Snapp, G. Child,
                    T. J. Mitchell, C. T. Palmer, Thomas P. Eskridge, H. P. Dickerson, A. D. Wren,
                    John M. Kinney, William J. Shumate, J. Wayt Bell, John N. Opie, Maj. John A.
                    Harman, D. C. McGuffin, Col. A. W. Harman, William F. Ast. Middle River
                    Township: Chairman William Crawford, Capt. T. J. Burke, John H. Parkins, I. J.
                    Parkins, A. T. Grooms, D. B. Hinton, Maj. James Walker, Jacob C. Roler, W. P.
                    Sheets, S. M. Crawford, A. Shomake, Jonathan Sheets, Charles S. Roler, D. B.
                    Hyde, Dr. H. B. Christian, E. B. Burke, Maj. William M. Wilson, E. L. Edmondson,
                    Hugh Connell, N. E. Lyman, Robert Kenney, Capt. C. G. Grattan, Dr. Samuel
                    Kennerly. South River Township: Chairman John Hamilton, George Bateman, W. A.
                    Abuey, A. G. Christian, J. T. Maupin, Jacob Forrer, Jacob Wisler, Dr. T. W.
                    Shelton, Rev. J. Killian, Maj. G. B. Stuart, H. L. Gallaher, William Chapman, W.
                    W. Clinedinst, W. B. Gallaher, Dr. T. G. Dellinger, Samuel H. Steele, F. M.
                    Finley, James Patrick, Col. D. S. Bell, R. C. Logan, Capt. E. Bateman, William
                    Hamilton, W. A. Mann, Charles Withrow. Riverheads: Chairman M. W. D. Hogshead,
                    R. N. Carson, William F. Smith, J. D. McGuffin, Adam Hawpe, J. S. Lightner, John
                    J. Larew, William Roan, A. A. Sproul, David Kunkle, J. Thomas McClure, J. A.
                    Bumgardner, A. Blauth, Capt. C. G. Merritt, William T. Rush, A. S. Turk, William
                    Steele, Capt. J. J. Martin, James Bumgardner, Sr., John Christian, Thomas A.
                    Lightner, C. J. Cameron, Col. J. D. Lilley, John Larew, John Fauber. North
                    River: Chairman Col. J. Marshall McCue, N. L. Blakemore, D. N. Van Lear, Capt.
                    Samuel Paul, Prof. T. J. White, George Craun, Samuel Forrer, Dr. Robeson, J. G.
                    Fulton, R. H. Dudley, Dr. Trevy, J. H. Plecker, William Howell, D. E. Mohler,
                    Frank Davis, Dr. William H. Davis, P. H. Wheeler, Maj. J. H. Ervin, R. A. Curry,
                    James Todd, Capt. W. H. Gamble, Chesley Kinney, J. A. Hamrick, James P. Byers,
                    Thomas S. Hogshead, George Dunlap, Capt. T. H. Dryden. Pastures: Chairman
                    Lorenzo Sibert, D. B. Taylor, Kennerly Craig, A. K. Clayton, S. E. Mugen, J. W.
                    Sitlington, N. Ryan, James Cross, Brown Allen, J. G. Stover, Ephriam Geeding,
                    Maj. William M. Tate, Samuel H. Bell, M. S. Cease, W. D. Rippetoe, Mr. Lackey,
                    Henry Forrer, William Kunkle, William Armstrong, R. S. Craig, B. O. Furgeson,
                    John Shouff, R. N. Wallace, Caleb Crone, Dr. D. Bashaw, Luke Woodward, L. R.
                    Boswell, J. S. Guy, G. W. McCutchen, Col. F. F. Sterrett, C. S. Thompson, A.
                    Knowles, Dr. A. Wilson, A. B. Lightner, John Roudebush, D. A. Seig.Central
                    Committee: M. G. Harman, A. H. H. Stuart, John B. Baldwin, William A. Burke,
                    John Echols, George Baylor, Thomas J. Michie, S. Travers Phillips, Joseph A.
                    Waddell, William H. Gorman, David Fultz, Hugh W. Sheffey, R. G. Bickle, C. R.
                    Harris, N. K. Trout, James H. Skinner, T. C. Elder, John M. Hardy, H. M. Bell,
                    P. B. Hoge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hale</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Hall, not G. W. Hale as reported last week, has been appointed
                    postmaster at Mt. Solon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gen. Lee to be President of the Valley R. R.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Harman asserted in a speech at the Court House that Gen. Lee would
                    accept the presidency of the Valley Railroad if it were offered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William E. Sheets will take the census in the northwest portion of Augusta
                    County. This is part of E. L. Houff's division. "He is a business man and we
                    doubt not will perform the duty promptly and efficiently."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William A. Harris, principal of the Wesleyan Female Institute,
                    purchased the residence and grounds of George M. Cochran, Sr., to serve as a
                    sight for expansion of the school. They plan to erect an additional building
                    immediately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A grand barbecue will be held at the fair grounds on Saturday. Gen. Robert
                    E. Lee and "other prominent gentlemen" will attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley R. R. Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Addresses were delivered at the Court House in favor of the Valley Railroad
                    subscription. Citizens are urged to attend the barbecue to show their support.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The committee advocating adoption of the county subscription to the Valley
                    Railroad calls on any supporters not yet involved to step forward and help
                    ensure the "material prosperity of this grand old county." "We must all put our
                    shoulder to the wheel and poll such a vote in favor of the subscription as will
                    secure to us this Road. This is the only chance we have of getting a Railroad
                    through this beautiful Valley." All supporters should at least attend the
                    barbecue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>But little business of general interest was transacted.</p>
                    <p>The following Township Officers appeared, and qualified and gave the required
                        bonds:</p>
                    <p>CONSTABLES.--Jno. B. Smith, D.B. Zimmerman, Wm. H. Cale, Jonas Lowman, Jas.
                        C.M. McClung, S.N. Patterson, A.T. Grooms, J.F. Heizer, J.F. Davis, J.A.
                        Stuart.</p>
                    <p>SUPERVISORS.--Wm. T. Rush, H.B. Seig, T.W. Shelton, John Paris.</p>
                    <p>ASSESSORS.--Jno. M. Kinney, G. W. Sutler, L.R. Roswell, J. Alex Kerr, P.H.
                        Wheeler.</p>
                    <p>COLLECTORS.--J.N. McFarland, Wm. L. Mowry, Jos. A. Wilson, R.G. Byers.</p>
                    <p>CLERKS.--J.G. Fulton, Jr., J.R. Merriken, J. S. McCorkle.</p>
                    <p>OVERSEERS OF POOR.--M. McAlear, J.F. Hoizer, Chas. Brooks, A. Rusmisel.</p>
                    <p>JUSTICES.--C.S. Roler, J.W. Gillespie, N.B. Koizer, I.W. Gilkerson, A.A.
                        Sproul, J.H. Rush, W.W. Clinedinst, D.W. Coiner, J. Huff, D. Heakel, L.F.
                        Waddell, T.S. Hogshead, G.A. Shuey.</p>
                    <p>COMMISSIONERS OF ROADS.--J.D. Lilley, P. Airhart, D.B. Hinton.</p>
                    <p>The appeal, road and motion dockets were ordered to be called for trial at
                        the September term next.</p>
                    <p>Rev. M.A. Taylor, of the M.E. Church South was authorized to celebrate the
                        rights of marriage.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowman</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>James C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grooms</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rush</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seig</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutler</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roswell</ln>
                        <fn>L. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>J. Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merriken</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCorkle</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAlear</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roler</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>N. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkerson</ln>
                        <fn>I. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rush</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clinedinst</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>T. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Airhart</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hinton</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discusses court business, mostly lists the names of men certified for
                    various town offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>George Harman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Harman Snapp, infant son of Archibald D. and Sarah C. Snapp, died in
                    Staunton on July 17th. He was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Overton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Gibson died near Fishersville at the residence of his father, Mr.
                    Overton Gibson. "The writer knew much of this young man in health and in
                    disease. A brighter and better character never lived in our midst. He possessed
                    every noble element which belongs to the gentleman, the man of business and the
                    devout christian. He was truly a stay and comfort to his aged father and
                    motherless brothers and sisters, whose irreparable loss with that of a whole
                    community they must feel most deeply." An account of his final moments is
                    included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
