<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.07.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/13/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-07-15">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">15</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.15.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.15.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>, of the 9th inst., has another
                        article on the subject of consolidation, and gives as a reason therefore,
                        that the propositions of Mr. Wilson, and Col. Baldwin, as counsel, were in
                        the interests of a salt monopoly, and very considerately says, that it
                        supposes that the <emph rend="italic">Staunton Vindicator</emph> was not
                        cognizant of the fact, that the object of the above named parties was to
                        create this monopoly, by preventing the transportation of Liverpool salt
                        beyond Lynchburg and establishing a price for their Southwestern Virginia
                        salt that would pay for the Railroad in two years, and professes its
                        unwillingness to believe that the <emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph>
                        would favor a project, which would so burden the people.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph> is correct. We were aware of no such
                        fact, nor can we glean it from, nor see it concealed in the propositions of
                        either Mr. Wilson or Col. Baldwin, which the <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>
                        publishes to sustain its assertion.--On the contrary we see the greatest
                        fairness in these propositions. A positive assurance against discriminating
                        tariffs, and the Legislature even requested to make any stringent amendments
                        to the charter of the Va. and Tenn. R. R. Co., it may deem proper to prevent
                        any discriminations.--Hence we repeat that we can see no salt or other
                        monopoly lurking in these propositions. If the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Whig</emph> can, it must have other data which it has not given to the
                        public, and which, for the satisfaction of the people and in defence of its
                        course, the Whig ought by all means to produce.</p>
                    <p>We believed that the consolidation bill was wrong in several particulars, and
                        that it would produce a monopoly, against the interest of the people and
                        State. Time will tell whether we were correct, but as yet we have seen no
                        cause to change our belief.</p>
                    <p>We are, as the Whig supposes, opposed to unnecessarily burdening the people,
                        and hence one ground of our opposition--the virtual giving away of near
                        $6,000,000 of the State's interests, and especially at a time when our
                        people are ground down with taxation.</p>
                    <p>This however, is one of the things of the past. Consolidation succeeded. If
                        it prove beneficial to the interests of the people and State, we shall be
                        much pleased, but we can not believe that will be the result. As all that
                        can be said will not avail just now to reverse the fiat of consolidation, we
                        shall await patiently the developments of the future, to sustain or condemn
                        us as to our course on the question.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>, we trust, will always find us, (as we
                        believe we were on the consolidation question) advocating the best interest
                        of the people. This, at least, shall be our endeavor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editor responds to a Richmond paper's insinuation that the former was not
                    aware of a consolidation attempt by Railroad officials to secure a salt monopoly
                    in Lynchburg. Insists the consolidation scheme is legitimate with no hint of a
                    monopoly grab. Only wants to protect the best interests of Virginians.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad and the Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It it estimated that in making the Valley R. R. through Augusta County,
                        $1,360,000 would be expended and put in circulation in the county, within
                        the next 2 years. Now if there is 40,000 inhabitants in the county, this
                        would be $34 for each man, woman and child, white and black, in the county.
                        By the new Act of Legislature, if the county votes a subscription to the
                        stock of the Valley R. R. of $300,000, it will be by a loan for 20 years,
                        upon which the interest will be to pay yearly, by a tax, until the dividends
                        of the stock held by the county will meet the interest, which will probably
                        be about two years after the county executes its bonds. This tax will be
                        $36,000 in two years, or 90 cents in two years for each man, woman and
                        child. It is said that a man once bet 1,000 pounds Sterling, that he would
                        stand on the end of London bridge and offer to sell genuine gold guineas at
                        a penny a piece for a whole day without selling ten of them. It is said he
                        won his bet having sold none. The offer was so good none would believe it.
                        The people of Augusta are offered $34 good money for 90 cents, but the
                        wiseacres shake their heads and say such bargains will ruin them. This is
                        the way it stands for two years. After this the dividends will pay the
                        interest and, in a very few years, this dividend will be increased to
                        probably 9 <emph rend="italic">per cent</emph> per annum. This estimate is
                        made from the dividends of similar roads having no better opportunities than
                        this one will have. This will make $27,000 a year, or $9,000 over and above
                        the interest, for a sinking fund toward paying the bonds, and allowing a
                        fair average of business and profits to this road for the 20 years, it will
                        bring, in dividends, enough to pay both principal and interest, and leave
                        the stock in the hands of the County, the dividends on which will nearly or
                        quite pay the entire State tax yearly for all time to come. This is no
                        Utopian idea. It has been done over and over again. There are many towns and
                        counties in New England, which are entirely free from taxation by having
                        bought stock in a successful Railraod, the dividends on which paid nearly or
                        quite all of the principal and interest of the purchase money, and there is
                        not a town or county in New England which would not accept such an offer as
                        Augusta County has, by an unanimous vote, and, however much we may dislike
                        the sentiments and politics of New England, any one who will travel through,
                        that county, with his eyes open, must admit that they are wiser in their day
                        and generation in the things that lead to material wealth than we are or
                        have been.</p>
                    <p>To enumerate the many advantages to the county of having the road speedily
                        completed, is to repeat what every one ought to know, and to reason with
                        those who are so far behind the age, or so dull as not to be aware of them,
                        seems like a hopeless if not a useless undertaking.</p>
                    <p>I can only say, sum up anew and compare the advantages and costs. Do it
                        calmly, fairly, and at once, for the time is near at hand when you must
                        decide whether Augusta County is to have a great through line of Railroad
                        from North to South or not. On the 6th of August you will be called upon to
                        vote for or against this subscription. Remember it is a question of <emph
                            rend="italic">a Railroad</emph> or <emph rend="italic">no
                        Railroad</emph>--a <emph rend="italic">final decision</emph> whether Augusta
                        County is to join in the great march of progress, or to lag behind and be
                        left to decay.</p>
                    <p>Rapbine Va. PROGRESS</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints an opinion article by an anonymous contributor giving an elaborate
                    justification for subscribing to the Valley Railroad. Outlines the minimal costs
                    and enormous benefits waiting for the town if only its citizens will support the
                    measure. Pleads with Staunton residents not to let Augusta County lag behind the
                    rest of the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.15.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Arthur</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Arthur Harman, H. A. McCue, and S. M. Williams, all of Augusta, have been
                    appointed cadets at the Virginia Military Institute.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Some of the convicts laboring on C. R. Mason's work beyond Milboro
                    mutinied. One guard was killed and six convicts wounded before the revolt was
                    quelled. Two convicts escaped.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funkhouser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Funkhouser thanks the members of the Augusta Fire Company and the white
                    and black citizens of Augusta who helped save his building and stock in a recent
                    fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The plank-kiln of Mr. Lushbaugh and Bro. caught fire and burned down last
                    Thursday. The fire consumed a large amount of lumber in the kiln and did several
                    hundred dollars in damage. Lushbaugh thanks the Augusta Fire Company for their
                    quick assistance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Drowned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Conrad</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Conrad Hensley, son of Robert Hensley, drowned near Waynesboro in
                    Blackwell's Mill dam while fishing. He was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bailey</ln>
                        <fn>Jethro B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jethro B. Bailey, a native of Rhode Island and formerly of New Orleans,
                    died in Staunton on July 11th. He was 62 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>W. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James E. Ross, son of W. O. and S. A. Ross, died in Mt. Sidney on July 1st.
                    He was 8 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitlock</ln>
                        <fn>Melvina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Melvina Whitlock died near Mt. Sidney on June 29th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Patterson died on South River on July 7th of consumption.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Areon</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Areon died near Salem Church on June 27th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Maria Harrison, daughter of Henry Harrison, died near Staunton at the
                    residence of her father on July 9th. She was 16 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.15.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
