<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.10.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-10-14">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.10.14.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.10.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gen. Robt. E. Lee is Dead!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper brings the news that Robert E. Lee passed away. "Virginia,
                    sorrow-laden, bends in agony over the loss of her greatest, purest and best
                    beloved son; the Southland weeps; the Nation mourns him gone; the whole world
                    unites in sorrowing sympathy." "Our beloved and noble old leader is dead, but
                    his memory will live forever in the hearts of his countrymen, and his name will
                    be honored through all time." Today's newspaper columns are bordered in black.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What Manufactures do for a Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following, which we clip from one of our exchanges, says the Belleville
                        (Ill.) <emph rend="italic">People</emph>, speaks volumes in favor of
                        encouraging manufactures in our midst, and also establishes the fact that a
                        few thousand dollars contributed by any city toward the establishment of
                        machine shops and manufactories, is money well invested: "In 1857, Aurora
                        had a population of less than 5000; the C.B. &amp; Q machine works were
                        located there at a cost of $200,000 to the citizens, and the present
                        population is 20,000. Galesburg had machine shops located there at about the
                        same time, and the ratio of increase of population is about that of
                        Aurora's. The machine shops of the C.A. &amp; St. L. R.R. were put up in
                        Bloomington in 1859, since which time it has doubled in population. The
                        Illinois Central put shops in Champaign in 1858, since which time the
                        increase of her population has been 5000. The machine shops of the C.C.
                        &amp; I. Road built at Logansport (Ind.,) by Mr. Young, in 1856, at a
                        cost to the citizens of $200,000, have since increased her population 6000.
                        Mr. Young also put up the Fort Wayne (Ind.) shops in 1856, at a cost of
                        $200,000 to the citizens, and the increase of population has been 15,000.</p>
                    <p>We clip the above, in order to exhibit to our people the great interest we
                        all have in securing the workshops of the C. &amp; O. R.R. at this
                        place, and also in the building up and fostering manufacturing
                        establishments here.</p>
                    <p>This is a matter generally acknowledged to be of the first importance to us,
                        but which our people do not seem to be willing to take hold of as they
                        should.</p>
                    <p>In several instances, in the above article we notice that towns have <emph
                            rend="italic">donated</emph> as much as $200,000 with immense results.
                        We call attention to this for a purpose. We can build up manufacturing
                        establishments here without such a cost and we think with as great results
                        to us. For instance, we are authorized, by parties <emph rend="italic"
                            >experienced</emph> and <emph rend="italic">responsible</emph>, to say,
                        that, if the citizens of Staunton will take stock to the amount of $25,000,
                        they will furnish an equal amount of capital and start an establishment,
                        which will employ 20 hands constantly, from the start, in the manufacture of
                        Plows and Mill furnishing goods. The number of hands employed will increase
                        after the business is started and will probably reach 50 or 100 constantly
                        employed.</p>
                    <p>This is a subject of interest to all. It secures an establishment managed by
                        experienced business men, which will add much to the business interests of
                        Staunton. It is certainly a step in the right direction, and, as an
                        experiment in building up Manufacturing establishments <emph rend="italic"
                            >here</emph>, backed by capital and experience, may be of untold value
                        to our entire community.</p>
                    <p>It is worthy the consideration of our people and as such we present it to
                        them for their calm reflection and, we trust, their prompt action.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives a detailed argument for raising money to establish manufactures and
                    machine works in Staunton. Lists examples and statistics from other cities in
                    the North to show how much profit and benefit for all citizens can arise from a
                    little investment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>An amount of business is being mapped out by the Legislature, yet but little
                        has been done by that body of general interest.</p>
                    <p>We notice in the proceedings of the Senate of Monday last, a resolution,
                        offered by Mr. Fitzpatrick, which is of direct interest to this and other
                        sections of the State visited by the late flood. His resolution was adopted
                        and instructs the committee on Finance to enquire into the expediency of
                        postponing the collection of the State tax of 1870 for twelve months in that
                        portion of the State visited by the flood, and to report by bill or
                        otherwise.</p>
                    <p>The loss to the people in certain portions of the State, due to the flood, is
                        immense, greater by far than the damage they sustained during the four years
                        of war.--The postponement of the collection of State taxes for twelve months
                        will be a great general relief, but numbers who are perfectly prostrated
                        pecuniarily will be illy able to pay two years' State taxes in a
                        twelve-month. If some bill were devised to relieve the damaged section of
                        the payment of this year's State tax entirely, it would be but a simple act
                        of justice. If that can not be done, let the payment of this year's State
                        tax be divided between the next <emph rend="italic">three</emph> years. Such
                        a course will relieve those who have suffered and enable and encourage them
                        to go to work speedily to repair the damages sustained.</p>
                    <p>This subject should meet with the prompt consideration of the Legislature and
                        as a matter of deep and general interests in this section we press it upon
                        them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a bill intended to procure tax relief to Virginia residents who
                    suffered during a recent flood. Urges the legislature to act swiftly on the bill
                    as a matter of justice for the flood victims.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Institution for the Deaf and Dumb and the Blind</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our readers will recollect the publication in the INDEX during last spring of
                        several articles urging an investigation into the management of the
                        Institution for the Deaf and Dumb and the Blind of Virginia.</p>
                    <p>Charges had been made by responsible parties as to the former conduct of that
                        charity and it was deemed a subject well worthy of public attention.</p>
                    <p>On the 16th of June last at a regular meeting of the Board of Visitors of the
                        Institution the articles above referred to were brought to the notice of the
                        Board, and thereupon, resolutions were passed by that body inviting an
                        investigation and offering to afford full facilities for it. The Board
                        resolved to meet in a called session in the present month the more
                        thoroughly to examine into the condition of the Institution, and invited one
                        of the editors of this paper to attend and aid in ascertaining the facts.</p>
                    <p>That called session was held on the 21st <sic>nst.</sic>, and in accordance
                        with the invitation tendered him, one of the editors of the INDEX, who is
                        familiar with the sign language and deeply interested in the matter of the
                        education and well being of the deaf mutes, attended and made it his
                        business to examine thoroughly into the conduct of the Institution, and the
                        condition of its inmates both as to the means of education and as to
                        personal comfort.</p>
                    <p>In pursuit of this object, conversation was had with various pupils, as well
                        as with the teachers, the books, the mode of teaching, the character of the
                        discipline, and, as far as might be, the progress made were observed, and
                        personal inspection was made of dormitories, tables, play grounds,
                        workshops, &amp;c. Inquiries were made also as to expenditures and
                        receipts.</p>
                    <p>The charges, it will be remembered referred to a period in the past, since
                        which time more or less of change in management and the personal of
                        instructors may have occurred.</p>
                    <p>Be that as it may, it gives us great pleasure to give the utmost publicity in
                        our power to the result of the investigation above recited.</p>
                    <p>That result was, in brief, such as to redound to the honor of the
                        Institution, and to those in whose charge it is.</p>
                    <p>The pupils are well cared for, comfortable, contented and well guided. The
                        system of teaching is that which has been proved by experience to be the
                        best adapted to the deaf mutes, and the progress made by the pupils is
                        creditable.</p>
                    <p>Finally, as to expenses: It was found that the average <emph rend="italic"
                            >per capita</emph> amount expended by the Institution for the
                        maintenance and education of its pupils was but little in excess of that
                        incurred at the large schools of the North--the excess being accounted for
                        by the different relative value of money.</p>
                    <p>The public will doubtless receive with pleasure the assurance that their
                        charity is well bestowed.</p>
                    <p>But there still remains one grievous cause of dissatisfaction with the
                        Institution. It is confessed alike by the teachers and the Board of
                        Visitors. It is the want of that higher class education which is bestowed
                        upon the deaf mutes in the schools at the North after they have gone through
                        their ordinary scholastic course.</p>
                    <p>The Principal of the Institution is now making efforts to establish such a
                        class, but those efforts are hampered by want of means.</p>
                    <p>Our Legislature must determine whether to aid those efforts.</p>
                    <p>Certain it is, that while every exertion seems to be made by the Institution
                        for its pupils, and while so far as their education goes it is good, yet
                        without that higher class of instruction they halt far behind the standard
                        of proficiency attained in other schools and just so far are the deaf mutes
                        of Virginia debarred from advantages offered to them in New York,
                        Connecticut, Missouri, Indiana and many other States.</p>
                    <p>This subject, however, should receive more attention than our present space
                        will allow. We shall return to it hereafter, and we hope that means may be
                        found of so enlarging the scope of the Institution as to allow it to bestow
                        upon its pupils an extent of instruction equal to that to be obtained in any
                        community.</p>
                    <p>The best guaranty that such further extent could be attained by it, were the
                        means afforded, is given by the efficiency to which it now attains, and to
                        which it gives us pleasure to testify.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on alleged charges of misconduct at the state Institution for the
                    Deaf and Dumb. Finds that the charges are groundless and the directors are
                    providing more than adequate care and education for the inmates. Admits that
                    there are not enough facilities to provide a higher education at the institution
                    but blames the legislature for that.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.10.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Fifer has been reappointed flour inspector for Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>B. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following have been appointed to the Board of Health by the President
                    of the City Council: Dr. A. M. Fauntleroy, Dr. B. M. Atkinson, and P. B. Hoge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sinclair</ln>
                        <fn>Lottie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Lottie Sinclair will make a balloon ascension on the first day of the
                    fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The German Baptists will hold a sacramental meeting in Moscow next Tuesday
                    and Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The registrars will open the registration books ten days before the next
                    election so that anyone qualified to register may do so.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>N. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>N. B. Hill of Staunton was appointed a member of the Board of Directors of
                    the Western Lunatic Asylum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the M. E. Church South will have a stand at the fair. They
                    plan to serve the "delicacies of the season."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mayor Trout ordered all the bells in Staunton rung upon receiving news of
                    the death of Robert E. Lee. The City Council immediately adjourned out of
                    respect for his memory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>City Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John W. Green</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Green Smith defeated Joseph A. Waddell in an election by the
                    legislature for Staunton City Judge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crowder</ln>
                        <fn>Tommy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tommy Crowder rented the Virginia Hotel Bar and Billiard Saloon and is
                    planning to open for business. "Tommy is No. 1 in his business, has a fine
                    supply of Liquors on hand, and, as this is his first start in business for
                    himself, will, we doubt not, receive a liberal support."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James L. McCutchen and Miss Rachel Buchanan, both of Augusta, were married
                    on September 27th by the Rev. H. Gilmore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Russel N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Batis</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Russel N. Wallace and Mrs. Mary Batis, both of Augusta, were married at the
                    American Hotel on September 15th by the Rev. H. H. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo S. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dill</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lorenzo S. K. McCutchen of Augusta and Miss Hattie Dill of Rockbridge were
                    married on September 22nd by the Rev. Mr. Riley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>Josie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Josie B. Richardson, wife of C. A. Richardson, died in Staunton at the
                    residence of her husband on October 13th. She was 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myer</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A. St.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Myer, son of William and Mary A. St. Myer, died near Parnassus on
                    September 29th. He was 17 years old. "Thus another in the prime of life has
                    passed from our midst. May this dispensation of Divine Providence be patiently
                    borne by the bereaved family."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porterfield</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca F. Kinney, wife of the late William Kinney and daughter of the
                    late Gen. Robert Porterfield, died at her residence in Staunton on October 7th.
                    She was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Ast died at his Staunton residence on October 13th. He was 75 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.10.14.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
