<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.06.17">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-06-17">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="12">June</month>
            <day norm="">17</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.06.17.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.06.17.02" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.06.17.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Augusta Church will hold a strawberry and ice cream festival
                    in the Church Grove on June 18th. The proceeds will go to repair the Old Stone
                    Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas C. Campbell of Staunton has been appointed one of the directors of
                    the Central Lunatic Asylum in Richmond that serves African American patients.
                    "Thomas Campbell is one of our most respected colored men, and is the best
                    appointment that could have been made among the colored people of this section."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brief item from the Richmond Enquirer praising Senator Waddell from
                    Augusta. He rarely involves himself in questions in which his constituents do
                    not have an interest, and when he speaks, he speaks to the point. "No Senator
                    commands more respect or attention."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "pioneers" will meet on Saturday with spades and shovels and process to
                    the Confederate Cemetery to "fix up" the graves. "Let all who can, be present,
                    and let us all unite in the Association proposed, the object of which is to
                    adorn and beautify, and keep in handsome condition the last resting place of our
                    Confederate dead."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noon</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>R. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>P. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of the Temperance Councils of Staunton met and proceeded to the
                    Confederate Cemetery to assist the Memorial Association in decorating the
                    soldiers' graves. They "paid their gift of love and affection for the fallen
                    heroes of the 'Lost Cause.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Confederate Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The surviving members of the 5th, 25th, and 52nd Virginia Infantry, and of
                    the artillery and cavalry companies from Augusta, and any other Confederate
                    veterans are expected to meet on Saturday with shovels and spades to "give one
                    day as a labor of love, to repair and dress the graves or our Confederate Dead."
                    The Stonewall Band will be present. The ladies are also invited to attend and
                    bring refreshments to the workers. A veterans association will be formed "to
                    keep special care henceforth over the graves of their fallen comrades."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Thursday last was the day appointed for paying our annual tribute to our
                        "loved and lost," who sacrificed themselves for us, and now "sleep their
                        last sleep" in the Confederate Cemetery near this place. The day was most
                        unpropitious, the rain falling in torrents during the
                        morning.--Nevertheless, a large crowd assembled at the Town Hall, and,
                        although the managers deemed it advisable to postpone the ceremonies to a
                        more pleasant day, formed a procession, headed by the famous Stonewall Band,
                        and, amid the rain, proceeded on foot and in carriages to the Cemetery. The
                        procession was composed of the Stonewall Band, Fire Companies, the Pioneers,
                        Councils of Friends of Temperance, a number of Ladies, volunteer Band and
                        citizens generally, all bearing wreaths and bouquets. Arriving at the
                        Cemetery, the Bands discoursed sweet and appropriate music and the crowd,
                        about 2000 persons, decorated the graves, not one of which but had its
                        tribute of love and affection. It was the more satisfactory to see, through
                        this most disagreeable weather, so large a crowd in attendance, and
                        evidences the fact that the heroism, devotion and self-sacrifice of those
                        who gave their all to the "lost cause," are held in the dearest remembrances
                        by those of us who live to lament it and their fall. In rain or sunshine our
                        annual tribute is due, and in rain or sunshine, our people are determined it
                        shall be paid.</p>
                    <p>The Pioneers, with shovels, spades &amp;c., proceeded to fix up those
                        graves most needing it, but, satisfied that concerted labor and means were
                        necessary to put in proper condition the last home of our buried brethren,
                        have instituted a movement, noticed elsewhere, to form an association to
                        take charge of and beautify the grounds of the Confederate Cemetery. This
                        will meet with the hearty accord of every well-wisher in the county, and we
                        hope to see the Association an immense affair.</p>
                    <p>The graves fixed up and decorated, the crowd slowly moved back to town, the
                        Bands discoursing appropriate music while passing through Thornrose Cemetery
                        and on their way back.</p>
                    <p>In the evening, the young ladies of the Deaf &amp; Dumb and Blind
                        Institution moved in procession, with flowers, headed by their Band, to the
                        Cemetery, and paid their tribute to their lamented Confederates whose
                        "Silent tents are spread on Fame's eternal camping ground." A mute and
                        touching appeal to the feelings and sympathies of all who witnessed it.</p>
                    <p>Altogether, the ceremonies of the day were most satisfactory. Although there
                        was not the usual number present, yet there was a very large number, and the
                        spirit, which induced the attendance of those present, was, itself, a most
                        appropriate tribute to their comrades and friends who fell in the great
                        struggle, in which nearly all of us participated or deeply sympathized.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses satisfaction with the turnout for local Memorial Day events
                    despite incessant rain. Lists the bands and organizations who attended and fixed
                    up the graveyards of fallen Confederate soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>William H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witz</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mandlebaum</ln>
                        <fn>Seymour</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn>J. Howard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>Talbott B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tyler</ln>
                        <fn>R. Matthews</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Union Royal Arch Chapter No. 2 elected officers at a meeting held in the
                    Masonic Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apperson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association and Orchestra held a concert at the Chapel
                    of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution. The paper singled out solos by Ms.
                    Winston and Ms. Apperson for special praise. Prof. Scharf delivered a number of
                    readings including Shamus O'Brien and the trial of Bardell vs Pickwick.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathenay</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathenay</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathenay</ln>
                        <fn>Cornealia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Mathenay, infant son of William M. and Cornealia Mathenay of
                    Staunton, died on June 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.06.17.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
