<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.03.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/02/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-03-18">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.03.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.03.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The long talked of Radical conference, for the purpose of uniting the
                        discordant Republican elements of the State, was held in Richmond on
                        Saturday last. Messrs. Porter and Platte, members of Congress, Senator
                        Lewis, Ex-Governor Wells and other Radicals played a conspicuous part in the
                        meeting. Messrs. McKenzie, Booker and Ayer, of the lower House of Congress,
                        sent letters expressing their hearty concurrence in the movement, while
                        Senator Johnston and the other Representatives, Messrs. Gibson, Milnes and
                        Ridgway declined to have anything to do with it.</p>
                    <p>After much discussion it was determined, by resolution, that the Executive
                        Committees headed by G. K. Gilmer, C.H. Porter and Gen. Wickham should
                        appoint five from each Republican committee in the State, who should be
                        authorized to invite the adherents of the different Republican factions to
                        meet in Richmond, on the 6th of April next, to reorganize the Republican
                        party of the State.</p>
                    <p>During the discussion Messrs. Wells and Porter expressed themselves in a very
                        conciliatory way, which considering the circumstances, was quite politic,
                        Porter, though at one time, branching off to assail Gov. Walker, and through
                        him the people in the State who voted for and elected him Governor.</p>
                    <p>It was left, however, for the gentleman, who was elected Lieut. Governor on
                        the ticket with Governor Walker, to denounce the men who voted for him. Who
                        would have thought that Jno. F. Lewis could play so ungenerous a part
                        towards his friends and supporters? And yet it is reported, that the Hon.
                        Jno. F. Lewis, who holds the position of U.S. Senator to-day at the hands of
                        "Rebels," expressed himself as "deploring the day when 'Rebels' should get
                        control of the State, and pitying the 'Union' men when that occurred."</p>
                    <p>How many Radicals voted for him for the position of Lieut. Governor? Judging
                        from the vote in this section, there must have been very few, for they voted
                        here, almost to a man, for Harris the colored nominee on the ticket with
                        Wells. How many Radicals were in the Conservative caucus, which
                            <sic>proclamed</sic> him the nominee of the Conservatives of the
                        Legislature for the position of U.S. Senator? Surely there were none, or it
                        would have been blazoned to the world long ere this. Was it the Radical, or,
                        according to Congressman Platte, the "Rebel" majority in the Legislature
                        which elected him U.S. Senator? We doubt not Mr. Lewis will agree that it
                        was the "Rebel" majority, which he seems so anxious to crush by marshaling
                        the Radical cohorts, and without the aid of which he would have remained a
                        quiet tiller of the soil in Rockingham, instead of being heralded as,
                        physically, the <emph rend="italic">tallest</emph> man in the U.S. Senate.
                        Then are we wrong when we say that in denouncing the "Rebels" he denounced
                        his friends--those who gave him the only political prominence he ever had,
                        and perhaps ever will have?</p>
                    <p>It was an act of the direst ingratitude, a slander upon the majority of the
                        people of Virginia, and without a parallel. He, alone, has kicked the prop
                        from under him which elevated him to position. If the fall should extinguish
                        his political existence it will be but <sic>a just a desert</sic>, and,
                        judging from the general condemnation it receives at the hands of the many
                        of all shades of political opinion, he will descend into his political
                        grave, "unwept, unhonored and unsung."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a meeting of Republicans in Richmond to try to mend the state
                    party. Condemns some of the members for throwing insults at "Rebels" even though
                    those same "Rebels" often got them elected in the first place. Has particular
                    venom for Lieutenant Governor Lewis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Homestead Act</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints an act passed by the general assembly outlining the
                    process by which homeowners can claim a homestead exempt from seizure for
                    defaulting on non-mortgage debts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.03.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Fannie J. Smith replaces the late Mary Row as postmistress at
                    Moffett's Creek, Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Good Advice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Virginians to support local mechanics, laborers, merchants,
                    and artisans. That is the best way to build the economy of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leonard</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Leonard the horse thief was arrested in Louisa Court House after J. T.
                    Parrent, Chief of Police, chased him for 75 miles before his horse gave out.
                    Parrent then telegraphed authorities in Louisa who made the arrest. Leonard had
                    stolen a horse from Burke's Stable in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eagle</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jefferson</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Conference of the M. E. Church South appointed H. H. Kennedy to a
                    position in Staunton, and Joseph J. Eagle and G. R. Jefferson to positions in
                    Churchville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rothwell</ln>
                        <fn>Eddie G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William S. Boyd and Miss Eddie G. Rothwell, both of Augusta, were married
                    at New Hope on March 10th by the Rev. J. H. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilbarger</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crickenbarger</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hugh G. Wilbarger and Miss Margaret Crickenbarger, both of Augusta, were
                    married on March 3rd at the residence of Jacob Cook by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>M. Addie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Albert J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Baldwin and Miss M. Addie Garber, daughter of Albert J. Garber,
                    all of Staunton, were married in Staunton at Trinity Church by the Rev. James A.
                    Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. R. C. Brown died in Waynesboro at the residence of her husband, Cyrus
                    Brown, on March 13th. She was 40 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dalhouse</ln>
                        <fn>Emma Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dalhouse</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dalhouse</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emma Jane Dalhouse, daughter of John H. and Catharine Dalhouse, died in
                    Waynesboro at the residence of her parents on March 14th. She was 26 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A committee of the M. E. Sunday School South passed resolutions of sympathy
                    and respect upon the death of Hattie Jane Harlan, a student at the school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.03.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
