<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.02.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-02-11">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.11.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The New Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a draft of the new state constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Just after the re-admission of the State to the Union, and when all our
                        people are anxiously hoping for the greatest possible improvement in the
                        pecuniary condition of one and all in the State, and that Virginia will take
                        the long talked of and lately vehemently promised rapid strides along the
                        road of progress and prosperity, there is a sudden blow given to the hopes
                        of even the least sanguine. Our Congressmen just seated, instead of taking
                        into consideration the best interests of our State and people, and
                        instituting legislation looking thereto, are found in consultation on the
                        subject--well, what do you think?--of organizing a new political party in
                        the State! Not to compare views as to the legislation best calculated to
                        promote the welfare and prosperity of our people, their constituents, but to
                        disturb them with the agitation of a new political party. Not as to what
                        will conduce to the greatest progress of Virginia, but to see if they can
                        devise a party to control her affairs and chain her to the car of
                        Radicalism.</p>
                    <p>We respectfully suggest to the gentlemen who represent Virginia in Congress
                        that parties are not made in a day or hour, and can not be called up like
                        spirits by Congressional mediums. They are the outgrowth <sic>of of</sic>
                        principles, to be lasting, and hence the folly of endeavoring to conjure
                        them from the vasty depths of the future. Instead of trying to run a party
                        "in the middle of political extremes in Virginia," you had better run "into
                        the middle" of the good feeling of all our people by measures calculated to
                        do good. The people would a great deal rather hear of you trying to remove
                        disabilities at one blow, so that they might select whom of their fellow
                        citizens they choose to serve them, or that you secure aid, so much needed
                        to develop Virginia's resources, in building her railroads, canals
                        &amp;c. than to be racking your brains to start new parties, which can
                        have no other result than to worry them.</p>
                    <p>Let go your political hobbies, gentlemen, and take hold of something useful.
                        The people demand it and you are but their servants--<emph rend="italic"
                        >now</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper expresses disgust with Virginia's new representatives, who seem
                    more concerned with forming new parties than providing for their constituents.
                    Reminds them who they serve.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor</emph>--In a former communication I endeavored
                        to show the importance of making our town a manufacturing place--how I
                        thought we might induce men of capital and experience to invest their means
                        in manufacturing enterprises in our midst. I now propose to show that a
                        purely agricultural community cannot be permanently prosperous. To make a
                        people prosperous and happy, we must have the miner, manufacturer and
                        mechanic laboring side by side with the farmer and planter in the same
                        community, if we wish to profit by our magnificent resources, increase our
                        wealth and keep step with the progress of intelligence and civilization. The
                        husband-man and shepherd of the barbarous ages used their fingers for forks
                        and the skins of their flocks for clothing, yet then Tubal Cains were forced
                        to supply them with knives and instruments of Brass. The savages of America
                        depended on their rude mechanical skill in constructing snares and bows and
                        arrows to procure their food, while the Hotentot of Africa owed their
                        precarious and miserable existence more to there ingenuity than to the
                        material fruits of the earth. The soil cannot be made to yield fruits
                        without some mechanical constructions. The burned stick of the Indian, the
                        wooden plow of the Roman, the rude coulter of our grandfathers or the steam
                        cultivator of to-day must be made use of. We would relapse into barbarism
                        without the aid of iron and those metals which subject all nature to our use
                        and pleasure, but we cannot obtain them without the miner and manufacturer,
                        nor can we fashion them to our wants without the skill of the mechanic, yet
                        science and knowledge are quite essential. The ancient manufacturer made
                        ingots of steel and the East Indian of to day blowing through his sheepskin
                        bag can produce half a pound iron per day. Science has increased the
                        production to one hundred pounds. Our ancestors in England, in 1600, carried
                        their coal, ore and iron on the backs of women and asses, and, fifty years
                        ago, the planters of Virginia rolled there hogsheads of tobacco from
                        Danville to Richmond. Steam now does the work with a thousand fold increase.
                        It is thus manifest that the miner, manufacturer and mechanic are not only
                        useful to the farmer and planter, but absolutely indispensable. They are the
                        "handmaids" of science and skill.</p>
                    <p>The miner, manufacturer and mechanic are not only necessary for the
                        production of food and clothing, but they furnish the means of promoting
                        intelligence and civilization, the necessities, comforts, pleasures and
                        luxuries of peace, and the implements of defence in war. These facts are
                        evident and it is manifest that the richest soils must become eventually
                        exhausted and valueless by constant drains on their resources without
                        recompense. A purely agricultural people therefore add nothing to the
                        permanent wealth of their country, while a combined manufacturing and
                        agricultural community grows rich. There are many examples, but let Virginia
                        and Massachusetts stand in evidence. The former was naturally rich but now
                        poor, the latter was naturally poor but now rich.</p>
                    <p>The mineral resources of our county are equal to our agricultural, but the
                        one cannot be properly developed without the other, and domestic industry
                        must be employed to accomplish the result. We all desire <sic>permant</sic>
                        material prosperity and let us work together then to secure it by fostering
                        mechanical and manufacturing as well as agricultural interests.</p>
                    <p>A CITIZEN</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anonymous letter promoting the expansion of mechanical enterprises in
                    the state. Says Virginia cannot remain solely agricultural, but must develop its
                    resources to include manufacturing to better its future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"North Side" writes the Vindicator and asserts that many citizens wish to
                    see the Valley Railroad extended to Salem. Public meetings will be held in
                    Moscow to petition the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company and call attention to
                    the issue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "the colored population continues to be thinned out
                    here." Forty individuals left town on Monday morning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association performed the cantata "Daniel" at the
                    Baptist Church last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. G. W. Samson, president of Columbia College, will deliver his
                    lecture on Jerusalem in the Baptist Church on Friday. The lecture is based on
                    his travels in the Holy Land. It will cover the city's "three mountains and
                    surrounding valleys; its walls, gates and towers; the Jewish-Christian
                    traditions as to holy places, and the scenes of Easter week; illustrating the
                    principles of the Christian faith." Admission is 25 cents, children and Sunday
                    School students 10 cents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Arrest of the Waynesboro Burglars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bull</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>Bill</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>Bill</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haines</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowles</ln>
                        <fn>Primus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clinedinst</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Deputy Sheriff Bull arrested a black man named Bill Mowry, aka Murray, who
                    was wanted for a number of burglaries. "He was known to be a desperate
                    character, and one that would resort to any expediency to accomplish his
                    purpose." On his testimony, warrants were issued for the arrest of a white man
                    named Alexander Bush, a white man named James Terrell, a black man named Jesse
                    Harden, and a black man named Sam Harden. All are wanted for robbing the store
                    of C. R. Haines, the home of Mrs. Wright, and stealing brandy from the
                    distillery of Simon Koiner, the property of John N. Crouse. Warrants were also
                    issued for a black man named Isaac Walker and a black man named Primus Bowles
                    for stealing from the smoke house of David Wines. Justice Clinedinst committed
                    all in custody to jail to await trial. The paper extends thanks to the sheriff
                    for chasing Murray through the brush and arresting him, even though the suspect
                    was armed with a Colt navy shooter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gen. John Echols of Staunton joined a number of the directors of the
                    Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad in riding on the road in a special train to White
                    Sulphur Springs. They returned to Staunton as guests of the Virginia Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutcheson</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reamer</ln>
                        <fn>Jenny M. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reamer</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gardner</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James H. Hutcheson, formerly of Greenville, and Jenny M. E. Reamer,
                    daughter of S. R. Reamer of Harrisonburg, were married at the residence of the
                    bride's parents on January 27th by the Rev. J. S. Gardner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eago</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Palmer of Newport and Miss Mary Eago were married on February 6th at
                    the residence of Mr. Palmer by the Rev. Mr. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
