<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.04.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/05/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-04-29">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The long-talked of Republican Conference assembled in Richmond on Thursday
                        last, and, after several days of labor, produced the following remarkable
                        declaration of principles:</p>
                    <p>1. An immediate enforcement of the fourteenth and fifteenth amendments to the
                        national constitution, in letter and in spirit, and the adoption of any
                        other measures necessary to guarantee universal freedom of thought, speech
                        and action.</p>
                    <p>2. A general and universal system of public education at public expense,
                        under national law, whenever such a system is not adopted and enforced by
                        State governments.</p>
                    <p>3. The fifteenth amendment having become a part of the constitution of the
                        United States, by which universal suffrage is secured to the masses of our
                        people, we declare in favor of universal amnesty, subject, of course, to the
                        legislation of Congress.</p>
                    <p>4. The encouragement of internal improvements by the State and nation,
                        keeping in view the careful protection of the interests of the <emph
                            rend="italic">people</emph> from the encroachments of <emph
                            rend="italic">monopolies</emph>.</p>
                    <p>5. An immediate, honest, and full enforcement of our new State constitution
                        in letter and in spirit.</p>
                    <p>6. A hearty and generous support of the administration of President Grant, in
                        its foreign, domestic and financial policy, and of the policy of the
                        Congress of the United States.</p>
                    <p>The first is ridiculous, from the fact the whole civil power of the country,
                        backed by the sword, is now enforcing these amendments, and that, at this
                        particular period, there is no opposition raised or likely to be raised
                        against their rigid enforcement, (however objectionable they may be to many)
                        from the extraordinary circumstances which now obtain. They are declared to
                        be fixed facts of the past, and therefore, ridiculous and farcical to be
                        introduced as principles of the present.</p>
                    <p>The Second is useless, though a generally obtaining principle. The
                        progressive spirit of the age demands the largest opportunities to all for
                        thorough education and all agree in this. Hence, as a distinctive principle
                        in a party, it is more than farcical to present it.</p>
                    <p>The Third seemingly declares for universal amnesty, but concludes by leaving
                        it to the whims of Congressional Legislation, and is, therefore, no
                        principle at all</p>
                    <p>The Fourth, though contested in the past, is scarcely to be made a subject of
                        contest in the present.</p>
                    <p>The Fifth may occasion an argument as to what is an "honest and full"
                        enforcement of the new constitution, "in letter and spirit." It is however
                        being enforced and we should judge <emph rend="italic">fully</emph>, from
                        the objections made by many who voted for it. Those who voted against it
                        seem willing, however, that it shall be carried out in the letter and
                        spirit. As a distinctive feature, it, like the rest, is a fizzle.</p>
                    <p>The Sixth, however, contains a most anomalous declaration--the endorsement of
                        the policy of the Administration and also the policy of Congress.</p>
                    <p>If there is one thing that we have most assiduously sought it is the policy
                        of the present Administration. We heard the cry of retrenchment proclaimed
                        throughout the land, and finding that national expenses loomed up higher and
                        higher, we looked in Webster to see if he really know what he was doing when
                        he "writ" the Dictionary, and came to the conclusion that he didn't.--We
                        have, by every other light, scanned the course of the present
                        administration, to get an idea of its policy, and were forced to the opinion
                        that it had <emph rend="italic">no</emph> policy. Congressional policy is
                        also as much a myth.--One day it admits a State, the next day it thrusts her
                        out of the Union. To-day eager for a general amnesty, to-morrow intensely
                        proscriptive. In fact, vacillating as the interest of party daily dictates,
                        and with <emph rend="italic">no other policy</emph> than to keep alive a
                        party, the death knell of which was inevitably sounded when reconstruction
                        was settled upon.</p>
                    <p>What a will-o-the-wisp chase will not the Richmond conferees take in pursuing
                        the policies of Congress and the Administration? Like the "little joker,"
                        now you see it--now you don't, and like the "thimble-rigger" we'll bet any
                        member of the conference that they can't tell where the little joker is, as
                        manipulated by Grant and Congress.</p>
                    <p>After carefully reading the above promulgation of principles, we can only
                        conclude that the great lack of the Radical conference was <emph
                            rend="italic">brains</emph>. Indeed the only exhibition of brains was
                        made by the colored State Senator Bland and to substantiate our statement,
                        we give an abstract of the remarks of Senator Bland below, and ask our
                        readers to contrast them with the silly programme of principles issued by
                        the leading lights of the party in Virginia, and judge for themselves:</p>
                    <p>Bland (colored) of Prince Edward, was called on, and urged at length the
                        repeal of all disqualifying and disfranchising laws passed by Congress. All
                        the rights which his race could demand having been secured by the adoption
                        of the fifteenth amendment, he was now, as indeed he was in the last
                        campaign, in favor of universal amnesty.--He was opposed to granting pardons
                        in detail. He wished to see every citizen of Virginia the equal in every way
                        of every other citizen. He hoped that such would be the action of the party,
                        and if it were not he would be compelled, as he had been before, to act
                        independently of it. Bland wished to see, and he would make every effort in
                        his power to see the wealth and the intelligence of the State in her
                        positions of official trust. The charge had been urged, and successfully, in
                        the last campaign, that it was the intention of the Republican party to
                        subject the control of the State to ignorance and poverty, to the utter
                        exclusion of wealth and intelligence. He considered the charge as too well
                        founded, and he was opposed to such a policy then and now.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Analyzes every plank in the state Republican platform and proceeds to show
                    how each one is either ridiculous or superfluous to present conditions. The
                    planks deal mainly with the fifteenth amendment, education, voter
                    qualifications, etc. Actually quotes a black member of the Republican convention
                    as coming out in favor of repealing all voting restrictions, and claims he is
                    the only sane voice among the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor:</emph>--There is misapprehension in the minds
                        of the people, in regard to the claim they will have on the stock they will
                        have in the Valley Railroad, provided the subscription is carried. My
                        opinion is well made up, that the stock, of $300,000, will belong to the
                        County, and, when productive, the dividends, as far as they go, will
                        diminish the taxes. Am I not correct? Please let us have your views.</p>
                    <p>Whilst on the subject, does the County yet hold its stock in the Chesapeake
                        &amp; Ohio Railroad, if not, what became of it?</p>
                    <p>QUERANDO</p>
                    <p>As to the first interrogatory in the above, we are pleased to state to our
                        correspondent that he is correct. The stock in the Valley Railroad, spoken
                        of, will belong to the County, and the dividends therefrom will go to
                        relieve taxation in the County. Indeed, we look for a great relief in County
                        taxation, in after years, from this very source, should the subscription be
                        carried. We regard it as an investment to be paid during twenty years, which
                        is ever after to be a continual source of revenue to the County and a
                        consequent continual relief to County taxation.</p>
                    <p>As to the question "does the County still hold its stock (of $20,000--200
                        shares) in the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Railroad? We are also glad to be
                        able to say that it does."--We have taken the trouble to examine the records
                        and find; that, on October, 27th 1863, an order of Court was made,
                        authorizing the County Treasurer to sell this stock. That on November 23rd
                        following, the Court decided that it did not have the authority to order the
                        sale of said stock, and rescinded the previous order for its sale.--On the
                        28th day of November, just five days thereafter, the Treasurer reported to
                        the Court that the 200 shares of stock had been sold, and asked the Court to
                        ratify said sale.</p>
                    <p>The vote was taken, six Magistrates being on the bench, and the motion to
                        ratify the sale <emph rend="italic">lost</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Thus it will be seen that the County still holds her $20,000 of stock in the
                        Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Railroad, and we trust, when that great road
                        reaches the Ohio, to see our people relieved from taxation to a considerable
                        extent, by the dividends which <emph rend="italic">must</emph> accrue to the
                        County from that source.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editor answers concerns from a correspondent about the County's financial
                    investments. Assures the correspondent that stock in the Valley Railroad will go
                    towards relieving taxation in the county and that the county still holds its
                    shares in the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Registration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Registration is set to begin on May 2nd, but it is thought the process will
                    be postponed. Registrars are required to give 10 days notice by posting notices
                    in each town they visit. Districts have not been divided into townships, and
                    registrars have not been appointed, however.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The commissioners are busily dividing Augusta County into six townships.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Scharf gave a dramatic reading at the Town Hall on Tuesday. The
                    audience enjoyed his talents, and hope he will perform in the summer and next
                    winter as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Experimental Lines</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The engineers of the Shenandoah Valley Railroad are running experimental
                    lines in Augusta County. They run from Fishersville, Waynesboro, and Staunton to
                    Greenville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association will perform on Tuesday night. Admission
                    is 25 cents. "The Association has been in existence over three years, and is now
                    an Institution of the town. It has in a marked degree improved the Church and
                    other Music of the town, and ought to be patronized by our people." The present
                    concert will consist of vocal solos, duets, and orchestral pieces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday last, for the first time in the history of the County Court of
                        Augusta, instead of a Presiding Justice a veritable Judge presided.--Judge
                        Hendron assumed his duties and discharged them in a manner that gave eminent
                        satisfaction to all.</p>
                    <p>He appointed the following officers to serve till their successors are
                        elected in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution:</p>
                    <p>CLERK OF THE COUNTY.--Wm. A. Burnett; and as his deputy, Jas. W. Baldwin.</p>
                    <p>SHERIFF OF THE COUNTY.--Geo. W. McCutchen; and as his deputies, Wm. Hoover,
                        Jno. W. Cline, R.G. Byers, J.H. Craun, W.A. Reed, Wm. H. Bull, R.T. Gamble
                        and Geo. Harlan.</p>
                    <p>COMMONWEALTH'S ATTORNEY.--James Bumgardner, Jr.</p>
                    <p>COMMISSIONERS OF THE REVENUE.--John Towberman, 1st District; and as his
                        deputy, Thomas M. Donoho. J.H. Stover, 2nd District; and as his deputy, John
                        G. Stover.</p>
                    <p>COMMISSIONERS IN CHANCERY.--Jos. A. Waddell and Thos. D. Ranson.</p>
                    <p>Rev. Saml. Driver was appointed and authorized to celebrate the rites of
                        matrimony.</p>
                    <p>Upon the petition of Wm. H. Marshall, a portion of the public road, no 18,
                        was ordered to be closed.</p>
                    <p>Jas. Reid, a very small colored boy, was tried for stealing a game rooster,
                        found guilty and sentenced to five days imprisonment in the county jail.</p>
                    <p>Ben Bragg, colored, tried on two cases of petit larceny, and acquitted.</p>
                    <p>Jas. T. Acord, tried on the charge of bastardy, was committed to jail in
                        default of the required security for judgment of court.</p>
                    <p>The titheables of John Silor, C. C. Francisco and John A. Shuey, were
                        respectively required to aid A.S. Borden, two days each in opening his
                        precinct of public road.</p>
                    <p>A motion having been made to the court by Col. M.G. Harman, President of the
                        Valley Railroad, to order an election on the proposed subscription to the
                        Valley Railroad Co. at the next general election, May 26th, the court
                        overruled the motion on the ground of want of jurisdiction.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bull</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>R. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donoho</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ranson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Driver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bragg</ln>
                        <fn>Ben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Acord</ln>
                        <fn>James T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silor</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Borden</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on cases and appointments given in the county court. Cases mainly
                    dealt with petty crimes and appointments were for various temporary
                    commissioners until replacements could be elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah M. Henkel and Charles Koiner, both of Augusta, were married at S. D.
                    Henkel's in New Market on April 13th by the Rev. S. Henkel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cain</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphrey</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Patrick H. Cain and Miss Virginia E. Humphrey, both of Augusta, were
                    married on April 14th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Henrietta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Burwell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Robinson and Miss Henrietta Gibson, daughter of Burwell Gibson, were
                    married near Staunton on April 20th at the residence of the bride's father by
                    the Rev. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. M. McClure of Indiana died at Arbor Hill at the residence of John Shuey
                    on April 22nd. He was 31 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulwiler</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine Fulwiler died at her residence in Dutch Hollow, Augusta
                    County, on April 10th. She was 101 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fairburn</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fairburn</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Fairburn, wife of William Fairburn, died near Parnassus on
                    April 17th. She was 63 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
