<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.01.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>02/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-01-14">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.14.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We felt it our duty, last week, to call attention to the operation of
                        National Banks in the South, and regret that circumstances force us to
                        continue the subject in this issue and that a little nearer home.</p>
                    <p>The meeting of Stockholders of the National Banks here were advertised to be
                        held on Tuesday last, at which time Boards of Directors were to be elected.
                        The National Valley held its meetings and re-elected the old Board of
                        Directors. The First National failed to hold its meeting of Stockholders,
                        because the proxies of about 40 per cent of the whole stock were sent to the
                        Bank and filled with the cashier's name. The U. S. Banking Law positively
                        prohibits any officer from acting as proxy, and hence no quorum being
                        present, the necessity of adjourning the meeting till February 17th, notice
                        of which was ordered to be published.</p>
                    <p>Before this meeting of the Stockholders was to be held, a meeting of the
                        Directors took place, and the salary of the <sic>casheir</sic> was raised
                        from $2,500 to $3,000, just 6 <emph rend="italic">per cent</emph> on one
                        half the capital stock of the Bank.</p>
                    <p>Considering that the capital stock of our Banks are the same, and that the
                        Deposites at the First National average from $100,000 to $110,000, while
                        those of the National Valley average from $130,000 to $140,000 and that the
                        cashier's salary of the latter is only $1,800, with no effort made to
                        increase the same, it seems strange that the Directors of the First National
                        should increase their cashier's salary to $3,000--Were they aware that the
                        cashier held proxies representing 40 <emph rend="italic">per cent</emph> of
                        the whole stock of the Bank, and that, if they failed to increase his
                        salary, he had it in his power to re-organize the Board to suit himself?
                        Whether they were intimidated or not, they have, by increasing the cashier's
                        salary to $3,000, virtually said to him, "you have made us large profits
                        during the past year off of the necessities of our patrons and we give you
                        $500 more as an inducement to fleece them to a greater extent than
                        heretofore. The people in this locality are in an extremity and will need
                        much assistance during the next year, see to it that you <emph rend="italic"
                            >shave</emph>--aye <emph rend="italic">slice</emph> them in proportion."
                        In this and in no other light can we view your action, Messrs. Directors.
                        Are you entirely oblivious of the circumstances which surround you? Do you
                        forget that the very existence of your Bank depends upon the will of the
                        public? If they refuse to deposite their funds in your hands, for fear that
                        you will use them to <emph rend="italic">skin</emph> their neighbors, or
                        will not offer to borrow for fear you will extort, as the unprecedented
                        increase of your cashier's salary, on account of the large profits he has
                        made out of the patrons of your Bank, seems to warn them, will you not cease
                        to be able to pay even the salaries of officers, much less derive a
                        dividend? Indeed, may not your Bank from that cause be compelled to cease
                        operation entirely? Then we hope you will consider this matter and place
                        yourselves and your Bank square before the public--make it promise a benefit
                        to community, instead of holding over our heads the threat of extortion,
                        which your late action forces as the only conclusion upon one and all.</p>
                    <p>We are unwilling to believe that the foreign Stockholders, many of whom are
                        Baltimoreans, and who have endeavored to assist our people by aiding in the
                        establishment of Banks here, and otherwise, would, for the mere profit to be
                        derived directly therefrom, place the very institutions, intended as a
                        benefit to an impoverished people, in the attitude of a detriment and a
                        damage.</p>
                    <p>This is the attitude of the First National at present, but there is yet time
                        to repair the error made. The deferred meeting of Stockholders is to take
                        place on Feb. 17th. Let them then elect a Board of Directors who will favor
                        only fair salaries and be content with fair profits. If their cashier is
                        unwilling to serve for a fair compensation, then appoint some other person.
                        There is no lack of Banking talent, experience and long tried, in this
                        community, which can be secured at a fair compensation, say from $1500 to
                        $2000. (We allude here to talent for legitimate banking--first rate <emph
                            rend="italic">shavers</emph> can be secured at much lower rates--say
                        $1000 <emph rend="italic">per annum</emph>.)</p>
                    <p>Stockholders see to this at your deferred meeting, and remove the odium which
                        attaches to the unprecedented salary just granted your cashier, simply on
                        the ground that he has made large profits at the expense and out of the
                        necessities of our people. The future popularity and consequent prosperity
                        and efficiency of your Bank depends largely on your action in this
                    matter.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports on the activities of local banks and denounces the
                    stockholders for raising bank employee salaries to unreasonably high levels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that 34 African American men left Staunton on Friday to
                    move further south, and many others plan to go.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>B. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A brick dwelling and frame kitchen on the farm of B. T. Bagby burned on
                    Thursday night. The fire destroyed $600 worth of furniture and did $3,000 worth
                    of total damage. Bagby was insured for only $1,700.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>La Rue's "celebrated corps of eighteen distinguished minstrels" will
                    perform in Staunton at the Town Hall on Friday and Saturday. The troop won rave
                    reviews in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. W. T. Richardson is stepping down as the pastor of the
                    Presbyterian Church of Waynesboro and is leaving the congregation to take a post
                    in Warrenton. All wish him well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Building Associations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elick</ln>
                        <fn>G. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ker</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoshour</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>T. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>B. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunkhouser</ln>
                        <fn>M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>C. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton building association held its annual meeting of stockholders.
                    It had been in operation for 35 months and the value of each share is $83.03.
                    The following officers were elected: J. B. Evans, president; A. M. Bruce, G. F.
                    Elick, J. H. Waters, E. M. Cushing, H. H. Peck, W. J. Nelson, directors; H. Ker,
                    secretary and treasurer; S. A. Hoshour, P. B. Hoge, T. A. Bledsoe, trustees. The
                    Mechanics Building Association also held its meeting. It has been in business 17
                    months and shares are worth $47.55. The following officers were selected: P. B.
                    Hoge, president; W. C. Eskridge, William H. Gorman, Dr. B. H. Atkinson, M. P.
                    Bunkhouser, W. H. H. Lynn, W. A. Burnett, directors; James Ker, secretary and
                    treasurer; J. A. Piper, C. E. Hoge, E. M. Cushing, trustees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn>Molly E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Berry and Miss Molly E. Shultz were married at the residence of the
                    bride's father in Greenville on January 11th by the Rev. William Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>I. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillum</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillum</ln>
                        <fn>P. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. I. W. Gilkeson and Miss Kate Gillum, daughter of the late Dr. P. G.
                    Gillum, were married in Greenville at the residence of the bride's mother on
                    December 23rd by the Rev. James Murray.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reede</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. P. Brown and Miss Martha Reede, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Stuart's Draft on December 30th by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>John Graham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Read</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edwards</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Graham Effinger and Miss Sallie H. Jones, daughter of the late John
                    Jones of Richmond, were married on January 6th by the Rev. C. H. Read, assisted
                    by the Rev. J. E. Edwards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackburn</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Blackburn and Miss Margaret Greaver, both of Augusta, were married
                    on December 30th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tutwiler</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echerd</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echerd</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Phillip D. Tutwiler and Miss Virginia Echerd, daughter of Phillip Echerd,
                    were married at the residence of the bride's father on the Long Glade by the
                    Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bridge</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lunsford</ln>
                        <fn>Serepta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lunsford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lockridge</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. J. W. Bridge and Miss Serepta Lunsford, daughter of William Lunsford,
                    all of Augusta, were married at Winter Green on January 5th by the Rev. John N.
                    Lockridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Janette Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Janette Taylor Bell, daughter of H. M. Bell of Staunton, died on January
                    2nd. "This community has scarcely been called upon to pay their last tribute in
                    a case of deeper sadness or greater grief." The grief and sympathy of each of
                    Janette's schoolmates was particularly touching.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frame</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Frame died near Spring Hill, Augusta County, at the residence of
                    his father on December 26th of consumption. He was 28 years old. He had been
                    living in Illinois but returned to Virginia in the hopes of regaining his
                    health.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.14.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
