<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.09.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/19/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-09-16">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.09.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.09.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>STAUNTON, VA., Sept. 9th, 1870.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Hon. Alex. H.H. Stuart:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>DEAR SIR:--Our present most estimable Representative in Congress, Hon. Wm.
                        Milnes, having announced his determination not again, under any
                        circumstances, to be a candidate for election, and being impressed, as we
                        are, with the conviction of the great importance to the District to have, as
                        its Representatives in the next Congress, a gentleman of the largest
                        experience in public affairs, and of the most comprehensive and
                        statesmanlike views of the proper policy of our Government in the future, we
                        respectfully, but earnestly, request you to allow us to announce you as a
                        candidate for election to a seat in the next House of Representatives of the
                        Congress of the United States, subject to the decision of the District
                        Convention proposed to be held in Harrisonburg on the 5th proximo.</p>
                    <p>We are, very respectfully,</p>
                    <p>Your obedient servants,</p>
                    <p>Jos A Waddell, John Paris, L R Waddell, D S Young, C T Cochran, Robt Cowan,
                        Wm Crawford, G K Harper, Davis A Kayser, M A Bright, W C Eskridge, Alex H
                        Sitlington, H M Bell, J Wayt, A F Kinney, Thos A Bledsoe, M Harvey Effinger,
                        H L Gallagher, Robert G Bickle, O C Morris, Thornton Berry, David S Bell, Wm
                        S McChesney, P O Palmer, Z D Shafer, H A Glenn, John Echols, John A
                        &amp; Y M Bickle, P B Hoge &amp; Bro., Wm B Kayser, Wm G Sterrett,
                        George Baylor, R H May, A D W Reed, A Gardner, Logan J Maupin, D R Williams,
                        Jos W Earman, Jas Bumgardner, jr., James F Patterson, J A Gilkeson, G W
                        McClure, A T Gilkeson, Theo Gamble, James H Blackley, P N Powell, F M Young,
                        A Hoge, Wm Frazeir, C W S Turner, C C Francisco, Jno B Evans, B F Points,
                        Thos J Michie, Jno A English, Jno B Hoge, Taylor G Hoge, Geo H Eyster, John
                        A Patterson, Lewis Whitmer, Thos P Wilson, S Travers Philips, D F Clemmer,
                        Jno H Parkins, Thos C Elder, Jas E Taylor, E T Kinney, James Ker, A M
                        Fauntleroy, H H Peck, B T Bagby, J Alex Waddell, T W Shelton, George Harlan.</p>
                    <p>STAUNTON, Sept. 12th, 1870.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Messrs. Jos. A. Waddell, John Paris, Leigh R. Waddell,
                            D.S. Young, C.T. Cochran and others:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>GENTLEMEN:--I have had the honor to receive your favor of the 9th inst., in
                        which you request me to allow you to announce me as a candidate for the
                        election to a seat in the next House of Representatives of the Congress of
                        the United States, subject to the decision of the District Convention,
                        proposed to be held in Harrisonburg, on the 5th proximo.</p>
                    <p>In reply, I beg leave to say, that if it shall be ascertained that your
                        invitation is in harmony with the general wish of the people of the
                        District, I will not feel at liberty to withhold such service as I may be
                        able to render.</p>
                    <p>In the fall of 1865, I was elected by a District, composed, in a large part,
                        of the Counties which constitute the present District, to a seat in the
                        House of Representatives, but was not allowed to qualify. Since that time,
                        my political disabilities, under the 14th amendment of the Constitution of
                        the United States, have been removed, by act of Congress, and in the event
                        of my election now, there would be no legal obstacle to my taking my seat.</p>
                    <p>It may be proper to add that if the voters of the District should honor me
                        with their suffrages, I should labor assiduously to accomplish the following
                        among other important objects:</p>
                    <p>1. The immediate removal of all disabilities, resulting from the civil war,
                        and the restoration of harmony and fraternal fellowship between all sections
                        of the country, which the abuses and usurpations of partizan power have
                        hitherto tended to prevent.</p>
                    <p>2. A tariff for revenue, to cover the expenses of an economical
                        administration, and to meet the just obligations of the Government, as
                        opposed to the existing system of exorbitant protection for special
                            <sic>monoplies</sic>, and undisguised partiality for favored interests.</p>
                    <p>3. Reduction of the present odious and oppressive scale of taxation, both as
                        applied to imports and internal revenue.</p>
                    <p>4. Rigid economy in every department of the Government, and retrenchment of
                        expenses.</p>
                    <p>5. Reform of the public service in all its branches, civil military and
                        naval.</p>
                    <p>6. A sound National Currency, equally distributed among the States, and
                        protected against speculations.</p>
                    <p>7. The rights of intelligent labor against all selfish combinations to
                        degrade and depreciate it.</p>
                    <p>8. Legislation by which the public lands will be reserved for actual
                        settlers, and as a resource of national credit, in opposition to the Radical
                        policy of enormous grants to speculators and corrupt schemes of
                        appropriation for the benefit of one portion of the country at the expense
                        of the other.</p>
                    <p>9. Aid from the Government of the U.S. in the most available form to complete
                        the line of Water Communication between the Chesapeake and Ohio.</p>
                    <p>10. Strict and impartial neutrality in the contests between other nations,
                        cultivating friendship with all, and entangling alliances with none.</p>
                    <p>In conclusion, Gentlemen, I pray you to accept my profound acknowledgments
                        for the confidence which you have shown in me, and for the very flattering
                        terms in which you have been pleased to convey your invitation.</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully,</p>
                    <p>Your ob't. servant,</p>
                    <p>ALEX. H.H. STUART</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a letter written by prominent conservatives asking Alex H.H. Stuart
                    to be their party's candidate for Congress and the latter's acceptance letter.
                    Stuart also spells out his platform, which includes removing all political
                    obstacles for former Confederates, reducing taxes and corruption, and observing
                    neutrality abroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.09.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sunday School Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Delegates from the Sunday Schools within the Baltimore Conference of the M.
                    E. Church South will meet in Staunton on November 24th. Each school should
                    choose its delegates and notify Rev. H. H. Kennedy, minister in charge of
                    Staunton Station.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Staunton's Female Schools opened this week for the fall term. "Staunton is
                    now looked upon, and justly, as a great centre of female education, and will be
                    more famous in this line in the future."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overholt</ln>
                        <fn>Emma A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seneker</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John L. Patterson and Miss Emma A. Overholt, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Waynesboro on September 5th by the Rev. J. E. Seneker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Bush died at his residence near Deerfield, Augusta County, on
                    September 7th. He was 87 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Geraldine F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Augustus F. M. Myers, infant son of Samuel K. and Geraldine F. Myers, died
                    on Christian's Creek, Augusta County, on September 4th. He was 4 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.09.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
