<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.10.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-10-28">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">28</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.10.28.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.10.28.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last issue we objected to the action of the Conservative District
                        Convention in nominating Judge John T. Harris as the Conservative Candidate
                        for Congress from this District, on the ground that it gave dissatisfaction
                        to the Conservatives, and that this action would split the party in this
                        District.</p>
                    <p>We asserted our willingness to support any man upon whom the party could be
                        rallied, expecting that the opposition to Judge Harris, as the nominee,
                        would result in bringing out some one, whom the Conservatives would support
                            <emph rend="italic">en masse</emph>.--There has been no action looking
                        to this end. Mr. Reynolds of Botetourt and Mr. R.A. Gray of Harrisonburg
                        have since announced themselves as independent candidates. Mr. Reynolds may
                        get a good vote in the upper and Mr. Gray in the lower end of the District,
                        but, as far as we can learn, neither one of these gentlemen can secure
                        voters enough to ensure their election, and with the vote that Judge Harris
                        will get, will so divide the Conservative vote, that the election of Douglas
                        Gray, the Republican candidate, will be almost a certainty.</p>
                    <p>In such a case, what is the duty of Conservatives?</p>
                    <p>We yield to no man in our objections to the action of the Convention, and, if
                        there seemed to us a chance of defeating the nominee, with the Conservative
                        vote, we would most assuredly embrace it, but we do not now believe this
                        possible. We have taken the opportunity to speak to a number from all
                        portions of this County, and some from adjoining counties, who objected
                        seriously to the nomination of Judge Harris, and who, almost invariably
                        expressed the opinion, that, in order to defeat the election of the
                        Republican Candidate in this District, they would have to unite on Judge
                        Harris. This then is our answer to the question above. Those, who object to
                        this, can and do not have any more serious objections to the action of the
                        Convention than we do, but we now regard it as reduced to a question of the
                        success of the Conservative or the Republican parties of the District. As
                        between the two we would take any man standing on the platform adopted at
                        Harrisonburg in preference to the best man in the District, who would
                        affiliate with the Republicans in Congress. For this reason, and for this
                        reason alone, we answer the question, propounded, as we do. In the next
                        Congressional contest, the people will manage their Ward and Township
                        meetings so as to have their sentiments fully represented in their District
                        Convention. The disaffection, exhibited now, will be a warning to future
                        Conventions, which will not soon be forgotten, but for the present we can
                        see but one course to defeat the election of the Republican Candidate,
                        viz;--to unite on the Conservative nominee, however objectionable his
                        nomination was to many of us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Objects to the nomination of Judge Harris as the Conservative nominee for
                    Congress. Nevertheless, is ready to support him in order to unite the
                    Conservative vote and defeat the Republicans in any way possible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Funeral Obsequies of Gen. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints an account of the funeral of Gen. Robert E. Lee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.10.28.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruhl</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Madame</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Madame Ruhl and Prof. Turner's orchestra will give a concert tonight in the
                    chapel of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public School Organization of Augusta County, VA</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. Byron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>B. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>K. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Elisha J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davies</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>J. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>B. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper lists members of the board of trustees and officers of the boards
                    of public schools for the townships of Augusta. Staunton: William J. Nelson,
                    chairman; P. Byron Hoge, clerk; H. M. Bell, clerk. Beverly Manor: A. W. Harman,
                    chairman; L. R. Waddell, clerk; John Towberman, clerk. Middle River: B. J.
                    Craig, chairman; K. B. Koiner, clerk; William Wilson, clerk. South River: James
                    M. Watson, chairman; C. H. Withrow, clerk; D. W. Hanger, clerk. North River:
                    Samuel Forrer, chairman; Elisha J. Bell, clerk; William H. Davies, clerk.
                    Pastures: John S. Guy, chairman; J. Frank Heizer, clerk; B. O. Ferguson, clerk.
                    Riverheads: William Thompson, chairman; A. S. Turk, clerk, C. G. Merritt, clerk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>J. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>Susan C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Frank Swink and Miss Susan C. Buchanan, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 12th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruebush</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nott</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Engleman and Miss Mollie E. Ruebush, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 9th at the residence of the bride's parents by the Rev. J. W. Nott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Robert Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Lee Cochran, son of George W. and Mary Jane Cochran, died near
                    Summerdean on October 12th. He was 7 months old. A poem accompanies the notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Vines died in Greenville at the residence of her husband, M.
                    D. Vines, on October 23rd. She was 60 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George H. Hunter died near Big Bend Tunnel on the C. and O. Railroad on
                    October 25th. He was 31 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.10.28.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
