<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.02.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>02/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-02-04">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>4</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.04.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor</emph>:--I saw an article in a late number of
                        your valuable paper, signed "A Citizen," setting forth the importance of
                        establishing manufacturing enterprises in our town. I agree with him that it
                        is most important that we, as a community, should so shape our course as to
                        induce parties of experience and capital to invest their means here, in such
                        manufacturing enterprises as will insure permanent prosperity, and think the
                        suggestions he makes are good and should claim the attention of our leading
                        business men, so that, when we get control of our own affairs, his plans may
                        be adopted.</p>
                    <p>But this is not all that is necessary for our prosperity. Some change in the
                        management of our Banks is most important. No legitimate business can pay 12
                            <emph rend="italic">per cent.</emph> for money, much less from 3 to 5
                            <emph rend="italic">per cent.</emph> per month, as I understand is the
                        case in at least one of them and presume it must be so as the Board of
                        Directors now give their Cashier a salary equal to 8 <emph rend="italic">per
                            cent.</emph> on their entire capital stock.</p>
                    <p>Now what we want is a Bank that will take good business paper at fair rates.
                        It may be that 6 <emph rend="italic">per cent.</emph> is not enough for
                        National Banks with small capital, but I am sure that 8 <emph rend="italic"
                            >per cent.</emph> would pay a dividend of 10 <emph rend="italic">per
                            cent.</emph> on the capital stock, which ought to satisfy any reasonable
                        stockholder. When these Banks were established here it was understood that
                        those merchants in the Northern cities, who took stock, did so for the
                        purpose of assisting the merchants and business men in our community and not
                        to rob them by charging usurious rates for money, and make 25 <emph
                            rend="italic">per cent.</emph> annually, as they are now doing. I would
                        just say to these Northern and other stockholders, be careful or you may
                        "kill the goose that lays the golden eggs." Our merchants buy their goods in
                        Baltimore, Philadelphia and New York, perhaps from some of these very share
                        holders and the time may come (by constant shaving by the Banks they have
                        established here for our benefit,) when these Staunton and Augusta county
                        merchants can not pay what they owe them for the goods purchased. Now the
                        question for them to decide is, whether they prefer to continue to sell
                        their goods and get the money, or take 30 <emph rend="italic">per
                        cent.</emph> on the few shares of Bank stock they hold in our Banks.</p>
                    <p>The fact is, Mr. Editor, too many of our people are engaged in the blood
                        thirsty business of shaving. It seems to me that it pervades all classes of
                        society and that each man is trying to see how much money he can make out of
                        his neighbor's necessities. Now let me urge upon all our people, Bankers and
                        others, to be content to do a legitimate business, if it don't make quite as
                        many greenbacks. I am sure it will create a better feeling among our people
                        and improve the business prospects of our town and county. It certainly is
                        no inducement to men experienced in manufacturing, and having the means to
                        build up manufacturing establishments in our midst, to learn that 2, 3 and 5
                            <emph rend="italic">per cent.</emph> per month is demanded and paid for
                        money here. The present usurious rates of interest, on the contrary, is an
                        impediment to our advancement. And with the assumption with which I started,
                        a change must be effected in the manipulations of our Banks and others. The
                        frowns of community now gather against the extortions practiced. But the
                        people must put their thoughts and feelings into practice. They have it in
                        their power to put down usury and they must do it. Then we can induce
                        capitalists to invest in our midst in legitimate business, such as "A
                        Citizen" suggests, and I am sure it will stimulate enterprise, thrift and
                        industry among our people, and start us on a sure road to wealth and
                        material prosperity.<lb/> STAUNTON.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Staunton" writes the Vindicator to support recent calls for development of
                    manufacturing in Augusta County. He also calls for reform in banking practice,
                    asserting that present rates of interest are usurious.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Acquitted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahaney</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Mahaney, accused of pushing George White to his death from the
                    parapet of the railroad bridge, was acquitted in his trial before Justice R. G.
                    Bickle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses the suggestion of Maj. Jed Hotchkiss as candidate for
                    Superintendent of Public Schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To Distillers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Col. Josiah Given of the Distillation Bureau of the Internal Revenue
                    Department and Commissioner Delano will meet with the distillers of Central
                    Virginia at a conference at Staunton on February 10th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Rockingham farmers are hauling their goods to
                    Staunton for sale despite the fact that they have railroad connections with the
                    outside world. The paper pleas for construction of McAdamized roads to
                    facilitate trade, and solidify Staunton's position as a major market.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutcheson</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George A. Hutcheson and Miss Maggie J. Robertson, both of Greenville, were
                    married on January 25th at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev.
                    Wilson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddle</ln>
                        <fn>Tabner L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Mahala J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tabner L. Riddle and Miss Mahala J. Allen, both of Augusta, were married on
                    January 27th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pifer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Follansbee</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob L. Pifer and Miss Margaret R. Harmon, both of Augusta, were married
                    on December 30th by the Rev. J. M. Follansbee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFall</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Radie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Follansbee</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James A. McFall and Miss Radie M. Harmon, both of Augusta, were married on
                    January 23rd by the Rev. J. M. Follansbee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hezekiah Bernard Curry, son of Rev. H. W. and Rachel Curry, died near
                    Spring Hill on January 24th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Korcheskie</ln>
                        <fn>John Arey Hiet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Korcheskie</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Korcheskie</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Arey Hiet Korcheskie, son of Joseph and Mary Korcheskie, died in
                    Spring Hill on January 24th. He was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antrim</ln>
                        <fn>George T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. George T. Antrim died at his residence near Fishersville on January
                    30th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Mary H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary H. Cochran, wife of B. F. Cochran, died at the residence of her
                    father, Isaac Hall, on January 31st. She was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine Virginia Kiracofe, wife of the Rev. J. W. Kiracofe, died in
                    Maryland on January 11th. Her remains were brought to Augusta and interred in
                    Mt. Tabor graveyard. She was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allor</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Allor died at his residence near Deerfield, Augusta County, on January
                    5th. "He was a soldier in the war of 1812, was an inoffensive, honest man, and
                    died without an enemy as far as known. He survived his wife but a short time. He
                    leaves several daughters and many friends to mourn their loss."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
