<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0085"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0085">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Miss Baldwin: A Brief Memoir," by
                    Armistead C. Gordon, March 6, 1925</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county miss baldwin a brief memoir, by armistead c gordon march 6 1925</title>
        <author>Gordon, Armistead C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 21 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0085</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498498</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Miss Baldwin: A Brief Memoir," by Armistead C.
                            Gordon, March 6, 1925</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county miss baldwin a brief memoir, by armistead c gordon march 6 1925</title>
            <author>Armistead C. Gordon</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>9 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Miss Baldwin, A Brief Memoir, The
                            McClure Co., Inc. Printers, Staunton, Virginia, p.3-11</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1925-03-06">1925-03-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Education, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-10-11">2005-10-11</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0085T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Account of Mary Julia Baldwin's heading of a school in wartime Staunton</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Miss Mary Julia Baldwin</hi>
                </p>
                <p>In November, 1863, there had been war in the Shenandoah Valley of Virginia for
                    more than two years. Three of the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse had galloped
                    back and forth through its once fertile expanse, and left in their wake death
                    and destruction and desolation; and the shadow of the fourth constantly loomed
                    on the horizon.</p>
                <p>Barns and fences had been burned, <orig reg="livestock">live stock</orig> had
                    been carried off, and agriculture, which had once made the region to blossom as
                    a rose, was at a standstill. Food and clothing and the bare necessities of life
                    were practically unobtainable. Flour sold at eighty dollars a barrel. Other
                    provisions were equally costly in comparison, and all were difficult to obtain.
                    Clothing for both men and women was beyond the purses of even the most
                    prosperous, who like their poorer neighbors wore their "old garments," or those
                    of more recent homespun manufacture. The Valley was filled with newly made
                    graves, and in the little town of Staunton, wounded men and prisoners were no
                    unaccustomed sight.</p>
                <p>By the summer of 1863 every school in the place had been closed on account of the
                    distractions and disasters of the War. Other things than education occupied the
                    minds and hearts of most of its men and women. The harsh inevitable present had
                    to be met as best might be. There was little time to reflect on the future and
                    to consider that when the misery of it all should come to an end a younger
                    generation would have to take up the burden of life; and in order to bear it
                    must be educated.</p>
                <p>Out of the stress and wretchedness of the time, which grew greater as the weeks
                    passed, emerged the heroic figure of a woman, who with clear vision looked into
                    the uncertain future, and with noble courage and indomitable resolution set mind
                    and heart to meeting the future's un-<pb n="4"/> escapable needs. Her earlier
                    life had been spent with no anticipation that her career was to be what it
                    became. Modest and retiring, at the age of thirty-four years, Miss Mary Julia
                    Baldwin was little known to the people of the community in which she lived as
                    possessing the latent qualities that were to make the great educator and wise
                    administrator, which her subsequent career so splendidly demonstrated.</p>
                <p>The Augusta Female Seminary had been established in the summer of 1842 by the
                    Reverend Rufus W. Bailey, a native of Maine, who had earlier taught in South
                    Carolina. Mr. Bailey was a scholarly man of much ability; and opening his school
                    for the education of girls and young women, with the advice and assistance of
                    prominent citizens in the town and county he made it from the start a seminary
                    of high grade, under Presbyterian influence and control.</p>
                <p>The corner-stone of the first building for the Seminary was laid on the 15th of
                    June, 1844; and in it was deposited a copper-plate engraved with the names of
                    the Trustees, officers, and pupils, and a copy of the Bible inscribed "The only
                    Book of Faith and first text-book of the Augusta Female Seminary."</p>
                <p>In 1845 the school was incorporated under the name of Augusta Female Seminary;
                    and it bore that title until two years before the death of Miss Baldwin, who had
                    made it one of the most distinguished and successful institutions of learning of
                    its kind in the United States, it was called the "Mary Baldwin Seminary."</p>
                <p>Mr. Bailey's administration, which lasted until 1849, was successful, as were
                    those of the several principals who came after him; yet at no time did the
                    school ever achieve the importance which was given it by the administration of
                    Miss Baldwin. Its last principal before her advent was Mr. John B. Tinsley, who
                    kept it open in the battle-years from 1861 to 1863. But the numbers of pupils
                    were greatly reduced and the places of boarders were filled with refugees who
                    fled to Staunton from the vicinity of the contending armies.</p>
                <pb n="5"/>
                <p>The auspices under which the Seminary had been founded were very favorable from
                    the standpoint of morality and religion; but for a time it was confronted with
                    financial difficulties. Its associations from the beginning were distinguished,
                    for it grew up in the shadow of a great church, that has numbered among its
                    pastors many of the most eminent divines of the Presbyterian denomination. James
                    Waddell, known to Americans as "the Blind Preacher," at one time ministered to
                    the congregation, and Joseph R. Wilson, the father of the great War President,
                    later served in its pulpit. The leading men of the community manifested a deep
                    and abiding interest in its welfare. The old church building where the <abbr
                        expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr> Mr. Wilson preached, and in which his famous
                    son was baptized, has for many years formed a part of the school-buildings; and
                    about the place young Wilson was accustomed to play when he occasionally visited
                    it in his childhood.</p>
                <p>But nothing ever served to so awaken it and set it on the high road to usefulness
                    and great achievement as did the coming of Miss Baldwin as its Principal.</p>
                <p>Miss Mary Julia Baldwin was the daughter of <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr>
                    William D. Baldwin, of Staunton, and Margaret L. Sowers, his wife. She was left
                    an orphan at the age of sixteen years and grew up under the care of her maternal
                    grandparents, who were people of piety and religious life. They early developed
                    her natural qualities and benevolence and self-sacrifice; and her heart went out
                    to the many poorer children of the town, whom she saw growing up, in the absence
                    of public schools, without the opportunities of even the most <orig reg="meager"
                        >meagre</orig> instruction. She first attracted attention as a teacher in
                    the Sunday School. Possessing a small competence derived from her father's
                    estate, she rented a modest school room, and enlisting the sympathy and aid of
                    several other young ladies, she opened a charity-school, which she conducted
                    with whole-souled devotion and success for several years. Her heart was in the
                    work, and even as a young woman she had formed the purpose of making teaching
                    her profession, not merely as a means <pb n="6"/> of support, but because of the
                    good she felt she could do and the useful career which it offered. Upon the
                    death in 1862 of her grandmother, with whom she lived, she rented suitable
                    premises and began the conduct of a private school.</p>
                <p>It was while engaged in this occupation which promised a modest success, and with
                    no thought or aspiration of a more ambitious or distinguished career, that she
                    was offered the vacant principalship of the Seminary.</p>
                <p>Among the Trustees of the institution was a citizen of Staunton, later well known
                    as a publicist and an author, whose interest in the Seminary had always been
                    marked, and who continued one of its best and most influential friends until his
                    death in the <orig reg="fullness">fulness</orig> of years, long after the <orig
                        reg="revitalized">re-vitalized</orig> school had come into its own. Mr.
                    Joseph Addison Waddell, a man of fine business sense and judgment and of eminent
                    piety, had observed the beneficent and unselfish life of the young
                    school-teacher, and knew her lofty character, her intelligent equipment, and her
                    administrative capacity. He approached her on his own motion with the
                    proposition that she should take charge of the Seminary as Mr. Tinsley's
                    successor, in conjunction with Miss Agnes McClung as matron and housekeeper.</p>
                <p>They were both disposed to regard the offer unfavorably, but through no feeling
                    other than one of modesty and a doubt of their capacity successfully to
                    undertake it. But Mr. Waddell, who possessed a well-founded confidence that
                    these two women could make a larger success of the school than any of the worthy
                    men who had preceded them were able to do, without arguing the matter further
                    with them, presented their names to the Trustees. They were elected, and
                    accepted the trust.</p>
                <p>Thus is came about that Miss Baldwin was one of the pioneers in conduct and
                    management of higher institutions of learning for young women in America. It had
                    been customary theretofore for such schools and colleges to be in charge of men,
                    but her experience demonstrated <pb n="7"/> the field to be one for which the
                    right type of woman was best adapted.</p>
                <p>The task which she essayed was one calculated, under the conditions that
                    confronted her, to <orig reg="appall">appal</orig> any person of feebler fiber
                    or weaker will. She had a clear understanding of its difficulties, an experience
                    in dealing with young women and girls, and a confident belief that it was the
                    finger of God that pointed the way in which she might accomplish the greatest
                    good for humanity. Her religious faith was very great, and to this faith, even
                    more than to her valiant spirit, her unusual ability, and her indomitable will,
                    the triumphant accomplishment of her mission in life in attributable.</p>
                <p>The sublime language and meaning of St. Paul's saying to the Philippians were in
                    her heart and mind and thenceforth were wrought into the fabric of her life: "I
                    count not myself to have apprehended: but this one thing I do, forgetting those
                    things which are behind and reaching forth unto those things which are before."
                    Animated by this spirit, she felt that, in the providence of God, failure was
                    impossible; and she never deviated from her set purpose.</p>
                <p>The school, which most people thought could not continue to struggle on in the
                    poverty, the distractions and the sorrows of the War, that were then at their
                    flood-tide, was advertised by the two new principals to open on the first day of
                    October, 1863. The buildings were almost entirely unfurnished, and there were
                    scarcely household articles enough remaining to equip the sleeping rooms of even
                    the Principals; and there was no furniture to be obtained in the shops. But the
                    two dauntless women were as resourceful as they were courageous. "In the
                    dilemma," says Mr. Waddell, "the Principals resorted to the expedient of
                    borrowing from their friends. No man would or could have started under such
                    circumstances; but many persons were ready and anxious to help two ladies so
                    well known and so highly esteemed. When a boarder was entered, all necessary
                    chamber and table furniture had to be borrowed <pb n="8"/> - bedding, towels,
                    chairs, dishes and plates, cups and saucers, knives and forks; and the dwellings
                    of many persons were stripped of all articles that could be spared."</p>
                <p>In the meantime by advertisement and the personal invitation of themselves and
                    their many friends, who were inspired by the energy and determination of the new
                    Principals, boarding-pupils from various directions were enrolled and
                    day-scholars were entered; and on the opening day the Seminary, refurnished and
                    re-equipped, though in a <orig reg="meager">meagre</orig> fashion, opened with
                    fifty-eight day-pupils and twenty-two boarders - probably a larger number than
                    in any preceding session.</p>
                <p>One of Miss Baldwin's distinguishing characteristics was the possession of a keen
                    knowledge and understanding of men and women. "Common sense" is a rarer and more
                    valuable faculty than "uncommon sense;" and the ability to "look through every
                    other man with silent sharp inspection" was a quality which she possessed in a
                    remarkable degree. She made no mistakes in choosing the teachers and officials,
                    whose selection rested chiefly with her; and among the earliest of her
                    instructors was the accomplished Miss Eliza Howard, a sister-in-law of <abbr
                        expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> William H. McGuffey, the famous professor of Moral
                    Philosophy in the University of Virginia, whose "Spellers," with their a-b's and
                    e-b's, and Primers and Readers opened up the ways of knowledge to many children
                    of a past generation. Miss Baldwin's adventure with the School greatly
                    interested <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> McGuffey; and recognizing her fine
                    qualities and her courageous efforts, he came to her academic assistance and
                    aided her freely with his experienced advice and counsel in organizing its
                    courses of instruction and its general educational plan and system.</p>
                <p>She had no foolish pride in her own knowledge or capacity; and with the modest
                    simplicity of wisdom and intelligence, she consulted those whose advice she
                    believed would be valuable, and upon whose interest in her plans she could
                    confidently rely as genuine and sincere.</p>
                <pb n="9"/>
                <p>Napoleon said that every soldier in his army carried a Marshal's baton in his
                    knapsack; and Miss Baldwin showed in her selection of associates and employees
                    that she understood and appreciated the meaning of the apothegm. It would be
                    pleasant, if space permitted it, to recall the roster of those who in her long
                    vigil and work of thirty-four years, rendered her the loyal and intelligent
                    assistance which is a splendid part of the history of the Seminary. To name only
                    a few of these noble women would be invidious; to mention them all in this paper
                    is impossible.</p>
                <p>In making the announcement of the opening of the School, Miss Baldwin further
                    exhibited her marked characteristic of common sense. Her whole life had been
                    spent in Staunton, where she was born; and no one knew better than she did the
                    economic straits to which the country had better than she did the economic
                    straits to which the country had been reduced by the ravages of war. As in the
                    case of producing the furniture for the school, she was equal to the yet more
                    difficult emergency of providing proper food for her boarders. The currency of
                    the time was very greatly depreciated; and while her patriotic devotion to the
                    cause for which her people were struggling burned with a steady flame to the
                    tragic end, she saw that in the devastated Valley little could be accomplished,
                    if she had to rely on purchases of supplies with the almost valueless
                    Confederate notes. She "stipulated," says Mr. Waddell, "that as far as possible
                    the payments for board and tuition should be made in country produce, - flour,
                    corn, meats, butter, poultry, eggs, vegetables, wood for fuel, hay for a cow,
                    and sorghum."</p>
                <p>The plan worked admirably, and the girls in the Seminary through her wisdom and
                    pre-vision fared, not sumptuously, but in some respects better than did the
                    fighting armies in the field.</p>
                <p>A characteristic account of the Seminary, in its wartime days under Miss Baldwin,
                    has been written by one of her former pupils:</p>
                <p>"Friends were very kind and sent contributions of every sort. The dinner-table
                    presented a queer appearance, set <pb n="10"/> as it was with odds and ends
                    gathered from everywhere, no two cups and saucers alike, here a kitchen knife
                    and there a silver one, while a stately cut-glass goblet was arranged alongside
                    of a heavy china mug; but young appetites are not fastidious, and the girls grew
                    strong and hearty, no matter if butter and gravy never appeared at the same
                    meal, or if their coffee was made from rye and sweetened with sorghum......The
                    furniture of the rooms, like that of the dinner-table, was collected here and
                    there, no two pieces being alike."</p>
                <p>The resolution and resourcefulness of the new administration overcame every
                    difficulty. The school became at once a great success, and so continued. But,
                    curiously enough, with the end of the war came a repetition of some of the chief
                    difficulties which it had encountered in 1863. The Principals had no money that
                    would pass current, and the friends who had loaned furniture were compelled to
                    reclaim it on account of the necessities in their own homes. But character in
                    business is the foundation of credit; and by degrees the Seminary was
                    refurnished. Within three years, after the surrender at Appomattox, the school
                    has 137 pupils, including not only those from Virginia, but others from Georgia,
                    West Virginia, Alabama, Florida, North Carolina, Louisiana, Tennessee,
                    Mississippi, Illinois and Ohio on its roster. It had ceased to be a local
                    institution; and its influence had begun to penetrate the whole South and parts
                    of the West.</p>
                <p>Of its subsequent development in buildings, equipment, faculty, broad scholarship
                    and beneficent moral and religious influence, there is no room to speak here in
                    detail, further than to state that in each of these phases of its life is
                    visible the influence of Miss Baldwin. Her ability as an organizer and as an
                    administrator was only one side of her splendidly rounded character as a great
                    educator. Another side, less known to the general public, but equally
                    significant in making the institution under her charge a notable success, was
                    what may be called the domestic one. In her contact with the members of her
                    faculty and with her <pb n="11"/> pupils, she illustrated that indescribable
                    influence, often exercised by individuals of unique mind and character, which
                    accomplishes results without fuss or parade, and so unobtrusively as almost to
                    escape observation. She possessed in large measure all the domestic virtues.
                    With her strong religious feeling and her original individualism were blended
                    unwearying compassion, good temper, conscientious devotion to duty, and an
                    affection, which while it was not unduly demonstrative, was always broad and
                    generous. In her personal habits of neatness, dignity, consideration, courtesy
                    and forbearance, she taught better lessons than those learned in books.</p>
                <p>Without pretensions to wide scholarship, but with the capacity to recognize its
                    value, in her selection of her teachers she looked to the establishment of the
                    highest standards in the School; and the diploma of the graduate became
                    thenceforth the conclusive testimonial of a thorough cultural and scholarly
                    proficiency.</p>
                <p>Benevolent and charitable to all worthy persons and objects, unselfish in her
                    dealings with her fellows, liberal in her contributions to religious causes, she
                    embodied in her career, to a degree unexcelled by that of any other American
                    woman, the qualities that are to be found in the great teachers of youth in
                    England and in this country, - of Arnold of Rugby, of William Everett of Quincy,
                    of the two Colemans and Gordon McCabe in Virginia, and of Moses Waddell, the
                    famous schoolmaster of Willington, South Carolina.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
