<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0073"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0073">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "A Large Family of Confederate
                    Soldiers," by Unknown, 1915</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county a large family of confederate soldiers, by unknown 1915</title>
        <author>Unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 5.3 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0073</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498486</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "A Large Family of Confederate Soldiers," by Unknown,
                            1915</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county a large family of confederate soldiers, by unknown 1915</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 page</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 23, p.
                            57, 1915</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1915">1915</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-04">2006-02-04</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0073T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Short piece on Augusta County family with many Confederate veterans</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Many prominent families of the South were fully represented in the Confederate
                    army, but the record of one family of Augusta County, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr>, can hardly be equaled. The Richmond Times-Dispatch some years ago
                    referred to this family as having the largest representation known in the army
                    of the Confederacy. The record is taken from Waddell's "Annals of Augusta
                    County," as follows:</p>
                <p>"James Bell, of Long Glade, had seven sons, of whom six served in the Confederate
                    army. Alexander died of disease contracted in the army; Addison was killed at
                    Chancellorsville in 1862; Luther died from disease in the service; William was
                    severely wounded at Kernstown in 1862; Daniel was wounded at Gettysburg; Frank
                    was also wounded; Samuel, the youngest son, was too young to join even the home
                    guard. The first, second, fifth, and sixth brothers were members of Company C,
                    5th Virginia Regiment, Stonewall Brigade. The third brother belonged to the 52d
                    Regiment, and the fourth to the Liberty Hall company, 4th Regiment.</p>
                <p>"The Bell boys came from fighting stock. An uncle, William Bell, was killed in
                    the Revolutionary War; <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> David Bell served in
                    the War of 1812; James Bell served in the 5th Virginia Regiment and died at
                    Swift Run Gap. His son, Brownice Bell, of the 25th Regiment, was taken prisoner
                    and died at Fort Delaware in 1863.</p>
                <p>"John Bell, brother of James and son of <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> David
                    Bell, had seven sons, all of whom entered the Confederate service. David,
                    Company C, 5th Regiment, died in the hospital at Lynchburg; Elisha, Carpenter's
                    Battery, was wounded at Antietam; William, Company C, 5th Regiment, was wounded
                    at Cedar Creek; Alexander, of the same company, was taken prisoner at Antietam
                    and died at Fort Delaware; Henderson, of the same company, was severely wounded
                    at Gettysburg.</p>
                <p>"Thomas Bell, a third brother, had two sons in the same regiment, one of whom,
                    Thomas M., was mortally wounded at Chancellorsville, and the other, James A.,
                    died of wounds received at Kernstown. A cousin, Thomas A., was killed at
                    Spottsylvania Courthouse; another cousin, Thomas R, was mortally wounded at
                    Hatcher's Run; while his brother John served in Fitzhugh Lee's cavalry.</p>
                <p>"Thus we have the extraordinary record of eighteen of the descendants of James
                    and Agnes Bell serving in the Confederate army, most of them in the same company
                    of the 5th Regiment. Five were killed in battle or died of wounds, while six
                    died of disease contracted in the army."</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
