<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0024"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0024">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "<abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr>
                    James. H. Waters," by James Bumgardner, Jr., May, 1913</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county capt james h waters, by james bumgardner jr may 1913</title>
        <author>Bumgardner, James Jr.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 6.2 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0024</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498456</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "<abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> James. H.
                            Waters," by James Bumgardner, Jr., May, 1913</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county capt james h waters, by james bumgardner jr may 1913</title>
            <author>James Bumgardner, Jr.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 21,
                            1913, p. 346</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1913-05">1913-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-02">2006-02-02</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0024T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>An obituary of Captain James H. Waters, a soldier in the Virginia 5th Infantry
                    Division.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p><abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> James H. Waters departed this life on May 13,
                    1913, at the Odd Fellows' Home in Lynchburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>,
                    in the eighty-fifth year of his age. He came from New Jersey to Staunton, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, in 1850. He engaged in business, married Miss
                    Elizabeth Carroll, a native of Staunton, and promptly identified himself with
                    the people of that place. He was one of the original enlisted members of that
                    renowned volunteer company, the West Augusta Guard, which was organized in 1858,
                    was in service during the John Brown raid in 1859, and on during the entire
                    period of the War of the States. It was in service during the late war with
                    Spain, and is now one of the best companies in the volunteer military service of
                    Virginia.</p>
                <p>At the organization of the company Captain Waters was elected first lieutenant;
                    and when the company was ordered to Charlestown during the John Brown raid,
                        <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> (afterwards <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col.</abbr>) William S. H. Baylor (who was later killed at Manassas on August
                    29, 1862, while leading the Stonewall Brigade in a desperate charge) was
                    prostrated with typhoid fever, and Captain Waters commanded the company.</p>
                <p>The West Augusta Guard was of the 5th Regiment of Virginia Infantry, in the
                    Stonewall Brigade. This regiment was organized about the 12th of April, 1861, as
                    "a volunteer regiment of Virginia militia," and William S. H. Baylor, captain of
                    the West Augusta Guard, was made colonel.</p>
                <p>On April 17, 1861, the West Augusta Guard, under command of Lieutenant Waters, by
                    command of the Governor of Virginia, left Staunton for Harper's Ferry. The order
                    of the Governor reached Staunton about 8 A.M. of that day, and the company
                    embarked about 6 P.M. of the same day. There were of the company on that April
                    day (1861) one hundred and twenty-five men, rank and file. When the roll was
                    called, one hundred and twenty-three answered to their names and boarded the
                    train. Captain Waters was commissioned as captain in May, 1861, and commanded
                    the company at Falling Waters, First Manassas, during the Romney expedition of
                    General Jackson, and at Kernstown. In July, 1862, he was made commissary of the
                    5th Regiment with the rank of captain, and was soon afterwards made commissary
                    of the Stone-wall Brigade, and served in that capacity until the close of the
                    war.</p>
                <p>In 1880 he was made chief of the police department of Staunton, in which capacity
                    he rendered devoted and efficient service until 1900, when he was retired by
                    reason of advanced age and infirmity. After his retirement as chief of police of
                    Staunton, Captain Waters went to the Odd Fellows' Home in Lynchburg, where he
                    remained until his death. His funeral service was held in the Odd Fellows' Home,
                    after which his body was transported to Staunton and on the 15th of May, 1913,
                    was buried in Thornrose Cemetery. His body was followed to its final resting
                    place by the three sole survivors of the men who originally enlisted in the West
                    Augusta Guard-viz., Henry Hyer, William Wholly, and James Bumgardner, <abbr
                        expan="Junior">Jr.</abbr></p>
                <p>Captain Waters was a member of the Episcopal Church, and his entire life was an
                    illustration of the best and noblest qualities of the Christian, the soldier,
                    and the gentleman.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
