<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0032"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0032">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "THIRD CONVENTION GRAND DIVISION OF
                    VIRGINIA," by unknown, 1898</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county third convention grand division of virginia, by unknown 1898</title>
        <author>unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 9 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0032</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498464</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "THIRD CONVENTION GRAND DIVISION OF VIRGINIA," by
                            unknown, 1898</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county third convention grand division of virginia, by unknown 1898</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 6,
                            1898, pp. 502-503</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1898">1898</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Education, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-12">2005-12-12</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0032T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Description of Virginia State United Daughters of the Confederacy chapter meeting
                    focusing on election of new officers and relations with a competing state
                    chapter.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The third annual convention of the Grand Division of Virginia was held in
                    Petersburg October 12, 13, at the A. P. Hill Camp Hall, which was handsomely
                    draped with Confederate and Virginia flags and bunting. The President, Mrs.
                    James Mercer Garnett, called the body to order at eleven o'clock, and the
                    convention was opened with prayer by <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr> H. L.
                    Derby. Mrs. Robert T. Meade, President of the Petersburg Chapter, delivered an
                    eloquent address of welcome. Mrs. Garnett responded, in the absence of Mrs.
                    Meredith, of Manassas. She paid a warm tribute to the historic city of
                    Petersburg and its brave sons and daughters. Both addresses were well received.
                    About fifty delegates were present, though eighty were due.</p>
                <p>The usual business-appointing committees, calling the roll of chapters and
                    delegates, reading the minutes, and hearing the reports of committees and of
                    chapters, together with the President's annual report and address-consumed the
                    first morning's session.</p>
                <p>Ten new chapters have been added since last convention, as follows: No. 31,
                    Pittsburg, <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr>; No. 32, Abingdon; No. 33,
                    Flora Stuart, at Pulaski; No. 34, Middleburg; No. 35, Palmyra; No. 36, Smyth
                    County; No. 37, Turner Ashby, at Winchester; No. 38, Essex, at Tappahannock; No.
                    39, Harrison Harwood, at Charles City Courthouse; No. 40., Cumberland
                    Courthouse.</p>
                <p>The reports showed that splendid work had been done in all the chapters in caring
                    for the Confederate living and dead, building monuments, collecting war records,
                    and using every effort to have proper histories used in Southern schools. It is
                    a matter of pride that Virginia has adopted for use in her public schools the
                    histories written by one of our Virginia Daughters, Mrs. Susan Pendleton Lee, of
                    the Mary Custis Lee Chapter, Lexington, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> These
                    histories were<pb n="503"/> warmly <orig reg="endorsed">indorsed</orig> by the
                    History Committee of the United Daughters of the Confederacy, on which Mrs.
                    Garnett represents Virginia.</p>
                <p>No afternoon session being necessary, the time was spent in pleasant drives
                    around Petersburg, by which the visitors had an opportunity of viewing the many
                    points of interest about the city. At night a handsome reception was given the
                    Daughters to meet the A. P. Hill Camp, with whom the ladies had much pleasant
                    talk.</p>
                <p>On Thursday morning the <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr><abbr expan="Doctor"
                        >Dr.</abbr> J. M. Pilcher opened the session with prayer. The unfinished
                    business and new business, together with resolutions of sympathy and respect for
                    Mrs. Davis and Mrs. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Stuart, on the deaths of
                    their daughters, occupied the first part of the day.</p>
                <p>The convention voted against any successor to Miss Winnie Davis, the first and
                    only Daughter of the Confederacy. The matter of union between the two divisions
                    in Virginia was again brought up, and for the third time in three years a
                    cordial invitation was sent to the First Virginia Division to unite with the
                    Grand Division, so as to have but one body in the State, the chapters in
                    Virginia now representing more than one-fourth of the whole United Society. A
                    committee was appointed to lay the matter of union before the convention of the
                    First Virginia Division, which met at Appomattox October 21. Miss Wiseman, of
                    Danville, acted as proxy for Mrs. Garnett, who was appointed by the Grand
                    Division, with Mrs. Watkins, of Petersburg, to bear friendly greetings and urge
                    union, as all now belong to the same general society and the aims and objects
                    are exactly the same. The request that a committee be appointed from the First
                    Virginia Division to confer with the committee from the Grand Division, so as to
                    arrange the union before the next <abbr
                        expan="United Daughters of the Confederacy">U. D. C.</abbr> convention, at
                    Richmond, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, was "declined," and the matter
                    "referred to the several chapters, to report next autumn." The Grand Division
                    stands ready for union in the State, as she has ever done since its
                    organization, offering equal rights and privileges to all. The fact that "the
                    Grand Division is twice as large as the Virginia Division" seems a strange
                    reason to give against union in the State. As will be explained later, in the
                    "reply to Mrs. Raines," it was an accident that two divisions were formed in
                    Virginia, and because no response was sent to Mrs. Garnett's offer to organize
                    for the general society, though the President stated a year later that she had
                    ordered it to be done.</p>
                <p>The election of new officers closed the second day's session, with a vote of
                    thanks for the charming hospitality tendered by the Petersburg Chapter.</p>
                <p>Mrs. Garnett, having filled the office of President of the Grand Division since
                    its beginning, declined reelection, and was then made Honorary President for
                    life. She expressed her pleasure at having her name always enrolled with the
                    officers of the Grand Divsion. Mrs. N. V. Randolph, of Richmond, and Mrs. R. T.
                    Meade, of Petersburg, also declined the presidency. Mrs. S. T. McCullough, of
                    Staunton, was elected. Mrs. McCullough is a daughter of <abbr expan="Major"
                    >Maj.</abbr> Hotchkiss, an efficient and favorite staff officer to Stonewall
                    Jackson. She is an officer in the "Jeb" Stuart Chapter at Staunton. Mrs. J. E.
                    B. Stuart, still refusing the presidency, for which she is each year nominated,
                    retains her place as First Vice President. The other Vice Presidents are Mrs. R.
                    T. Meade, of Petersburg; Mrs. J. N. Barney, of Fredericksburg; and Mrs. N. V.
                    Randolph, of Richmond. Mrs. Virginius Hall, Richmond, is both Recording and
                    Corresponding Secretary. Mrs. Samuel B. Walker, of Lexington, is Treasurer. Mrs.
                        <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> William Allan, of Lexington, is Historian.
                    Richmond was selected for the next convention, which will be the day before the
                    annual convention of the <abbr expan="United Daughters of the Confederacy">U. D.
                        C.</abbr> A beautiful tea was given the ladies at 5 P.M. by the hospitable
                    President of the Petersburg Chapter. The greatest harmony prevailed among
                    delegates, as it ever has among the chapters and individual members.</p>
                <p>Mrs. Garnett paid a tribute to the CONFEDERATE VETERAN and earnestly suggested
                    that each chapter should subscribe to it, and so keep in touch with Confederate
                    work at large.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
