<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0007"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0007">

    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "The Confederate Dead," by A. G.
                    Gordon, January 30, 1899</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county the confederate dead, by a g gordon january 30 1899</title>
        <author>Gordon, A. G.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent> 
        <num type="kilobytes">ca. 7.4 kilobytes</num>
      </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0007</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498439</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "The Confederate Dead," by A. G. Gordon, January 30,
                            1899</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county the confederate dead, by a g gordon january 30 1899</title>
            <author>A. G. Gordon</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: SHSP, Vol. XXV, p.382-384,
                        1898</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1899-01-30">1899-01-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>KEYWORDS</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-05">2005-12-05</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0007T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This article consists mostly of a poem by A. C. Gordon of Staunton, read at the
                    unveiling of the monument erected to the Confederate dead at Staunton, Va.</p>
            </div1>
            
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="underline">To the Editor of the Times:</hi>
                </p>
                <p>In reading the excellent address of <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> R. S.
                    Parks to the veterans [see ante pp. 354-364], as reported in your paper, and the
                    beautiful and fitting verses with which he closed, it occurred to me that you
                    would enjoy, if you have never seen it, or read it, the entire poem as delivered
                    by the author, the <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> A. C. Gordon, of
                    Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, upon the occasion of unveiling the
                    monument erected to the Confederate dead at Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr>, and I enclose you a copy. The late Professor George Fred. Holmes
                    told the writer of this that he considered Mr. Armistead Gordon's poem "the
                    finest on such an occasion he had read since the war." With many other
                    distinguishing qualities, I am happy that Virginia has in this son one who
                    writes so beautifully in verse.*<lb/><add place="inline" hand="h1">* He has written as well in prose. it
                        may be assumed, for, as fellow student with Thomas Nelson Page at the
                        University of Virginia, he yielded to the latter (it has been admitted),
                        some conceptions-upon which our dialect writer rose to fame and
                    wealth.</add></p>
                <p>G. JULIAN PRATT.</p>
                <p>Waynesboro, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, January 25, 1898.</p>
                <p>THE CONFEDERATE DEAD.</p>
                <p>"The grief that circled his brow with a crown of thorns was also that which
                    wreathed them with the splendor of immortality." - <hi rend="underline"
                        >Castelar's "Savonarola."</hi></p>
                <p>I.</p>
                <p>Where are they who marched away,<lb/> Sped with smiles that changed to
                    tears,<lb/> Glittering lines of steel and gray<lb/> Moving down the battle's
                    way-<lb/> Where are they these many years?</p>
                <p>Garlands wreathed their shining swords;<lb/> They were girt about with
                    cheers,<lb/> Children's lispings, women's words,<lb/> Sunshine and the songs of
                    birds-<lb/> They are gone so many years.</p>
                <pb n="383"/>
                <p>"Lo! beyond their brave array<lb/> Freedom's august dawn appears:"<lb/> Thus we
                    said: "The brighter day<lb/> Breaks above that line of gray."-<lb/> Where are
                    they these many years?</p>
                <p>All our hearts went with them there,<lb/> All our love, and all our prayers;<lb/>
                    What of them? How do they fare,<lb/> They who went to do and dare,<lb/> And are
                    gone so many years?</p>
                <p>What of them who went away<lb/> Followed by our hopes and fears?<lb/> Braver
                    never marched than they,<lb/> Closer ranks to fiercer fray.-<lb/> Where are they
                    these many years?</p>
                <p>II.</p>
                <p>Borne upon the Spartan shield<lb/> Home returned that brave array<lb/> From the
                    blood-stained battle-field<lb/> They might neither win nor yield;<lb/> That is
                    all, and here are they.</p>
                <p>That is all, The soft sky bends<lb/><orig reg="Over">O'er</orig> them, lapped in
                    earth away;<lb/> Her benignest influence lends,<lb/> Dews and rains and radiance
                    sends<lb/> Down upon them, night and day.</p>
                <p>Over them the Springtide weaves<lb/> All the verdure of her May:<lb/> Past them
                    drift the <orig reg="somber">sombre</orig> leaves<lb/> When the heart of Autumn
                        grieves<lb/><orig reg="Over">O'er</orig> their slumbers.-What care they?</p>
                <p>What care they, who failed to win<lb/> Guerdon of that splendid day-<lb/>
                    Freedom's day-they saw begin,<lb/> But that, <orig reg="amid">'mid</orig> the
                    battle's din,<lb/> Faded in eclipse away?</p>
                <p>All is gone for them. They gave<lb/> All for naught. It was their way<lb/> Where
                    they loved. They died to save<lb/> What was lost. The fight was brave.<lb/> That
                    is all; and here are they.</p>
                <pb n="384"/>
                <p>III.</p>
                <p>Is that all? Was duty naught?<lb/> Love and Faith made blind with tears?<lb/>
                    What the lessons that they taught?<lb/> What the glory that they caught<lb/>
                    From the onward sweeping years?</p>
                <p>Here are they who marched away,<lb/> Followed by our hopes and fears;<lb/> Nobler
                    never went than they<lb/> To a bloodier, madder fray,<lb/> In the lapse of all
                    the years.</p>
                <p>Garlands still shall wreathe the swords<lb/> That they drew amid our cheers;<lb/>
                    Children's lispings, women's words,<lb/> Sunshine, and the songs of birds<lb/>
                    Greet them here through all the years.</p>
                <p>With them ever shall abide<lb/> All our love and all our prayers.<lb/> "What of
                    them?" The battle's tide<lb/> Hath not scathed them. Lo, they ride<lb/> Still
                    with Stuart down the years.</p>
                <p>Where are they who went away,<lb/> Sped with smiles that changed to tears?<lb/>
                    Lee yet leads the lines of gray-<lb/> Stonewall still rides down this way;<lb/>
                    They are Fame's through all the years.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
