<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0083"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0083">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "The Last Roll: Capt. Henry Clay
                    Carter; Charles James Faulkner [separate obituaries]," by Charles James
                    Faulkner, 1929</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county the last roll capt henry clay carter charles james faulkner separate obituaries, by charles james faulkner 1929</title>
        <author>Faulkner, Charles James</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 7 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0083</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498496</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "The Last Roll: <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr>
                            Henry Clay Carter; Charles James Faulkner [separate obituaries]," by
                            Charles James Faulkner, 1929</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county the last roll capt henry clay carter charles james faulkner separate obituaries, by charles james faulkner 1929</title>
            <author>Charles James Faulkner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 37, p.
                            144, 1929</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1929">1929</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Veterans, Patriotism, Death/Casualties</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-03-21">2006-03-21</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0083T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Two obituaries of Virginian Confederate veterans, praising their service and
                    celebrating their lives</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p><abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Henry Clay Carter.</p>
                <p>From resolutions passed by Stonewall Jackson Camp, <abbr
                        expan="United Confederate Veterans">U. C. V.</abbr>, of Staunton, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, in honor of Commander Henry Clay Carter, the
                    following is taken:</p>
                <p>Commander Henry C. Carter answered to the Divine call on Sunday, February 24, in
                    his eighty-fifth year. His illness was brief, and he had been blessed throughout
                    his long and useful life with excellent health, vigor of mind and body.</p>
                <p>In June, 1862, at the age of eighteen, Henry Carter enlisted for the Confederacy,
                    joining Imboden's Partisan Rangers, afterwards known as McClanahan's Battery,
                    and served with honor throughout the war to the surrender at Appomattox. He
                    participated with his command in the major engagements at Port Republic,
                    Piedmont, White Post, New Market, Fisher's Hill, Williamsport, Gettysburg, and
                    many less important engagements. His devotion to the cause of the Confederacy
                    was constantly manifested by undaunted courage, fidelity, love, and loyalty. He
                    cherished the memories of war days, and his greatest pleasure in late years was
                    in service to his comrades and in active, helpful participation in every
                    movement looking to their comfort and honor. He cherished the memories of the
                    war days, and his greatest pleasure in late years was in service to his comrades
                    and in active, helpful participation in every movement looking to their comfort
                    and honor. He cherished the memories of the war, the sacred sacrifices of its
                    turbulent days, the heroes it developed, the undying comradeship created. He was
                    faithful and constant in his attendance upon this Camp, upon every memorial
                    occasion of the community, and attended every reunion possible of his comrades,
                    both State and general, having been at Little Rock in 1928.</p>
                <p>Stonewall Jackson Camp delighted to honor Commander Carter in life, and in his
                    death pay tribute to his memory.</p>
                <p>Committee: J. L. Dunlap, J. N. Britton. J. R. Mohler, Lieutenant Commander; J.
                    Wellington Spitler, Adjutant.</p>
                <p>Charles James Faulkner.</p>
                <p>In the same room of the historic old home, Boydsville, in Martinsburg, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, where he was born on September 21, 1847, death
                    came to Charles James Faulkner, Virginia gentleman, scholar, and former United
                    States Senator, on January 13, 1929. He died in his eighty-second year.</p>
                <p>When the father of Charles Faulkner was appointed Minister to France, the son
                    accompanied him to Europe, attending schools in Paris and Switzerland until
                    their return to America in 1861, when, in his fifteenth year, Charles Faulkner
                    entered as a student the Virginia Military Institute at Lexington. During the
                    desperate fighting in 1864, the battalion of cadets was rushed into action and
                    rendered heroic service in the battle of New Market. After that there was no
                    more schooling for these boys, and from that time to the end, young Faulkner was
                    in active service, as an aide on the staff of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr>
                    John C. Breckinridge, and later on the staff of <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Henry A. Wise, with whom he surrendered.</p>
                <p>Returning home, he studied under the direction of his father until 1866, when he
                    entered the law department of the University of Virginia, from which he was
                    graduated in June, 1868, and admitted to the bar a few months later, being then
                    twenty-one years old. In 1887, his reputation established as one of the ablest
                    jurists of the country and a leading citizen, he was elected to the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Senate, and there served twelve years with
                    distinction, serving on many important committees. Many honors came to him in
                    the different activities of his life, both at home and abroad, and he was loved
                    and honored by those in all walks of life. He is survived by two sons and two
                    daughters.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
