<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0026"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0026">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "When <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee Lost Hope of Success," by A. S. Colyar, 1893</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county when gen lee lost hope of success, by a s colyar 1893</title>
        <author>Colyar, A. S.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8.2 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0026</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498458</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "When Gen. Lee Lost Hope of Success," by A. S.
                            Colyar, 1893</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county when gen lee lost hope of success, by a s colyar 1893</title>
            <author>A. S. Colyar</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 1,
                            1893, p. 324-325</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1893">1893</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, Reunification, Slavery, State Government, Military
                        Strategy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-03">2006-02-03</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0026T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This account from a member of the Confederate Congress describes the secret
                    committee to decide whether to continue the war in 1864. Lee's testimony was
                    that there was no point to further battles and that he could not defend Richmond
                    for long because of a lack of supplies. It also describes the process that led
                    to the appointment of the Southern commissioners who met with Lincoln at Hampton
                    Roads in 1865.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> Washington Gardner, of Michigan, who carried
                    a gun in battle for the Union, and was severely wounded at Resaca, <abbr
                        expan="Georgia">Ga.</abbr>, spent a few days in Nashville recently <hi
                        rend="underline">en route</hi> from Chickamauga, where he went as
                    commissioner to locate points in the battleground. Although a private in the
                    war, has been elevated to Department Commander of the Grand Army in Michigan.
                    Mr. Gardner is an able minister, an astute lawyer, and a thrilling lecturer.
                    While in Nashville his friend, <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> Fred Dunn,
                    invited him, <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> A. S. Colyar, and the editor of
                    the VETERAN, to Belle Meade, the magnificent farm of <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> W. H. Jackson. Mr. Colyar was a member of the Confederate Congress,
                    and is an active lawyer of ability. On the pleasant journey Mr. Gardner was
                    entertained by a story that is now being made of record. Mr. Colyar has written
                    about it as follows:</p>
                <p>S. A. Cunningham-Dear Sir: In answer to your request I give you what, in
                    substance, I related to you and Mr. Gardner the other day. The Hampton Roads
                    effort at settlement, in which Messrs. Hunter, Stephens, and Campbell acted as
                    commissioners, came about in the following manner: John B. Baldwin, of Virginia,
                    member of the House of Representatives, and who was a Colonel under <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee during the first year of the war, said to me
                    one night in December, 1864, that he was greatly depressed, as <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee had that day informed him that the cause for
                    which he was fighting had to fail-that he would be compelled to give up Richmond
                    and disband his army for the want of supplies. Mr. Baldwin said he hardly felt
                    that he had the courage to say what ought to be said in the House, as he knew
                    Mr. Davis and many members of the House still believed the war could be
                    prosecuted to a successful termination. Before we separated it was agreed that
                    he, Mr. Baldwin, should introduce into the House a resolution for the
                    appointment of a committee to inquire into our ability to carry on the war. This
                    Mr. Baldwin did the next day in secret session. The resolution was promptly
                    passed and the commit-<pb n="325"/>tee appointed. Mr. Baldwin, perhaps the
                    ablest man in the House, was made chairman. I, with several other members, was
                    put on the committee. The first thing the committee did was to take the
                    deposition of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee. Then the evidence of other
                    general officers was taken. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee said in his
                    evidence that he would be compelled to give up Richmond and disband his army for
                    the want of supplies, and in answer to a direct question put by the chairman, he
                    said he could devise no means of carrying on the war. The other general officers
                    sustained him.</p>
                <p>The taking of this proof lasted some time; I can not now remember how long, but
                    we were waiting on some witnesses. This evidence created in the committee a
                    profound impression. The feeling was that another battle ought not to be
                    fought-that the further shedding of blood was useless. The report made to the
                    House produced a discussion that was by no means free of acrimony. It was hoped
                    and believed that Mr. Davis would at once take some steps looking to a
                    settlement. This was not done, and after consulting <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Atkins and others, and after conferring with Mr. Stephens, who was
                    Vice-President, and getting his consent to act, I wrote the resolutions-which
                    Mr. Stephens himself rewrote and reformed-and afterward introduced them in
                    secret session, asking the President to appoint Stephens, Hunter, and Campbell
                    to confer with Mr. Lincoln on the subject of bringing the war to a close. While
                    the debate was progressing, and before a vote was taken, a member, Mr.
                    Barksdale, of Mississippi, intimated that the commission would be created if the
                    debate was stopped, and that no vote need be taken. Thereupon Mr. Davis
                    appointed Mr. Hunter, of Virginia, Mr. Campbell, of Louisiana, and Mr. Stephens.
                    But as Mr. Stephens informed me when he came back, and I think he substantially
                    states it in his book, the conditions of the authority forbade any settlement
                    except on the basis of independence.</p>
                <p>Mr. Stephens was of opinion when he returned that Mr. Lincoln was willing-the
                    Union being restored, slavery having already been abolished-that the war should
                    end, and all Federal troops be withdrawn from the Southern States, and leaving
                    the Southern State governments intact just as they were before the war. In other
                    words, trusting the Southern people to keep the agreement without force, or
                    coercion through territorial government. The specific instructions given the
                    commissioners were not known to Congress, certainly not to the House of
                    representatives, and when the commissioners returned and reported a failure a
                    great effort was made by public meetings to intensify the war feeling. One great
                    meeting was held in Richmond, where Mr. Benjamin was the principal speaker.</p>
                <p>Mr. Colyar does not report all of this conversation. Mr. Gardner asked him about
                    Mr. Davis, raising the question of his faith in final success, and he replied
                    that Mr. Davis evidently believed that Providence would eventually overrule for
                    the Confederacy, as was the result of Washington's struggle for American
                    independence.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
