<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0030"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0030">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "FAIR WOMEN AT THE CENTENNIAL," by
                    unknown, 1897</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county fair women at the centennial, by unknown 1897</title>
        <author>unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 6 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0030</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498462</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "FAIR WOMEN AT THE CENTENNIAL," by unknown, 1897</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county fair women at the centennial, by unknown 1897</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 5,
                            1897, p. 183</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1897">1897</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Education, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-12">2005-12-12</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0030T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Announcement of reunion for alumni of the Mary Baldwin Seminary in Nashville in
                    1897.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The "Old Dominion" will be represented by the fair women in the Colonial Dames,
                    the Daughters of the Revolution, and the Daughters of the Confederacy, and, too,
                    the <orig reg="Alumni">Alumnae</orig> Association of the Mary Baldwin Seminary.
                    It will hold its reunion with the Tennessee <orig reg="Alumni">Alumnae</orig>,
                    as queens of the occasion.</p>
                <p>The Augusta Female Seminary, in Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, was
                    chartered in 1842. Miss Baldwin assumed charge in 1863, and four thousand girls
                    have been blessed by her example and training. Great was the rejoicing when the
                    dear <hi rend="underline">alma mater</hi> was named the "Mary Baldwin
                    Seminary" in her honor. The officers of the Association are: President, Bettie
                    Guy (Mrs. Winston); Treasurer, Miss Janet K. Woods; Recording Secretary, Miss
                    Augusta Bumgardner; Corresponding Secretary, Nellie Hotchkiss (Mrs. S. T.
                    McCullough), all of Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> Each State has
                    one or more Vice Presidents. The Tennessee Vice Presidents are: Max Overton
                    (Mrs. J. M. Dickinson), of Nashville; Tempie Swoope (Mrs. George W. Darrow), of
                    Murfreesboro; Mrs. Reba Metcalf McNeil, of Mhiis; assisted by Clara May Erwin
                    (Mrs. Walter G. Coleman), Vice President at large. These ladies serve as
                    Chairmen of the Nashville Committee.</p>
                <p>On June 15 a special car will leave Washington, <abbr
                        expan="District of Columbia">D. C.</abbr>, over the Chesapeake and Ohio
                    railroad, collecting passengers alogn the route and passing the famed
                    battlefields of 1861-<abbr expan="1865">65</abbr>; Monticello and the University
                    of Virginia; Staunton, the well-known home of schools; the famous White Sulphur
                    Springs and other summer resorts, down through the beautiful New River Canyon,
                    and the rich Kenawa Meadow, the blue grass region of Kentucky, arriving at
                    Nashville June 16. The Cedar Room in the Women's Building will be headquarters
                    for all Seminary girls, but the reception of June 17 will be in the assembly
                    room of the Women's Building. There the further programme will be announced.
                    Every former pupil is asked to attend all the meetings to help make the reunion
                    a success. All who wish to take the special car will notify Mrs. Walter G.
                    Coleman at Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, before June 1. Special
                    rates have been given the party; while the day coach will have every comfort,
                    there is no extra charge for it, and a sleeper will be from $1.50 to $2 extra.
                    Those who expect to attend the reunion will please notify Mrs. J. M. Dickinson
                    at Nashville. The Maxwell House will be the central point, but private board at
                    reasonable rates can be secured in Nashville. There will be another meeting in
                    October. A special car will leave Norfolk over the Norfolk and Western railroad
                    on October 4, taking passengers at the junctions of Petersburg, Lynchburg,
                    Roanoke, Knoxville, and Chattanooga. The grand mountains and rich pastures of
                    Southwestern Virginia, Lookout Mountain, and Missionary Ridge will be enjoyed en
                    route.</p>
                <p>October 7 and 8 will again see the <orig reg="Alumni">Alumnae</orig> Association
                    in session in the Assembly Room. The social pleasures promise to be many, but
                    are such personal affairs that they will only be announced to those present at
                    the meetings.</p>
                <p>These lines carry a greeting to all old "Seminary girls," with the hope that
                    those who are not already members will write to Mrs. Walter G. Coleman, 346 East
                    Beverley Street, Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
