<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0025"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0025">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Harper's Ferry in 1861," by F. M.
                    Burrows, 1893</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county harpers ferry in 1861, by f m burrows 1893</title>
        <author>Burrows, F. M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 11.3 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0025</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498457</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Harper's Ferry in 1861," by F. M. Burrows, 1893</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county harpers ferry in 1861, by f m burrows 1893</title>
            <author>F. M. Burrows</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 1,
                            1893, p. 103-104</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1893">1893</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Battle Description, Camp Life, Church/Religious
                        Activity, Veterans, Troop Movement, Military Strategy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-02">2006-02-02</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0025T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This essay gives a first-hand account of the seizure of Harper's Ferry in 1861
                    and the subsequent several months stationed there.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>FIRST EVENTS OF THE WAR IN VIRGINIA AND MARYLAND.</p>
                <p>F. M. Burrows, Company B. Thirteenth Virginia Infantry, Fort Worth, Texas: From
                    time to time many articles have been published purporting to give a true history
                    of the early occupancy of Harper's Ferry in 1861, which have been incorrect. One
                    account is that "the first Southern soldiers at Harper's Ferry were about 1,600
                    Mississippians, who captured the place about the 15th of May." As a high private
                    in the Culpepper Minute Men, I left Culpepper, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr>, at 3 A.M., the 18th day of April, 1861, for Harper's Ferry.</p>
                <p>These commands of Virginians were sent there: West Augusta Guards, Staunton,
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, sixty men; Louisa Blues, Louisa
                    Court-house, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, seventy-five men; Montpelier
                    Guards, Orange Court-house, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, sixty men;
                    Gordonsville Greys, Orange County, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, fifty men;
                    Monticello Guards, <orig reg="Charlottesville">Charlottsville</orig>, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, sixty men; Brandy Rifles, Culpepper County,
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, forty men; Boomerangs, Winchester, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, forty men; Continental Guards, Charlestown,
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, forty men; Letcher Artillery, Culpepper,
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, thirty-five men; University of Virginia
                    Students, <orig reg="Charlottesville">Charlottsville</orig>, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, one hundred and twenty men; Culpepper Minute
                    Men, Culpepper, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, sixty men. Imboden's
                    Artillery, of four guns, and a full complement of men, followed us on the 18th.
                    The Lanier Guards, of Baltimore, came to us on the 23d, making in all about
                    seven hundred and fifty men, rank and file. We reached Manassas Junction about 8
                    A. M., took trains for Strausburg, arrived there about 1 P. M., got dinner,
                    which had been prepared by the good ladies, then took up our line of march for
                    Winchester, about eighteen miles distant, arrived in time for a late super,
                    which the good ladies there had literally spread all over town. We boarded a
                    train of box cars at 11 P. M. for Harper's Ferry, via Charleston; arrived at the
                    Ferry just before daybreak on the 19th. Nearly all of us had guns of some kind,
                    except the Letcher Artillery, a company of boys. They were empty-handed, and
                    when the first long roll was sounded it was amusing to see them hurry to their
                    quarters and fortify themselves with sticks and stones. <abbr expan="Major"
                    >Maj.</abbr> George A. Wheatley, now a merchant in Austin, Texas, was Captain,
                    and a very young brother of the writer was First Lieutenant.</p>
                <p>It will be clearly seen that there were none but Virginians at Harper's Ferry for
                    three weeks or more, save the Baltimoreans and <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr>
                    Duncan's Kentuckians, about three hundred strong. The command was a fine one.
                    The Kentuckians were generally men of wealth and refinement, and they were well
                    prepared to care for themselves financially, having their repeating rifles,
                    cow-horn powder flasks, and bullet moulds. The <abbr expan="Honorable"
                    >Hon.</abbr> R. E. Beckham, now District Judge at Fort Worth, was one of the
                    boys from Kentucky who wore the fur cap and long green blouse.</p>
                <p>The first soldiers were ordered out by a telegram from <abbr expan="Governor"
                        >Gov.</abbr> Letcher, direct to the various Captains of the State Militia,
                    dated Richmond, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, April 17. An extra session of
                    the Legislature passed the ordinance of secession at 2 A. M. on the 17th. When
                    the news reached <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Barbour that the troops were
                    marching on Harper's Ferry, he, being in command of the Government's works,
                    abandoned his post and had the buildings fired. The destruction would have been
                    complete but for the timely efforts of the citizens, including workmen in the
                    shops, who, with their small hand engine and a large stationary one belonging to
                    the Government, subdued the flames. It was the little house for this hand engine
                    that John Brown used as a fort in 1859. We reached Harper's Ferry about daylight
                    on the 19th. Our train stopped on a high trestle on the Shenandoah river side.
                    While we were waiting for orders to leave the train some one put twenty or more
                    kegs of powder under the trestle, set a match to the fuse, and ran. One of our
                    men, seeing what had been done, jumped from the train and severed the fuse.
                    Finally we landed in good shape, and made a descent upon the town, not knowing
                    what we would encounter, without one round of ammunition. We took up our
                    quarters in the buildings that remained intact, and in the churches and
                    school-houses. For the first week the citizens were very shy of us, but soon
                    became communicative and delivered to us many hundreds of <orig reg="mini"
                    >minie</orig> rifles and muskets, and innumerable parts of guns. We found many
                    guns hidden away under floors and between and under mattresses. The machinery,
                    unhurt by the fire, was speedily put in motion, and many of the old <orig
                        reg="employees">employes</orig> were set at work and furnished all the
                    commands with the latest and most approved guns.</p>
                <p>The first officer in command was <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Nalle. Then
                    came <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr><abbr expan="Joseph">Jos.</abbr> E.
                    Johnston, who succeeded him, and who appointed Stonewall Jackson a Colonel. Each
                    of them occupied the mansion on the hill belonging to <abbr expan="Major"
                    >Maj.</abbr> D. B. Lucas, <abbr expan="United States Army">U. S. A.</abbr> Next
                    came <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> A. P. Hill, of the regular army, who had
                    recently resigned and was made Colonel of the Thirteenth Virginia Infantry.</p>
                <p>Our company was quartered in the paint shop, and it was the writer's luck to be
                    detailed with the <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> John W. Bell, a prominent
                    lawyer of Culpepper, to police and ditch our camp. It was rich indeed to see our
                    near-sighted lawyer handle a spade and hear his comments, such as, "This is a
                    nice business for a lawyer in good standing, a gentleman, and a member of St.
                    Stephen's Church vestry, to be put to ditching the first Sunday in camp!" He is
                    now Judge Bell, a brother of <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> P. Hansborough
                    Bell, who was a native of Virginia, who landed at Velasco, Texas, in 1836, * * *
                    * and was made Governor of Texas in 1850. He subsequently served in Congress,
                    then married, and settled in North Carolina. As a recognition of his patriotic
                    services, and as an aid to him in his old age, the Twenty-second Texas
                    Legislature, in 1891, voted him a donation of land and a liberal pension.</p>
                <p>We remained at Harper's Ferry until about the middle of May, when we were called
                    to arms and made a forced march to Shepherdstown. We were caught in a terrific
                    hail storm in an open field, no possible place for shelter, and it was a
                    question with us whether we would survive the storm or not.</p>
                <p>The Lanier Guards, of Baltimore, deserve special mention. George Lanier, of
                    Lanier <abbr expan="Brothers">Bros.</abbr>, wholesale dry goods merchants in
                    Baltimore, equipped and sent off this company to join us at Harper's Ferry.
                    Times were exciting there then. This scheme was adopted to get out of the city
                    in a body: A funeral procession was planned. Loading a coffin with guns, and
                    making preparations for a decent burial, they took carriages and followed the
                    hearse to London Park Cemetery, a few miles west on the Catonsville road. When a
                    safe distance from the city the coffin was opened, and quickly each man was
                    armed and on his way to <pb n="104"/>join the young Confederacy. Many of the
                    Lanier Guards were engaged in the attack on Federal soldiers when they made that
                    memorable march up Pratt street in Baltimore.</p>
                <p>About June 27 we were ordered from Harper's Ferry to Winchester, thence on a
                    march to Romney, and thence to New Creek Station, on the Baltimore &amp;
                    Ohio Railroad, where we first <orig reg="smelled">smelt</orig> gun powder. A
                    small force of Federals held the bridge crossing the north fork of the Potomac
                    river near the station. We surprised them, captured a swivel and a stand of
                    colors, charged the enemy, ran them off, and burned the bridge. A few of us
                    crossed the bridge, followed the retreating enemy a short distance, and upon
                    returning found the bridge on fire, and we on the wrong side of the river. Our
                    only alternative was to wade through a swift, clear, rapid stream fully five
                    feet deep.</p>
                <p>After the battles of Bull Run and Manassas it was the writer's privilege to stand
                    picket at the farm-house of a good old Mrs. Taylor, a few miles east of Fairfax
                    Station. It was there I learned the true meaning of the word Manassas, and how
                    it originated. A faithful old negro man belonging to Mrs. Taylor met a
                    neighboring brother, and addressed him about as follows: "Uncle Willis, kin yer
                    tell me how dey got dis name Manassas fur dis place down dar whar dey has all
                    dem big guns?" "I dunno, Brer Ephriam, cep'ing tis we is de man, and dem Yankees
                    whar cum down here is de asses; dats how we gets de name Manasses, I speck."</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
