<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0084"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0084">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Valiance of Capt. Charles Morgan,"
                    by R. D. Firebaugh, April 1909</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county valiance of capt charles morgan, by r d firebaugh april 1909</title>
        <author>Firebaugh, R. D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 6 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0084</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498497</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Valiance of Capt. Charles Morgan," by R. D.
                            Firebaugh, April 1909</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county valiance of capt charles morgan, by r d firebaugh april 1909</title>
            <author>R. D. Firebaugh</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran 17:4 (April
                            1909), p.163</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1909-04">1909-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Military Authority, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-09-14">2005-09-14</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0084T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>An article written in the wake of Capt. Charles F. Morgan's death, recounting
                    Morgan's bravery during the Civil War.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The recent death of my old friend, <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Charles F.
                    Morgan, who was the brigade inspector for General Imboden's command, reminds me
                    of an incident to which I was an eyewitness and which I feel should be recorded.</p>
                <p>Captain Morgan was the son of Colonel Morgan, Superintendent of the Virginia
                    Penitentiary at Richmond before the war. Captain Morgan was a gallant soldier of
                    the Confederacy, and was never happier than when in a charge. When the surrender
                    at Appomattox took place, Imboden's Brigade, hearing the news, disbanded near
                    Lynchburg. I was detailed in charge of broken-down horses near Middlebrook,
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, with two comrades, who were absent from
                    their horses the day of the occurrence to which I refer, April 17.</p>
                <p>Gilmer's Battalion, an independent organization of Confederates, was retreating
                    south through the Valley of Virginia, believing they might be handled roughly by
                    the Federals, who regarded them as bushwhackers. These men, numbering some
                    sixty-five to eighty, were mounted, some without saddles, some even without
                    bridles, and some on foot. They picked up every available horse with a <abbr
                        expan="Confederate States">C. S.</abbr> or <abbr expan="United States">U.
                    S.</abbr> brand, and took horses belonging to private individuals. I decided to
                    follow them in the hope that I might persuade them to relinquish the horses
                    belonging to private soldiers. When I overtook them, I told the leader that I
                    took him to be a gentleman and stated my business, explaining that they had the
                    private property of my comrades. He replied that if I would follow them until
                    they got better mounted I might have the horses. I agreed to this, and rode
                    along with them until in sight of Brownsburg, when we met <abbr expan="Captain"
                        >Capt.</abbr> Charley Holt, of the <abbr expan="62nd">62d</abbr> Virginia
                    Regiment. I told him my trouble, and he instructed me to pass ahead of them into
                    the village, where I would find Captain Morgan at a certain house; that he
                    (Captain Holt) would stay with these men and see that they did not flank the
                    village. I found Captain Morgan as instructed and stated the case to him. He
                    inquired if I was armed, and to my reply that I thought it best to go unarmed he
                    stepped back into the house and armed himself. By this time the men were coming
                    up the street, and Captain Morgan, cocking both his pistols, halted them and
                    demanded the horses, saddles, bridles, telling them he would die right there if
                    they did not give them up without any parleying, that these horses belonged to
                    his men. They obeyed him at once, complaining as a pretext that the house at
                    which they got the horses had a Union flag displayed.</p>
                <p>I do not claim any credit for this piece of bravery, as I was unarmed. It was
                    simply the determination of Captain Morgan that secured the result. They knew if
                    they attempted to pass him he would get two or three of them before they could
                    fire on him. Gilmer's men were not cowards; they did very valuable service for
                    the Confederacy. This shows what grit and determination sometimes accomplished.
                    I was a member of Company I, <abbr expan="62nd">62d</abbr> Virginia Mounted
                    Infantry, Imboden's Brigade.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
