<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0034"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0034">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "THE STONEWALL BRIGADE BAND," by J.
                    A. Hiner, Staunton, Va., 1900</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county the stonewall brigade band, by j a hiner staunton va 1900</title>
        <author>Hiner, J. A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0034</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498466</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "THE STONEWALL BRIGADE BAND," by J. A. Hiner,
                            Staunton, Va., 1900</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county the stonewall brigade band, by j a hiner staunton va 1900</title>
            <author>J. A. Hiner, Staunton, Va.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 8,
                            1900, p. 304</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1900">1900</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Medicine/Hospitals, Patriotism, Reunification, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-12">2005-12-12</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0034T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>A short history of the Stone wall Brigade Band from its pre-war origins to its
                    postwar fame.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The last meeting of the United Confederate Veterans surpassed all previous
                    meetings in many respects, notwithstanding the almost incessant rainfall.</p>
                <p>The most noteworthy and historic attraction of the great reunion at Louisville
                    was the famous Stonewall Brigade Band, of Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr>, which is comprised of thirty-eight handsome, athletic men. While
                    there are but six of the original veteran members in active service, the others
                    are all sons of veterans. It is not only the high degree of musical genius that
                    makes this band celebrated, but the magic of its name, together with the glory
                    which it has won from its organization down to the present day. This historic
                    association was organized in 1855, under the name of the "Mountain Saxhorn
                    Band," which name it retained until the commencement of the war between the
                    States, at which time it was mustered in as the Fifth Virginia Regiment Band.</p>
                <p>At the first engagement the Stonewall Brigade had with the enemy the band
                    organized itself into a surgeon corps, and so faithfully and intelligently
                    performed field and hospital duties that officers and men recognized the value
                    of its services. In all subsequent battles the band's devoted ministrations were
                    in requisition, and always promptly and faithfully rendered, which won for it
                    the proud name of Stonewall Brigade Band, by an order of the immortal Christian
                    soldier, Stonewall, read on dress parade at Camp Winder.</p>
                <p>At Appomattox <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Grant issued an order to allow
                    the members of the band to take their instruments home with them, which are now
                    on exhibition in their band hall. These instruments are probably the only
                    complete set in existence that were used during the entire civil war, and have
                    attracted much attention in Northern cities. They were exhibited by the band
                    during their engagement at the World's Columbian Exhibition, in Chicago, and at
                    the Louisville Reunion.</p>
                <p>The band occupied a post of honor at the funeral of <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Grant, in New York, and has attended nearly all the famous military
                    and civic demonstrations in this country, being the only amateur band recognized
                    by the authorities of the World's Columbian Exhibition.</p>
                <p>This band was not only the pride of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Jackson's
                    Brigade, but each member was the personal friend of the General, and he
                    earnestly desired its perpetuation. Only a few days before his death he
                    expressed the wish that the Stonewall Brigade Band would continue to live
                    through the succeeding generations of Confederate soldiers and their sons. Soon
                    after his death the members of the band had a conference and decided that their
                    great general's wishes shoudl be held sacred, and that the Stonewall Brigade
                    Band should live.</p>
                <p>This noteworthy company of musicians elicit the highest praises and encomiums
                    wherever they go, and the rendition of national airs and Southern meoldies has
                    won for them a world-wide fame as a patriotic band.</p>
                <p>It was indeed a pathetic and touching scene to look upon the old veterans,
                    ex-Federals as well as ex-Confederates, who crowded about the Stonewall Brigade
                    Band to hear the soulful music of this grand organizations as they discoursed
                    the patriotic melodies at the memorial exercises at Cave Hill Cemetery,
                    Louisville. In the eyes of many of these old veterans could be seen silent
                    tears, because the impressive ceremonies brought back to them memories of
                    friends who are no more.</p>
                <p>The veterans were so delighted with the Stonewall Brigade Band that they said:
                    "Surely we can never have another reunion without it."</p>
                <p>The personnel of this band is above the average of musical aggregations. Their
                    genteel deportment and manly bearing is so exemplified on all occasions that
                    they are given ovations wherever they visit. The members of the band so
                    ingratiated themselves into the good graces of the Louisville people that they
                    were taken to the homes of some of the wealthiest citizens and banqueted in the
                    most lavish style, and steps have already been taken by the management of the
                    triennial conclave of the Knights Templars of 1901 to have Stonewall Brigade
                    Band participate in the festivities of that notable gathering.</p>
                <p>In this renowned musical organization the South feels pride. This band is proud
                    of its locality, the beautiful Shenandoah Valley of old Virginia. That valley
                    was trampled and defaced by the warring hosts who met there in mortal combat,
                    yet after the surrender the members of the Stonewall Brigade Band returned to
                    their desolated homes and took up the thread of life once more under the most
                    adverse circumstances. Such men as have been members of this band are the true
                    lifeblood of the country to which they belong. They elevate and uphold it,
                    fortify and enable it, and shed a glory over it by the lives and characters
                    which they bequeath.</p>
                <p>This famous band will be thoroughly at home to the Grand Camp of Virginia
                    Veterans, which will convene at Staunton October 10, 1900.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
