<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0071"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0071">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "The Record Junior Chapter," by
                    Unknown, 1914</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county the record junior chapter, by unknown 1914</title>
        <author>Unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 5.5 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0071</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498484</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "The Record Junior Chapter," by Unknown, 1914</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county the record junior chapter, by unknown 1914</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 22, p.
                            300, 1914</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-03-21">2006-03-21</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0071T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Blurb about the new "junior" members of the SCV and UDC</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The Staunton Juniors, Sons of Confederate Veterans and Daughters of the
                    Confederacy (auxiliary to the J.E.B. Stuart Chapter, Staunton, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>), was organized April 4, 1914, by Mrs. J.F.F.
                    Cassell, ex-President of the J.E.B. Stuart Chapter. She is a daughter of Jacob
                    H. Plecker, who served in Company F, 62d Virginia Regiment, and rendered gallant
                    service in the battle of New Market, May 15, 1864. The fiftieth anniversary of
                    this battle has just been celebrated by a semicentennial celebration at New
                    Market, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <pb n="301"/>
                <p>This Chapter of juniors is the largest ever organized. Letters have come to Mrs.
                    Cassell from every State where Confederate Chapters exist asking particulars of
                    her record-breaking campaign to secure this unprecedented number. Love for the
                    Confederate cause and the empty sleeve first prompted her to try to leave
                    something permanent and lasting in the hearts of the young people when we have
                    ceased from our labors. So she made a personal, systematic canvass of the town
                    and county. It took seven weeks, not only working during the day, but using the
                    telephone in the evening for the country children. Three hundred and twenty-six
                    names appeared on the roll for the first meeting. To give all a fair chance to
                    become charter members, it was decided that those who entered their names by the
                    next monthly meeting should be considered charter members, and in this way the
                    membership quickly ran up to five hundred. A great many are descendants of
                    Augusta County veterans, now residents of other States. The youngest member
                    enrolled was two days' old; the oldest member, eighteen years.</p>
                <p>The enthusiasm and patriotism of these boys and girls are wonderful. They already
                    have their own Chapter badge designed especially for them, and they are
                    arranging for Flag Day and several other means of raising money for the needy
                    Confederate veterans in the near future.</p>
                <p>Mrs. Cassell has been ably assisted by Mrs. E. H. Surber, a daughter of <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> William H. Harman, of the 5th Virginia Infantry,
                    who has the music in charge and trained the children for Memorial Day.</p>
                <p>In the group of officers are many grandchildren of prominent generals who
                    rendered valuable service in the War between the States.</p>
                <p>The officers are: Director, Mrs. Julius Frederick Ferdinand Cassell; President,
                    Miss Constance Dana Curry; Vice Presidents, Miss Harriet Young Echols, Miss
                    Virginia Henry Holt, Miss Elinor Schell Surber, Miss Merrill Cushing Yost;
                    Recording Secretary, Miss Margaret Lynn Templeton; Corresponding Secretary, Miss
                    Ida May Digges; Treasurer, James Lilley Templeton, Jr.; Registrar, Miss Carrie
                    Sublett; Historian, Miss Annestine Crawford; Custodian, Winniett Peters
                Harman.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
