<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0005"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0005">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Tenth Annual Reunion of the Virginia
                    Division Army Northern Virginia Association. Address of Major H. B. McClellan,
                    of Lexington, Ky., on the Life, Campaigns, and Character of Gen'l J. E. B.
                    Stuart.," by Major H. B. McClellan, October 27, 1880</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county tenth annual reunion of the virginia division army northern virginia association address of major h b mcclellan, of lexington ky on the life campaigns and character of genl j e b stuart by major h b mcclellan october 27 1880</title>
        <author>Lee, General W. H. F. and McClellan, Major H. B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes">10.8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0005</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498437</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Tenth Annual Reunion of the Virginia Division Army
                            Northern Virginia Association. Address of Major H. B. McClellan, of
                            Lexington, Ky., on the Life, Campaigns, and Character of Gen'l J. E. B.
                            Stuart.," by Major H. B. McClellan, October 27, 1880</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county tenth annual reunion of the virginia division army northern virginia association address of major h b mcclellan, of lexington ky on the life campaigns and character of genl j e b stuart by major h b mcclellan october 27 1880</title>
            <author>General W. H. F. Lee and Major H. B. McClellan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: SHSP, Vol. VIII, p. 433-436,
                        1881</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1880-10-27">1880-10-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Family, Patriotism, Reunification,
                        Veterans, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-12">2005-12-12</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0005T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>The journal provides an introduction for and a transcription of Major H. B.
                    McClellan's speech about General J. E. B. Stuart. General W. H. F. Lee preceded
                    McClellan with introductory remarks about the spirit of the soldiers of the
                    Civil War, who had fought nobly for their "country" (he does not specify which
                    country). Ideas of reconciliation are evident in Lee's tone. McClellan's speech
                    praised Virginia, J. E. B. Stuart, and Stuart's family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>On Wednesday evening, October 27th, 1880, a large crowd packed the Hall of the
                    House of Delegates to its utmost capacity.</p>
                <p>At the appointed hour the orator of the evening, Major H. B. McClellan was
                    escorted into the hall by the president of the Association (General W. H. F.
                    Lee) and members of the Executive Committee, and was received with loud
                    applause.</p>
                <p>General Lee called the meeting to order, and <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr>
                    Dr. J. William Jones opened with prayer.</p>
                <p>General Lee said that he esteemed it a pleasure and an honor to extend to the
                    audience a cordial welcome to this tenth annual reunion of the Virginia Division
                    of the Army of Northern Virginia. He concluded from the brilliant audience
                    before him that the people still cherished the memory of the brave men who
                    during the four years of the unequal contest bore themselves nobly, and proved
                    themselves worthy of the land that gave them birth and the cause for which they
                    fought.</p>
                <pb n="434"/>
                <p>He said that the Association had hitherto been very fortunate in its annual
                    orators, and that he felt sure they were peculiarly fortunate on the present
                    occasion. He had the honor of presenting as the orator of the evening a
                    gentleman distinguished alike in war and in letters. He was fortunate, also, in
                    the selection of his theme, since he was to speak of the life and character of
                    the great cavalry chief on whose staff he had personally served, and with whom
                    he had witnessed and participated in the great battles of the Army of Northern
                    Virginia.</p>
                <p>It gave him great pleasure to be able to introduce as orator of the evening,
                    MAJOR H. B. MCCLELLAN, late <abbr expan="Assistant Adjutant General">A. A.
                    G.</abbr> of the Cavalry Corps <abbr expan="Army of Northern Virginia">A. N.
                    V.</abbr>, now president of Sayre Female College, Lexington Kentucky.</p>
                <p>Major McClellan was greeted with loud applause, which was frequently repeated as
                    he proceeded to deliver in graceful style the following<lb/> ADDRESS.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Mr. President, Comrades,</hi>,<lb/><hi
                        rend="underline">Ladies and Gentlemen:</hi></p>
                <p>I am honored in being permitted again to stand upon the soil of Old Virginia. My
                    spirit has been stirred to its depths as I have received the greetings of
                    comrades with whom I have stood side by side in the day of battle; and, as I
                    look into your faces, I can but wish that I were worthy to present my subject.
                    Bear with me while I attempt to speak to you of one whom even Virginia may be
                    proud to enroll among her noblest heroes..</p>
                <p>James Ewell Brown Stuart was born in Patrick county, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr>, on the 6th day of February, 1833. He died in Richmond, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, on the 12th of May, 1864, of a wound received
                    the day previous at the Yellow Tavern. His age at his death was 31 years 3
                    months and 6 days.</p>
                <p>Through five generations his ancestry is traced back to Archibald Stuart, <abbr
                        expan="Senior">Sr.</abbr>, a native of Londonderry, Ireland, but of Scotch
                    Presbyterian parentage, who, early in the eighteenth century, was compelled by
                    religious persecution to seek refuge in Western Pennsylvania. Here he remained
                    in seclusion for nearly seven years before his family could venture to join him.
                    Removing to Augusta county, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, about 1738,
                    Archibald Stuart, <abbr expan="Senior">Sr.</abbr>, acquired large landed
                    estates, which he divided between his four children.</p>
                <p>His second son, and third child, Major Alexander Stuart, was, early in the
                    Revolutionary War, commissioned major of the regiment commanded by Colonel
                    Samuel McDowell; and, during Colonel McDowell's <pb n="435"/> illness, commanded
                    the regiment at the battle of Guilford Court-house. Two horses were killed under
                    him in this action, and he himself, dangerously wounded, was left upon the
                    field, and was captured by the enemy. He was subsequently exchanged, and his
                    sword was returned to him. This valued relic is now in the possession of his
                    grandson, the <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> Alexander H. H. Stuart, of
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p>Judge Alexander Stuart, the youngest son of Major Alexander Stuart, was a lawyer
                    by profession, and resided at various times in Virginia, in Illinois, and in
                    Missouri. He held many honorable and responsible offices in each of these
                    states. He died and was buried in Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                    His eldest son, the <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> Archibald Stuart, of
                    Patrick, the father of our general, was an officer in the war of 1812. He
                    embraced the profession of law, and throughout his long and eventful life was
                    actively engaged in the practice of his profession, and in political life. He
                    represented first the county of Campbell, in the Virginia legislature, and was
                    afterwards repeatedly elected from Patrick county to the same body. He was a
                    member of the famous Convention of 1829-30, and of the Convention of 1850, in
                    which he was actively associated with the <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr>
                    Henry A. Wise. He represented the Patrick District in the Federal Congress
                    during the <hi rend="underline">Nullification</hi> period, and was a strong
                    supporter of Mr. Calhoun in that crisis. Concerning his personal character I
                    quote the words of another:</p>
                <p>"Archibald Stuart was known far and wide, both for his splendid talents and his
                    wonderful versatility. A powerful orator and advocate, he charmed the multitude
                    on the hustings, and convinced juries and courts. In addition to these gifts, he
                    was one of the most charming social companions the state ever produced.
                    Possessing wonderful wit and humor, combined with rare gift for song, he at once
                    became the center of attraction at every social gathering. Among the people of
                    the counties where he practiced, his name is held in great respect, and his
                    memory is cherished with an affection rarely <orig reg="equalled">equaled</orig>
                    in the history of any public man."</p>
                <p>It is not wonderful that such an ancestry should have produced the hero whom
                        <orig reg="tonight">to-night</orig> we honor. Rightfully did he inherit the
                    stern devotion to duty and principle which caused Archibald Stuart to seek
                    refuge in the wilds of Pennsylvania, rather than endure tyranny and oppression
                    in his native land. Rightfully did he inherit the constancy and gallantry of the
                    major who led his regiment at Guilford Courthouse, and who yielded his sword
                    only when disabled by wounds and deserted by his men. Rightfully did he inherit
                    that joyous temperament which made his father the delight of the social circle,
                    and that <pb n="436"/> magnetic power by which he could impress himself upon,
                    and control other men.</p>
                <p>To Archibald Stuart, of Patrick, and his wife, Elizabeth Letcher Pannill, of
                    Pittsylvania, was born a family of four sons and six daughters. Among these our
                    general was the seventh child and youngest son. Of his brothers, William
                    Alexander Stuart, of Russell county, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, alone
                    survives.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
