<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0098"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0098">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Memorial Day!," by Local Department,
                    June 15, 1887</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county memorial day , by local department june 15 1887</title>
        <author>Local Department</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Doug</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 45 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0098</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498510</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: "Memorial Day!," by Local Department, Wednesday, June 15,
                            1887</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta memorial day , by local department wednesday june 15 1887</title>
            <author>Local Department</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Staunton Spectator, June 15,
                        1887</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1887-06-15">1887-06-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Patriotism, Reunification, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-12">2005-12-12</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0098T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This is an enthusiastic, celebratory, and detailed report of the Memorial
                    festivities, filled with praise for veterans and tribute to the old Confederacy,
                    while at the same time pointing toward the need for sectional reconciliation.
                    The article prints several of the speeches that were delivered at the Memorial
                    Day celebration, and these echo the sentiments of the article itself.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">THE BLUE AND THE GRAY!</hi>
                </p>
                <p>NATIONAL AND CONFEDERATE FLAGS BLENDED IN TOKEN OF PEACE AND FRIENDSHIP.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">The Observance Demonstrates Sentiments of Mutual Esteem and
                        Perpetual Union.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">THE GRAND CELEBRATION.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>ALL BUSINESS SUSPENDED-THE STREETS AND BUILDINGS BEDECKED WITH FLAGS AND BANNERS.</p>
                <p>DECORATIONS AT THE CEMETARY</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">THE ORGANIZATIONS IN COLUMN.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>TEN THOUSAND PEOPLE PRESENT.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Governor LEE and General Averill,</hi><lb/> OPPONENTS IN
                    WAR-IN PEACE, FRIENDS.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">General IMBODEN, of Virginia, and <abbr expan="Honorable"
                        >Hon.</abbr> A.J. McCALL, of New York,</hi> --AND- [bold]CARLTON McCARTHY,
                    of Richmond, ADDRESS THE AUDIENCE AT THE OPERA HOUSE</p>
                <p>The coming of the ninth of June as it annually approaches is a time which revives
                    memories endeared and hallowed. It is the day which the Augusta Memorial
                    Association, since its organization, has set apart to commemorate the services,
                    and to honor the memory, and to strew garlands upon the graves of Confederate
                    soldiers who sleep in death. The Confederate grounds in Thornrose Cemetery, and
                    the spacious acres of that home of the dead, never were in lovelier attire than
                    they were on Memorial Day. To secure a result so desirable, the committees of
                    the Cemetery Company and of the memorial section and private owners of squares
                    were carefully engaged in seeing to it, and according to the order of
                    arrangements flowers were placed upon the graves in the early part of the day.</p>
                <p>PREPARING FOR THE EVENT.</p>
                <p>The President of the Association, Captain G. Julian Pratt, in council with his
                    co-laborers, secured the active assistance of the Stonewall Brigade Band, and
                    the ladies of the city and county, who formed themselves into an Auxiliary
                    Committee for the purpose, and for several weeks, by day and by night, they
                    labored unceasingly for the result which was attained-to so replenish the
                    treasury of the Association that the Monument Committee might see its way clear
                    to erect the monument the succeeding year. By the first and second renditions of
                    "Paradise and the Peri," and by the bountiful dinner on Memorial Day which was
                    so much enjoyed by the people, they have placed at the service of the Committee
                    a sum approximating $650 and for their devotion to the sacred purpose, they have
                    received the profound acknowledgement of the Memorial Association and the entire
                    community, and their fame has gone abroad as it is recited by the hundreds of
                    visitors who vied with each other in rewarding them for their efforts.</p>
                <p>The Stonewall Brigade Band, through its splendid discipline and business methods,
                    took charge of the feature which was to secure the military, the bands, the Odd
                    Fellows, the Fire Companies and other organizations, and the number of the
                    various bodies in the column attest the efficiency with which the Band, which
                    reflects so much of the martial spirit of the city, performed its duty. At their
                    music quarters, where refreshments were bountifully served, was an open
                    reception to the various bodies they had invited. The Odd Fellows also provided
                    for their brethren with a generous hospitality.</p>
                <p>THE GUESTS.</p>
                <p>General and Mrs. Averill, with Mr. and Mrs. McCall, of New York, their friends,
                    arrived by the Baltimore and Ohio train Wednesday afternoon. The General and his
                    party were received by Captain Pratt and his Committee, and by Mr. Ro. W. Burke,
                    his host, to whose residence he and his wife were conveyed. Mr. and Mrs. McCall
                    were the guests of G. G. Gooch, <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq.</abbr> General Jno.
                    D. Imboden, now of Bristol, <abbr expan="Tennessee">Tenn.</abbr>, and Mr.
                    Carlton McCarthy, of Richmond, arrived by the evening train on the Chesapeake
                    and Ohio line. The latter at once repaired to the residence of Major Nelson H.
                    Hotchkiss, his sister, Mrs. Hotchkiss, and other friends, being in waiting for
                    him. Captain Long and <abbr expan="Lieutenants">Lieuts.</abbr> O'Rork and
                    Kinney, of the Staunton Artillery, took charge of General Imboden, and with
                    Judge McCue, the host of the General, drove down to the Valley depot to unite in
                    the reception of General Averill.-Our citizens generally, and several visitors
                    in the city at the time, immediately called upon General Averill and the other
                    guests who had arrived.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> Carter Berkeley went with a special carriage over
                    to Waynesboro' Wednesday night to bring Governor Lee who was expected by the
                    morning train, Thursday, on the <abbr expan="Shenandoah Valley Railroad">S. V.
                        R. R.</abbr> from the South, but owing to failure of connection, he came
                        <hi rend="underline">via</hi> Lynchburg and Charlottesville and reached
                    here about 9 o'clock on the extra which also brought hundreds of visitors. The
                    Governor was taken immediately by his host, M. Erskine Miller, <abbr
                        expan="Esquire">Esq.</abbr>, to his residence where General Averill and
                    other gentlemen met him. The Stonewall Brigade was in place to honor him as they
                    did the arrival of General Averill the evening before.</p>
                <p>THE COLUMN FORMED.</p>
                <p>At ten o'clock a detachment of the Artillery stationed on Sears' hill opened the
                    military feature of the day with a national salute. Mr. J. A. Patterson, the
                    Chief Marshal, with his aids, commenced the formation of the column. In a
                    carriage drawn by four black horses were Governor Lee and General Averill,
                    escorted by <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Pratt, President of the
                    Association, <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> Ed. Echols and <abbr
                        expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> Carter Berkeley. General Imboden, Mr. McCarthy,
                    Mr. McCall and <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr><abbr expan="Doctor">Dr</abbr>.
                    Nelson, the Chaplain, were in other carriages, attended by escorts.</p>
                <p>In the column were the Stonewall Brigade-, the Harrisonburg-, the Laurel Hill-,
                    Augusta Cornet-, Mt. Sidney-, and the Colored Band of Staunton. The military
                    companies were the Harrisonburg Guards, Captain O. B.Roller; the Staunton
                    Artillery, <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> J. T. Long; and the Staunton
                    Colored Infantry, <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Smith.- The three Staunton
                    Fire Companies-the Hook and Ladder, with their carriage and implements, and the
                    other with their Hose Reels, all handsomely ornamented with flowers and
                    flags-presented a really attractive appearance, as did the Catholic Hibernian
                    and Beneficial Society, and the Staunton, Lexington, Harrisonburg, and Clifton
                    Forge Odd Fellows, all in their glittering regalia. The Harrisonburg Band wore
                    ripe green uniform, and black hats with red plumes. The Stonewall was in Summer
                    uniform of the regulation coat, white pants and white helmets. Citizens on
                    horseback and in carriages were promptly placed in the column, and when it moved
                    with the honored guests, the principal point of attraction, reverberating
                    artillery and the long line of more than a mile with the joyous shouts of
                    thousands of gladdened hearts, the scene was undescribably grand.</p>
                <p>THE MARCH.</p>
                <p>At the word of command "forward" by the Chief Marshal, the direct movement was
                    taken up. The Cemetery was reached, and through its winding avenues and around
                    the broad squares where our Confederate heroes sleep, silent and solemn honors
                    were paid their memories which are held in tender affection as fadeless as the
                    evergreens that cast their shadows over their graves. Returning to the city the
                    ceremonies continued.</p>
                <p>AT THE OPERA-HOUSE.</p>
                <p>The organizations in the procession were assigned to seats, which were filled by
                    the throng of ladies and gentlemen. Mrs. Averill was in the box on the left
                    attended by ladies and gentlemen. Upon the stage, a large company were seated,
                    and soon the guests came in, General Averill and Governor Lee, side by side. As
                    they came upon the stage, the cheering was prolonged and together they bowed in
                    acknowledgement of the honor. The Stonewall Brigade Band, at intervals, played
                    "Joycia Tist N. Y., <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> March," Dixie," "Hail
                    Columbia" and "Yankee Doodle," which caused cheering and clapping of hands by
                    the multitude.</p>
                <p>President Pratt arose after silence had been restored and said:--</p>
                <p>"To-day we have assembled to honor the memories of our dead comrades, to lay a
                    wreath upon the sodded mound which covers their heroic clay, and Blue and Gray
                    unite in the tribute to that sublime devotion which dared to die, and the
                    heroism and valor which is now a Nation's heritage.</p>
                <p>"I welcome you comrades and friends to a victory of peace, in which one of the
                    bravest and truest of those who fought for the Union, in the noble nature which
                    speaks for itself, comes to you no longer leading his fiery troops, but to add
                    his tribute to the brave men who died for what they believed to be right."</p>
                <p>When concluding, he invited <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr> James Nelson,
                        <abbr expan="Doctor of Divinity">D. D.</abbr>, to offer prayer, which he did
                    in an eloquent, impressive, and appropriate manner.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Governor">GOV.</abbr> LEE INTRODUCES <abbr expan="General"
                    >GEN.</abbr> AVERILL.</p>
                <p>As <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Lee stepped to the front of the stage to
                    introduce <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Averill, he was greeted with cheers.
                    His remarks on this occasion, as is usual with him, were peculiarly happy and
                    appropriate. He commenced by alluding to the Jonathan-and-David-like friendship
                    which had existed between himself and <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Averill
                    since they were fellow-students at West Point, and which had continued unbroken
                    through all the vicissitudes of peace and war from that time to this. They were
                    cadets together at West Point where their friendship was first formed. When
                    Averill was graduated, he was sent to Carlisle barracks as drill-master, and
                    when Lee was graduated the following year, he was sent on the same service to
                    the same place, and there their friendship continued to grow. After that, they
                    were sent to the frontier, where they served together under the same flag-"the
                    stars and stripes." They had been taught to entertain different views as to the
                    extent and powers of the Federal and State Governments-the one, the New York
                    cadet, that certain powers were unreservedly delegated, and that the Union of
                    the States was indissoluble; and the other, the Virginia cadet, that those
                    powers were reserved to the States, and that the State of Virginia in entering
                    into the compact of Union had expressly reserved to herself the right to
                    withdraw when her interests or honor demanded, or when she should consider
                    herself aggrieved or her rights denied her by the Federal Government. The North
                    maintaining the former view and the South the latter, and there being no
                    peaceful tribunal to settle the question, it became an "irresponsible conflict,"
                    and the issue was submitted for settlement to the stern arbitrament of war. The
                    Northern officer rallied to the flag of the Union, whilst the Virginian officer,
                    in loyal obedience to the call of his State, returned to his home to defend his
                    mother State to the best of his ability. The war thus begun, continued for four
                    years. During this time, both of them became Generals, commanding cavalry, and
                    their forces were sometimes pitted against each other in deadly conflict. <abbr
                        expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Lee said of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr>
                    Averill that he fought us bravely, but fairly, and like a true soldier made no
                    war upon the defenceless.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Lee said that whilst Averill was returning
                    from his raid on Lynchburg, he had gone to intercept and capture him, expecting
                    to meet him at Covington, but he was recalled and reductantly obeyed the order,
                    and thus they failed to meet. If they had met, said <abbr expan="Governor"
                    >Gov.</abbr> Lee humorously, "the longest pole would have gotten the
                    persimmons." He was thus trying twenty-odd years ago to catch and bring Averill
                    to Staunton, said <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Lee, and now he is here to
                    speak for himself. His presence here under these circumstances shows that the
                    war is, indeed, over, and that the question that divided the country is settled,
                    and that we are now one people, with one destiny, and with one flag.</p>
                <p>This, he said, is a magnificent demonstration in memory of the loved and lost,
                    and no brave man can do otherwise than approve it. That they were brave and good
                    soldiers cannot be denied by those who were foes in war; for if they were not,
                    how is it that it required four long years for a strong government with a
                    million of men to conquer them? Among them, were "Stonewall" Jackson, who rose
                    from the quiet college professor to become a star in the red firmament of war,
                    and the brave and noble and self-sacrificing Jeb. Stuart, who, on being told
                    that his child at home was sick, said: "I must leave my child in the hands of
                    God-my duty requires me here."</p>
                <p>Looking at <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Averill, <abbr expan="Governor"
                    >Gov.</abbr> Lee said, your presence here under these happy auspices clearly
                    indicates that we are in the dawn of revived national feeling, and that we now
                    have peace that is disturbed by no cannons save those fired in memory of the
                    brave and honored soldiers who fell in both armies. Whether they fell in the one
                    army or the other, said <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee, if they did their
                    duty as true and manly soldiers should, he was proud of them as Americans.</p>
                <p>In concluding, <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Lee said he would now introduce
                    him who was the New York Cadet at West Point, and afterwards the distinguished
                        soldier,-<abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> W. W. Averill, of New York.
                    (Great applause.)</p>
                <p><abbr expan="GENERAL">GEN.</abbr> AVERILL'S ADDRESS.</p>
                <p>As <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr>. Averill arose and stepped forward, he was
                    greeted by the vast audience with great cheering. The following is the full text
                    of his excellent address:-</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Fellow Countrymen:</hi>-I thank you for the honor that
                    your invitation brought to me, and for the great pleasure of meeting you on this
                    occasion of the yearly reawakening of the cherished memories of your departed
                    soldiers.-Your courteous summons made me happy by informing me that I was yet
                    alive, for to be forgotten is to be dead, and I gladly come to assist in a
                    Memorial service which shall keep alive in memory the days and deeds of those
                    brave men of yours who are not dead but living immortally-just beyond the bourne
                    of earthly sense. (applause.)</p>
                <p>Undoubtedly there are many people in our country who were acquainted with the war
                    at long range and are not yet aware that it is over. And some double-tongued
                    statesmen who may feel surprised that one who had invaded and pervaded your
                    country with an active armed force, should be asked to receive your hospitality
                    on an occasion like this, when you are perpetuating the sad but heroic memories
                    he had helped to create.</p>
                <p>When I was last here,<lb/> TWENTY-THREE YEARS AGO,<lb/> these hills had been
                    resounding with the dreadful thunder of artillery and the deadly rattle of
                    musketry, and the dust of these tramled fields had been reddened with the blood
                    of contending armies.</p>
                <p>Now, the Shenandoah Valley brims to the mountain top with the quiet atmosphere
                    and sunny glow of peace, and the fields, as far as the eye can reach, are
                    covered with a billowing mantle of prosperity. (applause.)</p>
                <p>Where once, out-posts and pickets were set to guard my command against a brave
                    and persistent enemy, I now stand alone a welcomed guest, (applause). I thank
                    God and you for the changed conditions. I have experienced every vicissitude of
                    war, including being killed -for I have been half killed twice-(laughter), but
                    of all the triumphs I have ever enjoyed this victory of peace to-day is the
                    grandest and most satisfactory. (applause.)</p>
                <p>Among the<lb/> CAUSES OF THIS NOTABLE EVENT<lb/> I recognize, first,a growing
                    custom which will satisfy the universal longing of all men to escape oblivion
                    when their turn shall come to stand the test of remembrance. Secondly, I
                    recognize in my own welcome the highest compliment that you could pay to my
                    command by remembering that when it was here in your country fighting for a
                    restoration of the Union and the preservation of our nationality, it did not
                    attack the defenceless-that it fought your soldiers with courage and energy but
                    held your homes as far as possible sacred from the touch of war. (applause.)</p>
                <p>Since your invitation to me was announced. I have received letters from many of
                    my officers and men in different parts of the country, expressing their
                    gratification at your action.</p>
                <p>Your surviving soldiers remember<lb/> MY COMMAND;<lb/> they remember how, when
                    new and untried, it fought your army of West <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                    in August, <abbr expan="1863">'63</abbr>, at Rocky Gap, near White Sulpher
                    Springs, without discredit, for twenty-four hours; how it again attacked and
                    routed that army at Droop Mountain in November of that year, and you cannot
                    forgot how a portion of my command, 2,500 mounted men, penetrated your lines
                    beyond 150 miles, and destroyed the valuable supplies of Longstreet and the
                    railroad at Salem, and that same 2.500, after doing their work of destruction,
                    turned their faces northward and faced the wintry tempests of December <abbr
                        expan="1863">'63</abbr> and "marched, climbed, slid and swum" through and
                    around 25,000 of your best and bravest, and escaped capture; how, early in <abbr
                        expan="1864">'64</abbr>, 2,250 of them led their horses in single file over
                    the mountains of West Virginia and descended upon the Tennessee railroad near
                    Wythville, holding in a bloody embrace the 5,000 of <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> John Morgan for four hours, thus preventing his junction with the
                    forces of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Jenkins at Dublin, and ensuring the
                    defeat of the latter at Cloyd Mountain; you all remember our part in the
                    Lynchburg expedition, and the division of Ramseur in Early's army, and
                    especially the Stonewall brigade commanded by the gallant <abbr expan="General"
                        >Gen.</abbr> Lilley, (applause) will remember the loss of their battery and
                    two or three hundred men at Carter's farm near Winchester, in July, <abbr
                        expan="1864">'64</abbr>; and the division of McCausland cannot forgot
                    Moorfield when it was surprised at dawn of day on August 8th, <abbr expan="1864"
                        >'64</abbr>, and lost its battery, colors, and a large number of its men and
                    horses; and my great and good friend, your gallant soldier Governor will carry
                    through life an attestation of our attack on your left at Winchester, on the
                    19th of September, <abbr expan="1864">'64</abbr>, whereby the brilliant
                    prospects which awaited the heroic efforts of Early's army were turned into
                    hopeless defeat. And finally the wonderfully active army of Early and the
                    gallant Lomax, who commanded its left, at Fisher's Hill, will recollect the
                    assault of my division which turned his left and brought sudden victory to our
                    arms.</p>
                <p>All these remembrances are still glowing and glorious, but above them all shines
                    the ever-lasting golden challenge to the men and women of <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va.</abbr> to recall an instance where the sanctity of a home was invaded
                    by any officer or man of my division, without swift and condign punishment
                    overtaking the offender.-Sweet as the fragrance of flowers will be to my
                    officers and men this recognition of their discipline and high sense of duty
                    which you extend to their commander to-day. My men, proud of their character as
                    soldiers, tasted in those terrible days the first fruits of duty done, when my
                    division formed a part of a larger force and they saw women come to their gates
                    with white faces and dishevelled hair, and heard them inquiring of the passing
                    column for Averill's men to protect them, (great applause.)</p>
                <p>Among those who greet me here to-day I observe the beaming faces of a generation
                    who must have been too young to realize the tremendous struggle of life and
                    death to which this occasion mainly relates, and whose notions about its cause
                    and conduct must be dim, and perhaps they sometimes wonder what it was all
                    about. But they need not regret their lack of understanding, for very few of our
                    leading men in government, literature, legislation or politics, at that time, or
                    even this day, have reached down to the broad and truthful premises, which
                    should underlie any philosophical and<lb/> CANDID CONSIDERATION OF THE ORIGIN
                    AND RESULTS OF THE WAR,<lb/> not remembering that organized aggregate of
                    humanity called <hi rend="underline">society</hi>, the <hi
                        rend="underline">parent</hi> of government, derives its character from the
                    character of the labor that supports it-that the people of the North and South
                    were sustained by entirely different forms of labor-that the different social
                    conditions which resulted, were originally united by the ties of helplessness
                    and mutual dependence in resisting the oppressive exactions of the mother
                    country and achieved the independency of the Republic, and afterwards tried to
                    perfect and perpetuate the Union of States by adopting the Constitution-that
                    great men of both social conditions strove earnestly and long to maintain the
                    Union in spite of the natural and irresistible diversities which sprang from
                    social, political and commercial antagonisms between these different social
                    conditions, the accumulating aggravations of which no government devised by man
                    could repress, until it fell to the lot of the eighth generation of Americans,
                    no longer able to control or harmonize them, to resort to the arbitrament of
                    arms. Then followed a heroic period which gave birth to great names, glorious
                    achievements and heroic deeds. One of these antagonistic social forms had to be
                    crushed. The strength of anything is measured by the force required to break it.
                    The strength of Southern society was measured by a million men and
                    $3,000,000,000. Incidentally and necessarily the character of human labor became
                    homogeneous throughout the land. Political parties had no more to do with the
                    cause of the war than the church militant has to do with earthquakes.
                    (applause.) The costly lesson we learn was that labor is the lever that moves
                    the world of human life and in a republic it must be free. Human labor is
                    Godlike in this, that it materializes thought and is creative in its functions.
                    It is unrequited whenever any portion of its wages are expended on fictitious
                    values.</p>
                <p>The Nation can remember with honorable pride that<lb/> SOUTHERN MEN WERE GREAT IN
                    WAR;<lb/> it remembers that when their cause was hopelessly lost they were
                    greater in accepting with the dignity of brave men the conditions and
                    consequences of defeat; but posterity will never forget that they showed
                    themselves greatest in meeting promptly and manfully the exigencies of free
                    labor. (applause.) For over 2,000 years mankind has been instructed and
                    civilization benefited by a picture of Cincinnatus called from his plow to
                    assume the dignities and wield the power of the Roman state. A far greater
                    picture in its effects and benefits was furnished mankind when your Governor,
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Fitzhugh Lee, (applause), whom I mention
                    as representing the best and highest type of Southern manhood, after the war
                    took off his coat and put his hand to the plow for the first time. (applause.)</p>
                <p>God who gave us our path and motion in the universe and said "By the sweat of thy
                    face shalt thou eat bread," will smile on a people who recognize and respect the
                    dignity of labor.</p>
                <p>Amid the elder generations before me I recognize the faces of those who must have
                    been my comrades of the war. We certainly were comrades in several relations. In
                    our campaigns and battles the same sky covered us, the same storm drenched us,
                    we were bespattered by the same mud and begrimed by the same dust and our
                    marches and fatigues were contemporaneous and coequal. We assaulted each other
                    until we became well acquainted. (applause.) With regard to the personal
                    feelings existing between those who were acquainted with each other or were
                    friends when the war divided them, I may mention<lb/> A CONVERSATION I ONCE HAD
                    WITH PRESIDENT LINCOLN,<lb/> which may be of interest. It was shortly after the
                    first great cavalry battle of the war, at Kelley's Ford, on the Rappahannock,
                    early in 1863. The President came down to visit the Army of the Potomac opposite
                    Fredericksburg and to review it. He did me the honor to send for me to visit him
                    in the evening. We had an interview of an hour in his tent. He asked me many
                    questions about the army, and especially the Cavalry Service and its great
                    expense. He expressed great interest in the fight we had at Kelley's Ford, and
                    enquired particularly about the Confederate commanders. I told him how the fight
                    came to pass, and showed him a note which I had received from General Fitzhugh
                    Lee, with reference to his wounded. He put on his spectacles and read it
                    carefully. Then he asked: "Were you and General Lee friends?"</p>
                <p>"Certainly," said I, "always had been."</p>
                <p>"What would happen," he asked, "Should you meet on the battle field?"</p>
                <p>"One or both of us would be badly hurt or killed," I said, "obliged to be, Mr.
                    President."</p>
                <p>He leaned that picturesque and mournful face of his on his hand, and after a
                    pause, said with emotion, "Oh, my God, what a dreadful thing is a war like this,
                    where personal friends must slay each other and die as friends!"</p>
                <p>I told him that "undoubtedly Lee thought he was doing his duty, and I knew I was
                    doing mine."</p>
                <p>"Yes," said Mr. Lincoln, "I understand your feelings, but there are many who
                    would think that you ought to hate each other."</p>
                <p>Finally, he said: "General Averill, I wish you would give me this letter of
                    Lee's."</p>
                <p>"Surely, take it, Mr. President," I replied; and I have been told by one of his
                    biographers that he carried the note in his pocket for a long time, and would
                    frequently show it.</p>
                <p>This statement of personal relations and feelings seemed to make a revelation to
                    Mr. Lincoln, for he had a heart and an understanding large enough to consider
                    every emotion of all the people in this country, which he so longed should be a
                    nation. (applause.)</p>
                <p>THE MEMORIES OF THE FOUR YEARS' WAR<lb/> which cluster above the graves of the
                    "Blue" and the "Gray," are identical and equally dear to the surviving comrades
                    of each. There is one grand memory which we may ever enjoy, the fortitude and
                    devotion of American soldiers, North and South, and their manhood in battle will
                    not fail to awaken the admiration of mankind so long as any people are called
                    Americans. (applause ) The grandest efficient result of the war was to fortify
                    our nation with a public opinion which has since environed the world. Where is
                    the nation that does not recognize its power? or that can afford to disregard
                    it. The migrating thousands who are pouring into our country from all nations
                    and races, attest the universal and continued effect and grandeur of that
                    opinion. It needs no thundering navy nor consuming army to make it manifest.</p>
                <p>Our future path as a nation has been untrodden by any other and our destiny is
                    beyond human ken. Our industries will become more varied and definite, and as
                    their equation approaches perfection, the Nation will near the long repose of
                    contentment, and the rhythm of free and requited labor will move the peoples of
                    the earth to a higher social development and to a more general union of mankind.</p>
                <p>The persistent and universal force on earth which moves people to build churches,
                    is the same which has assembled you to-day-the worship of the Godlike in
                    man;-the recognition of the Image in which we are created.<lb/> PATRIOTISM<lb/>
                    is not an inspiration, it is a necessary condition of social existence. It is
                    the threshold of religion. Outside this threshold men are brutes. Inside, we
                    behold all that man has discovered and created-Society, Government, Language,
                    Literature, Science, and Art.</p>
                <p>This undying mother of civilization,-Religion-is the first necessity experienced
                    and the last comfort relinquished in every human life. In this mother's arms, we
                    are suspended between two infinities, as in a hammock one end of which is held
                    by Memory, the other by Hope. The history of this Nation, the only one which can
                    now be studied from its beginning, is already a new and original page in the
                    story of the world. Not yet a hundred years old; and on a new continent, a
                    nation that employs two million men in a social war, and succeeds in uniting
                    itself and knitting its people together is certainly original. Another wonderful
                    thing is that the very soldiers of both armies who did the fighting enjoy the
                    readiest mutual confidence and brotherly esteem, and mayhap in spite of
                    indifferent and ignorant politicians, they and their children will become the
                    strongest social cement of our permanent union.</p>
                <p>We dashed together like waves on rocks,<lb/> We fought till the ground was
                    red;<lb/> We met in the shuddering battle shocks,<lb/> Where none but the freed
                    soul fled.</p>
                <p>Now side by side in the Nation's life,<lb/> And shoulder to shoulder are we;<lb/>
                    And we know by the grip of our hands, strife,<lb/> What the strength of our love
                    may be.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="General">GEN.</abbr> JOHN D. IMBODEN INTRODUCES MR. A. J. M'CALL, OF
                    NEW YORK.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Imboden said that the duty had been assigned to
                    him to introduce the venerable <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Jackson, of
                    Tennessee, but that gentleman had been prevented by sickness from attending, and
                    he would introduce instead Mr. A. J. McCall, of New York, a friend and neighbor
                    of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Averill, who had accompanied him to this
                    city. Before doing that, he hoped he would be pardoned for giving expression to
                    some sentiments which had occurred to his mind whilst <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Averill was speaking. It was an evidence and a result of the
                    advanced christian civilization of this country that such fraternal feelings
                    should now exist between people who had so recently had millions of men engaged
                    in hostile conflict, and that it should be brought about chiefly by the very men
                    who were engaged in that conflict. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Imboden
                    said that the South was right in the fight she made, but still he believed that
                    it was better for her and the nation and the human race that she failed to
                    accomplish her purpose. In concluding, he introduced Mr. McCall, of New York.</p>
                <p>MR. M'CALL'S REMARKS.</p>
                <p>This venerable gentleman then, leaning upon a cane, came to the front, and made a
                    few very pleasant remarks. He said that he had not expected to have anything to
                    say, and would not attempt a speech, but only a little talk. He said he was here
                    now, because he<pb n="?"/> had been here on a visit sixteen years ago, and was
                    so pleased that he could not refrain from coming here on this occasion with his
                    friend and neighbor, <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Averill. He was greatly
                    pleased with the manifestation of fraternal feeling here exhibited which he knew
                    to be honest and unfeigned. Though persons may differ in their opinions, they
                    should still be friends. He liked persons to express freely their honest
                    convictions. He always did that himself, and he liked for others to do likewise.
                    His friendly remarks were heard with pleasure and were greeted with applause.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Colonel">COL.</abbr> J. C. SHIELDS INTRODUCES Mr. CARLTON M'CARTHY,
                    OF RICHMOND</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> J. C. Shields then introduced Mr. Carlton
                    McCarthy, of Richmond, the author of "Soldier Life in the Army of Northern
                    Virginia," which he did as follows:-</p>
                <p>This feature of our memorial ceremonies would be incomplete without the
                    participation of the private-the individual soldier-who, as he has been sketched
                    by the gentleman that will now address you, "Was moved by the heart which is
                    greater than the mind, secure in his own rectitude of purpose and accountable
                    only to his God."</p>
                <p>The duty I am called upon to perform, in introducing him, is one of special
                    personal pleasure to me, for he won his renown whilst serving in the battery of
                    which I had the honor to be the first commandant. I introduce private Carlton
                    McCarthy, of the First Company, Richmond Howitzers, author of "Soldier Life in
                    the Army of Northern Virginia" and Secretary of the Association of that army.</p>
                <p>MR. CARLTON M'CARTHY'S SPEECH:</p>
                <p>As a representative of the vast and honorable constituency, of the private
                    soldier, he did credit to himself and reflected honor upon the constituency he
                    represented. His speech in matter and manner was unique, and <hi
                        rend="underline">sui generis</hi>-it was like no other, and was its own
                    parallel. The manner of its delivery was easy, graceful, and humorous, whilst
                    its matter was pregnant with apherisms of wisdom.- Whilst he was so considerate
                    as to announce, before he entered upon his address, that it would not displease
                    him in the least degree if persons should leave whilst he was speaking, for
                    whilst all knew how long the speeches of those were who preceded him, no mortal
                    man could tell how long his would be. Such was the manner in which he interested
                    and entertained the audience, that none availed themselves of the privilege he
                    so generously accorded them, but heard him through, and wished him to continue
                    longer. His patriotic sentiments, warm Southern devotion, sound maxims, pointed
                    wit, and genial humor, not only pleased, but captivated his vast audience. He
                    seemed to have possessed the "Open Sesame" to the intellectual treasure-house of
                    Seneca, from the number of nuggets of wisdom he presented of that ancient
                    Grecian sage. His frequent quotations of Seneca caused a smile in the audience,
                    when he paused, and humorously said, "It seemed that he was not allowed to be
                        <hi rend="underline">original</hi>." He repelled with indignation the
                    idea that Confederate soldiers were rebels and traitors, and asked, "Are we
                    paying memorial honors to criminals, to traitors? No, they were patriots who
                    fought, bled, and died for their country. Their cause was right-the South <hi
                        rend="underline">was</hi> right, and will <hi rend="underline"
                    >always</hi> be right." Turning to <abbr expan="Generals">Gens.</abbr> Lee and
                    Averill on the stage he said, "The military men are not always impartial judges,
                    and sometimes give the award to the wrong man." He is what the North would
                    denominate an "unreconstructed rebel." Though his sentiments were extreme, his
                    sincerity and honesty of conviction were so palpable, and his humor so genial,
                    that they were received with pleasure even by those who did not concur with him
                    ; for they approved his patriotism and Southern devotion, even if they did not
                    agree with his opinions.</p>
                <p>During his speech, his quaintness of manner and the originality of his views,
                    elicited applause and frequent bursts of laughter.</p>
                <p>THE FINALE.</p>
                <p>During the afternoon, the fine company of infantry, Captain Roller, from
                    Harrisonburg, which received so many commendations, appeared in front of the
                    City Hall and exercised in dress parade-the Harrisonburg Band furnishing the
                    music. The parade over, the, the line of march for the depot was taken up amid
                    huzzas and cheering for the Harrisonburg contribution to the interest of the
                    day.</p>
                <p>The regular and special trains had brought large crowds to Staunton, and at the
                    hour for returning all had departed. From the surrounding country, and by all
                    the modes of travel known to the rural districts, the people, old and young,
                    white and colored, had joined in the ceremonies of memorial day, and, before
                    nightfall, were on the way to their homes.-They came not empty-handed and only
                    to observe, but brought with them provisions for the dinner furnished under the
                    auspices of the ladies, and many baskets of flowers to bedeck the graves of the
                    honored dead.</p>
                <p>AN INTERESTING LECTURE FROM THE NIGHT PREVIOUS.-By invitation of the Staunton
                    Artillery, General Imboden, who was the first commandant of the company, which
                    was organized in November, 1859, was under promise to lecture for its bedefit,
                    and filled the engagement at the Opera House on the night of the 8th. General
                    Averill and Mr. McCarthy were present on the stage. Captain Long and <abbr
                        expan="Lieutenants">Lieuts.</abbr> O'Rork and Kinney of the Artillery
                    escorted General Imboden to the stand. There was another veteran there-that
                    matchless soldier and accomplished gentleman, Captain James Bumgardner, <abbr
                        expan="Junior">Jr.</abbr>, who had been designated to introduce-no, not that
                    as he said-but to announce General Imboden's appearance before the audience.
                    That was done in a style worthy of the speaker and the occasion. General
                    Imboden, he said, was here in the county of his birth, and the scene of his
                    early life, and the services of his matured manhood. Here he had filled high
                    public station, and was a representative of the great old county for many
                    sessions in the legislature. Coming on to the times when war opened upon us he
                    was referred to in connection with the splendid command with which he entered
                    the services, and closed by naming a few of the incidents in battle and the high
                    record the battery had made.</p>
                <p>General Imboden, in his opening remarks, gave an interesting sketch of the times
                    as they were in November, 1859, when the company was formed, and the early
                    efforts to equip it with a battery, calling up his interviews with Governor
                    Wise, General Dimmock, and the rapidly crowding events that came to pass.-Here
                    he paused awhile to speak of the "West Augusta Guards," that fine infantry
                    company then in existence here, and the noble spirits, both officers and men, it
                    embraced.</p>
                <p>The march to the lower Valley and Harper's Ferry, the special service he and his
                    command were ordered to execute, the battle of Manassas, and the artillery
                    conflict between the Staunton battery of four smooth-bore 6-pounders without
                    infantry support, and Ricket's and Sherman's batteries of 12 rifles and 2
                    howitzers, were described in a manner as thrilling as they were true. The
                    Federal batteries were disabled and Ricket wounded and carried from the field
                    were the results before the Staunton battery had orders to retire, for they
                    failed to reach it became the staff-officer bearing them had fallen, and the
                    immortal Bee, the brigade commander, had been slain immediately after they were
                    issued.</p>
                <p>From Manassas to the Potomac, and then on every field where its scores of
                    conflicts were merely named, he said it was reported distinguished by every
                    General officer under whom it served. At Manassas, it held a position, and could
                    not be dislodged, and thereby delayed McDowell's movements, and on the other
                    hand gave Johnston and Beauregard advantages they otherwise could not have
                    had-if indeed the position it so sublimely maintained was not the turning point
                    of that eventful day. He referred to the fact that the Virginia troops were
                    mustered in 1861 for one year only, but whilst in the lower Valley and before
                    the battle of Manassas, he mustered his command in the service for the war, and
                    reported his certified roll to headquarters. It was the first Virginia company
                    so placed in the service. He made an eloquent and fervent appeal to the citizens
                    of Staunton and Augusta to sustain this old and war-worn command. A veteran of
                    the war who served through it as a member was now its commander. He was a brave
                    and good soldier then, and should now, in his efforts to maintain the
                    organization, receive the cheerful co-operation of the community.</p>
                <p>The <hi rend="underline">Century</hi> Magazine will contain the history of
                    the Staunton Artillery written by <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Imboden in
                    his vigorous style. Names of his comrades of the company came fast and in
                    scores, with his tributes of admiration and affection. It was with tremulous
                    voice he spoke of Tom Harman as noble a spirit and as true a man as he ever
                    knew. The eulogy of few words that was spoken of that gentleman was truly
                    impressive and sank deep in the hearts of all who knew him.</p>
                <p>THE AUGUSTA MEMORIAL ASSOCIATION IN ANNUAL MEETING.-At 4 o'clock in the afternoon
                    the association assembled in the Council <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the transaction of business.
                    President Pratt in the Chair, and Mr. Morgan Argenbright, Secretary, present.</p>
                <p>Reports were made from the various committees and by the Treasurer. The Monument
                    Committee was authorized to erect the monument during the coming fiscal year,
                    with the view of having it ready to be unveiled on the memorial day in 1888.</p>
                <p>Captain Pratt declined a re-election and insisted that he should have his way in
                    that matter, but the association would take no excuse, nor consider any appeal
                    he made, and by a unanimous vote directed the Secretary to declare him
                    re-elected. Encomiums upon his services and the splendid success, as the day in
                    all its features had demonstrated, were pronounced by many gentlemen, all
                    overruling his earnest request that he should be relieved, and that Captain
                    Lewis Harman be placed in the position of President. None were more opposed to
                    such a proceeding than Captain Harman himself, who declared that Captain Pratt
                    must serve until the monument crowned the beautiful heights of Thornrose
                    cemetery. Mr. Newton Argenbright as Secretary, and Mr. Joseph E. Rollins as
                    Treasurer, were unanimously re-elected. This is the sixteenth year of Mr.
                    Rollins' services in that office.</p>
                <p>Messrs. W. L. Bumgardner, J. D. Lilley, J. A. Patterson, J. C. Shields, A. H.
                    Fults, and J. T. Long, were made Vice Presidents.</p>
                <p>Messrs. J. C. Marquis; J. N. McFarland, F. B. Berkeley, Lewis Harman, and B. A.
                    Hamilton were again constituted the executive committee.</p>
                <p>The monument committee is as follows: J. C. Marquis, W. L. Olivier, J. N.
                    McFarland, J. D. Lilley, Silas Walker, G. J. Pratt, W. H. Gamble, Jos. A.
                    Wilson, J. E. Rollins, and J. Hotchkiss.</p>
                <p>Governor Lee, General Averill, General Imboden, Carlton McCarthy, A. J. McCall,
                    and H. M. Lee, were made honorary members.</p>
                <p>The services of the Ladies' Auxiliary Society and of the Stonewall Brigade Band
                    in aid of the purpose of the Association were referred to in touching words by
                        <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> McFarland and others and the thanks of
                    the Association unanimously tendered to them.</p>
                <p>The elegant carriage in which were seated <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Lee
                    and General Averill, drawn by four splendid black horses, the reins in the
                    skillful hands of William Britt were from the fine livery of Mr. Alexander
                    Harman, and could not fail to add to the pleasure of the distinguished guests,
                    who, being famed cavaliers, must be admirers of good blooded and spirited
                    steeds.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
