<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0069"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0069">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Col. John Doak Lilley," by Unknown,
                    1914</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county col john doak lilley, by unknown 1914</title>
        <author>Unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 6.9 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0069</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498482</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Col. John Doak Lilley," by Unknown, 1914</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county col john doak lilley, by unknown 1914</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 22, p.
                            33, 1914</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Veterans, Death/Casualties, Education</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-04">2006-02-04</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0069T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Obituary for distinguished Confederate veteran of Staunton</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The death of <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> John Doak Lilley, of Staunton,
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, on June 13, 1913, removed a most useful
                    and honored citizen, a man of true worth and unquestioned integrity. He was one
                    of three brothers who served the Confederacy faithfully, his two brothers being
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Robert Doak Lilley and James C. Lilley,
                        <abbr expan="Junior">Jr.</abbr>, courier to General Lee.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> John D. Lilley was born September 5, 1841, at
                    Greenville, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, and was educated in the schools
                    of Greenville, Staunton, and at the Virginia Military Institute, Lexington. In
                    1861 he left the Institute with the corps of cadets under <abbr expan="General"
                        >Gen.</abbr> Stonewall Jackson for Richmond, where the cadets were detailed
                    to drill recruits, and he was appointed to command the Brunswick Blues and
                    Nottaway Grays at the burial in Richmond of Henry L. Wyatt, the first
                    Confederate soldier killed in battle.</p>
                <p>After two months the Cadet Corps was disbanded, and Colonel Lilley returned to
                    Staunton, where he assisted <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> John B. Baldwin in
                    organizing the 52d Virginia Infantry. He was offered a position on the staff of
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Jubal Early, but declined, and took the
                    first lieutenancy of Company I, <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> C. R. Mason
                    commanding, in the regiment he had assisted in organizing. The regiment was
                    ordered to McDowell, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, and wintered on top of
                    the Alleghany Mountains. Captain Mason was detailed by General Jackson to take
                    command of the forces building bridges and roads, and Colonel Lilley succeeded
                    him as captain of the company. In this capacity he fought in the battles of
                    Alleghany Mountain, December 13, 1861; McDowell, May 7, 1862; Front Royal and
                    Winchester, 1862; Cross Keys and Port Republic, June 8 and 9, 1862. He was then
                    promoted to the rank of major, and on July 1, 1862, he fought in the battle of
                    Malvern Hill, and was with Stonewall Jackson in his famous march around General
                    Pope's army which terminated in the battle of Cedar Mountain. At the second
                    battle of Manassas, August 25, 1862, Major Lilley was severely wounded in the
                    thigh, and before he could be gotten from under fire he was shot in the left leg
                    and arm. During his convalescence he was detailed enrolling officer at
                    Lexington, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, and while serving in this capacity
                    he assisted in the burial of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Stonewall
                    Jackson, whose body was brought to Lexington in May, 1863.</p>
                <p>Rejoining his regiment, Major Lilley fought in the battles of the Wilderness, and
                    on May 19, 1864, at Spottsylvania <abbr expan="Courthouse">C. H.</abbr> he was
                    wounded in the right hand. As soon as possible Major Lilley again rejoined his
                    regiment and was appointed on the general court-martial at White Oak Swamp,
                    where he served until the day before the battle of that place, when he was
                    promoted to the rank of colonel and commanded his old regiment, the 52d, in the
                    battle until the commander of the brigade, General Lewis was killed. when
                    Colonel Lilley was ordered to take command of the brigade October 27, 1864. The
                    next day, while superintending the <orig reg="reinforcement"
                    >reenforcement</orig> of the breastworks, his hand and arm were accidentally
                    crushed, and he was so disabled as to be ordered to the rear.</p>
                <p>Returning to Staunton, Colonel Lilley found that Milroy and the Federals were
                    about to enter that town, so he went to Waynesboro; and in order to avoid
                    capture he and a companion, Alex Fishburn, secured horses and, swimming South
                    River, took refuge in a cabin in the mountains. A few days after this he started
                    to Lynchburg by way of Lexington. Eight miles from Lexington he met Colonel
                    Spangler, who informed him of General Lee's surrender, showing his parole.</p>
                <p>After these stirring days were over, Colonel Lilley settled on a farm, Buffalo
                    Hill, formerly owned by his great-grandfather. In 1870 he was made surveyor of
                    Augusta County and later road commissioner, and as a member of the school board
                    did much for the schools of Riverheads District. Through his efforts more than
                    any other a handsome monument was raised to the Confederate dead in Thornrose
                    Cemetery, Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> He is survived by his
                    wife, formerly Miss Anna Smith, of Greenville, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr>, and four sons.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
