<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0090"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0090">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "My First Raid with Mosby. A Graphic
                    Pen-Picture of a Night Attack as told by a New Recruit.," by A Member of Company
                    A., December 21, 1887</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county my first raid with mosby a graphic pen picture of a night attack as told by a new recruit , by a member of company a december 21 1887</title>
        <author/>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes">16</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0090</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498503</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "My First Raid with Mosby. A Graphic Pen-Picture of a
                            Night Attack as told by a New Recruit.," by A Member of Company A.,
                            December 21, 1887</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county my first raid with mosby a graphic pen picture of a night attack as told by a new recruit , by a member of company a december 21 1887</title>
            <author>A Member of Company A.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 page</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Staunton Spectator, December 21,
                            1887</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1887-12-21">1887-12-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Death/Casulaties, Military Strategy,
                        Prisons/Priosners, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-09-27">2005-09-27</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0090T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>A Confederate veteran's detailed-and romanticized-account of his first
                    participation in a nighttime raid.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>On the 22nd of April, 1864, some forty or fifty Rangers met at Hooper's shop,
                    near Middleburg, in response to a hasty call circulated the night before. It was
                    late in the day when we moved out on the road; for the Federal camps were but a
                    short day's march from the rendezvous, and our enterprise was to be one of those
                    night adventures which have made Mosby so famous as a Partisan. Except that the
                    head of the column was directed toward Alexandria, we had no intimation of the
                    character of the service we were going upon. But our chieftain himself rode in
                    the van, and no one entertained any misgiving as to the result of whatever
                    venture he had in store for us.</p>
                <p>As we moved along the dusty highway, or made a short cut across the fields; over
                    hill, through dell; now in the broad glare of the evening sun, now beneath the
                    delicate shade of the woods, just putting on their spring verdure-I sat silent
                    on my horse, endeavoring to take in the thousand ideas that crowded on me. The
                    situation was novel and full of romance to my boyish mind. Each man as he passed
                    and repassed me-now moving to front, now falling back to the rear, in the
                    helter-skelter march-or stopped to crack a joke or quiz the new recruit, was a
                    study to me.</p>
                <p>And a motley crew they were in those early days of the Command. There rode an
                    aged sire whose reverend grey locks, straggling from beneath his cocked and
                    plumed hat, seemed to utter pitiful protests against the companionship in which
                    they were. Beside him was a boy, whose youthful looks were far more suggestive
                    of the nursery than of the war-path. Side by side rode the planter's proud son
                    and the overseer's boy; the banker dressed in fine soft officers' gray, richly
                    trimmed with gold lace, and the poor adventurer whose suit of Union blue
                    betrayed how dependant he was upon the "spoils of the chase."</p>
                <p>One spirit seemed to possess them all-that of devil-may-care hilarity. The merry
                    song, the jovial laugh rang out along the line, Jest and joke followed amusing
                    anecdote; and now a group crowded together in the narrow road to listen to some
                    old veteran's tales of the Regular Service. The Colonel seemed to encourage this
                    disposition, and frequently would summon some distinguished talker to the front
                    and call for such and such a favorite yarn.</p>
                <p>The levity struck me at first as singularly out of place. Here rode these men on
                    the most serious business that ever engaged human enterprise. But a few short
                    hours at most, were between them and the terrible charge, the deadly encounter
                    and, for aught that any knew, death. Yet they rode on to it,</p>
                <p>"As some gudelie companie<lb/> To a midnight reveirie."</p>
                <p>But my young spirit soon caught the contagion, and I too laughed with the loudest
                    and jested with the merriest. Surely, soldiering with Mosby must be the jolliest
                    life in the world!</p>
                <p>As the shades of night fell, "a change came over the spirit" of their
                    entertainment. The jest was still bandied, but it seemed to be put with more
                    delicacy: the tale was still told to cager listeners, but it was more fitted for
                    a lady's bower. The songs, that had rolled forth all the day in quaint medley
                    from knots here and there or a solitary singer down the line, were hushed, and
                    from the choir that had now assembled at the head of the column came floating
                    back upon the night plaintive music, inspired by thoughts of home and loved
                    ones. Soon all other sounds had ceased and every ear was set to catch the notes.
                    I thought I saw more than one tear upon grim faces glisten in the moonlight as
                    the voices of those who waited for our coming home seemed to echo the words of
                    the song, now sung with a pathos I never heard <orig reg="elsewhere">else
                    where</orig>,</p>
                <p>"We shall meet, but we shall miss him"</p>
                <p>The song ceased, and a great sigh of relief seemed to go up from the moving mass
                    of men. Then a merrier strain was struck, the chorus caught up along the line,
                    and we were the same <orig reg="lighthearted">light hearted</orig> fellows as
                    before.</p>
                <p>I recollect that we had just emerged from the shadows of a forest through which
                    we had marched for some miles and entered an old field, when the sounds in front
                    hushed or rather sunk into a murmur, and the words came down the line:</p>
                <p>"Silence -----------pass it back."</p>
                <p>Oh! my heart jumped into my throat. That began to look like business.
                    Instinctively, my hand sought my gun. A grum<del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Regular, who rode by my side,
                    and of whom, by the way, nothing was known but his <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> name--Nick
                    Skeldon--saw the movement and said,</p>
                <p>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>
                </p>
                <p>I was too much mortified to ask any further questions just then. I felt that I
                    had betrayed my greeness and perhaps a shade of nervousness, and didn't care to
                    pursue the subject.</p>
                <p>Nothing was heard but the tread of the horses, moving over the hard, crisp
                    turf-distressingly suggestive to my mind of "muffled drums and funeral marches."
                    And to their lugubrious measures <hi rend="underline">came</hi> solemn
                    thoughts, and <hi rend="underline">went</hi> my martial enthusiasm.</p>
                <p>Just then my attention was attracted by some sounds on our flank; and I looked to
                    see several dusky <orig reg="forms">froms</orig> gallopping toward us over a
                    hill.</p>
                <p>"There they are," I cried in an excited voice; and in a twinkle my carbine was
                    cocked and at my shoulder. Nick's hand was on my arm, with no gentle pressure,
                    as he hoarsely growled:</p>
                <p>"Don't be <orig reg="such">sech</orig> a tarnal fool-them's our scouts. What the
                    devil did you leave <orig reg="your">yer</orig> mammy <orig reg="for"
                    >fur</orig>?"</p>
                <p>The question was a pertinent one, that's a fact; and one that my own heart echoed
                    with considerable unction. But I was not in a frame of mind to go into a
                    critical self-examination-much less to make confidences to my blunt friend. So I
                    stammered out something about "I didn't know," "command being surprised" <orig
                        reg="etc.">&amp;c., &amp;c.</orig></p>
                <p>The <orig reg="newcomers">new comers</orig> pushed to the front and made their
                    communications to the Colonel. The line of march was at once changed, and we
                    struck, at single file, down through the thickest, darkest, loneliest pine
                    forest in all that dreary country. This move was not very <orig reg="reassuring"
                        >reasuring</orig> to me. At once, every dark tale of ambuscade I had ever
                    heard recurred to me with a force that nothing but my surroundings could have
                    given them. Nor did the weird wail of a a whip-poor-will, that every now and
                    then came moaning up out of the pines, tend much to soothe my nerves. But when
                    the dismal hoot of an owl suddenly boomed out on the night, I well nigh jumped
                    from my saddle. I could not define the impression it made on me at first. E'er
                    long it was heard again, and just in front of the <orig reg="vanguard">van
                    guard</orig>, as before. This time my fancy identified it, and I recognized in
                    the hoarse "Whoo--hoo" the signal of a Yankee vidette warning his fellows of our
                    approach.</p>
                <p>Again, and yet again, at regular intervals, and just in advance of us the ominous
                    croak was heard; and each time I became more and more fully convinced that the
                    next interruption to the gloomy silence would be a volley of musketry from the
                    bushes; and each time, Nick's last question repeated itself to me with increased
                    force.</p>
                <p>At length we reached a deep hollow in which was a little glade. Dismounting, we
                    disposed ourselves about upon the grass to rest; for it was past midnight. I had
                    begun to feel something of relief, when a Sergeant came around calling for
                    Carbineers to go with the Colonel on a <orig reg="reconnaissance"
                    >reconnoisance</orig>.</p>
                <p>Now you must know that Carbines were very scarce among Mosby's men. None but very
                    new <orig reg="recruits">rescruits</orig>, who had not yet learned better, and
                    older ones whose verdancy was constitutional and who would never learn better,
                    carried them. Possibly I would fall with equal justice into either class. At any
                    rate, I was one of a very few who had Carbines that night; and had the
                    questionable distinction of getting on the detail.</p>
                <p>Leaving our horses behind, some half dozen of us set out upon the scout. After
                    travelling some distance through the woods, we struck a <orig reg="highway"
                        >high-way</orig>; and turning into it, moved briskly along. The moon had
                    gone down; but we had not proceeded far before we distinguished some men coming
                    toward us, also on foot. I felt the iciest nervous chill crawling up my back;
                    and, despite the warnings I had already received, my hand was on its way to my
                    gun-lock, when the colonel whispered.</p>
                <p>"Keep quiet, booys. We'll show them a trick."</p>
                <p>Then a voice from the approaching party called.</p>
                <p>"Halt! Who comes there?"</p>
                <p>"A detail from the ---- New York. Who are you?" the Colonel replied, with a
                    perfect Yankee twang.</p>
                <p>"Patrol from the ----- Michigan Cavalry. Let one of you raise his hands and
                    advance."</p>
                <p>"Suppose one of you advance-you seem to be the larger party."</p>
                <p>I will state, by the way, that we had been marching in single file, and but two
                    or three of us were visible to the approaching party.</p>
                <p>Without more ado, an unsuspecting Yank came promptly forward. When he came up to
                    us he found a revolver presented to his breast and was greeted with the
                    encouraging injunction.</p>
                <p>"Give the alarm, and I will blow your heart out. Turn around and tell the others
                    that "<orig reg="it's">its</orig> all right, to come on."</p>
                <p>And so he did; and five more of Uncle Sam's gallant defenders marched confidingly
                    up to the muzzles of six carbines and quietly surrendered.</p>
                <p>Our captives, as they had said, were a patrol from a neighboring picket post, on
                    their regular round. With a little persuasion of a certain kind they were
                    induced to discover to us the location of the reserve post and the positions of
                    the videttes. Taking one man with him, the Colonel went off to verify their
                    report, and sent the rest of us back to the troop.</p>
                <p>It was not far from day-break, when he returned and ordered us up. Our sabres,
                    spurs, canteens and everything that might rattle and make a noise, were left
                    with our horses and the prisoners in charge of a small detail. As I moved off
                    with the rest, I could not but own to an unfeigned regret that the selection of
                    the "horse detail" had not been determined by the same considerations, as the
                    one that thad been made earlier in the night.</p>
                <p>I shall never forget that grim and stealthy march. Creeping along in Indian file
                    through the deepest hollows, and darkest shades; never a sound, but the dull,
                    smothered tread of the men, or the frightened scream of some bird as we scared
                    it from its roost, or the rustling through the bushes of some varmint aroused
                    from its lair; moving a while in one direction, and then in another, to avoid
                    the videttes, we kept on-slowly, but surely, approaching our prey.</p>
                <p>Suddenly I was awakened from my mediations by the coughing of a horse, and looked
                    to see a dark mass looming up in the <orig reg="center">centre</orig> of a small
                    clearing whcih we had just reached. Fortunately, the horse's cough was a
                    stubborn one, kept up for several moments, and effectually drowned the sound of
                    our footfalls as we circled half around the glade, still keeping the cover of
                    the woods. Then it ceased, and all was as silent as the grave. I distinguished
                    sveral horses out of the dark pile in front of us; and at once took in the
                    situation. This was the picket post.</p>
                <p>Just then one of our men trod upon a stick which cracked beneath his foot. And at
                    once a quick, excited voice called to us.</p>
                <p>"Who comes there?" and almost simultaneously with the challenge, the sentinel
                    fired his piece.</p>
                <p>"Charge them, men!" the colonel cried.</p>
                <p>And there were shots, and yells <orig reg="and">an</orig> running men and
                    snorting horses, and-and-well, that's pretty much all I knew about the fight.
                    Out of a hazy sense of uncertainty as to whether I was on my feet or head, there
                    comes to me the recollection that I started in the charge with the others; that
                    as I started a bush knocked my hat from my head; that half stopping to pick it
                    up, the thought occurred to me that it would be eminently judicious to let it
                    lie there and lay myself down quietly beside it; that by the time I had
                    abandoned the idea and started on, a few straggling shots were winding up the
                    fight. And then, with shame I realized what a record I had made in this my first
                    engagement; and determined that it would never do in the world to say that I had
                    passed though it without firing a gun. So raising my carbine and directing it
                    toward the quarter where I thought the enemy ought to be, I fired perhaps the
                    last shot of the skirmish.</p>
                <p>The suprise had been so complete that there had been little opportunity for
                    resistance. In fact many of our men were in among the prostrate forms of the
                    Federals before they had fairly aroused from their slumbers. A few of them were
                    shot by the first volley before unwinding <orig reg="themselves"
                    >themseves</orig> from their blankets. I believe none of them escaped except the
                    sentinel, who must have dashed away into the darkness before his piece was
                    fairly exploded.</p>
                <p>We supposed there had been no casualties upon our side. But when we all gathered
                    together again, my old friend Nick reported one wounded in the following
                    characteristic style.</p>
                <p>"I come through the fight all right. But while I was standing on the bank after
                    the Yanks had caved, some derned greenhorn let his gun go off behind me and shot
                    me in the heel."</p>
                <p>I didn't say anything.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
