<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0099"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0099">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Memorial Day," by Unknown, June 15,
                    1887</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county memorial day, by unknown june 15 1887</title>
        <author>Unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Doug</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0099</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498511</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Memorial Day," by Unknown, June 15, 1887</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county memorial day, by unknown june 15 1887</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Staunton Spectator, June 15,
                        1887</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1887-06-15">1887-06-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, Patriotism, Reunification, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-12">2005-12-12</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0099T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In the wake of the recent Memorial Day, this article expresses southern wishes
                    for reconciliation and calls for the North to match that sentiment (in the
                    process accusing Republican presidential candidate John Sherman of constantly
                    waving the "bloody shirt" in the North, and accusing northerners of embracing
                    that tactic).</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>ITS LESSON-A STRIKING CONTRAST</p>
                <p>THE STAR-SPANGLED BANNER AND THE "BLOODY-SHIRT"-THE PAST AND THE FUTURE</p>
                <p>The observance on the 9th <abbr expan="instant">inst.</abbr>, of the annual
                    memorial services in honor of the soldiers who sleep in the "bivouack of the
                    dead," was not only remarkable for the great numbers who were present, and the
                    success of every feature of it, for which great credit is due to all who
                    participated in efforts to make it such, but also for the fact that it
                    demonstrated in a most conclusive manner that our people cannot only fraternize
                    with, but cherish esteem and entertain admiration for, the most prominent and
                    efficient officers and men who made vigorous, but fair, war upon their soldiers,
                    whilst they were manly and soldierly enough not to make war upon defenceless
                    civilians, but acted the part of true soldiers in holding the homes of wives and
                    children sacred from intrusion and outrage, as was shown by the cordial manner
                    in which ten thousand of our people, male and female, greeted the presence on
                    that occasion of General W. W. Averill, of New York. It shows how very easy it
                    would be, if the people of the North generally would exhibit a similar feeling
                    of friendship for the people of the South, to make the Union in the future a
                    thousand times stronger than it has even been in the past, as it would then be
                    cemented by mutual esteem and affection, and be united in bonds stronger than
                    "hooks of steel."</p>
                <p>It would seem that the North, which was the stronger and the conquering power,
                    should have been the first to exhibit magnanimity, and to inaugurate
                    demonstrations of fraternal feeling, and to counsel and practice oblivion of
                    past animosities, and to cherish and nourish feelings of national and fraternal
                    friendship. But the South, though the weaker and the conquered and humiliated
                    party,-though overrun and trampled upon during the war, and treated worse for
                    several years after, has gained a prouder moral victory than the North, in that
                    it is the first to conquer feelings of personal and sectional animosity and to
                    extend the hand of friendship and cordial union "across the bloody chasm." In
                    the South, the ensanguined nether garment, yclept "the bloody-shirt," is not
                    known. It is never waved in the southern breeze. Its home is in the North, where
                    it is still waved aloft by politicians chiefly who never smelt gunpowder during
                    the war,-who belong to that valiant class who are "invisible in war, and
                    invincible in peace"-of whom John Sherman, a Republican candidate for the
                    Presidency, is a conspicuous example.</p>
                <p>Whilst our people are, by thousands, greeting with cordial friendship a
                    distinguished Federal General who gave us much trouble during the war; and
                    whilst they are cultivating fraternal and national feelings, John Sherman is
                    making speeches in the West, to advance his candidacy for the Presidency, in
                    which he vigorously waves the "bloody-shirt," and strives to revive the feelings
                    of animosity which existed during the war, and to make the people of that
                    section believe that the citizens of the South are the enemies of the
                    county-that they are rebels and traitors and deserve to be proscribed and denied
                    their just share in the management of the government. He is either very blind to
                    the sentiment that exists there, or else the people there are far behind the
                    South in national sentiments and fraternal feeling. He must either be very
                    unwise, or else the people there are very sectional in their sentiments and very
                    hostile in their feelings. The contrast presented is very striking, and the
                    South occupies the vantage-ground. As we said before, the moral victory-greater
                    than that of arms-is with the South. She waves the Star-Spangled Banner, whilst
                    the Republicans of the North wave the "bloody-shirt." We have an abiding faith
                    that the Star-Spangled Banner will triumph over the "bloody-shirt," and that all
                    will yet be well, and that we will live in peace and harmony as brethren of a
                    common country; and that, in the patriotic and eloquent language of Major Baker
                    P. Lee, in his Memorial address at Norfolk, May 19th 1887, "as one people with
                    one country, we will look backward with a common pride, in contemplation of the
                    valor of both sections. As one people with one country, we will look forward
                    with a common purpose in a common patriotism, for the promotion of the
                    interests, for the maintenance of the honor, for the expansion of the power, for
                    the support of the dignity of our government, without remembering, either on the
                    one side or the other, that there was ever a war between us. We have a great
                    people, a great country, and a great Government, with a glorious past, and, let
                    us hope, with a still more glorious future." So may it be, is our most devout
                    wish.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
