<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0014"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0014">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Inscriptions for Memorial to Women
                    of Confederacy," by W. E. Gonzales, November 1, 1910</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county inscriptions for memorial to women of confederacy, by w e gonzales november 1 1910</title>
        <author>Gonzales, W. E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 9 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0014</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498446</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Inscriptions for Memorial to Women of Confederacy,"
                            by W. E. Gonzales, November 1, 1910</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county inscriptions for memorial to women of confederacy, by w e gonzales november 1 1910</title>
            <author>W. E. Gonzales</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: SHSP, Vol.XXXVIII, p. 359-362,
                            1910</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1910-11-01">1910-11-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-01-27">2006-01-27</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0014T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This is a collection of the proposed incriptions for a monument to the women of
                    the Confederacy in Columbia, South Carolina.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Beautiful Sentiments Composed by Editor W. E. GONZALES, of the
                        Columbia State, for South Carolina's Tribute-Lauds Courage of Southern
                        Soldier and Those He Left Behind Him.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Inscriptions which are to be placed upon the South Carolina monument to be reared
                    to the women of the Confederacy have just been decided upon and made public in
                    Columbia, <abbr expan="South Carolina">S. C.</abbr></p>
                <p>A number of writers complied with the request and the proposed inscriptions were
                    submitted anonymously to a committee. As a result of the work of this committee,
                    the commission has adopted the inscriptions proposed by Captain William E.
                    Gonzales, editor of the Columbia <hi rend="underline">State</hi> and
                    secretary of the commission.</p>
                <p>The two principal inscriptions were selected several months ago, but, owing to
                    delays occasioned by correspondence between the commission and the sculptor in
                    Paris regarding mechanical strictures and other details, the inscriptions are
                    only now available for publication.</p>
                <p>The monument commission asked a committee of five to pass on about thirty of the
                    compositions considered worthy of their consideration. That committee was
                    composed of Miss McClintock, president of the College for Women; Stanhope Sams,
                    Litt. D.; the <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr><abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr>
                    W. M. McPheeters, Professor Yates Snowden, LL. D., and Colonel U. R. Brooks.</p>
                <p>The commission adopted the report of the committee of judges. Captain Gonzales,
                    being a competitor, had absented himself from the meeting and his compositions
                    were selected as the inscriptions for the south and north sides of the monument.</p>
                <p>The four next succeeding compositions were submitted in the order reported by the
                    committee, by <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> George Armstrong Wauchope, head of
                    the English department of the University of South Carolina, by <abbr
                        expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> E. S. Joynes, professor emeritus of modern
                    languages at the university, by the <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr> A. M.
                    Fraser, <pb n="360"/> D. D., of Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, who
                    last summer was invited to become president of the Columbia Theological
                    Seminary, and by W. Banks Dove, formerly superintendent of city schools of
                    Washington, <abbr expan="North Carolina">N. C.</abbr>, and now Assistant
                    Secretary of State. Their respective works are submitted in this article as
                    exhibits A, B, C and D.</p>
                <p>Following is the formal inscription prepared by the commission:<lb/> To<lb/> The
                    South Carolina Women of<lb/> the Confederacy.<lb/> 1861-<abbr expan="1865"
                    >'65</abbr>.<lb/> Reared<lb/> by the Men of Their State.</p>
                <p>The Legislature's part will be conveyed in a line "Enacted by the General
                    Assembly of the State of South Carolina" legible on a scroll being held up to
                    the women by a bronze cupid.</p>
                <p>Following are the two inscriptions accepted for the North and South sides<lb/>
                    (South Side)<lb/> In this Monument<lb/> generations unborn shall hear the<lb/>
                    Voice<lb/> of a grateful People<lb/> testifying to the sublime Devotion<lb/> of
                    the Women of South Carolina<lb/> in their Country's need<lb/> Their
                    unconquerable spirit<lb/> strengthened the thin lines of grey<lb/> Their tender
                    care was solace to the<lb/> stricken.<lb/> Reverence for God<lb/> and
                    unfaltering Faith in a righteous<lb/> Cause<lb/> inspired Heroism that
                    withstood<lb/> the immolation of sons<lb/> and Courage that bore the agony
                        of<lb/><pb n="361"/> suspense<lb/> and the shock of disaster.<lb/> The
                    tragedy of the Confederacy may<lb/> be forgotten<lb/> but the fruits of the
                    noble Service<lb/> of the Daughters of the South<lb/> are our perpetual
                    heritage.</p>
                <p>(North Side.)<lb/> When reverses followed victories; when want displaced plenty;
                    when mourning for the flower of Southern manhood darkened countless homes; when
                    government tottered and chaos threatened the women were steadfast and unafraid.
                    They were unchanged in their devotion, unshaken in their patriotism, unwearied
                    in ministrations, uncomplaining in sacrifices, splendid in fortitude they strove
                    while they swept. In the rebuilding after the desolation their virtues stood as
                    the supreme citadel with strong towers of faith and hope around which
                    civilization rallied and triumphed.</p>
                <p>The other inscriptions, which were already decided upon, are as follows:</p>
                <p>This monument is erected to keep alive in the hearts of future South Carolinians
                    the virtues, services and sacrifices of the women of the Confederacy who, by
                    their constancy, under the trials and sufferings of war by their inspiring
                    sympathy with the men at the front by their tender ministrations to the sick and
                    wounded; and by their material aid and unwavering fidelity to the common cause,
                    have won the undying love and gratitude of the people of the South, and have
                    bequeathed to their children from generation to generation the priceless
                    heritage of their memory.</p>
                <p>To The Women<lb/> of the Confederate South<lb/> Whose Constancy<lb/> Sustained
                    the Courage <lb/> of the Confederate Soldier<lb/><pb n="362"/> in Camp and
                    Field<lb/> Whose Virtue protected his Home<lb/> Whose Service ministered to his
                    needs<lb/> Whose tender care nursed his sufferings<lb/> Whose affection cheered
                    his dying hour<lb/> Whose smile welcomed his return<lb/> And Brightened the
                    Poverty<lb/> of his<lb/> Desolate Home</p>
                <p>They knew their cause was just. They put their trust in God. They gave their men
                    to the war, and cheered them on to immortal deeds and endurance and to death.
                    They ministered to the sick, the wounded and the dying. They braved unspeakable
                    dangers in their defenseless homes. They welcomed poverty as a decoration of
                    honor. In defeat and desolation they inspired the rebuilding of States. They
                    have adorned the whole land with monuments to their fallen heroes.</p>
                <p>Erected in memory of those who in the sorrow of the silence and separation
                    endured the agony of a conflict they might not share, whose courage sustained
                    the Southern soldier amid the carnage of the battlefield, whose love and
                    fidelity soothed the suffering of his sickness, whose gentle hand brushed from
                    his pale face the gathering dews of death, whose faith and fortitude faltered
                    not in the darkest hour, whose inspiration transformed the gloom of defeat into
                    the hope of the future, and whose memory shall not be forgot even in the hour of
                    peace.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
