<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0097"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0097">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Confederate Memorial Day," by Local
                    Department, Wednesday, June 8, 1887</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county confederate memorial day, by local department wednesday june 8 1887</title>
        <author>Local Department, Staunton Spectator</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Doug</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 10 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0097</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498509</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: "Confederate Memorial Day," by Local Department, June 6,
                            1887</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta confederate memorial day, by local department june 6 1887</title>
            <author>Local Department</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Memorial Day,
                            Staunton Spectator, June 8, 1887</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1887-06-08">1887-06-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Military Authority, Patriotism, Reunification, Veterans, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-12">2005-12-12</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0097T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This is a preview of the upcoming festivities for a Civil War veterans' reunion
                    on Memorial Day, written with affection for the veterans, as well as for all the
                    participants in the celebration.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p><hi rend="bold">ORDER OF PROCESSION</hi><lb/> Mounted Police.<lb/> Stonewall
                    Band.<lb/> All Military Organizations.<lb/><hi rend="underline"
                    >Band.</hi><lb/> City Council in Carriages.<lb/><hi rend="underline"
                    >Band.</hi><lb/> Guests in Carriages.<lb/> Ex-officials and officials of
                    Augusta Memorial Association<lb/><hi rend="underline">Band.</hi><lb/> Odd
                        Fellows.<lb/><hi rend="underline">Band.</hi><lb/> Hibernians.<lb/><hi
                        rend="underline">Band.</hi><lb/> Knights of Labor.<lb/><hi
                        rend="underline">Band.</hi><lb/> Sons of Confederate Veterans Mounted<lb/>
                    " " " " on foot<lb/> under command of <abbr expan="Sergeant">Serg't</abbr> J.
                    Alex Bumgardner.<lb/> Dunsmore's Business College.<lb/><hi rend="underline"
                        >Band.</hi><lb/> Staunton Fire and Hook and Ladder Companies.<lb/> Trades
                    Union.<lb/> Citizens on Horseback, in Carriages, and on foot.</p>
                <p>The procession in command of Chief Marshal J. A. Patterson, Jr., will move
                    promptly at ten o'clock. Line of march from corner of Main and New Streets,
                    thence up Main to Thornrose cemetery, returning by Main to Green, up Green to
                    Frederick, down Frederick to Augusta, down Augusta to New Court House, thence to
                    New, up New to Main, thence to the Opera House.</p>
                <p>Organizations will form in the following order:</p>
                <p>Military on New street, south of Main, with right on Main.</p>
                <p>City Council in carriages on South side of Main between Augusta and New.</p>
                <p>Guests on North side of Main between New and Market.</p>
                <p>Odd Fellows on New North of Main with right on Main.</p>
                <p>Hibernians on Augusta North of Main, right on Main.</p>
                <p>Knights of Labor on Augusta, South of Main right on Main.</p>
                <p>Sons of Confederate Veterans on Augusta with right resting on left of Knights of
                    Labor.</p>
                <p>Dunsmere's Business College on Augusta with right on left of Hibernians.</p>
                <p>Fire and Hook and Ladder Companies on New street, North of Main with left on
                    Main.</p>
                <p>Citizens on Market street, North and South of Main.</p>
                <p>Returning to the Opera-House arrangements will be made for seating all
                    organizations and guests.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Order of Exercises</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Address of welcome by the President.</p>
                <p>Prayer by <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr><abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr>
                    Nelson.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="underline">Music.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Introduction of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Averill by <abbr
                        expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Fitzhugh Lee.</p>
                <p>Address of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Averill.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="underline">Music.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Introduction of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Jackson, of Tennessee by <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr> J. D. Imboden.</p>
                <p>Reply of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Jackson.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="underline">Music.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>Introduction of Private Carleton McCarthy by <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> J.
                    C. Shields.</p>
                <p>Reply of Private Carleton McCarthy.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="underline">Music.</hi>
                </p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Announcements.</hi><lb/> FINALE.</p>
                <p>Meeting of Augusta Memorial Association in Council Chamber at 3 P. M. Election of
                    officers, <abbr expan="et cetera">&amp;c.</abbr></p>
                <p>Immediately after the close of the exercises at the Opera-House, all are invited
                    to partake of dinner served by the ladies of the Association at the Skating
                    Rink, the proceeds of which are for the benefit of the monument fund.</p>
                <p>The day will close with a rendition of Paradise and the Peri in the Opera-House
                    by native talent. The success attending this exhibition on a former occasion is
                    sufficient warrant for its repetition.</p>
                <p>COMMITTTEE ON RECEPTION.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Major">Maj.</abbr> Jed Hotchkiss, <abbr expan="Honorable"
                    >Hon.</abbr> J. A. Cochran, H. St. Geo. Tucker, <abbr expan="Esquire"
                    >Esq.</abbr>, <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> A.C. Gordon.</p>
                <p>COMMITTEE TO RECEIVE THE PRESS.</p>
                <p>H.C. Tinsley, <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq.</abbr>, <abbr expan="Honorable"
                    >Hon.</abbr> J. Yost and <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> J.C. Shields.</p>
                <p>THE ROUTE OF TRAVEL BY THE GUESTS-<abbr expan="Governor">Gov</abbr> and Mrs. Lee
                    and party will reach Waynesboro' junction from the southwest on the morning
                    train on the Shenandoah Valley <abbr expan="Railroad">R. R.</abbr> Henry St.
                    Geo. Tucker, <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq.</abbr>, will meet them at the junction
                    on behalf of the Memorial Association. A carriage, drawn by four black horses,
                    will be in readiness for the trip to Staunton. Waynesboro' will be in full
                    demonstration by the people and the street arched in decorative style. Upon the
                    arch in blooming lines will be the inscription, "Welcome to our Fitz." The
                    Waynesboro' escort will be headed by Sergeant E. G. Fishburne of <abbr
                        expan="Company">Co.</abbr> E., First <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                    Cavalry, the command of the Governor in 1861.</p>
                <p>On passing Fishersville, another demonstration will meet the Governor, the
                    whole-souled veteran, <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> O. Benton Coiner, in
                    command. Their large waving banner will float the inscription, "Augusta Welcomes
                    the Governor of Virginia."</p>
                <p>General and Mrs. Averill and party will also arrive at Waynesboro' junction
                    to-day at 2 P. M., and will reach this city by the West-bound train of the
                    Newport News and Mississippi Valley <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> at 5.38 P.
                    M.</p>
                <p>Generals Imboden and Jones and Mr. Carleton McCarthy, the distinguished private
                    and Secretary of the Association of the Army of Northern Virginia, will arrive
                    to-day.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Imboden will be the guest of Judge Jno. Howard
                    McCue.</p>
                <p>THE MEMORIAL DINNER AND DECORATIONS.-The notice now made can only renew to a
                    limited extent of the county the desires of the committees in charge of the
                    Memorial Dinner and the decorations to-morrow.</p>
                <p>Cooked meats and pickles are desired. Send these contributions early in the
                    morning to the Skating Rink.</p>
                <p>The flowers for decorating the graves should be sent to the City Hall. This
                    service will be rendered early in the forenoon. Let the flowers come in, in
                    large quantities, early in the morning.</p>
                <p>BUSINESS HOUSES TO BE CLOSED AND DECORATED.-The committee to wait upon the
                    merchants and tradesmen of the city received a cheerful compliance from all to
                    the request that they would close their places of business and decorate their
                    houses as far as it might be practicable. Doors will be closed at 10 A. M. and
                    remain so till 1 1/2 P. M.</p>
                <p>MEMORIAL ARCHES.-In front of the City Hall and above the Post-Office, spanning
                    Main street, are arches twined in evergreen. Upon each will be the following
                    inscriptions-"Our honored dead"-"Blue and Gray." Few words they are, but
                    comprehensive, beautifully appropriate, and sacred in the affections of all
                    hearts.</p>
                <p>SONS OF THE CONFEDERATE SOLDIERS will be assigned a place in the column. They can
                    appear mounted or on foot. An appropriate place will be assigned them by
                    reporting to one of the marshals.</p>
                <p>A. A. Spitzer, of Richmond, Grand Master of the <abbr
                        expan="International Order of Odd Fellows">I. O. O. F.</abbr> of Virginia
                    has accepted the invitation of the Staunton Lodge to be here on Memorial
                Day.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
