<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0003"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0003">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "B. P. Noland to I. M. St. John," by
                    B. P. Noland, 1878</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county b p noland to i m st john, by b p noland 1878</title>
        <author>Noland, B. P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0003</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498435</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "B. P. Noland to I. M. St. John," by B. P. Noland,
                            1878</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county b p noland to i m st john, by b p noland 1878</title>
            <author>B. P. Noland</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: SHSP, Vol. III, p.107-108,
                        1877</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1874-04-16">1874-04-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Home Front, Military Authority</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-05">2005-12-05</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0003T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This is a letter from former Confederate Chief Commissary B. P. Noland to former
                    Confederate Commissary-General I. M. St. John, in which Noland discusses the
                    state of the Subsistence Bureau in the last days of the Confederacy. Noland
                    writes in response to an inquiry by John. Noland notes that transportation had
                    been mostly destroyed by the last months of the Civil War, crippling the
                    Subsistence Bureau. He also notes that John helped organize an effort to help
                    the Bureau during the last phase of the war.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Middleburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">VA.</abbr>, April 16, 1874.</p>
                <p>Dear General-My absence from home for a month, and the consequent accumulation of
                    business, imposes on me the necessity of making but a brief and hurried answer
                    to your inquiries.</p>
                <p>Had I the time it would give me pleasure to give you, as desired, a full
                    statement of the organization and working of the Subsistence Bureau, and its
                    condition when you were appointed Commissary-General in February, 1865. I have
                    read with care your statement to Mr. Davis of the operations of the Subsistence
                    Bureau during the dark and closing days of the Confederacy, when you were the
                    chief of that Bureau, and so far as I was cognizant of them, or was at the time
                    informed, I think the statement entirely correct. I was Chief Commissary of
                    Virginia, with the rank of Major and Commissary, was stationed in Richmond, with
                    my office in the same building with that of the Commissary-General, and was in
                    close association with him. I think the plan adopted by your predecessor,
                    Colonel Northrop (which was continued by you), for obtaining for the use of the
                    army the products of the country, was as perfect and worked as effectively as
                    any that could have been devised.<pb n="108"/></p>
                <p>Each State had its chief commissary; was laid off in divisions, with an officer
                    in each, and the <hi rend="underline">divisions</hi> subdivided, with agents
                    in each of them. All these officers had the authority to impress supplies; and
                    with this power and the money which was furnished them without stint, all
                    supplies which could be spared from the support of the non-combatants were
                    obtained for the use of the army. The accumulations at the supply depots were
                    regularly reported by the subordinate officers to the Chief Commissary of the
                    State, and by him to the Commissary-General, who, either by general or special
                    order, directed their disposition.</p>
                <p>I recollect well when you took charge of the Bureau, that our condition was
                    almost desperate, not because our supplies were exhausted (though exhaustion at
                    a not remote future was looked to and seriously apprehended), but because our
                    transportation from points where supplies were accumulated had almost entirely
                    failed us. All the railroads were in bad condition, and several of the most
                    important ones had been so damaged by the enemy's cavalry as to be unavailing
                    for the transportation of supplies for weeks at a time.</p>
                <p>Your action was prompt, energetic and efficient. Your appeal for temporary aid
                    from private resources was nobly responded to by the people. The damaged roads
                    were speedily repaired, and very soon we felt, as I well recollect, in a
                    comparatively comfortable condition; and thus we continued until the evacuation
                    of Richmond. I have no means of stating the quantities of supplies on hand at my
                    several depots at or about that time, for all my official papers were burned,
                    but I know that in Richmond, Danville, Lynchburg, Staunton, Charlottesville,
                        <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c.</orig>, the accumulations were large. I left
                    Richmond at 1 o'clock of the night Richmond was evacuated, with orders from you
                    to make Lynchburg my headquarters, and be ready to forward supplies from that
                    point to the army. I never heard of any order for the accumulation of supplies
                    at Amelia Springs. If such order was given it must have been after the
                    evacuation of Richmond was determined on, and when railroad transportation could
                    not be had; prior to that time such order could readily have been complied with.</p>
                <p>Regretting that I cannot make a more full and satisfactory response to your
                    inquiries,<lb/> I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</p>
                <p>(Signed) B. P. NOLAND,<lb/> (Late) <hi rend="underline">Major and Chief
                        Commissary for Virginia, C. S. A.</hi><lb/> General I. M. ST. JOHN, <hi
                        rend="underline">(Late) Commissary-General C. S. A.</hi></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
