<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0094"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0094">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "The Approaching Unveiling of
                    Jackson's Statue. Who Will Speak and Who Will be Present-Preparations for the
                    Event.," by Unknown, July 8, 1891</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county the approaching unveiling of jacksons statue who will speak and who will be present preparations for the event , by unknown july 8 1891</title>
        <author/>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes">7 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0094</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498506</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "The Approaching Unveiling of Jackson's Statue. Who
                            Will Speak and Who Will be Present-Preparations for the Event.," by
                            Unknown, July 8, 1891</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county the approaching unveiling of jacksons statue who will speak and who will be present preparations for the event , by unknown july 8 1891</title>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Staunton Spectator, July 8th,
                            1891</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1891-07-08">1891-07-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Military Authority, Patriotism, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-10-11">2005-10-11</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0094T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This is an article about the upcoming unveiling of the Stonewall Jackson statue
                    in Lexington, Virginia, full of praise for the general and his fellow
                    Confederates and Virginians. This is a great example of the adulation for
                    Stonewall Jackson that gripped the Lost Cause ideology, the South, and even the
                    nation--and in this case, Augusta County--in the late nineteenth century.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Tuesday, July 21st, less than three weeks from this time, the heroic bronze
                    statue of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Stonewall Jackson will be unveiled
                    above the vault, in which his remains now lie, in the Lexington Cemetery. Every
                    effort is now being put forth by the friends and admirers of the great soldier
                    here and elsewhere, to make the occasion a fitting testimonial of the
                    appreciation by his people of his great achievements as well as spotless private
                    life. The affection and admiration in which his memory is held, and the fine
                    railroad facilities of which the town is possessed, will unite to cause such a
                    gathering of old Confederate veterans and friends here as will not probably take
                    place again on Virginia's soil.</p>
                <p>The full details of the program have not as yet been determined.</p>
                <p>This much is known. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Jubal A. Early will on that
                    day deliver an address upon Jackson as a Soldier. This address will be delivered
                    at eleven o'clock from a platform in the grounds of Washington and Lee
                    University. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Wade Hampton will preside, and
                    among the distinguished surviving Confederates who have signified an expectation
                    of being present are <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Beauregard, <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr> John B. Gordon, <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Rosser, <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> W. H. Payne. The
                    procession will be formed on the University grounds, whence it will proceed down
                    Henry street to Main street and up that street to the cemetery, where the Statue
                    will be unveiled. A general's salute of seventeen guns will then be fired by
                    veterans of the Rockbridge artillery with the same cannon with which they won
                    enduring fame at First Manassas.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> James A. Wallker, the only surviving commander
                    of Jackson's brigade, will be chief marshal of the procession. He will arrive
                    here on Saturday, the 18th, and will then select his aids. The veterans of the
                    Stonewall Brigade, 500 strong, will head the procession, and leading them will
                    be the old Stonewall Brigade band. In the line will be the R. E. Lee Camp of
                    Confederate veterans of Richmond, and with them veterans from New Orleans, about
                    175 strong; the Stonewall Camp of Confederate Veterans of Winchester, 150;
                    Confederate Veterans' organization from Baltimore, 400 strong; Confederate
                    Veterans' Camp from Salisbury, <abbr expan="North Carolina">N. C.</abbr>, 200
                    strong; Rockbridge Artillery, 75; Clark County Cavalry, 57, and other veteran
                    organizations, and visiting soldiers who will be present. Following these will
                    come the volunteer soldiers. Among those who will certainly be present are the
                    Second Virginia regiment, <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> J. A. Nulton, of
                    Winchester, commanding, about 300 men.</p>
                <p>THE DECORATION OF THE TOWN.<lb/> The work of decoration has been placed in charge
                    of a <orig reg="committee">committiee</orig> of which Mr. E. L. Graham is
                    chairman. The committee held its first meeting on Monday afternoon in the
                    Franklin Hall and outlined its work, which consists in decorating public places
                    about the town. Most of them are places with which General Jackson was more or
                    less intimately associated when a citizen of Lexington. The places selected are
                    the old Jackson mansion house on Washington street, the Presbyterian lecture
                    room, the Institute, the University Chapel, the Court House and the Franklin
                    Hall. Arches will also be placed on prominent points of the streets through
                    which the procession is to pass.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
