<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0072"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0072">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Virginia Division Notes," by Mrs. A.
                    A. Campbell, 1914</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county virginia division notes, by mrs a a campbell 1914</title>
        <author>Campbell, Mrs. A. A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 9.7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0072</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498485</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Virginia Division Notes," by Mrs. A. A. Campbell,
                            1914</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county virginia division notes, by mrs a a campbell 1914</title>
            <author>Mrs. A. A. Campbell</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 22, p.
                            493, 1914</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-04">2006-02-04</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0072T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>A fondly written update about recent annual convention of the VA Division,
                UDC</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The nineteenth annual convention of the Virginia Division, <abbr
                        expan="United Daughters of the Confederacy">U. D. C.</abbr>, held in Bristol
                    September 23-26, is a happy memory and an inspiring retrospect. The delightful
                    plans made by the hostess Chapter under its attractive President, Mrs. Hagan,
                    were beautifully executed, and ideal weather added to the success of the
                    occasion. From the auspicious "Welcome Evening" to the last note of "Blest Be
                    the Tie That Binds," which preceded adjournment, harmony and enthusiasm were
                    apparent, while the various committees of the hostess Chapter were unremitting
                    in their zeal for the pleasure and comfort of their guests. All business
                    meetings were held in the Hotel Bristol, where delegates were entertained at
                    luncheon each day by the Bristol Chapter. A handsome reception by Bristol
                    Chapter, a reception by Sycamore Shoals Chapter, <abbr
                        expan="Daughters of the American Revolution">D. A. R.</abbr>, and an
                    automobile ride were among the festivities enjoyed by ail the delegates. A
                    charming feature of the meeting was the exquisite music rendered by Bristol's
                    gifted musicians.</p>
                <p>The convention was called to order by Mrs. S. A. Riddick, State President,
                    Wednesday morning. After the reading of the <abbr
                        expan="United Daughters of the Confederacy">U. D. C.</abbr> Ritual, the
                    memorial service was impressively conducted by Mrs. E. H. O'Brien, a former
                    beloved President of the Virginia Division. Many loving words were spoken of
                    those who have entered the life eternal, and the solemn thought was impressed
                    that we know not how soon the "Vale, in aeternum vale" may be pronounced above
                    our dust.</p>
                <p>The roll call of Chapters indicated an attendance of two hundred representatives
                    from the one hundred and thirty-one active Chapters of the Virginia Division.
                    The report of the <pb n="494"/> President depicted a year of fine achievement
                    and steady growth, six hundred and ninety-seven new members being added, one new
                    Chapter chartered, and several others in process of organization.</p>
                <p>The Treasurer, Mrs. L. B. Allen, reported the <hi rend="underline">per
                    capita</hi> tax paid on over nine thousand members and the financial status of
                    the Division satisfactory. Statistics are not given lest the Secretary of the
                    treasury suspect us of hoarding.</p>
                <p>Much regret was felt at the absence of the Second Vice President, Miss Cowan, the
                    Third Vice President, Mrs. Blenner, the Custodian, Miss Berkeley, and the
                    Custodian of the Virginia Division Badge, Mrs. James Mercer Garnett.</p>
                <p>The Fourth Vice President, Mrs. Cabell Smith, who has eminent domain over the
                    junior work, reported the wonderful development in this department, and
                    especially mentioned Mrs. Cassell's five hundred juniors. The flag offered by
                    Mrs. Merchant as Shiloh Director was won by Lee Chapter Auxiliary, of Richmond,
                    and was presented by Mrs. Merchant in appropriate words, to which Mrs. Montague,
                    President of Lee Chapter, gracefully responded on behalf of the Auxiliary.</p>
                <p>The Recorder of Crosses, Mrs. James E. Alexander, reported five hundred and
                    twenty-nine crosses bestowed, and urged the Chapters to file applications one
                    month before date of bestowal.</p>
                <p>The Chairman of the Relief Committee, Mrs. Randolph, reported the increased
                    appropriation from the legislature obtained through her efforts and also the
                    completion of the list of beneficiaries who can be reached by the State Auditor
                    on this fund, and Chapters were reminded that many others are paid by the
                    Virginia Division Relief Fund the monthly stipend of three dollars, contributed
                    by the Chapters to the State Treasurer, Mrs. Allen, and generous support of this
                    fund was insisted upon if these needy old women and others as destitute claim
                    our help.</p>
                <p>The report of the Educational Committee was read by Mrs. Yates McAlpine Wilson,
                    President of Stonewall Chapter, Portsmouth, and increased interest in this work
                    was evident.</p>
                <p>Other committee reports showed that chairmen had been diligent in the discharge
                    of their duties. Chapter reports conformed admirably to the conciseness required
                    and revealed splendid work accomplished. One especially gratifying fact was the
                    number of new members present from recently formed Chapters, promising to become
                    fine material for the extension and upbuilding of the Division and for its
                    future usefulness.</p>
                <p>Mrs. Charles E. Bolling, of the Stonewall Jackson Monument Association, reported
                    that on Flag Day, May 1, $7,163 had been contributed, about half of this sum
                    being raised in Richmond. Those Chapters which had not observed the day were
                    reminded that remittances could still be sent to Mr. E. D. Hotchkiss, Treasurer
                    of the Association, Richmond, and it is sincerely hoped that every Chapter will
                    be proud to have a share in erecting this memorial to our immortal Jackson.</p>
                <p>The two amendments offered to the constitution were carried, one giving to State
                    officers and chairmen of standing committees the privileges of delegates, the
                    other fixing the <hi rend="underline">per capita</hi> tax at twenty-five
                    cents. Several admirable recommendations offered by the State President were
                    unanimously adopted. Much routine business was transacted and some minor changes
                    made in appropriations. The cordial invitation of Danville Chapter and Ann Eliza
                    Johns Chapter to hold the next convention in Danville was gratefully accepted.</p>
                <p>The Historical Evening was a triumph for the State Historian, Miss Preston, whose
                    eloquent tribute to Maury will long be remembered. Mrs. Alexander Stuart, of
                    Abingdon, and Mrs. Frank Anthony Walke, of Norfolk, added greatly to the
                    occasion by charming articles delineating varied aspects of the life of the
                    great pathfinder of the sea. The State flag, offered by Miss Preston as the
                    historical prize, was won by Rawley Martin Chapter, of Chatham, and was
                    presented by Miss Preston in a most attractive speech.</p>
                <p>The time limit retired several valued officers, among them our capable Recording
                    Secretary, Mrs. Merchant, whose fine business capacity and administrative
                    talents have long been recognized in the organization.</p>
                <p>The officers elected are as follows<lb/> President, Mrs. S. A. Riddick,
                    Smithfield.<lb/> Vice Presidents, Mrs. C. W. Sumter, Christiansburg; Miss
                    Shannon, Portsmouth; Mrs. B. A. Blenner, Richmond; Mrs. Cabell Smith,
                    Martinsville.<lb/> Recording Secretary, Mrs. H. H. Andrews, Bristol.<lb/>
                    Corresponding Secretary, Mrs. E. H. Williams, Smithfield.<lb/> Treasurer, Mrs.
                    L. B. Allen, Salem.<lb/> Registrar, Miss Lucy Wood, Richmond.<lb/> Historian,
                    Miss N. C. Preston, Seven-Mile Ford.<lb/> Recorder of Crosses, Mrs. James E.
                    Alexander, Alexandria.<lb/> Custodian, Mrs. J. F. F. Cassell, Staunton.<lb/>
                    Custodian Virginia Division Badge, Mrs. James Mercer Garnett, Baltimore, <abbr
                        expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
