<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0093"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0093">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "Alex. H. H. Stuart. Statesman and
                    Patriot. Venerable in Years, and Admired by his Countrymen, Has passed Away.,"
                    Staunton Spectator, February 18, 1891</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county alex h h stuart statesman and patriot venerable in years, and admired by his countrymen has passed away staunton spectator february 18 1891</title>
        <author/>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes">10 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0093</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498505</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "Alex. H. H. Stuart. Statesman and Patriot. Venerable
                            in Years, and Admired by his Countrymen, Has passed Away.," Staunton
                            Spectator, February 18, 1891</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county alex h h stuart statesman and patriot venerable in years, and admired by his countrymen has passed away staunton spectator february 18 1891</title>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Staunton Spectator, February 18,
                            1891</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1891-02-18">1891-02-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Military Authority, National Government, Patriotism,
                        State Government, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-09-28">2005-09-28</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0093T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This is a lengthy and laudatory obituary for Alexander H. H. Stuart. In the
                    excerpts below, the obituary praises Stuart and also warmly remembers Augusta's
                    role-as relunctant but noble participant-in the Confederacy and the Civil War,
                    while at the same time illustrating the very negative memories of Reconstruction
                    and its legacy that were so prominent at the close of the nineteenth century,
                    throughout the white South.</p>
</div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The Spectator appears <orig reg="today">to-day</orig> in the "habiliments of woe"
                    in honor of the memory and character of a useful, distinguished and honored
                    citizen, a wise statesman, orator and patriot, who has passed away. <abbr
                        expan="The Honorable">Hon.</abbr> Alexander Hugh Holmes Stuart is no more,
                    having died peacefully at his residence in this city about 1 o'clock P. M. last
                    Friday, <abbr expan="February">Feb</abbr>, 13th, at the advanced age of 83
                    years, 10 months, and 11 days, with the reward due a long and useful
                    life-deserved honors, esteem, reverence, and troops of friends. His death causes
                    a void in this community that cannot be filled. For more than half a century he
                    had been a conspicuous memeber of this community, and, during that time, did
                    more than <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> else to advance its interests. In
                    all public enterprises he was in the van. He was the projector of many, and the
                    able and zealous advocate of all. In all that <orig reg="concerned"
                    >coucerned</orig> the interests and advancement of the community, he was an
                    optimist with the most hopeful views, and even in his advanced age, when bowed
                    with the weight of years, he still retained his progressive spirit, ever seeking
                    and suggesting some policy or enterprise that would be beneficial.</p>
                <p>In political questions, as in those of material interests, he was always in the
                    front, and so clearly did he forecast the future, that in many cases he seemed
                    to be endowed with the gift of prophecy. He was not only an eminently useful
                    man, but possessed many of the qualities of a great man. He was not only a man
                    of great intellect and broad views which made him a statesman, but he was, also,
                    an orator in the true sense of the term. He was a man of commanding presence,
                    six feet four inches in height, with a more than usually handsome face, with a
                    dignity of bearing and a courteous manner which commanded respect, and won the
                    esteem and good-will of his audience, His manner as a speaker was very graceful;
                    his voice was melodious and flexible, and readily responded to his emotions; his
                    intellect was strong, enabling him not only to understand the most difficult
                    questions, but to be able to present them so lucidly and to illustrate them so
                    clearly as to enable the common mind to comprehend them readily-thus he was
                    enabled to convince the judgment and by his eloquence to move the hearts of his
                    audience.</p>
                <p>For his ancestry, early life, education, preparation for his profession, and his
                    career therein, we refer our readers to the "Memorial Minute or the Staunton
                    Bar," prepared by his intimate and long-attached friend, <abbr expan="Major"
                        >Maj.</abbr> T. C. Elder, which appears elsewhere in this issue.</p>
                <p>[...]</p>
                <p>AGAIN IN THE STATE COUNCILS</p>
                <p>Mr. Stuart was called by the people of Augusta to serve them again in the State
                    legislature, electing him to the Senate in 1857. He was a member of the body
                    during the Presidential contest of 1860 which resulted in the election of Mr.
                    Lincoln to the Presidency. Great events came rapidly one after another. In the
                    early part of 1861, a State convention was called to take charge of the
                    impending interests of the people and the State government in the fearful crises
                    plainly discerned. Though holding his seat as a member of the Senate, the people
                    elected him with John B Baldwin and George Baylor to the convention,
                    representing the supreme authority of the state and the people, which finally
                    dissolved their relations to the Federal <orig reg="government"
                    >goverment</orig>.</p>
                <p>The history of that period of the war, and subsequents events, and his
                    participation in them is fresh in the minds of the people of this day. He was
                    one of the many noble and leading and wise and patriotic men upon whom the State
                    and Confederate governments and the people leaned for aid and safe counsel, and
                    not in vain. He was among the first and the ablest who strove to prevent
                    conflict, and save the Union, if possible, consistent with the sovereignty of
                    his State and the constitutional rights of the people. And when the war was
                    gradually exhausting our resources, and dark clouds enshrouding our hopes, he
                    was a leader among the people of his county in providing to furnish additional
                    succor from their already depleted store houses of supplies.</p>
                <p>THE SAFETY OF THE STATE AND THE LIBERTIES OF THE PEOPLE.</p>
                <p>The Federal legislation after the war, which dismantled the State and placed the
                    liberties and the rights of the people in the hands of military power, brought
                    upon the scene of troubles without number the gloomiest days of all for the
                    future. In efforts to avert deplorable consequences, and inspire hope by united
                    counsels, a State convention of representatives of the people assembled in
                    Richmond in the latter part of 1867, and, with one heart and mind, Mr. Stuart
                    was called to preside, and to be the chief advisor of the course to be pursued.
                    To the State Committee which he appointed, with Raleigh T. Daniel as Chairman,
                    the most important duties were assigned The Underwood Constitution, if adopted
                    as it came from the convention, which had a majority latent upon evil, and
                    nothing but <hi rend="underline">evil</hi>, for the State and people, would
                    fill our cup of misery to the brim. The remedy of relief was in the proceedings
                    which created what is known as<lb/> THE COMMITTEE OF NINE,<lb/> and through it
                    the way was opened for deliverance, and Mr. Stuart was the chief actor in the
                    drama. That history was recently wrtten by himself at the request of the
                    Virginia Historical Society, and the greatest work of his life, and of
                    importance second to no single occurrence in the history of a people struggling
                    for their safety, is among the valued archives of his State and the country.</p>
                <p>THE LAST TWENTY YEARS.</p>
                <p>The last twenty years of Mr. Stuart's life in many respects may be rated in value
                    to the people of this community and country as were those of his prime manhood;
                    serving again in the House of Delegates; President of the Valley Mutual Life
                    Association; Rector of the University of Virginia; a member of the Board of
                    Trustees of the Peabody Education Fund; President of the Virginia Historical
                    Society, and alive, even down to the last days of his life, to every movement in
                    behalf of the progress and development of his section and the country, and
                    withal exercising a constant watchfulness, and expressing views as the political
                    questions of the times were to be considered, the great old statesman
                    accomplished as so beautifully expressed by Major Elder in the memorial
                    proceedings of the Stautnon bar, all there was of life to crown his labors, and
                    when the summons came to leave the scenes of life, as <abbr expan="Captain"
                        >Capt.</abbr> Bumgardner said in his beautiful tribute to his character, he
                    sought repose in the "sleep that knows no waking"-<lb/> "Like one who draws the
                    drapery of his couch<lb/> About him, and lies down to pleasant dreams."</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
