<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AM0100"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="AM0100">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: "My Childhood Recollections of the
                    War," by A. F. Robertson, January 19, 1915</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county my childhood recollections of the war, by a f robertson january 19 1915</title>
        <author>A. F. Robertson</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes">23</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">AM0100</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498512</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: "My Childhood Recollections of the War," by A. F.
                            Robertson, January 19, 1915</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county my childhood recollections of the war, by a f robertson january 19 1915</title>
            <author>A. F. Robertson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library,
                            The Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1915-01-19">1915-01-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Church/Religious Activity, Family, Home Front, Military
                        Authority, Patriotism, Race Relations, Slavery, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-09-19">2005-09-19</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="AM0100T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This is a sentimental account of late antebellum wartime white southern female
                    childhood, written by the daughter of Augusta County figure A. H. H. Stuart, but
                    epitomizing "Lost Cause" ideas of an antebellum plantation ideal of exotic (even
                    "happy") slaves and bucolic peacefulness: part of a vision that was dominant in
                    the first decades of the twentieth century. This account also contains
                    romanticized and dramatic images of the Civil War and the Confederacy--a part of
                    the larger "Lost Cause" ideology that also put forth the glorified plantation
                    images. And there is a romanticized passage about Robert E. Lee.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>The years go on - yet <orig reg="someone">some one</orig> still tells the story
                    which is never finished - the oft told tale of war and the Confederacy - cavalry
                    and artillery veterans have told it from their point of view - now comes one
                    from the infantry - a child's recollection of the war. If the I's and my's and
                    We's and me's come too often to the front, remember how small is the horizon of
                    childhood, and how entirely the world is bounded by his own little life and
                    emotions.</p>
                <p>Even at the early age of five years the terrible events of war were burnt into my
                    memory with fire and blood. No<del hand="h1">e</del> account of these days would be
                    correct without the relation of domestic life as it then existed, nor could the
                    younger generation understand a child's life in Confederate times without a
                    knowledge of his environments. I shall, therefore, tell the story as I first
                    remember it - at the beginning of the war and again when nearing its close.</p>
                <p>Born in the days of slavery and my childhood having been spent under the old
                    regime, no picture of it would be complete without its background of black
                    people among whom I was raised. My brother and I were the youngest of a large
                    family of grown children, and arrived in this world greatly to the regret of the
                    whole connection. Our white family was largely outnumbered by the colored. The
                    servants connected with the town houses were Aunt Kitty, the cook, and her
                    assistant, Uncle Davy, Uncle Peyton, the carriage driver, John, the butler,
                    Millie, the housemaid, Aunt Rachel, Nancy Ballard, Sarah and Mat.</p>
                <p>It was a great delight to us to steal off to the kitchen where Aunt Kitty reigned
                    somewhat despotically, and as the evening closed and the tallow dip was lighted,
                    to hear kind old Uncle Davy (who had trances) tell of his visits to heaven. We
                    were dreadfully afraid of Uncle Peyton. Mama said we was "an imprudent rascal",
                    but we must not tell on him, for if we did, Papa might sell him - and he had
                    never sold a <orig reg="slave">salve</orig> in his life. John the butler was a
                    terrible character who cut <del hand="h1">on</del>us on the legs<pb n="2"/> with a tea
                    towel if we <orig reg="dirtied">dirted</orig> the dishes or walked over the
                    waxed floors. When we used the plates between meals we licked them well and
                    stealthily replaced them on the pantry shelf. The horrid <del hand="h1">a</del>ogre of my
                    childhood was Nany Ballard, the washerwoman, to whose care I was sometimes
                    committed. Many a weary hour have I sat by the ironing table in fear and
                    trembling, looking into her ugly black face and sick with the smell of sour
                    starch and scorched iron holders.</p>
                <p>Our old black mammies had all died off, and I never remember to have been crooned
                    to sleep on the ample bosom of a faithful slave. My earliest recollections are
                    of being put to bed by two half grown negro girls, Sarah and Mat, by the light
                    of a wood fire in the nursery. If we had been particularly good throughout the
                    day - had helped to carry chips or tote <del hand="h1">wo</del>wood - we were rewarded by
                        c<del hand="h1">r</del>harming stories of wild "critters and <orig reg="haunts"
                    >hants</orig> and <orig reg="spirits">sperrits</orig>" while we trembled in bed,
                    and the little darkies lay full length in front of the crackling fire. Had we
                    been mean and stingy - like <orig reg="poor">po'</orig> whi<del hand="h1">e</del>te trash
                    - refusing to share our taffy or horsecakes - woe betide us!</p>
                <p>Didn't we hear the death watch in the wall, ticking for us - or the screech owl
                    outside calling for us? Didn't we see the "hundred legs" on the wall just
                    waiting till white <orig reg="children">chillun</orig> went to sleep to bore
                    down in their "years"? Can I ever forget the bloody cat I met on the stairs, or
                    the sighs through the garret key hole where old Miss's Spirit used to whisper
                    every night? Shall I ever cease to remember the time my faithful nurse came
                    after me on all fours, a bear skin over her back, a horrid mask on her face! Yet
                    we loved the little darkies, and played happily with them. We had glorious days
                    on top of the chicken coop, eating walnuts and r<del hand="h1">w</del>aw turnips, and
                    grand slides down the ice house, with occasoinal raids on my grandmother's
                    damson trees and current bushes.</p>
                <p>In happy summer days we went to our farm, "Rosebanks" where our bachelor uncle
                    lived; the mill, the barn, the cooper's shop, the servant's quarters, were
                    delightful haunts where the "white <orig reg="children">chillun</orig>" were
                    always welcome. There we visited the old decrepit darkies in their homes - Aunt
                    Sally, who used to spin at a great wheel and who gave us pomegranates and
                    marigolds from her little garden. And there was Granny, a little toothless old
                    woman who smoked a pipe by her fireside, and <hi rend="underline">would</hi>
                    hug us in her bony arms. It was in her cabin I heard for the first time a
                    cricket on the hearth.</p>
                <p>Uncle Jerome brought us partridge <orig reg="eggs">aggs</orig> from the harvest
                    field, and at twilight Uncle Jeff - a silent little yellow man, played for us on
                    the fiddle. Every Saturday "Monkey Jim" <pb n="3"/> came from the farm with the
                    cart. My sister called it her "Ship Africa". "Monkey" drove old Kit at the rate
                    of three miles an hour. "Kit" was a fat, freckled, white mare; "Monkey" was a
                    little black, bald-headed old man. His small flat head was covered with an old
                    slouch hat which rested on a pair of enormous outstanding ears; small furtive
                    eyes, a great wobby nose and scattered rows of teeth set in the kinky hairy face
                    of the little old dwarf, made up an appearance singularly grotesque. Every week
                    he came with what provisions could be gathered from the farm, each time he
                    brought a little "poke" of something for us children. I never heard him speak
                    except to say with a grin "<orig reg="Your uncle">Y' oncle</orig> sent you <orig
                        reg="something">sumpin</orig>"! Aunt Mary Ann always knew where the best
                    apples grew in the orchard, and she let me churn under the cool sycamore tree.
                    She taught me to milk old "Crump" and showed us where Lola hid her litter of
                    darling puppies.</p>
                <p>But best of all I loved my daily ride on John the Baptist - "Bullgy Dingo" my
                    uncle called him, but he said Aunt May was a "Hard Shell", so she raised the big
                    red bull and named him "John the Baptist". The fun in riding him was that he
                    always got up <hi rend="underline">behind</hi> first, and it was so hard to
                    keep from falling off.</p>
                <p>How we loved Aunt Maty Ann! I can see her now - a big, bronze Indian-like woman
                    standing with one hand on her hip and with the other holding a <del hand="h1">g</del>big
                    sea shell to her lips; her face is toward the west for it is sundown, and on the
                    shell she blows a mighty blast to call the laborers home. Then the evening
                    falls, and the hands come in, and as I go to sleep I hear them singing, and the
                    sweet sound of water falling over the mill wheel.</p>
                <p>Such was our early life.</p>
                <pb n="4"/>
                <p>One night I lay on the hearth rug playing with my favorite cat, my father and
                    mother were talking very earnestly, when suddenly a dog howled, the cat sprang
                    up in terror, the door was burst open, and in rushed two masked men with drawn
                    swords, uttering dreadful cries. My heart stood still with horror for they
                    exclaimed "The Yankees are coming to cut off your Papa's head and burn down the
                    house and eat <del hand="h1">u</del>you up". In obeyance to my fa<del hand="h1">h</del>ther's stern
                    commands, off came the masks and two gay young cousins stood disclosed in the
                    bravery of new uniforms and brass buttons - all excitement for the coming fray.
                    That was my first introduction to war!</p>
                <p>The early days of the Confederacy were very gay and interesting to a child, for
                    we lived on excitement and "little pitchers" heard and saw all that was going
                    on. There was music in the streets and gay, young soldiers drilling in their
                    handsome uniforms. The girls cheered them on, throwing flowers and kisses while
                    the band played "Dixie" and the troops went marching by. Indoors they laughed
                    and sang bright war songs, and made haversacks and tobacco bags. My pretty
                    cousin sewed on a beautiful silk flag for "her captain" and my sister said she
                    was making a petticoat for Billy Blank because he wouldn't go to war! Sometimes
                    "Sears Hill" and "Dogwood" were full of tents, and we children used to watch the
                    soldiers standing guard or dragging cannon from the arsenal opposite the Mary
                    Baldwin Seminary. Often they said the Yankees were coming, and one night at home
                    I heard most <orig reg="curious">cruious</orig> noises under the floors and in
                    the garret, something like spirits - only louder. When I went there, my mother
                    and sisters were stooping down over a candle, and with hatchets were pulling up
                    the floors; back in the cra<del hand="h1">k</del>cks and corners they were poking bacon
                    and silver and all sorts of things. I crossed my heart I would not tell, then
                    made all the children wretched by saying that I knew grown up people's secrets
                    which even the Yankees could not find out! But they did come and search the
                    house and steal e everything that was left in the smoke house and store room,
                    and all the bacons except old Brutus, and he was hid in the cellar. Then they
                    cut the spokes in Papa's fifteen-hundred dollar wood wagon! We children went out
                    and cursed the Yankees, and seesawed on the back fence and sang loud as we
                    could;</p>
                <p>"Jeff Davis rides a white horse,<lb/> Abe Lincoln rides a mule.<lb/> Jeff Davis
                    is a gentleman,<lb/> Abe Lincoln is a fool".</p>
                <p>At that time I was very proficient in songs and oaths, which seemed perfectly
                    justifiable on such occasions.</p>
                <pb n="5"/>
                <p>We had very plain fare in those days, so whenever we had "Secsh" pudding or other
                    dessert, <orig reg="someone">some one</orig> raised a little Confederate flag on
                    the dinner castors to celebrate the event. There was a scarcity of evertyhing,
                    and the women went to work knitting socks, and making gloves, and dresses from
                    the lindsey which was woven on the farm. I thought my sisters looked beauitful
                    in their red flannel garabaldi waists and the hats which they made of plaited
                    straw and trimmed with rooster tails. We gathered the balls from sycamore trees,
                    from which my mother made ink, and we helped to make toilet soap and draw the
                    tallow candles out of the deep tin moulds. A "Confederate candle" was a famous
                    Christmas gift, for it lasted nearly winter, and was indeed a labor of love. It
                    was made of yards and yards of cotton wick which we passed slowly through melted
                    bees wax until it became thick and firm; then it was coiled and twisted in many
                    fanciful patterns around a smooth upright <orig reg="stick">sitck</orig>
                    fastened firmly into a wooden block or pedastal. The top of it was lighted and
                    candle unwound, a few inches at a time, as it was needed.</p>
                <p>In the summer time we went barefooted, greatly to my joy, as my shoes, which were
                    made by Uncle Monroe, creaked horribly and were full of sharp wooden pegs. I
                    shall never forget a beautiful little slipper which one of my cousins captured,
                    among other things, when on a cavalry raid. It just fit me, but we could never
                    find the mate. I put it on and sat on my other foot, hoping the children would
                    admire it, and that nothing would happen to make me get up.</p>
                <p>We had few playthings in those days, but no doll ever gave greater delight than
                    my cat "Minnie" dressed up in a baby frock and cap, and no mechanical toys were
                    ever more entertaining than tumble bugs and June beetles we played with out of
                    doors. Every Christmas Aunt Mary Ann sent us great hog bladders from the farm,
                    and at daylight we jumped upon them with our feet, awakening the family with
                    terrible explosions. Our home-made Confederate stockings were never found empty.
                    In the toe there was a big red apple, at the heel, a yellow one, then ginger
                    cakes and apple leather, walnuts, pop-corn, dried persimmons, and taffy made of
                    sorghum molasses. Somehow <hi rend="underline">it</hi> was always wrapped in
                    newspaper and we had to lick a great deal of ink and war news before we detached
                    it from the stocking. Sometimes there was nice roasted pig-tail sticking out of
                    the top. Sometimes a switch or a bundle of ashes - that was for cursing - but it
                    was always the Yankees!</p>
                <pb n="6"/>
                <p>As I grew older it seemed to me the house and the town were always full of
                    soldiers coming and going; tents on the hills one day, the next day, done in
                    great wagon trains. About that time two charming girls came to stay with us. My
                    father called them "refugees", and said the Yankees had driven them out of
                    Winchester because they did so much for our soldiers and were so brave and kind.
                    They made our house very gay and lively with their music and all they had to
                    tell about the war.</p>
                <p>One day a boy told me that "Old Jube" was in town, and that General Lee was in
                    our parlor to see my moother. All of us had heard of General Lee and I
                    determined to see him for myself. Stealing into the front hall and hiding behind
                    the partly open door, I peered into the room. And there, according to my
                    childish fancy I saw <hi rend="underline">a king</hi>, a grand and beautiful
                    man with gray hair, gray uniform and wonderful dark eyes! There was no crown on
                    his forehead or golden sceptre in his hand, yet he was the realization of all
                    that I had read in story books, - it was His Majesty, the King! He saw me
                    peeping through the door, and, rising from his chair, he took me by the hand and
                    led me into the room. He placed his hand upon my curls and said they were
                    pretty, then lifting me upon his lap he gently kissed me on the lips. I was but
                    a child, yet I felt as I did in after years when the Bishop laid his hands upon
                    me - that I had been blessed and consecrated by his touch.</p>
                <p>War was now familiar talk. On Sundays when we went to Church our minister often
                    read out news of battles and lists of the wounded. I recall one
                    especi<del hand="h1">l</del>al day when he told of an impending battle <orig
                        reg="and asked">andasked</orig> the congregation to go home and make lint
                    for the soldiers, how children and grown people, without waiting for dinner,
                    turned down their plates on the table and began to scrape and ravel on them old
                    linen napkins for the wounded. I remember a dark, sad day when teh rain poured
                    in torrents and a long line of gray went marching to the dull thud of a drum. A
                    crowd had collected on the steps of the Baptist Church, and among them,
                    unmindful of the people or the weather, stood a beautiful young woman. Her hands
                    were clasped, her eyes were raised as if in supplication, while on her uncovered
                    head and flowing black hair, the rain beat down unmercifully. Wedded that day to
                    be widowed the next, some strange foreboding had told her. There she stands
                    forever in my memory, more enduring <pb n="7"/> than marble or bronze, a living
                    monument of grief! Later the troops came straggling back, muddy, wounded,
                    footsore, the women faltered not, but with white set faces they comforted and
                    relieved. I stood by my mother's side with averted face, holding sponges and
                    basin, while she dressed the bloody wounds of soldiers just in from the battle
                    line. Five wounded men lay in our house at one time and even the children were
                    kept busy waiting on them. As they convalesced, they amused themselves putting
                    paper shoes on my cats, carving rings out of buttons, and baskets from peach
                    seeds, or cutting watermelon rinds into intricate patterns for sweetmeats. Later
                    on the Blind Institution was taken for a hospital, and in the present chapel
                    were rows upon rows of wonded men on cots; among them moved brave daughters of
                    the Confederacy, ever ready to minister to suffering and alleviate pain. The
                    North basement served as a morgue, and I remember running by in terror of the
                    dead men, longing yet fearing to look in.</p>
                <p>Towards the close of the war when Yankees <orig reg="overran">over ran</orig> the
                    town, old men often asked for guards to protect their homes and families. On one
                    such occasion a young soldier was sent to our house, but hardly had he arrived
                    when he was taken suddenly ill. We had no tolerance for Union troops, yet when
                    my mother looked upon the boy, so near the age of her own young son, she was
                    moved with compassion, and sent us with a pillow for his head, White and
                    suffering he lay beneath the trees, until my father brought him in and
                    ministered to his needs, and my mother provided food suitable for him.</p>
                <p>He proved to be refined and educated, and during the course of conversation he
                    mentioned his father's name-a distinguished one of the North. Unknown to the
                    boy, this gentleman had, before the war, been a warm friend and colleague of my
                    father's. Naturally his story was not believed, but after the surrender my
                    father received a grateful letter from this friend saying the boy owed his life
                    to the kindness of my mother. This youth, for love of adventure, had run away
                    from Harvard, enlisted as a private in the army, and was a son of the brilliant
                    lawyer and statemsan, William M. Evarts of New York!</p>
                <p>Hope grew dim but war went on. The <abbr expan="Virginia Military Institute">V.
                        M. I.</abbr> cadets were ordered to the field and the battle of New Market
                    was fought. A brave young cousin was brought back to us wounded, and my boy
                    soldier brother limped back on blistering feet, only <pb n="8"/> to have his
                    mother wash them with her tears and bind them up for longer marches and watches
                    in the dreadful trenches around Richmond. Our food was low, our servants had
                    gone, some to heaven- some to freedom. We had one stray negro boy who was our
                    cook. Now "Amos" was a lover of melody and a sitter in the sun, and while he
                    played the Jew's harp on the back fence, a Yankee slipped into the kitchen put
                    mud in the cymblins and hunks of chewing tobacco into the boiling cabbage! My
                        <orig reg="father">fahter</orig> was furious and told them both to go -
                        <hi rend="underline">somewhere</hi>, I have forgotten <hi
                        rend="underline">where</hi> - and when they <hi rend="underline"
                    >went</hi> we had no cook and no dinner.</p>
                <p>Out on the fa<del hand="h1">m</del>rm Aunt Mary Ann still blew the big sea shell, but there
                    were none to answer to her call. An old man sat in the mill - his white head on
                    this hand, while the miller looked out of the window and the sound of the
                    grinding was low.</p>
                <p>Then came the last terrible scenes of war. The skies were <orig reg="red"
                    >read</orig> with a great conflagration and soldiers galloped rapidly through
                    the streets. Along the railroad tracks and in the flat below us the depots were
                    on fire. Amidst the crackling, roaring flames, fell flying stones. We heard deep
                    intonations and explosions, as great masses of the arched stone bridge were
                    hurled into the air.</p>
                <p>Standing against this lurid background of smoke and fire, I saw a
                    maje<del hand="h1">x</del>stic old woman; her white hair was flying in the wind. With
                    hands uplifted she pointed to the smoking ruins and like some prophetess of old,
                    called down from heaven wrath and imprecations on the slayers of her sons. So
                    dark, so dreadful is this picture, I will not dwell upon it!</p>
                <p>One day in early spring I was skipping along the road from my grandmother's house
                    when I saw a young man coming quickly towards me. He was greatly excited and out
                    of breath, and as he drew near called out "General Lee has surrendered"! Hot
                    indignation boiled within me and I exclaimed "That's a lie, and you know it".
                    Then I ran rapidly homeward. The tears were streaming down my father's face, but
                    the women sat stolidly gazing at each other and said "The war is over". Yes, the
                    war was ended.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
