<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0006"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0006">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Colonel McClure To Page M. Baker,"
                    by Colonel A. K. McClure, June 11, 1901-April 25, 1903</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county colonel mcclure to page m baker, by colonel a k mcclure june 11 1901 april 25 1903</title>
        <author>McClure, Colonel</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>VCDH Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 19.5  </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0006</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498523</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Colonel McClure To Page M. Baker," by Colonel A. K.
                            McClure, June 11, 1901-April 25, 1903</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county colonel mcclure to page m baker, by colonel a k mcclure june 11 1901 april 25 1903</title>
            <author>Colonel A. K. McClure</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Vol. 21
                            (1913), pp. 339-341</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Patriotism, Reunification, Veterans, State Government, National
                        Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-05-12">2006-05-12</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0006T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Correspondence between Colonel McClure and Andrew Carnegie imploring the latter
                    contribute to the relief of Confederate Veterans and set aside civil War
                    divisions.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>COLONEL McCLURE TO PAGE M. BAKER.</p>
                <p>PHILADELPHIA, April 25, 1903.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Mr. Page M. Baker, New Orleans, <abbr expan="Louisiana"
                            >La.</abbr>-My Dear Friend:</hi> I told you during my visit to New
                    Orleans that I would send you the correspondence I had with Mr. Carnegie about a
                    contribution from him of a million or more in aid of the helpless Confederate
                    soldiers. The original letter to Mr. Carnegie sent by Colonels Hayes and
                    Bonnaffon was entirely their own conception, and they sent it to me because they
                    knew I was personally acquainted with Mr. Carnegie. They are both veteran
                    soldiers and many times wounded in battle. Colonel Hayes is one of the foremost
                    members of the Carlisle bar, and Bonnaffon is treasurer in the office of the
                    collector of the port in this city, and is one of the very few pensioners of the
                    country who, when he was appointed to a government office paying him $3,000 a
                    year, notified the Pension Department that his pension would be restored to the
                    treasury as long as he held a public office, and he has done so for the last
                    four or five years. You will see, therefore, that the appeal to Carnegie was
                    made by Union soldiers of the very best type.</p>
                <p>I was greatly disappointed in Mr. Carnegie's final letter of declination. You
                    will see the answer I made to him, but no reply has ever come.</p>
                <p>This correspondence has been seen by no one outside of the parties to the
                    correspondence with the single exception of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr>
                    Custis Lee. I sent it to him with the request that he see it and return it to
                    me, which he did, and I send it to you with the same instructions, excepting
                    that you are at liberty to take a copy of it if you think proper and return the
                    papers I send you, but at present it must not be published. I desire simply that
                    there shall be in the possession of some one a knowledge of this correspondence,
                    who has seen it and who may some time have occasion to refer to it. You can,
                    therefore, if you wish, take a copy of the letters and then return them to me.</p>
                <p>We had a very delightful time in your city, and, indeed, in the entire journey of
                    8,700 miles through the South and far West and the far North. The generous
                    hospitality extended by your people, and especially by yourself, will always be
                    among the most grateful memories of my life.</p>
                <p>Yours truly, A. K. McCLURE.</p>
                <p>McCLURE TO CARNEGIE.</p>
                <p>PHILADELPHIA, June 11, 1901.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="The Honorable">Hon.</abbr> Andrew Carnegie,
                        Skibo Castle, Ardgay, Scotland-My Dear Friend:</hi> Considering our
                    intimate acquaintance in our earlier days, it is needless to say that I have
                    followed with unusual interest the great strides you have made in the business
                    world and the large accumulation of wealth which you are so generously
                    appropriating in the interest of humanity and the advancement of enlightened
                    civilization. The <orig reg="enclosed">inclosed</orig> letter addressed to you
                    by two of our bravest and best Union soldiers, both of whom were probably once
                    personally known to you, and both of whom yet carry Southern bullets in their
                    bodies, was given to me by them with the request that I should forward it to you
                    with my own views on the subject. Mr. Hayes is a leading member of the Carlisle
                    bar and a many times wounded veteran, and Mr. Bonnaffon is also a wounded Union
                    soldier who made a most creditable record during the war. Coming from them, the
                    appeal they make to you for aid to the crippled and helpless veterans of the
                    Confederacy will doubtless induce you to give consideration to the subject. The
                    suggestion is theirs and not mine, but I heartily <orig reg="endorse"
                    >indorse</orig> every word they say.</p>
                <p>I have been many times through the South during the last more than twenty years,
                    and have each year been more and more impressed with the terrible want that
                    prevails among a considerable class of those who battled for their convictions
                    in the Southern cause. There are not many of them yet surviving, and it would
                    not require a very large amount, relatively speaking, to add very much to their
                    comfort in the sorrowing evening of their lives. I have visited several of the
                    homes which have been established by the Southern States; but the limited means
                    of the Southern people and governments make it impossible for them to furnish
                    relief to any more than a very small percentage of those who, by reason of
                    wounds or broken health in military service, are entirely unable to earn their
                    bread.</p>
                <p>These helpless people were your foes and mine, and we earnestly strove to defeat
                    them; but we are all proud of the heroism they exhibited, and point to their
                    achievements and monuments as telling the story of the gallantry of the American
                    people. The war, sadly as it is deplored, has brought the richest blessings to
                    the whole country. It has given us a measure of advancement which would have
                    been undreamed of in your day or mine, and you have gathered the richest harvest
                    from this matchless progress which was largely stimulated by our great fraternal
                    conflict. You are giving your millions freely to the cause of education and to
                    the cause of humanity. Would it not be grateful to you to add a million or more
                    as a fund to furnish bread to the broken Confederate veterans? The national
                    government cannot do it, as it is forbidden by political expediency. The
                    Southern States cannot do it, because they are financially unable to bear the
                        <pb n="340"/> expense; and I can think of no nobler or better field for your
                    generous philanthropy than to respond to this appeal of two heroic and highly
                    respected Union soldiers by making some provision to temper the sore misfortunes
                    of the disabled Confederate soldiers.</p>
                <p>Yours truly, A. K. MCCLURE.</p>
                <p>CARNEGIE TO McCLURE.</p>
                <p>SKIBO CASTLE, ARDGAY, N. B., 24th June, 1901.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">My Dear Colonel:</hi> Your signature throws me back to
                    the first time I heard or saw you, when you were making a great speech in the
                    legislature at Harrisburg. I have often wondered what your career would have
                    been had you remained in public life and not gone into the editorial sanctum. I
                    sympathize deeply with the Southern people and have tried to show this by
                    contributions to the libraries at Atlanta, Richmond, and other places, also for
                    Tuskegee. You may be sure I shall keep the South in mind, but the form you
                    suggest needs thinking over and does not appeal to me as exactly the best one.</p>
                <p>With every good wish, always very truly yours,<lb/> ANDREW CARNEGIE.</p>
                <p>McCLURE TO CARNEGIE.</p>
                <p>PHILADELPHIA, July 8, 1901.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="The Honorable">Hon.</abbr> Andrew Carnegie,
                        Skibo Castle, Ardgay, Scotland-My Dear Friend:</hi> It was refreshing to
                    receive your very kind letter of the 24th ult., as it recalls some of the most
                    grateful memories of my life. I hope indeed that you will give very serious
                    consideration to the suggestion made by two gallant and wounded soldiers,
                    Colonel Hayes and Colonel Bonnaffon, which I <orig reg="enclosed"
                    >inclosed</orig> to you, for I feel sure that if you understood the conditions
                    of the South you would feel that you could not in any way better use a million
                    or more of money. I am sure it would give more relief to the children of sorrow
                    than any other way that you could expend it.</p>
                <p>I have seen these people in their Soldiers' Homes, which are very limited, and
                    have had every opportunity of knowing how fearfully dependent some of these old
                    soldiers are, with their States and their communities really unable to give them
                    bread. Pubic sentiment has reached a point when such a gift would be generally
                    regarded as a national benefaction, and I most earnestly urge upon you favorable
                    consideration of the proposition.</p>
                <p>Sincerely yours, A. K. McCLURE.</p>
                <p>McCLURE TO CARNEGIE.</p>
                <p>PHILADELPHIA, January 29, 1902.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Mr. Andrew Carnegie, New York City-My Dear Friend:</hi>
                    I was surprised to see your letter addressed to Colonel Watterson and myself on
                    the subject of a contribution from you in support of decayed newspaper men. I
                    certainly never suggested such an application and have made no application to
                    you directly or indirectly for such a contribution. I agree entirely with the
                    views expressed in your letter. Colonel Watterson in his enthusiasm, that seems
                    to have been inspired by the very cordial reception he received here when I
                    presented him to the Pen and Pencil Club, came out with his public appeal to you
                    in support of the home for newspaper men. That was my first knowledge of his
                    purpose to make such an application. I know of no class of men that is so well
                    able to take care of its own brethren who should become superannuated in
                    newspaper work as the journalists of the country; and while I am heartily in
                    sympathy with the movement to establish a home for those who may need it, I
                    believe that the plan now in course of execution will be quite equal to its
                    accomplishment.</p>
                <p>You will remember, my dear old friend, that some months ago I wrote you in
                    Scotland transmitting a personal appeal to you from two of our bravest and best
                    Union soldiers, both bearing honorable scars, appealing to you for a
                    contribution in aid of the helpless Confederate soldiers of the South, as
                    previously stated. I have been much through the South during the last twenty
                    years, and have watched the advancement of that heroic people under the most
                    adverse circumstances with intense interest. Even in their extreme poverty they
                    have done something for the utterly helpless soldiers of the South; but there
                    are very many to-day who are in absolute want, and the Southern States are not
                    able to give them the needed aid.</p>
                <p>I never was more earnest nor sincere in my life than in the appeal I made to you
                    to devise some plan to aid the utterly helpless and breadless Confederate
                    soldiers of the South. We have made provision for our Northern soldiers with the
                    most generous liberality, as is shown by our payment of nearly $150,000,000
                    annually for many years in support of pensioners and Soldiers' Homes, and those
                    who are capable of filling civil trusts are by law given the preference. The
                    sectional bitterness between the North and the South has perished; the soldiers
                    of the blue and the gray have been side by side in the recent war with Spain in
                    support of the flag, and I think the time has come when some great
                    philanthropist like yourself could render the greatest possible service with the
                    same amount of money by appropriating a few millions for the support of the
                    entirely helpless Confederate soldiers of the South.</p>
                <p>In your answer to me you seemed to appreciate the claims of the Southern soldiers
                    for some recognition, but doubted the method I suggested. I now beg to renew the
                    proposition, and ask you to give it careful thought and to evolve some plan
                    satisfactory to yourself by which you can rear what I believe would be ever
                    regarded as the greatest monument you will leave to testify to your tireless and
                    most generous efforts in well-doing.</p>
                <p>Yours truly, A. K. McCLURE.</p>
                <p>CARNEGIE TO McCLURE.</p>
                <p>NEW YORK, 1 February, 1902.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">My Dear Friend:</hi> I have forgiven the Southern
                    soldier, but I could not bring myself to give for his support as such. I have
                    forgiven General Lee for his blunder, but I do not like to see his statue in the
                    Hall of Fame.</p>
                <p>These people made a sad mistake, having struck at their country.</p>
                <p>I am afraid that I forgive, but do not forget, which the humorist says is trying
                    to settle with the Lord at fifty per cent on the dollar.</p>
                <p>I should really like to see you and shake you by the hand again, and this is one
                    of the ends I shall have in view next visit to Philadelphia. You are one of the
                    few still with us who stand for auld lang syne.</p>
                <p>Sincerely, with every good wish, ANDREW CARNEGIE.</p>
                <p>McCLURE TO CARNEGIE.</p>
                <p>PHILADELPHIA, February 3, 1902.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Mr. Andrew Carnegie, New York City-My Dear Friend:</hi>
                    Thanks for your very kind letter. I am sorry you take the view you do of the
                    Southern people, but I know that I am an exception to the general rule in my
                    views. I was much in the South beginning five years after the war and for twenty
                        <pb n="341"/> years thereafter, and the fact that I did not find a man in
                    the South whose acquaintance I thought worth cultivating who did not go with his
                    people in the War of the States taught me to judge them generously. They fought
                    as bravely and earnestly as we did and for a principle that they had maintained
                    from the foundation of the government and that never had been overruled until it
                    was finally settled by the terrible arbitrament of the sword. I have forgiven
                    them, although I was one of the few in the North who suffered very severely by
                    the ravishes of the war, because I know that they were just as sincere as I was;
                    and the monuments which they have erected in the South may now be accepted as
                    monuments, not to the Confederates, but as testimonials of the heroism of the
                    American people. However, you have settled the question, and that ends it.</p>
                <p>I want very much to see you and have a chat with you. I am crippled in hand and
                    foot and get about very badly, but otherwise never was in better health in my
                    life and able to do as much work as at any time. One by one our old friends are
                    dropping out until very few remain; and as the circle is lessening, it becomes
                    more and more sacred. When you get over this way let me know in advance and we
                    will cross legs and have a good talk.</p>
                <p>Sincerely yours, A. K. McCLURE.</p>
                <p>COL. A. K. McCLURE.</p>
                <p>Colonel McClure was editor in chief of the Philadelphia Times from 1873 to 1901.
                    His fame as a statesman and a patriot extends from the Atlantic to the Pacific.
                    The following interesting incident was related by <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col.</abbr> T. T. Wright, of Nashville, in a tribute to Colonel McClure when at
                    the time of his death the flag over the Statehouse at Nashville was hung at
                    half-mast as a testimony of the Southern people's appreciation of his friendship
                    for them:</p>
                <p>"Colonel McClure was as loyal to the South as though he were Southern-born. This
                    in the face of the fact that the Confederates burned his magnificent home near
                    Chambersburg, <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr>, during the war. <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Page Baker, of New Orleans, told me of that
                    incident. Colonel Baker was in <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Robert E. Lee's
                    command, and the Confederate army was marching through Pennsylvania. Near
                    Chambersburg Colonel Baker noticed a splendid residence surrounded by beautiful
                    lawns. On the porch of the residence stood an aristocratic woman curiously
                    watching the army pass. Colonel Baker approached her and asked for a glass of
                    water. She graciously obtained it for him, and they had a five-minute chat,
                    during which the lady spoke of some of the Confederate soldiers despoiling her
                    grounds. Colonel Baker offered to place a guard around the property to protect
                    it, but she showed him a note from General Lee in which he expressed regret at
                    the action of his men and offered to do anything in his power to protect her
                    property. A few days later, when the army again passed the place, the
                    magnificent residence was in ruins.</p>
                <p>"Even after that treatment Colonel McClure did not let his sorrow or his anger
                    interfere with his love for the South. On one occasion, when given a reception
                    in Birmingham, some one remarked to Colonel McClure that the Confederates should
                    not have burned his property. 'Ah !' replied McClure, 'but General Sherman
                    should not have used the torch in the South, either.' From this one incident you
                    may catch a glimpse of the liberality, the broad-mindedness, and the splendid
                    character of the man.</p>
                <p>"Any project in the South which seemed worthy of encouragement received Colonel
                    McClure's hearty support," Colonel Wright added to his tribute. "His influence
                    has caused millions of dollars to be invested in the Southern States. He scorned
                    financial profit from his efforts to increase the prosperity of the South, and
                    nothing could induce him to give space in his publications to any project which
                    he deemed unworthy of support."</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
