<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0044"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0044">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Complimentary," by Unknown, January
                    1, 1915</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county complimentary, by unknown january 1 1915</title>
        <author>Unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 6.4 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0044</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498556</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Complimentary," by Unknown, January 1, 1915</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county complimentary, by unknown january 1 1915</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: "Complimentary," Kauffman's
                            Progressive, January 1, 1915; originally printed in the "Greencastle
                            Pilot" Volume 3, No. 43, Nov. 13, 1862; edited by James W.
                        M'Crory</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1915-01-01">1915-01-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-14">2006-02-14</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0044T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In 1915, Kauffman's Progressive reprinted this article--originally published in
                    1862--written by some of the volunteer militia men who were called to
                    Pennsylvania to protect against invasion, which describes the good deeds
                    citizens of Greencastle performed for the volunteers.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Among the many fine things said by our contemporaries, in regard to the
                    hospitality extended by our people to the volunteer Militia-who rushed to arms
                    so promptly to defend our border-we find the following elegant compliment in the
                    Western Star, published at Beaver, <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> The
                    entire sketch of the campaign, written by the editor-O. S. Long-is so
                    interesting that we are sorry we have not the space to publish it entire:</p>
                <p>"But, before leaving Greencastle, it is fitting that we speak of the kindness of
                    the people manifested to us in various ways, <orig reg="everywhere">every
                    where</orig> we were welcomed and treated with much courtesy and respect.</p>
                <p>"Numerous instances of grateful benevolence came under our observation and there
                    was scarcely a man in our company, at least, who was not the recipient of some
                    mark of favor from the inhabitants during our stay in the vicinity of
                    Greencastle.</p>
                <p>One or two examples I will mention. On Sunday night, after, our weary march from
                    Hagerstown, six tired and hungry soldiers went to the town, hoping to he able to
                    purchase at one of the taverns, a supper something better than could be had in
                    camp. They went together from one tavern to another, receiving everywhere the
                    declaration that nothing to eat could be obtained. Dispirited and almost sick,
                    they were about to return disappointed to the camp, when as a last resort, they
                    entered the back yard of a private dwelling and stated their wants to a lady
                    whom they found there. With true womanly kindness she ministered to their
                    necessities and soon prepared for them a supper such as, in the estimation of
                    the soldiers, a monarch might have envied. We ascertained that the name of the
                    noble lady to whom we were indebted for supper that night, is Miss _____
                    Fatzinger, and though the act of charity was in itself a small one, yet, it
                    indicated the right kind of a spirit. It is now long past, but by neither of the
                    six soldiers will it be forgotten, and we now publicly renew to her expressions
                    of thanks.</p>
                <p>"To Mr. Allison, a substantial farmer living about a mile from Greencastle, we
                    are also under many obligations. He and his estimable and accomplished wife gave
                    us food and shelter for the night, and to him we are indebted for a visit to the
                    battle-field of Antietam. We might enumerate many other instances of kindness
                    bestowed upon us by the the citizen of Greencastle and vicinity but these must
                    suffice. Our duty as historian would be but imperfectly discharged, however, did
                    we fail to mention the effect which "a little brief authority" had upon our
                    Brigadier <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Kneass of Philadelphia. On Wednesday
                    morning before we left Greencastle, a number of us went to a hotel for
                    breakfast. When the bell rang we crowded into the dining room, and took seats at
                    the table. <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Kneass, with some of his staff had
                    already taken seats and were eating when we came in, <orig reg="whereupon">where
                        upon</orig> he became highly indignant that Privates should be permitted to
                    eat at the same table with his highness, and, when the landlord remarked that he
                        "<orig reg="considered">donsidered</orig> one man as good as another," for
                    the heresy, the <orig reg="General">Gerneral</orig> promptly ordered him under
                    arrest."</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
