<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0051"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0051">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Speech of Jefferson Davis," by
                    unknown, June 7, 1871</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county speech of jefferson davis, by unknown june 7 1871</title>
        <author>unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>VCDH Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 10 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0051</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498563</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Speech of Jefferson Davis," by unknown, June 7,
                            1871</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county speech of jefferson davis, by unknown june 7 1871</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: The Valley Spirit (Chambersburg,
                            Pennsylvania), June 7, 1871, p. 2</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871-06-07">1871-06-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Military Government, National Government, Reunification, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-05-13">2006-05-13</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0051T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>The Valley Spirit prints excerpts of a Jefferson Davis speech decrying
                    Reconstruction to challenge "lost cause" characterizations of his address.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Mr. Davis made a speech at Atlanta, Georgia, last week, which Radical journals
                    are denouncing as an attempt to <orig reg="resuscitate">recuscitate</orig> "the
                    lost cause." They charge that he is still rebellious and intends "to fire the
                    Southern heart" again. We can not so construe his speech. On the contrary, he
                    makes a distinct disclaimer of any such intention. We quote the following
                    extract from his address:</p>
                <p>There are many things which I might say to you to-night, but which I feel it
                    would be imprudent for me to utter. If I should speak to you of the past I
                    should speak of memories that are sad. If I should speak to you of the present
                    it would be to recount a tale of tyranny and wrong that we have not the power to
                    redress, and under which, therefore, it is more manly and noble for us to fold
                    our arms and suffer with quite and patient dignity. If I speak of the future,
                    then, I am liable to be misrepresented, and you held responsible for every
                    speculation that I may choose to utter. But, my friends, as I stand here
                    to-night and look upon your kindly, honest faces I feel that there are a few
                    plain words that may be received by you as the expression of my opinion in
                    regard to the future. Then, I say, I despair not of your liberty. I despair not
                    of the triumph of liberty. I believe that truth will live eternally, and that
                    wrong cannot always endure. When Galileo was bound to the torture rack for
                    asserting his theory that the world was a globe and turned upon its axis and was
                    there forced to recant, as soon as the screw was relaxed he cried out of the
                    deep and irresistible convictions of his soul, "But it still moves." And so the
                    great truths uttered by your fathers still live, and the principles they
                    enunciated and for which they contended still move, and will once more be felt,
                    if you will but be true to the right. <hi rend="underline">Let no one say that
                        I counsel a recovery and an enjoyment of these principles by the red hand of
                        battle. I trust that I may not be misrepresented upon this point.</hi> I
                    shall die in the firm faith and belief that the era of true liberty will ere
                    long dawn upon the South. <hi rend="underline">If they who carried the
                        victorious banner and exulted in the strength of their triumph could have
                        known, when you came forward and said that you had given up your arms and
                        were now ready to submit to the laws of the land, and could have understood
                        how true your word was, how high were your principles of honor, it would not
                        have been necessary to exact harsh pledges and to pass oppressive laws to
                        bind you</hi>. (Applause.) <hi rend="underline">Force should never have
                        been exerted when the unimpeachable word of a Georgian was pledged, for the
                        world cannot furnish bayonets enough to make a Georgian prove more faithful
                        to his obligations than his oath could do</hi>. (Applause.) Peaceful,
                    then, you are desirous of being to-day; peaceful you have been, peaceful you are
                    ever. When human patience has sometimes given way there are those who sometimes
                    take the law into their own hands, because there is no justice to be served in
                    any other way; but these are mere accidental occasions. There is no organization
                    in the South-there never was-whose purpose is resistance to the Government. (A
                    Voice-"That's so.") Though we are compelled to submit to the presence of power,
                    yet our manhood and our self-respect can be preserved. Peace is what we hope
                    for, peace we desire, and peace we will have. I have nothing to say to you
                    to-night of politics, and, my friends, I hope you have nothing to do with them.
                    You have political power, and its exercise is only postponed until the coming of
                    that event which I certainly anticipate-the restoration of your constitutional
                    rights. (Applause.) Let us, then, stand still and quietly await developments.
                    The men of the North, like yourselves, love their government and understand
                    their rights, and men of the north have no idea of surrendering in their own
                    country those great bulwarks of constitutional liberty, the right of trial by
                    jury, the right to elect their own officers and the right to determine their own
                    internal policy, and as soon as their prejudice and hatred against the South are
                    removed and they see that by the unlawful action of those in power toward the
                    South these sacred rights of theirs are in danger of being invaded, they will
                    become your adjuncts and you will hold the balance of power and in that hour
                    your power will be great and your success will be great. (Applause.)</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
