<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0018"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0018">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "The Burning of Chambersburg," by A.
                    K. McClure, 1905</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county the burning of chambersburg, by a k mcclure 1905</title>
        <author>McClure, A. K.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>VCDH Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 24</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0018</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498535</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "The Burning of Chambersburg," by A. K. McClure,
                            1905</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county the burning of chambersburg, by a k mcclure 1905</title>
            <author>A. K. McClure</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>12 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Old Time Notes of Pennsylvania,
                            Vol. 1, Ch. LXVI (pp. 158-169), 1905</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Economy, Home Front, Military Authority, Troop
                        Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-05-15">2005-05-15</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0018T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Description of the burning of Chambersburg that hiasizes the connection between
                    General Hunter's harsh treatment of Lynchburg and his incompetence and the
                    Confederate motive and opportunity to attack the town.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Chambersburg Destroyed by the Brutal Vandalism of Hunter in the Lynchburg
                    Campaign-Its Destruction Made Possible by Hunter's Military Incompetency-Reports
                    of McCausland's Movement from Mercersburg to Chambersburg-The Vandalism of Many
                    Intoxicated Confederates While the Town Was Burning-A Heroic Woman Saves One of
                    the Author's Houses and Barn-Chambersburg Could Have Been Fully Protected by the
                    State Force Organized by Governor Curtin, but It Was Sent to the Potomac to Save
                    Hunter.</p>
                <p>NEXT to the battle of Gettysburg, the echoes of the most thrilling event of the
                    Civil War in the North come from the burning of Chambersburg on the 30th of
                    July, 1864, by a Confederate cavalry force under the command of General
                    McCausland, and it is only in vindication of the truth of history that I state
                    that the destruction of Chambersburg was chiefly, or wholly, provoked by the
                    brutal vandalism of General Hunter in the Lynchburg campaign, and its execution
                    was made possible by his military incompetency.</p>
                <p>Hunter succeeded Sigel in command of the Shenandoah Valley in the spring of 1864,
                    and was ordered by General Grant, then battling with Lee south of Spottsylvania,
                    to advance upon Lynchburg and destroy the enemy's lines of communication and
                    resources at that point. On the 5th of June General Hunter met a comparatively
                    small force of the enemy at Piedmont, and defeated it, and after its retreat he
                    formed a junction with Crook and Averill at Staunton and marched toward
                    Lynchburg by way of Lexington, where he arrived on the 10th. Hunter lost his
                    opportunity to <pb n="159"/> capture Lynchburg by his delay at Lexington, where
                    he was guilty of many brutal acts of vandalism, such as the burning of the
                    private residence of Governor Letcher, the Military Institute, and taking away
                    or destroying memorable statues connected with the university founded by
                    Washington and bearing his name. When Hunter arrived in front of Lynchburg, he
                    found that General Earley had been ordered by Lee to make a forced march to meet
                    him, and Earley occupied a position of such strength that Hunter declined to
                    give battle. He explained that his failure to engage Earley for the capture of
                    Lynchburg was his want of adequate ammunition, but if the statement is to be
                    accepted as the true one, it simply proved the incompetency of a commander going
                    into an enemy's country, so far from his base, with an army helpless for want of
                    ammunition.</p>
                <p>Hunter retreated along the Gauley and Kanawha Rivers to the Ohio, and returned to
                    his base at Harper's Ferry by the Baltimore &amp; Ohio Railroad. His
                    circuitous retreat uncovered the valley, and enabled Earley not only to take
                    possession of it, but to advance upon Washington, defeat General Lew Wallace at
                    the Monocacy on the 9th of July, and compelled Grant to send Wright's corps from
                    the Army of the Potomac to save the Capital. When Earley reached the outer
                    defenses of Washington he found that General Wright was there with his corps,
                    and that it was impossible for him to make a hopeful assault upon the Capital.
                    He hastily fell back and reached Martinsburg with a vast train of supplies that
                    had been gathered in his march. Hunter had arrived from the West when Earley
                    reached Martinsburg, and he crossed the river and gave battle to Earley, but was
                    defeated and compelled to recross the river and place his command in a defensive
                    position between Hancock and Harper's Ferry. General <pb n="160"/> McCausland's
                    cavalry brigade was on Earley's left, and General Averill's Union cavalry
                    brigade on Hunter's right.</p>
                <p>On the 28th of July General Earley directed McCausland to take his own mounted
                    brigade and the cavalry brigade of General Bradley T. Johnson, numbering in all
                    nearly 3,000 men, and proceed to Chambersburg, where he was ordered to levy a
                    tribute of $100,000 in gold or $500,000 in United States currency, and to burn
                    the town if the requisition was not responded to. On the 29th McCausland crossed
                    the Potomac at Cherry Run and McCoy's Ford, and advanced by way of Clear Springs
                    and Mercersburg upon Chambersburg. The people of the town were advised by
                    telegrams from Mercersburg of the advance of McCausland's command, and a scene
                    of indescribable confusion ensued. The money in banks and as much of the
                    property in stores as could be gotten away were hurriedly shipped to distant
                    points, but it was known that General Averill's command was somewhere near
                    Hagerstown with railway communication, and General Couch, who was in command of
                    the department with his headquarters at Chambersburg, confidently expected to
                    have General Averill's force there before McCausland could arrive, if he
                    continued his advance toward the town.</p>
                <p>When McCausland started on his raid the enemy's division of Rhodes and Ramsler,
                    and the cavalry brigade of Vaughan, crossed the river at Williamsport. Vaughan
                    moved on as far as Hagerstown, <abbr expan="Maryland">Md</abbr>. Averill was
                    thus threatened on both flanks, and fell back into Pennsylvania, reaching
                    Greencastle, only twelve miles from Chambersburg, by sundown of the day that
                    McCausland marched from Mercersburg to Chambersburg. Averill's command could
                    easily have been brought to Chambersburg in two or three hours. <pb n="161"/>
                    When General Couch found that McCausland was continuing his march to
                    Chambersburg, having passed through Mercersburg to the <orig reg="Pittsburgh"
                        >Pittsburg</orig> pike, he sent three urgent <orig reg="dispatches"
                        >despatches</orig> to Averill, at Greencastle, which were given to Averill's
                    own orderlies for immediate transmission to him, but to these Couch received no
                    reply, and near daylight, when McCausland had his command in line on Federal
                    Hill, where his guns commanded the town, Couch was compelled to hurry away in
                    the last train held for the purpose, with his staff and a few orderlies, they
                    being the only force he had in the place. He had a home guard in the town, of
                    which I was a member, and we were sent out to picket the road along which
                    McCausland was supposed to be advancing. As we were expected to hide in fence
                    corners, I changed my dress for an old suit that could not be damaged by any
                    amount of exposure, and left my watch, pocket-book, etc., in the bureau drawer
                    at home. We remained out on the picket line for two or three hours, when General
                    Couch sent word for us to return, as the enemy was approaching, and we should
                    not be exposed to danger, as we could accomplish nothing.</p>
                <p>I went directly to the headquarters of General Couch, and remained with him until
                    early the next morning, when McCausland's command was within a few miles of
                    Chambersburg. Couch had no force at Chambersburg beyond a little squad of less
                    than twenty men under the command of an Irish corporal. They were sent out early
                    in the day, and they advanced until they saw the signs of the enemy's approach,
                    but they did not permit themselves to be seen, nor their presence made known to
                    the enemy until after dark, when the gallant corporal so maneuvered his handful
                    of men that McCausland supposed he was confronted by a regiment, and so stated
                    in his official <pb n="162"/> report. The corporal knew the roads perfectly, and
                    he had his men scattered, and every now and then fired as the enemy appeared to
                    be approaching. So admirably did he manage his little force that McCausland was
                    not able to advance between Mercersburg and Chambersburg any faster than two
                    miles an hour. Toward daylight the corporal returned to headquarters and
                    reported that the enemy's force was about 3,000, and was then within two miles
                    of the town. As Couch could get no communication from General Averill, he was
                    entirely helpless and notified his staff and the little band of men who had been
                    fighting all night, that the train he had had in readiness for some time would
                    leave in half an hour.</p>
                <p>I had left my home the year before, when Lee's army came, because of reliable
                    admonitions that I should avoid capture, but as this was only a raid that could,
                    at the most, last for a few hours, as we hoped to have Averill come to our aid
                    at any time, I refused General Couch's earnest appeal to accompany him, and
                    started out to my home, only to find my wife and family much more concerned
                    about getting me away than about the advance of the enemy. Couch sent a staff
                    officer to my house renewing the appeal for me to leave, and just then a close
                    friend drove up in front of my house in a buggy, stopped and insisted upon me
                    going with him. I accepted his invitation, as I hoped to be able to return to
                    Chambersburg the following day, and we drove to Shippensburg, but before noon we
                    had the first reports from Chambersburg that the town was in flames and
                    vandalism running riot. In the evening my wife and family joined me at
                    Shippensburg and reported that only the family Bible had been saved from the
                    house, as it was picked up by Mrs. McClure's mother as she took her departure,
                    and an oil portrait of myself that hung in the parlor had <pb n="163"/> been
                    hastily torn from the hook by Miss Reilley, who escaped with it through the back
                    door.</p>
                <p>The <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr><abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> Niccolls,
                    then pastor of the Chambersburg Presbyterian church, resided quite close to my
                    home, and when he found the squad enter it he hastened to the house and gathered
                    up a number of my clothes, but they were rudely taken from him and thrown into
                    the fire. The work of burning the town was performed in the most hurried and
                    brutal manner. Many of the command became wildly intoxicated from the liquors
                    they found in the saloons and cellars, and while a large portion of the command
                    revolted at the vandalism exhibited by many, they were powerless to prevent it,
                    and for several hours the command was engaged in plundering and firing all the
                    buildings in the center of the town. Bradley Johnson was the active commander,
                    and he was most vindictive and merciless. He had left his home at Frederick,
                    where he was a lawyer in good practice, to join the Confederacy, and when Lee's
                    army marched through Frederick two years later, by Johnson's order his own home
                    was burned, as he never expected to be able to occupy it again, and his lot was
                    cast with the people who regarded all in the North as implacable foes.</p>
                <p>Fortunately, this burning of Chambersburg occurred in daylight of a sunny
                    midsummer day, and the sick and feeble were all removed from the peril of the
                    flames. When the work of the destruction of the town had been well under way,
                    two squads were ordered out to destroy the property that belonged to me on a
                    farm at the edge of the town. Captain Smith, son of ex-Governor Smith, of
                    Virginia, headed the squad that burned my residence and barn. Mrs. McClure was
                    ill, but able to be about in her room; and Captain Smith himself entered her
                    chamber and notified her that she must be out of the house within ten minutes.
                    She asked <pb n="164"/> permission to take some valuable mementoes from the
                    home, but it was rudely denied. She then reminded him that the same command, or
                    part of it, had camped on the place under General Jenkins, who commanded the
                    advance of Lee's army in the Gettysburg campaign, that the barn was their
                    hospital, and that she herself ministered to them, and handed him a letter
                    written to her by one of the sufferers when they moved toward Gettysburg; but in
                    ten minutes both barn and house were enveloped in flames-the barn containing the
                    entire crops from the large farm. Mrs. McClure and those with her walked several
                    miles in the country, where they were finally taken charge of by a neighbor and
                    driven to Shippensburg.</p>
                <p>On the southern end of the farm there was a brick residence and small barn, and
                    Colonel Gilmore, of Baltimore, commanded the squad that was ordered to destroy
                    the buildings. He rushed into the house and found Mrs. Boyd and her two children
                    at breakfast. They were rudely and peremptorily ordered to leave the house at
                    once, as he had orders to burn it and could not delay for a minute. She asked
                    permission to finish her breakfast, but it was refused. She was a woman of
                    heroic mold, and the wife of one of the most gallant troopers of the border,
                    Colonel Boyd, later known in Philadelphia as connected with the publication of
                    our "City Directory." She arose from the table, bidding her children to prepare
                    at once to leave, and while they were gathering their little belongings, she
                    said to Colonel Gilmore: "Do you know whose house this is?" To which he answered
                    "Certainly, it is Colonel McClure's," and Mrs. Boyd replied: "The house belongs
                    to him, but it is now the home of myself and children, and of my husband,
                    Captain Boyd, of the Pennsylvania cavalry," to which she added that Colonel
                    Gilmore could now proceed <pb n="165"/> to the destruction of the property. He
                    at once lifted his hat and answered that he would not burn the home of so
                    gallant a soldier, and he made a hurried retreat from the place.</p>
                <p>Captain Boyd was the most notorious scouting trooper on the border, and his name
                    was as familiar in Virginia as Moseby's was in Pennsylvania. Gilmore well knew
                    that if he burned the home of Captain Boyd, a score or more of Virginia homes
                    would pay the penalty. Fifty suburban houses were passed on the outskirts of the
                    town by the squad of burners to reach my home and destroy it, and a like number
                    of suburban houses were not disturbed by the Gilmore party that went to destroy
                    the improvement at the southern end of the farm. At eleven o'clock in the
                    morning McCausland received word from the scouts that Averill was approaching,
                    and he gathered up his force hastily, and moved rapidly across the North
                    Mountain into Fulton County. Averill reached Chambersburg a few hours after
                    McCausland had left the town, and he pursued McCausland, finally brought him to
                    bay after three days of pursuit and defeated and scattered his command. He found
                    in the enemy's camp many of the valuables which had been taken from the homes of
                    Chambersburg.</p>
                <p>The actual losses sustained by the people of Chambersburg in the destruction of
                    personal and real property were finally adjudicated by a State commission that
                    gave $1,628,431.58 as the aggregate value of individual property destroyed. Such
                    a loss in a town of 4,000 population made up entirely of residences and business
                    places, without any large manufacturing establishments, plunged the entire
                    community into the starless midnight of despair. Many were at once hopelessly
                    bankrupted, many more struggled to rebuild their homes and places of business at
                    a time when <pb n="166"/> everything commanded inflated prices, and struggled
                    for years to save themselves, but finally had to yield, as property depreciated
                    while debts accumulated. The few who had wealth in country farms or securities
                    could afford to rebuild their homes, but that number made up a very small
                    percentage of the sufferers of the town.</p>
                <p>The burning of Chambersburg would have been utterly impossible if the steps the
                    State had taken, under Governor Curtin's earnest efforts to protect the border,
                    had been allowed to serve their purpose. The Governor had a number of regiments
                    organized solely for border defense within the State, but they were accepted in
                    the military service of the government only on the very proper condition that in
                    any emergency they should be subject to the orders of the government. More than
                    enough of these regiments than would have been needed to defeat McCausland in
                    Chambersburg passed through the town within a few days before its destruction to
                    reinforce Hunter on the Potomac, as he was then threatened by Earley, and
                    Averill, whose force alone would have been sufficient to protect the town, was
                    not at his headquarters near Greencastle when the <orig reg="dispatches"
                        >despatches</orig> reached there, but was finally found, when too late to be
                    of any service, sleeping alone in a fence corner some distance from his command,
                    and his orderlies did not know where to find him. He was a gallant soldier, had
                    been making forced marches to save his own command that he supposed was
                    threatened on one flank by Vaughan, and on the other by McCausland, and he never
                    dreamed of McCausland making the raid by Mercersburg to Chambersburg. He was
                    doubtless exhausted, and thought that the only duty he could have for immediate
                    performance was to save his command from destruction.</p>
                <p>I stated at the outset of this chapter that the destruc-<pb n="167"/>tion of
                    Chambersburg was chiefly or wholly provoked by the vandalism of Hunter in his
                    Lynchburg campaign, and that its execution was possible because of his
                    incapacity. Already sufficient facts have been given in this statement to show
                    that he was utterly incompetent to handle his army, not only up to the time when
                    McCausland started on his raid, but if he had been equal to his important trust
                    McCausland never would have been permitted to escape on any such mission. In his
                    march through the Valley from Lexington to Lynchburg he had been guilty of the
                    most flagrant violation of the rules of civilized warfare. He had burned the
                    homes of Senator Hunter, of Charlestown, his own first cousin, and bearing the
                    name of General Hunter's father; of Confederate Congressman A. R. Boteler, whose
                    wife was a cousin of General Hunter; of Governor Letcher, then Governor of the
                    State; of J. T. Anderson, connected with the great Tredegar Iron Works, in
                    Richmond; of E. I. Lee, a leading private citizen of the State, and the Virginia
                    Military Institute. All of these were grand old colonial homes, and they were
                    destroyed without any warrant or even decent excuse whatever. In addition to
                    these, many private homes were gutted by his troops, their contents wantonly
                    destroyed, and the historic statues at Lexington were broken or taken away. Of
                    course, he destroyed all the mills and factories on the line, as is common when
                    a movement is made to impair the resources of an enemy, but from the time he
                    started on his campaign until he was driven into retreat by a circuitous route,
                    there were unmistakable marks of the most brutal vandalism along his entire
                    track.</p>
                <p>Earley had driven Hunter from Lynchburg, where he retreated without accepting
                    battle. With Lee's crippled condition in front of Grant, it was not possible <pb
                        n="168"/> for Earley to remain on the Potomac, and he gave the order to
                    McCausland to proceed to Chambersburg and demand a ransom sufficient to cover
                    the private property wantonly destroyed by Hunter in his raid, or failing in
                    that to inflict a like punishment upon Chambersburg.</p>
                <p>General Earley, in a pamphlet published some time after the war, entitled "A
                    Memoir of the Last Year of the War for Independence by the Confederate States of
                    America," speaking of the burning of Chambersburg, said: "For this act I alone
                    am responsible, as the officers engaged in it were simply executing my orders
                    and had no discretion left to them."</p>
                <p>In the same paper he recites in detail many acts of vandalism committed by Hunter
                    in Virginia without excuse or provocation, and adds that it was necessary to
                    carry the same method of warfare into the North to insure the safety of homes
                    and properties in the South.</p>
                <p>While Earley does not give any special reasons for selecting Chambersburg on
                    which to inflict this retribution, it was well known then that throughout the
                    South it was believed that John Brown made his base in Chambersburg, where he
                    planned his wild raid on Harper's Ferry in 1859, solely because the people of
                    Chambersburg were in sympathy with him. It was a natural supposition, but
                    entirely untrue. There was not a single citizen of Chambersburg who knew John
                    Brown as John Brown, during the six weeks or two months he made that town his
                    residence. He was known only as <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> Smith, and not a
                    single resident of the place had any suspicion of his real purpose, as he
                    announced to all that he was planning important mineral developments in
                    Virginia. I saw John Brown a score of times or more during his stay there,
                    conversed with him on several occasions, and never doubted that <pb n="169"/> he
                    was the man he represented himself to be; but the fact that Chambersburg was
                    made his base created deep-seated prejudice in the South against the town, and
                    it is more than probable that, but for the John Brown raid, Chambersburg might
                    not have been decreed to crucification for General Hunter's vandalism and
                    incompetency.</p>
                <p>General Earley doubtless believed that he would halt the destruction of property
                    in the South by the burning of Chambersburg, but from the 30th of July, 1864,
                    until the close of the war, not a single State in the South, where our armies
                    penetrated, entirely escaped fearful retribution for the destruction of the old
                    Cumberland Valley town. On the slightest pretext the Union soldiers, then
                    scattered all through the South, were urged to deeds of vandalism when some
                    desperate leaders would give out the cry: "Remember Chambersburg." I met a
                    Southern lady in Columbia five years after the war, whose home and all it
                    contained were burned by Sherman's army. She told that the squad rushed into her
                    home, ordered her to leave it, and to the cry: "Remember Chambersburg," applied
                    the torch and left it in ashes; and a hundred Southern homes were destroyed for
                    every half-score that were destroyed in Chambersburg. It was a costly
                    retribution to Chambersburg, but it was a twenty-fold more costly retribution to
                    the South. Fortunately, before another year had passed away peace came at
                    Appomattox, and the inmates of Southern homes no longer shuddered at the cry:
                    "Remember Chambersburg."</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
