<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0068"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0068">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Capt. Dahlgren's Daring Charge," by
                    John W. P. Reid, April 18, 1919</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county capt dahlgrens daring charge, by john w p reid april 18 1919</title>
        <author>Reid, John W. P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 19.4</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0068</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498578</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Capt. Dahlgren's Daring Charge" by John W. P. Reid,
                            April 18, 1919</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county capt dahlgrens daring charge by john w p reid, april 18 1919</title>
            <author>John W. P. Reid</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kauffman's Progressive News,
                            4/18/19</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1919-04-18">1919-04-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Home Front, Military Authority, Military Strategy,
                        Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-03-20">2006-03-20</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0036T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Reid gives his account of his exploits conveying prisoners for a Colonel
                    Dahlgren.</p>
            </div1>
            
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Through the Streets of Greencastle in Which He Captured the
                        Famous Dispatch From Davis to Lee at Gettysburg</hi>
                </p>
                <p>As Told by John W. P. Reid An Eye Witness Who Met Dahlgren at the Old Bull's Eye
                    and at His Request Took Captured Prisoners to Mercersburg</p>
                <p>Zanesville, Ohio<lb/> April 14, 1919</p>
                <p>Editor:</p>
                <p>Part 2 The night of July 3rd, 1863 I roomed at old Hollar hotel then run by
                    McNulty who had placed me in charge, so far as protecting his family during his
                    absence-said he was going away to save his horses-and wished me to room there,
                    so his family would have some one to protect them-no charge for board and
                    lodging pursuance of my promise I selected Pump room I turned in about 12
                    midnight- weather hot laid down on top of cover, with pants and stockings on,
                    shortly after daylight, the waiter (Lewis) rapped at door, saying <abbr
                        expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr> there is going to be a big fight. Where I
                    asked "He replied out on Diamond: I pulled venetian blind and saw 9 <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> drawn up
                    in recess of diamond (Eachus corner). I hustled <unclear>on</unclear> my coat,
                    vest and low shoes ran down stairs and just as I opened door on porch, the Nine
                        <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> charged down <abbr expan="South">S.</abbr>
                    Carlisle <abbr expan="Street">St.</abbr>, when I got to Rowe's corner, the
                    Cavalry and fleeing Rebels who had turned tail were mixed up with the ones going
                    North. Rebs, coming would fire too high, balls striking the trees. I ran along
                    pavement and followed as fast as I could to high ground at Negro church, whence
                    I could see pike as far as Scott W. Fleming's. I saw no one when going up, but
                    several were out along street as I returned. An hour or two thereafterwards
                    Cavalry returned with 33 prisoners. The excitement having subsided I went
                    elsewhere. Farmers coming into town for three days past had reported hearing
                    cannon; in the evening persons living outside of Greencastle but near it,
                    reported hearing rumbling of wagons. M. D. Reymer and myself concluded we would
                    walk out to Ruthrauffs and verify report. We sat on the stones and talked for
                    quite a while and could readily hear rumbling of wagons. The evening was cloudy.
                    As we returned, Thomas Pawling came out of door on <abbr expan="East">E.</abbr>
                    Baltimore <abbr expan="Street">St.</abbr>, said to me, "<abbr expan="Captain"
                        >Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren was in Dining room and wished to see me." I said I
                    don't know Dahlgren-can't understand why he wishes to see me, Pawling insisted
                    that I go in, he would introduce me, that he had piloted <orig reg="Dahlgren"
                        >Dahlgreen</orig> from Meade's army at Gettysburg, <abbr
                        expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr>, that Meade had offered <orig reg="Dahlgren"
                        >Dahlgreen</orig> a Brigade of Cavalry, but <orig reg="Dahlgren"
                    >Dahlgreen</orig> had said a company would be sufficient for scouting as he
                    could cover more ground rapidly. After much instance, I went in with Pawling and
                    he introduced me to <orig reg="Dahlgren">Dahlgreen</orig> who at that time was
                    examining a map. <abbr expan="Dahlgren">Dahlgreen</abbr> said he wished to get
                    rid of prisoners as he purposed getting in front of Lee's retreating army and
                    the prisoners would be in his way-that he could spare only 5 men and a <abbr
                        expan="Sergeant">Sergt.</abbr> I told him I was not in service, that I
                    risked my life if caught-hanging would be my lot. He then asked me if I would
                    not risk my life for my country, etc., finally it was decided that I should
                    enlist a sufficient number of my late company (K) I sent out word by several
                    bystanders to different members-went to my boarding House (Hauses) donned my
                    uniform, returned to Pawlings-none of my company put in an appearance. Five
                    youths of about 16 years volunteered-the only surname of only one I remember, a
                    brother of Michael Wagner, a member of <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> K. this
                    young man enlisted afterward, if I remember correctly.</p>
                <p>So much delay had occurred that it was 10 o'clock before we left Pawlings and
                    raining a little, when we reached Stoner's school house on Mercersburg pike I
                    concluded to stop, put Rebels in school house, guarded by the boys the pike to
                    be picketed by two of the <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> I had lost so much
                    sleep that when I sat down to rest I fell asleep and the two pickets stayed on 2
                    hours instead of one hour, when relieved they grumbled some Pawling had thrown a
                    canteen of Gin over my head in starting. I handed it to them, told them to take
                    a big drink, they did so- when it got in its work, I was declared a "Foine <abbr
                        expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr> At day-break I ordered Rebels to be brought
                    out of school house, march to be resumed the <abbr expan="Sergeant"
                    >Sergt.</abbr> refused, saying there were no sense in moving so early. I called
                    a couple of boys to come, when they arrived, I told the <abbr expan="Sergeant"
                        >Segt</abbr> You know Dahlgren had told you I had command. You will now
                    either march or I will place you under arrest, take your horse and ride instead
                    of walking. He obeyed. I then detailed two of the <abbr expan="Cavalry"
                    >Cav.</abbr> having best horses to act as rear guard, directing the one having
                    swiftest horse to go farthest toward <pb n="4"/>Greencastle, the other to keep
                    in sight of him and if Rebels pursued us to at once notify me; the rest of us
                    marched to <orig reg="Upton">Upon</orig> and there I called at the houses
                    telling who I was, reason for being in Upton and asking for food. The citizens
                    called on responded generously, I ordered Prisoners to sit on hotel porch fed
                    them first then the Guard and was eating my lunch when down the Eastern hill as
                    fast as his horse could run, came one of the rear guard detail, hat off,
                    swinging it, yelling, Rebels are coming. When hastily formed prisoners in line,
                    turned into road running to Conococheague Creek, mud and water ankle deep, when
                    we arrived at by-road going to Mercersburg, took it and when in sight of <orig
                        reg="Mercersburg">Mercesburg</orig>, farmers told us "The Rebels were in
                    Mercersburg. I then detailed 2 <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> to ride to
                    Mercersburg, they returned informing me the soldiers were Cavalry of Milroy's
                    army who had retreated when Winchester was taken, crossing the Potomac river
                    into Fulton County. We marched into town, I reported to commander, turned over
                    prisoners and Dahlgren's Cavalry. The commander told me he intended attacking
                    Rebel wagon train. This plan he carried out and the Rebel wounded, surrendered
                    with captured wagons were placed in College Buildings at Mercersburg and
                    remained for months a charge upon Mercersburg community. Several of the boys
                    left for Greencastle as soon as prisoners were delivered, but I remained in
                    Mercersburg a couple of hours. When I returned from Mercersburg, I left pike at
                    2nd, dam, then via 1st, dam, from spring to alley, past school houses, through
                    Presbyterian church yard across street to Hauses, at once took off my uniform
                    and donned my civilian dress. The Rebels had Cavalry pickets on Long's and
                    adjacent hill, passed Hauses going on Picket and returning, <orig reg="sabers"
                        >sabres</orig> clicking and horses' hoofs sounded loud in the still night. I
                    slept but little Sunday night, <orig reg="window">widow</orig> up, revolver
                    cocked, by me. if Rebels came to arrest me, I intended to jump out on kitchen
                    roof thence to ground and run, only use revolver as last resort.</p>
                <p>About 1:30 p.m. Monday Greencastle saw the last of Lee's invasion: within an hour
                    after Johnny's departure, a few Union <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> came
                    from Chambersburg and posted result of Gettysburg battle on Union pole standing
                    on Diamond.</p>
                <p>As to Dahlgreen, report said he arrived at Leitersburg, <abbr expan="Maryland"
                        >Md.</abbr> just as the advance of Lee's retreating army arrived there, that
                    he fought it as long as he could with the few men he had-fell back to
                    Hagerstown. fought there until overpowered, report was that he was wounded in
                    leg, that it was amputated, how much was amputated, I never heard-if true
                    couldn't have been entire as he returned to <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr>
                    service and was killed in engagement as narrated in Judge Wilhelm's oration at
                        <abbr expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> Home-coming of 1917. <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Dahlgren never had any troops under his command
                    in vicinity of Greencastle after Lee's Invasion. He may have visited <abbr
                        expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr>, if he did I think I would have known of it.</p>
                <p>In all the addresses made at Home Comings my name has never been mentioned. In
                    Sketch of 126 <abbr expan="Regiment">Reg.</abbr>, Page 30, my name is mentioned
                    for the first and only time and without rank, as being for a while Ambulance
                    Officer. I was detailed as commander of Brigade Ambulance for a purpose which
                    did not materialize.</p>
                <p>Who acted as Quartermaster at Washington when <orig reg="Quartermaster"
                    >Q.M.</orig> supplies were drawn and who receipted for them? Who acted as Field
                        <orig reg="Quartermaster">Q. M.</orig> when <orig reg="Quartermaster">Q.
                    M.</orig> stayed on safe side of Rappahannock? (Chancellorsville battlefield).
                    Page 6 of Sketch who swore in <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> K. 126 <abbr
                        expan="Regiment">Reg.</abbr> and who paid recruiting said <abbr
                        expan="Company">Co</abbr>!</p>
                <p>I have had the Sketch at least 17 yrs. never read <orig reg="descriptive"
                        >discriptive</orig> parts until I commenced my present contribution hence
                    never noted omissions as to my name and rank. As very few remain alive of <abbr
                        expan="Company">Co.</abbr> K., I have no desire to renew former antagonisms.
                    In preceding reminiscences I have used first person to indicate I personally
                    know where of I write.</p>
                <p>Of the names registered in 1917 Home-coming I recollect about a half dozen.</p>
                <p>Respectfully,<lb/> John W. P. Reid<lb/> 1107 Lexington <abbr expan="Avenue"
                    >Ave.</abbr><lb/> Zanesville, Ohio</p>
                <p>P.S. I have heretofore stated I detailed two of <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr>
                    to remain in rear where we marched toward Mercersburg. When acting as rear guard
                    they were to follow, but concluded to ride into Greencastle, get a drink, in
                    pursuance of that place, they <orig reg="rode">road</orig> from <abbr
                        expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> while Rebel <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr>
                    pickets stationed on Longs &amp; adjacent hill saw that they started in
                    pursuit of them captured one, and followed after the one who <orig reg="rode"
                        >road</orig> down pike in Upton, as far as a house situated on East side of
                    hill from the top of which you can look down upon Upton. The man <orig
                        reg="occupying">occuping</orig> the house was cutting wood for breakfast.
                    They asked him if any Yanks had passed, he <orig reg="replied,">rplied</orig>
                    No. The squad then about faced and went back to picket host. Had they ridden to
                    top of hill, they would have seen us and what there would have happened can
                    easily be conjectured.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
