<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0031"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0031">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "The Election of Lincoln," by
                    unknown, June 25, 1920</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county the election of lincoln, by unknown june 25 1920</title>
        <author>unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>VCDH Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 6 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0031</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498543</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "The Election of Lincoln," by unknown, June 25, 1920</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county the election of lincoln, by unknown june 25 1920</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kauffman's Progressive, June 25,
                            1920</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1920-06-25">1920-06-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-05-13">2006-05-13</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0031T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Description of how residents of Greencastle heard of Abraham Lincoln's election
                    in 1860.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">How the <orig reg="News">Mews</orig> Came to Greencastle and
                        by Whom Brought on a <abbr expan="Cumberland Valley Railroad">C. V. R.
                        R.</abbr> Hand Car from Chambersburg</hi>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">The Parties Were Jacob Stover, Michael McHogan, Daniel Stover,
                        Samuel Illginfritz and David Ziegler </hi>
                </p>
                <p>It is always with interest that we note anything associated or connected with the
                    life of Abraham Lincoln. He was not only the highest and best type of American
                    manhood but one hundred per cent American. His simple life brought him close to
                    the people. It is an inspiration for every American boy however humble his home
                    in entering upon or fighting the <orig reg="battle">oattle</orig> of life to
                    remember and compare advantages with Lincoln. Few will find the obstruction,
                    such as lay in his path, but many will be the advantages favorable to the young
                    of this day and generation.</p>
                <p>His life of earnest endeavor and never tiring will to accomplish something in
                    life worth the effort, overcome his lack of education, admitted him to the bar,
                    brought him face to face in a joint discussion with <orig reg="Douglas"
                    >Douglass</orig>, from his own state, Illinois, and <orig reg="introduced"
                        >introuduced</orig> him to the people of the United States, which secured
                    him the nomination for president in 1860. To know Lincoln was to be his friend.</p>
                <p>His was the second nomination by the Republican party. Feeling ran high. The
                    Democratic party was in power and the South was in the saddle. Every energy of
                    the Republican party was mustered for victory and when it came Greencastle like
                    all other sections of the country was prepared to give it promptly to the people
                    with the least loss of time.</p>
                <p>In order to do so, and as the towns telegraph service was not so perfect as
                    today, Jacob Stover, David Ziegler, Samuel Illgenfritz, Daniel C. Stover and
                    Michael McHogan, secured the <abbr expan="Cumberland Valley Railroad">C. V. R.
                        R.</abbr> hand car and worked their way to Chambersburg in time to be
                    present and hear the election returns as they came into the office of the late
                    Colonel McClure, who was state chairman of the Republican party, where they were
                    given out to the crowd that had assembled both on the in and outside. According
                    to Uncle Jacob's story the returns were slow in coming in but finally the tick
                    of the instrument was heard that relieved the wires that carried the news which
                    formed the basis of <orig reg="Lincoln's">Lincolon's</orig> election. "New York
                    City twenty-five thousand democratic.', read the telegram. Colonel McClure
                    sprung to his feet and said; "That insures the election of Lincoln. The
                    Republicans will come to <orig reg="Harlem">Harlam</orig> river with from
                    seventy-five to a hundred thousand of a majority." Three cheers for Lincoln, and
                    before the <orig reg="excitement">excitment</orig> had died down every piece of
                    furniture in the office was broken to pieces.</p>
                <p>As the news came in it proved the wisdom of his judgment and when the returns
                    assured the election of Lincoln beyond all question of doubt the hand car was
                    again pressed into service and with all <orig reg="speed">spend</orig> rushed to
                    Greencastle to make known the result, which was waited in suspense by the
                    people. On arriving in Greencastle the news of Lincoln's election was made known
                    and a crowd soon assembled among which was Doctor Davison in his night clothes.
                    There was great rejoicing and a demonstration followed.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
