<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0035"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0035">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "An Interesting and Correct Account
                    of Colonel Dahlgren Adventures in and Around Greencastle," by Dr. F. A. Bushey,
                    March 4, 1921</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county an interesting and correct account of colonel dahlgren adventures in and around greencastle, by dr f a bushey march 4 1921</title>
        <author>Bushey, Dr. F. A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 12 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0035</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498547</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "An Interesting and Correct Account of Colonel
                            Dahlgren Adventures in and Around Greencastle," by Dr. F. A. Bushey,
                            March 4, 1921</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county an interesting and correct account of colonel dahlgren adventures in and around greencastle, by dr f a bushey march 4 1921</title>
            <author>
              <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> F. A. Bushey</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kauffman's Progressive, March 4,
                            1921</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1921-03-04">1921-03-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Home Front, Military Strategy, Patriotism, Troop
                        Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-03-17">2006-03-17</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0035T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Bushey writes of his encounter with a Colonel Dahlgren, a Union officer whom
                    Bushey admired greatly. Dahlgren recruited Bushey to guide a small party through
                    enemy-occupied territory to General Meade's headquarters to deliver mail, then
                    returned Bushey home and send Bushey along before a skirmish with Confederate
                    forces.</p>
            </div1>
            
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Gives Data From Residents Who Lived Here at the Time of Lee's Invasion and Who
                    were Active in Support of the Union</p>
                <p>"Mr. Pawling's recollection of the Dahlgren raid." On the morning of July 2, 1863
                    James C. Morehead came to my house and into the bar-room, he called me to one
                    side and told me there were union soldiers camped out in Allisons woods, and
                    inquired if it would be safe for them to come into town. I replied that I
                    thought it would be safe, for the rebels had all gone through, but a few
                    stragglers. Mr. Morehead ate his breakfast, and then went for <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren and his party and I think it was
                    between 7 and 8 o'clock, when Dahlgren and his men came to my house and ate his
                    breakfast.</p>
                <p>They did not all eat at my house but were divided up among the neighbors, my
                    recollection is that there were 12 mounted men in the party, <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Dahlgren, Sergeant Cline, and ten privates.
                    After breakfast, they captured quite a number of rebel stragglers, who were
                    going backward and forwards on the roads in the meantime There were Scouts and
                    pickets sent out the <orig reg="rail">oail</orig> road and turnpike southward.
                    and James Moorehead returned and reported a party of rebels coming. <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren then marched his men from in front of
                    my house down to the square and stationed them at the north front of Kreps and
                    Prathers store, and ordered all the citizens to keep in doors The citizens that
                    were permitted to stay out doors were <orig reg="directed">diricted</orig> to
                    stand on the corner of George W. Zeiglers' pavement and gave the signals to
                        <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren showing the approach of the
                    rebel party. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Dahlgren and his men were out of
                    sight of the rebels, until the mail carrier and his guards got near the corner
                    of the square then <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Dahlgren ordered his men to
                    left half-wheel and charge as one man, the union soldiers drew their <orig
                        reg="sabers">sabres</orig> and with a terrific impulse and yell, threw
                    themselves upon the rebel party, who taken by surprise, surrendered. <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Dahlgren ordered the rebels to surrender their
                    arms, which they did promptly, giving up two small bags of mail; and all their
                    arms. There were about twenty five prisoners taken all of whom were placed under
                    Sergeant Cline, together with all the soldiers under Captain Dahlgren and these
                    together, with other rebel <orig reg="stragglers">straglers</orig> that had been
                    picked up by the Union soldiers, making a bunch of forty or fifty rebels, all of
                    which were promptly marched out the Leitersburg road, toward Emmittsburg, <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Dahlgren said to me, "come," and I went with him
                    up to my house. he stopped and said. I would like to have you go along with me
                    to General Meades' headquarters. for I have some official documents of great
                    importance, which the general must see as soon as possible. You have been kind
                    to us and you are acquainted with the roads and people. I did not want to go and
                    leave my wife and children, and told him he must get my wife's consent before I
                    could think of going. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren then asked
                    "Where is your lady? I told him she was in the dining room. He and I went in to
                    see her, and there I witnessed the true and genuine greatness of the man-his
                    magnetic influence over others. In addressing my wife he was so kind and
                    courteous yet so determined, he seemed so <orig reg="great">grea</orig> when
                    compared with my wife's consent for me to go, and I got out my gray horse that I
                    had ridden in the charge with the soldiers and we started by the same route, The
                    prisoners had been taken, whom we overtook and passed near Canebrake school
                    house. Then we separated, <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren, a
                    sergeant two mounted orderlies with the captured mail and myself, started for
                    Waynesboro. When we arrived at the latter place, one of the orderlies horses
                    became very lame.</p>
                <p>There was only one horse, in the town, and he was reported to be a very good one,
                    so sergeant Cline and the orderly took the horse, but the citizens said the
                    owner was a rebel sympathizer, and should take him. <abbr expan="Captain"
                    >Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren, that noble man, said it was a war necessity, and so we
                    left the lame horse and a voucher for <orig reg="the">thh</orig> price of the
                    horse.</p>
                <p>After getting something to eat, we started for the mountain. When we got to the
                    top of the mountain, we heard the cannonading at Gettysburg. <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren heard it first and said "they are at
                    it." That decided me to go to Gettysburg following the sounds of the cannons. We
                    stopped a while and rested and fed our horses, opened the mail bags, and read
                    what letters we wanted to, some of them were the finest love letters I ever
                    read, and all kinds as you may suppose. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr>
                    Dahlgren had the official <pb n="2"/> documents in his boat.</p>
                <p>When we got down the mountain we met a man whom I knew, he said "Tom where are
                    you going?" I told him about the mail, and he said the rebel pickets are about
                    two miles from here. I asked him how we could get to union headquarters. He
                    directed us to go off toward Emmittsburg and we followed his directions for one
                    or two miles, when I approached a house and again inquired. The gentleman
                    pointed toward a clump of timber, and "the rebel picket is there," so we rode
                    across wheat fields and through timber, passed two other rebel picket posts, and
                    finally got into the union lines after dark. Then <abbr expan="Captain"
                    >Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren commenced asking of all parties for <orig reg="Meade's"
                        >Mead's</orig> headquarters. We finally found we were near Emmittsburg. We
                    rode all night and just at daylight July 3rd, 1863 we reached <orig
                        reg="Meade's">Mead's</orig> headquarters. The General had heard of <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren capturing the rebel mail, and was
                    anxious to see our party. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren, sergeant
                    Cline and myself were taken into a room and all the officers sent out. <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Meade read the dispatch and said captain (to
                    Dahlgren) and Mr. Pawling, this is worth millions of dollars, to the United
                    States for General Lee has asked for <orig reg="reinforcements"
                    >re-inforcements</orig> and Jeff Davis says he cannot send him any more, that
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Grant has <orig reg="Pemberton"
                    >Pimberton</orig> with 30,000 men surrounded and will have to surrender to
                    Grant. "General <orig reg="Meade">Mead</orig> thought there were 10,000 rebel
                    soldiers at Washington." I told him there were none to speak of. Then you ought
                    to have heard ME plead for soldiers to go back to Greencastle. I wanted a
                    Brigade of Cavalry. <abbr expan="Sergeant">Sergt.</abbr> Cline said we could not
                    get supplies there for that number of men, I said Greencastle and neighborhood
                    would feed men and horses, and so at last <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr>
                    Dahlgren and Cline agreed upon one company, (100 men) which we secured at once,
                    and started for home by way of Mount Hope and Shady Grove, and camped in woods,
                    east of town. I wanted <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren and <abbr
                        expan="Sergeant">Sergt.</abbr> Cline to go with me to town, but they would
                    not, and directed me to go to Greencastle and let them know if any rebels were
                    around. I went home, I was very tired, having been in the saddle thirty-six
                    hours, and I went to bed. Samuel Detrick, James Moorehead and others were on the
                    lookout, so Sam Detrich came to my room, before daylight and woke me up, and
                    told me the rebels were coming. I got up, got my gray horse, again rode out to
                        <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren, woke him up out of a puddle of
                    water, for it had rained that night. He got onto his horse, and we came to John
                    Ruthrauff's Hill, from there we could see along the railroad, as far as
                    Fleming's. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr><orig reg="Dahlgren"
                    >Dahlgred</orig> said to me, "is there a way by which we can attack <orig
                        reg="their">there</orig> army from this town." He said they might fire the
                    town or some of the citizens might get hurt-see the kindness of the man,-I told
                    him we could go back to the <orig reg="Hagerstown">Hrgerstown</orig> road and
                    get down to the Williamsport pike and struck the rebels at John Hades. Then
                    there was a hot time for about two hours and we captured a lot of prisoners. The
                    rebel wagon guard of perhaps 2000 soldiers came upon us and were too strong, so
                    we fell back to the Hagerstown road, and as near as I could judge about 500
                    rebel Cavalry followed us. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Dahlgren saw that
                    they were in too great force for us to resist, so he formed a line of battle on
                    the Hagerstown road, and commenced firing rapidly. That stopped the rebels.
                    Captain Dahlgren came up to me and said "you had better get out of this, if the
                    rebels get you, they will hang you." Now from this thoughtfulness you can see
                    the kindness of the man.</p>
                <p>You ought to have seen me and <orig reg="the">tue</orig> gray mare get up that
                    stony lane at Stines. These were the last words I heard him speak and the last I
                    ever saw of him. There was quite a skirmish there, and I afterward heard that he
                    was the last to leave the field of battle, and that the rebels ran him so close,
                    that he dismounted from his horse and got into an oats field. He escaped but the
                    rebels Captured his horse.</p>
                <p>The End</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
