<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0063"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0063">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "The Contest," by A True Republican,
                    October 5, 1869</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county the contest, by a true republican october 5 1869</title>
        <author>"A True Republican"</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes">6 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0063</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498573</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "The Contest," by A True Republican, October 5, 1869</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county the contest, by a true republican october 5 1869</title>
            <author>A True Republican</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Public Opinion, Chambersburg, PA,
                            October 5, 1869</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va. (microforms)</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1869-10-05">1869-10-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, Patriotism, Reunification</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-09-24">2005-09-24</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0063T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This is a letter decrying ex-rebels for revolting against the country and linking
                    those efforts with postwar Democratic efforts to defeat Republicans and
                    Republican Reconstruction.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Mr. Editor.-War was commenced by the Rebels of South Carolina against the United
                    States government. Now, these rebels and traitors-or, others of the same spirit,
                    at home, have taken a stand against the Republican party, and the just and equal
                    laws of our land-and as we are surrounded by foes on our right and left, in
                    front and rear, who are secretly and openly endeavoring to bring reproach upon
                    the Republican party for defeating the war which was detrimental to this Union,
                    and now wish to defeat our party so that they can aid the south that they may be
                    successful in plunder and rule the country. They would assault you as they did
                    Fort Sumpter, and if successful, have our Forts taken and if needs be, our
                    people murdered, for doing their duty as they did in protecting the property of
                    the federal government. The political leaders of the Democratic party are hugely
                    crying about the expense of the war, which they forced upon us, and now want our
                    people to submit, and endure great outrages and insults, and I think it is high
                    time to resent them at the ballot box in October next. We had in every sense
                    obeyed the scriptural injunction, and after having been smitten on the one
                    cheek, turned the other to our assailants-and we have sought peace-yea peace, at
                    almost any price consistent with our self-respect and to the preservation of our
                    honor as a people; and have we not quietly overlooked many hostile
                    demonstrations, and without number, which no other nation would have submitted
                    to, but would have been prompt to punish all such offenders. Now they run at
                    large and ask us to support them at the coming election, for what, that they may
                    be successful in having control of all things to do as they please-rob the
                    government to satisfy their friends that care not for ruin and devastation.</p>
                <p>With these facts yet before us, I do think that it becomes every good man and
                    every worthy citizen, and all who love their country-and all who feel a desire
                    that their country be blessed, with speedy peace and prosperity, such as no
                    other coutnry ever enjoyed, and think of the good old days we used to have.</p>
                <p>I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> say that it becomes all such, and <hi
                        rend="underline">
                        <orig reg="everyone">every one</orig>
                    </hi> too, for himself to show his colors openly and above board to his
                    neighbors and the world at large, by displaying the glorious "stars and stripes"
                    of this again happy country, which has been bought by the patriotic blood of our
                    forefathers, and bequeathed by their last wills, which were written and sealed
                    in crimson gore as an everlasting inheritance, not to be blotted out by rebels
                    and traitors, as has been want to do during the war.</p>
                <p>We must and will keep it sacredly, yea, and defend it until the last departing
                    spark of life shall have fled, if necessary. Alas! we did, and will, again if
                    necessary, and may the God of battles assist us strong and victorious-as he hath
                    done, and will do in time of peril-every son and patriot who may be engaged in
                    this glorious struggle of Republicanism, for freedom, for justice and for the
                    support of the constitution and the laws of our blessed and happy land, will be
                    richly rewarded. It was during the war, "by their works shall ye know them"-now
                    so let us say too, that by <hi rend="underline">their votes</hi> shall we
                    know every true Union man.</p>
                <p>Let the Republican party take a firm stand, and let it be the duty of every
                    citizen to sustain its efforts to maintain and uphold the honor of the party,
                    and vote the whole Republican ticket. In union there is strength.</p>
                <p>A TRUE REPUBLICAN<lb/> Harrisburg, <abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> 28,
                1869</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
