<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0033"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0033">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Underground Railroad," by unknown,
                    January 13, 1922</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county underground railroad, by unknown january 13 1922</title>
        <author>unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>VCDH Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 7 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0033</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498545</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Underground Railroad," by unknown, January 13, 1922</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county underground railroad, by unknown january 13 1922</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kauffman's Progressive, January
                            13, 1922</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1922-01-13">1922-01-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Slavery, Race Relations</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-05-13">2006-05-13</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0033T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Account of one fugitive slave's experiences in Greencastle's underground railroad
                    as well as a description of retaliation undertaken by free black residents of
                    Greencastle against a black man who collaborated with the authorities to capture
                    runaway slaves.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Which Passed Through Greencastle on its Way North Over Which
                        Many a Slave Passed to his Freedom</hi>
                </p>
                <p>How Ben Lewis a Slave Catcher Met His Just Dues at the Hands of the Colored
                    People of Greencastle</p>
                <p>In last week's issue of the <abbr expan="Kauffman's Progressive">K. P.</abbr>
                    News we made mention of the Underground Railroad which had a station in
                    Greencastle, where passengers arrived and departed after night. During the day
                    the road was inactive for the want of passengers who would not take the
                    dangerous chances of daylight travel. There were no signboards up along the road
                    as now, which reads "stop, look and listen," but that caution was more strictly
                    observed, than now. In fact, the travelers were all cautioned and cautious. The
                    rule was to stop, look and listen on all occasions, danger ahead or not.</p>
                <p>One night in December 1861 a traveler on the Underground Railroad arrived in
                    Greencastle and not knowing where to go for the necessary information to
                    continue his journey, found his way to the Antrim House, now Hotel McLaughlin,
                    then conducted by Thomas Pauling, to whom he made his statement and was directed
                    to John Kauffman, whose home was pointed out on North Washington street, as the
                    one to take care of, provide for and help him on his way.</p>
                <p>A few minutes later a light and cautious rap on the front door of the Kauffman
                    residence brought the head of the family to a window on the second floor and he
                    made inquiry who was there and what was wanted, to which came the reply; A
                    runaway slave from "Virginia". I will be down in a few <orig reg="moments"
                        >moment</orig> came the <orig reg="response">reponse</orig>, and he was, to
                    find on opening the door a tall, stout colored man, not yet out of his twenties,
                    who on invitation stepped upon the inside and told his story. He had listened to
                    many of these stories and there was nothing new or exciting in it. It was the
                    same old story voicing the sentiments of revolutionary times-"Give me liberty or
                    give me death."</p>
                <p>Mrs. Kauffman was giving attention to a sick child and had not retired. She was
                    asked if she could prepare the colored man something to eat, which she did.
                    After a good warming and rest, for the night was cold, he was dismissed with
                    full instructions how to reach the next station.</p>
                <p>There the story ends, but that is not all. It has a sequel, startling, though
                    true. The law at that time was so framed as to make every subject of a free
                    state a slave catcher and to aid and abet one in his escape was a <orig
                        reg="criminal">crimial</orig><orig reg="offense">offence</orig> punishable
                    by fine, if not, imprisonment. Then again there were those who made capturing,
                    reporting and returning slaves to their owners a business for the reward. They
                    not only kept an eye on fugitive slaves but were on the lookout as well for
                    their aiders and <orig reg="abettors">abeters</orig>.</p>
                <p>Ben Lewis of Greencastle a colored man was one of them; he worked for Major
                    Hollar, at the National Hotel as hostler. Here it was that he would meet the
                    colored fugitives as they would come into town, form their acquaintance, get
                    their confidence, and then report them to their owner and get the reward. It was
                    a money making business and he had some very fine horses he drove and would
                    often invite a fugitive to ride with him and in this way get the particulars.
                    When sure of his man he would invite him to his home and by his graciousness
                    hold him until he could get word to his owner who would order his arrest or come
                    for him.</p>
                <p>This was getting the nerve of the colored people of the town and they made up
                    their minds they would not stand such conduct by one of their color longer. They
                    put their heads together and Ben Lewis was the recipient of a very polite and
                    pressing invitation to go with them on a fixed date to the creek to enjoy a
                    day's fishing. Ben Lewis, never forgot that day as long as he lived. At a given
                    signal those in hiding bounced on him and punished him <orig reg="severely"
                        >severeally</orig>, after which they <orig reg="applied a">applieda</orig>
                    coat of tar and feathers and then threw him in the creek and let him to sink or
                    swim, live or die, survive or perish, while Meshach Smith, Jessie Bond, James
                    Lewis, and several others who made a beeline for Greencastle.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
