<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0060"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0060">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Where Buried: Soldiers of the Civil
                    War as Kept by the Late J. B. Byers," by J. B. Byers, April 9, 1920</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county where buried soldiers of the civil war as kept by the late j b byers, by j b byers april 9 1920</title>
        <author>Byers, J. B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 6.3 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0060</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498570</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Where Buried: Soldiers of the Civil War as Kept by
                            the Late J. B. Byers," by J. B. Byers, April 9, 1920</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county where buried soldiers of the civil war as kept by the late j b byers, by j b byers april 9 1920</title>
            <author>J. B. Byers</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kauffman Progressive, April 9,
                            1926</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1926-04-09">1926-04-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Veterans, Death/Casualties, Race Relations</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-09-19">2005-09-19</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0060T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>A list of where veterans are buried. A colored cemetery and individual are
                    listed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Many Have Been Raised From the Graveyards and Taken to the
                        Cemetery</hi>
                </p>
                <p>The following is a list of dead as kept by the late John Boggs Byers of the
                    veterans of the Civil war and where buried. After the war he took charge of
                    marking the soldiers graves with flags which he kept up until within recent
                    years, when he died. Since that time it has fallen into other hands and is and
                    will be kept up as long as the spirit of devotion finds lodgment in the human
                    heart for our heroes who have passed on. Many of the soldiers buried in the
                    graveyards in and around the town have been removed and taken to Cedar Hill
                    cemetery, where sleeps the majority.</p>
                <p>Cedar Hill Cemetery</p>
                <p>Henry Swisher, Simon Rupley Jr., A K Brentsholts, Levi Yous. George W Shook,
                    Archibald Raymer, J Gilmore Rowe, W F Patton T S. Riley, Wm. Rhoadarmer, Captain
                    George H Miller, Col. J A Davidson, Captain W. H. Davison. W D Detrick, Jonathan
                    Pentz, Dr. M H King, Samuel B Lane, James Hill, Conrod Hartman. William Parker,
                    William Stover, John Repp, Wash Hollenberger, S J Sampson, Dr. T M Kennedy,
                    Isaac Snively, John Robinson. Alexander Shamon, Jeremiah Mummert, George H
                    Missavy, Captain M Treher, Jonas M Frye, Charles H Frye, John Frye, John B
                    Davison, Jacob Helfrick, George Alexander, Albert Alexander, Jacob B Secrist.
                    Ruom Foust, S H Prather, John Alten (colored) John Williams (colored) Andrew
                    Patterson (colored) Josiah Pulpis, Henry Bartle, Alexander Akins, P B Hollar,
                    James Glenn. Colonel George Cebier William Gardner, H M Popper, John Ward Jaceb
                    Wilt, Henry Shrader, E B Carpenter, George Whitmore, John Schmidt L C Martin, S
                    S Easton, Nicholas Greenawalt, Thomas Duffie, Spanish War Jeremiah O Cleary,
                    Alexander Gorden. George Carbaugh, William Anderson, (colored) Timoth Anderson,
                    Samuel Shickel, Joseph Carney, Jacob Fox, James Wilson Haller, Roman Gordon,
                    John Smith George Pensinger, Harry Bricker, John Garner, Daniel Hellane. William
                    Quest, Frank M Stoner, John T. Koonts, James Cleary. N K Martin, Henry Hoster,
                    Geo. Rebush, John Garner, W H Palmer, William Quest, N R Martin, R Groseman, R
                    Snyder. John Sweigert, Cyrun Peterson, Harry Davison, Daniel King, T J Nill.</p>
                <pb n="2"/>
                <p>Lutheran Cemetery</p>
                <p>M D Reymer, William Pansinger, Samnel Frederick, Andrew Pool, David N Pensinger,
                    Jeremiah Pensinger, D H Mowen, Samuel Jerome King, Isaac Hissong, George
                    Wardman.</p>
                <p>Reformed Cemetery</p>
                <p>William Burton, John Burton, William Hollinger, W S Cooper</p>
                <p>Moss Spring</p>
                <p>James Mitchell, John Gaff</p>
                <p>United Brethen</p>
                <p>Peter Waisner, William Sire, John Simpson</p>
                <p>Rihl Monument</p>
                <p>Corp. William H Rihl</p>
                <p>Colored Cemetery</p>
                <p>Thomas Middleton, Mashack Smith, George Young, John Smith</p>
                <p>Browns Mill Cemetery</p>
                <p>Henry Cordell, Jacob H Stover, William Peterman, George Bartle, William Gaff,
                    Jerome Beaver, John Stoner, Levi Schultz.</p>
                <p>Middleburg Cemetery</p>
                <p>Washington Koonse, Harrison Mellinger, David M Frederick, James W. Casey, Samuel
                    Ringer.</p>
                <p>Shanks Cemetery</p>
                <p>Jasper McLanahan, Alfred McAfee, G W. Barbaker, David Gearhart, Johny Fisher</p>
                <p>Upton Cemetery</p>
                <p>Andrew Schrilly, G W Garlinger, William Davis.</p>
                <p>Eshelman Cemetery</p>
                <p>John Hayman, Samuel Musesleman</p>
                <p>Macedonia Cemetery</p>
                <p>Robert Snyder, George Elliott, John M Wagner.</p>
                <p>White Church</p>
                <p>Ruben Grosmen.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
