<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0043"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0043">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Resolutions," by Unknown, September
                    3, 1915</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county resolutions, by unknown september 3 1915</title>
        <author>Unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 7.5 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0043</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498555</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Resolutions," by Unknown, September 3, 1915</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county resolutions, by unknown september 3 1915</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: "Resolutions," Kauffman's
                            Progressive, September 3, 1915; originally published in the "Greencastle
                            Pilot" Volume 3, No. 43, Nov. 13, 1862; edited by James W.
                        M'Crory</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1915-09-03">1915-09-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Education, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-14">2006-02-14</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0043T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In 1915, Kauffman's Progressive reprinted this article--originally printed in
                    1862--which contains a resolution from the teachers of Greencastle calling,
                    essentially, for educating the children to believe in the Union cause and spread
                    the teachers' belief in the evil nature of the secession of the South.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>At a meeting of the Teachers District Institute of the township of Antrim and
                    Borough of Greencastle the President appointed a committee to draft and report a
                    series of resolutions on the state and condition of the country. The committee
                    at the next regular meeting submitted the following preamble and resolutions,
                    which were unanimously adopted:</p>
                <p>Whereas, our beloved and once happy country has hitherto been to us all a kind
                    and nourishing parent, under whose liberal and <orig reg="beneficent"
                        >beneficient</orig> hand we have enjoyed all the immunities and privileges
                    that a country could bestow upon its people:</p>
                <p>And whereas, That <orig reg="country">conntry</orig> is now struggling with one
                    of the most unholy, inhuman, and unrighteous civil wars that ever cursed our
                    earth, threatening to overthrow the great and good institutions which were
                    purchased with the hearts-blood of our illustrious ancestors, and threatening
                    also to blot from the world the last ray of hope to the suffering subject of
                    tyranny and oppression in all quarters of the globe:</p>
                <p>And whereas, the nation is now bleeding at every pore and struggling with its
                    mighty foe for its very existence; therefore.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That setting aside all feeling of prejudice that may have sprung out of
                    party sentiments, that we show ourselves worthy (at least in fidelity to our
                    country) of the responsible positions that we occupy as <orig reg="molders"
                        >moulders</orig> of the minds of the rising generation, upon whose shoulders
                    will some day rest the responsibilities of the nation.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That all the feeling of our hearts are enlisted in sympathy with our
                    beloved country, in its trying hour of peril and danger, and that we scorn from
                    us, with utter disdain and contempt, any who would consciously do or say
                    anything that is calculated to dishonor or impair the dignity of its fair fame.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That the doctrine of State's Rights over the sovereignty of the United
                    States, is a doctrine fraught with innumerable dangers to the prosperity and
                    success of the institutions of our country, and therefore should be frowned down
                    by every true lover of the Union.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That we believe the rebellion to be an uncalled for and unprovoked one
                    having for its object none of the interests of the masses, but being intended to
                    overthrow the temple of liberty and construct upon its ruins the fabric of
                    aristocracy and monarchy.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That as the blessings of a free and undivided country have been
                    bequeathed to us by our immortal sires, we are bound by every consideration of
                    honor to transmit them <orig reg="unimpaired">unimpared</orig> to our posterity.</p>
                <p>Resolved that we recognized in Abraham Lincoln the lawful executive of the land,
                    and deeply sympathize with him in his efforts to crush this unholy and fiendish
                    rebellion and restore peace and prosperity to our once happy but now distracted
                    country.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That our most devout sympathies are with the thousands of our
                    fellow-citizens who are enduring the privations and incurring the dangers of war
                    in the fields of battle, and for their families who are bereaved and
                    disconsolate on account of their absence and danger.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That we are opposed to any terms of peace, except such as are,
                    honorable, just and fair, and will restore the country to one un-dividing whole,
                    without a single star being erased from its ensign of unity.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That we, as teachers of the youth of our country, unite in endeavoring
                    to instill into their minds that love of country that will render them true
                    patriots, and worthy of the trust that will in the future be confided to them.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That a suitable text book upon the Constitution of the United States
                    should be introduced as a branch of study for the larger pupils of our public
                    schools.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That though the circumstance of the times are arduous, yet the interest
                    of education, of morality and of our country demand that public education should
                    continue as heretofore.</p>
                <p>Resolved, That a copy of the for-going be given to the respective Boards of
                    Directors in whose employ we are, and that they be published in the Greencastle
                    Pilot, the Chambersburg Spirit &amp; Times, the Repository &amp;
                    Transcript, and School Journal of the State.</p>
                <p>Reporter.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
