<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0053"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0053">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin: "Burning of Chambersburg--Retaliatory," by
                    Fielder C. Slingluff, November, 1909</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin burning of chambersburg retaliatory, by fielder c slingluff november 1909</title>
        <author>Slingluff, Fielder C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine Neale</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 21 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0053</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498565</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin: "Burning of Chambersburg--Retaliatory," by Fielder C.
                            Slingluff, November, 1909</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin burning of chambersburg retaliatory, by fielder c slingluff november 1909</title>
            <author>Fielder C. Slingluff</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Confederate Veteran, Volume XVII,
                            Number 11, November, 1909, pp. 559-561</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="2006-05-12">2006-05-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Military Authority, Military Strategy, Patriotism,
                        Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0053T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Former Confederate soldier Fielder C. Slingluff gives a first-hand account of the
                    burning of Chambersburg, Pennsylvania and the subsequent capture of many of the
                    Confederate soldiers who participated in the burning. Slingluff defends the
                    decision to burn the town by describing the extensive destruction of farms,
                    homes, and towns in the South by the Union army.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>An interesting contribution to war literature is an account of the burning of
                    Chambersburg, Pa., by a Baltimore lawyer who was present at the destruction of
                    the town as a member of the 1st Maryland Cavalry. For twenty-five years this
                    narrative has been tucked away in archives, and now appears in a Baltimore
                    paper. It is a letter to Mr. Ephraim Hiteshew, of Chambersburg, Pa., and is a
                    reply to some reminiscences compiled by a Mr. Hoke, of Chambersburg. The letter
                    tells of the destruction.</p>
                <p>Fielder C. Slingluff, of Baltimore, wrote on August 1, 1884, to Mr. Hiteshew at
                    Chambersburg, Pa.:</p>
                <p>"<hi rend="italic">My Dear Sir:</hi> I have received the papers sent me by
                    you containing Mr. Hoke's reminiscences of the burning of Chambersburg and have
                    carefully read them. At your request I give you my recollection of the events
                    which immediately preceded and followed that occurrence. I write from the
                    standpoint of the private soldier, having had no knowledge of the reasons which
                    dictated official orders at the time, nor had my associates. We simply obeyed
                    orders. * * *</p>
                <p>"Mr. Hoke's articles are as temperate as possible from one whose house was burned
                    by an enemy and, as he thinks, without justification. It is true he calls us
                    'villains' occasionally, and says we seemed accustomed to the business from the
                    expert way in which we proceeded to the task. I will not quarrel with him for
                    this, but will take a look at these villains to see who they were then and what
                    they are now. I had just left college when I joined the Confederate army. When
                    we went to Chambersburg, I belonged to the 1st Maryland Cavalry. This regiment
                    was composed of the very first young men of our State. If they were not guided
                    by the strongest instincts of principle in going into the Southern army and
                    staying there, they were certainly a very peculiar set of young men, for there
                    was anything but pleasure and comfort in our lives. We were generally hungry,
                    slept winter and summer in the open air on the ground, got no pay that we could
                    buy with, were scantily clad, and were apt to be killed in battle. I believe the
                    unbiased man must say this was patriotism, although he can if he wishes
                    reconcile his conscience by calling it 'misguided' patriotism. And you may be
                    surprised to know that these young 'villains' have generally developed into good
                    citizens and successful men. Go where you will through our State, and you will
                    find them respected and at the head of the communities in which they live. In
                    business I can name you a dozen of the leading houses in this city whose members
                    were with Johnston and McCausland. The bar throughout the State is full of them,
                    and they are in many cases among the leaders of their circuits. They are doctors
                    in good standing in their profession; and many of the most thrifty farmers in
                    this State, whose fine farms attest devotion to duty and to home, especially in
                    such counties as Howard and Montgomery, were also present on that occasion.</p>
                <p>"In addition to our regiment, there were five or six other regiments in the
                    brigade, most of them from Southwest Virginia and the Valley of Virginia. The
                    men who composed these regiments were the substantial citizens of their
                    respective counties, and would compare favorably with the like number selected
                    from any agricultural community in our country.</p>
                <p>"Now you would like to know if the men whom I have described justified the
                    burning of your town in their individual capacity irrespective of the orders
                    from headquarters under which they acted. I must say to you frankly that they
                    did, and I never heard one dissenting voice. And why did we justify so harsh a
                    measure? Simply because we had come <pb n="560"/> to the conclusion that it was
                    time for us to burn something in the enemy's country. In the campaign of the
                    preceding year, when our whole army had passed through your richest section of
                    country, where the peaceful homes and fruitful fields only made the contrast
                    with what he had left the more significant, many a man whose home was in ruins
                    chafed under the orders from General Lee, which forbade him to touch them; but
                    the orders were obeyed, and we left the homes and fields as we found them, the
                    ordinary wear and tear of an army of occupation alone excepted. We had so often
                    before our eyes the reverse of this wherever your army swept through Virginia
                    that we were thoroughly convinced of the justice of a stern retaliation.</p>
                <p>"It is no pleasure to me to have to recall the scenes of those days, nor do I do
                    so in any spirit of vindictiveness, but I simply tell the truth in
                    justification. We had followed Kilpatrick (I think it was) in his raid through
                    Madison, Greene, and other counties, and had seen the cattle shot or hamstrung
                    in the barnyards, the agricultural implements burned, the feather beds and
                    clothing of the women and children cut in shreds in mere wantonness, farmhouse
                    after farmhouse stripped of every particle of provisions, private carriages cut
                    and broken up, and women in tears. I write of what I saw myself. We had seen a
                    thousand ruined homes in Clark, Jefferson, and Frederick Counties-barns and
                    houses burned and private property destroyed-but we had no knowledge that this
                    was done by 'official orders.' At last when the official order came openly from
                    General Hunter and the burning was done thereunder, and when our orders of
                    retaliation came, they met with the approbation, as I have said, of every man
                    who crossed the Potomac to execute them.</p>
                <p>"Of course we had nothing personal against your pretty little town. It just so
                    happened that it was the nearest and most accessible place of importance for us
                    to get to. It was the unfortunate victim of circumstances. Had it been farther
                    off and some other town nearer, that other town would have gone and Chambersburg
                    would have been saved.</p>
                <p>"And now, having given you the feelings and motives which actuated us, permit me
                    to give my views of how your people felt about the affair. I must be frank
                    enough to say that I think the reason the tribute demanded of you was not paid
                    was because you people had no idea that the Rebels would carry out their threat
                    to burn; nor was this confidence shaken until the smoke and flames began to
                    ascend. I know that this is directly in the teeth of Mr. Hoke's tribute to the
                    patriotism of his fellow-townsmen, that sooner than pay money to the Rebels they
                    saw their homes laid in ashes; but he is himself a little illogical, for he
                    gives greater condemnation to a cruel enemy for burning out a helpless people
                    after they had shown to them that the banks had removed their deposits, and it
                    was impossible for them to get the money demanded. Had your people believed that
                    the town was actually in danger, I think they could have raised enough money to
                    have avoided the catastrophe.</p>
                <p>"Why this confidence of security? It grew out of the position taken by your
                    people during the war-that we were Rebels, soon to be conquered; and that
                    whatever cruelties were inflicted upon the homes of these Rebels were in the
                    nature of penalties for rebellious conduct; and that such like acts would never
                    dare to be attempted against loyal men. It was further strengthened by the fact
                    that when the whole of Lee's army was in your State no atrocities were
                    committed. I saw this confidence, almost amounting to contempt, on our march to
                    your town itself, when the negotiations preliminary to the fire were in
                    progress. I happened with a comrade or two to get behind the command on the
                    march to the town, and in passing through a village of some size (I think it was
                    Mercersburg) the knots of men on the corners poked fun at our appearance and
                    jeered us, and never seemed to consider that the men upon whom they expended
                    their fun had pistols and sabers in their belts and might use them. The strange
                    part of the matter to us was to see able-bodied young men out of service-a sight
                    never seen in the South during the war. In Chambersburg itself it seemed
                    impossible to convince your people that we were, in earnest. They treated it as
                    a joke or thought it was a mere threat to get the money, and showed their sense
                    of security and incredulity in every act.</p>
                <p>"When the two brigades of Confederate cavalry marched to your town, the order
                    came for certain regiments and portions of regiments to enter and burn it. Our
                    regiment as a whole, according to the best of my recollection, was not sent in;
                    but there were several detachments from it on different kinds of duty sent
                    there, and I was with one of them. It was afterwards a source of congratulation
                    to our men that they had not been detailed for the purpose; for although they
                    regarded it as a proper measure of retaliation, they did not seek the unpleasant
                    task. The men who actually applied the torch may be classed in three divisions:
                    First, those whose own homes had been ravaged or destroyed or whose relations
                    had suffered in that way. These men were anxious for the work to begin, and the
                    spirit of revenge which actuated them made them apparently merciless. There were
                    many such in the brigade. Second, the far larger portion who simply obeyed
                    orders as soldiers and who saved what they could and to whose humanity and
                    liberal construction of the orders given them no doubt you must be thankful for
                    the portion of the city that was saved. Third, the men to be found in all armies
                    who looked upon the occasion as an opportunity to plunder and who rejoiced in
                    wanton destruction. This last element was, I am glad to say, small; but I have
                    no doubt to those who unfortunately came in contact with them they were but
                    types of the whole command.</p>
                <p>"As I had never seen the town before and did not know the names of your streets,
                    I can give you no detailed account of the burning. After it began, it was
                    quickly done. Men pleaded to have their houses saved; but the women acted in a
                    much calmer manner after they understood the thing was inevitable, and in some
                    cases excited our admiration by their courage and defiance. I saw a number of
                    houses fired, but I saw no abuse of the citizens. Through the scenes of terror
                    which your people passed I have read Mr. Hoke's annals in vain to find mention
                    of an unarmed citizen injured or a woman insulted. Some of the men became
                    inflamed with liquor, but I believe they were few. The most usual method of
                    burning was to break the furniture into splinters, pile it in the middle of the
                    floor, and then fire it. This was done in the beginning; but as the fire became
                    general it was not necessary, as one house set fire to another. Most of the
                    houses were vacant when fired, the occupants having fled.</p>
                <p>"When the command was given to retire, it was quickly done. One little incident
                    which happened after we left the town will illustrate all I have said about the
                    feeling which actuated many of our soldiers. I think it was two or three miles
                    from town (it may have been more or less) that some of us halted for a few
                    minutes for water and perhaps something to eat. A brick farmhouse with a porch
                    was located on the road with a pump to the side of it. Not far off was what we
                    called a Pennsylvania 'Dutch barn,' larger than the house. <pb n="561"/> It was
                    full of the recently gathered harvest, and bore all the evidence of a plentiful
                    yield to a good farmer. I hitched my horse to the lightning rod on the side of
                    the barn next to the house, and was returning to get him when some one cried:
                    'Fire!' In an instant the barn was in flames. I had hardly time to unhitch my
                    horse. Some of our party demanded in angry tones of two troopers who came from
                    the barn and mounted their horses what they meant by such uncalled-for
                    vandalism. The reply was, 'Why, d- it, they burnt our barn,' and on they rode. *
                    * *</p>
                <p>We recrossed the Potomac with some little opposition from an iron-clad car in our
                    front on the track of the B. &amp; O. Railroad, which was struck by a ball
                    fired by the Baltimore Light Artillery and immediately left. We also had quite a
                    severe little fight in the Blue Ridge Mountains, near Cold Spring, on the
                    advance, in which several from our regiment were killed and wounded, and in
                    which a body of your cavalry showed great spirit and determination; but aside
                    from this we had no fighting at all. Hoke says that when Averill came up to us
                    in the Moorefield Valley and captured and scattered our command they charged us
                    with the cry of `Remember Chambersburg,' and cut us down without mercy. The fact
                    is, we were down when he charged us. I will give you the plain, prosaic facts,
                    of which I was an unfortunate witness and victim.</p>
                <p>After we recrossed the Potomac, we marched to the Moorefield Valley to rest and
                    recuperate after a severe campaign. There is no lovelier spot in all Virginia
                    than this little mountain-locked valley; and as it had escaped the desolation of
                    war, it was the very spot for rest. Our regiment was camped nearest the river,
                    and the company to which I belonged was nearest the river of all. My messmate
                    and I had crossed the fence from the field in which the regiment was camped make
                    our bed in a soft green fence corner, so that I believe we were the nearest of
                    the whole brigade to the enemy. We had camped quietly for a day or two, when in
                    the middle of the night the order came to `saddle up.' We were soon ready for a
                    reported advance of the enemy; but after waiting an hour or two with no further
                    orders the men gradually got under their blankets and went to sleep. Just at the
                    break of day I felt a rude shock, which I supposed came from the careless tread
                    of a comrade, and I made an angry remonstrance. This was followed by a kick
                    which I thought came from a horse. I, furious, threw the blanket from over my
                    head and found a couple of Averill's men with cocked pistols at my head, one of
                    whom said: 'Get up, you -- Chambersburg-burning -- !' I got up at once, and
                    mildly intimated that I had nothing to do with the burning of Chambersburg, and
                    considered it altogether wicked and unjustifiable.</p>
                <p>"As soon as I collected my thoughts 1 took in the situation. I saw the blue-back
                    column of Averill winding down the road and breaking off into the fields where
                    our men slept. I saw them, to my utter humiliation and disgust, dashing in among
                    the men and waking them up from their sleep. Some of our command who had heard
                    the rush of the charge succeeded in mounting their horses and escaping. With
                    such some shots were exchanged, but the greater part of our regiment was caught
                    asleep and captured without firing a shot.</p>
                <p>"As soon as the comrade with whom I was sleeping (a cousin of mine) and I had
                    given up our arms the usual and almost invariable compliments which pass on such
                    occasions took place. 'I want them boots,' said trooper No. I. I had just gotten
                    them in Hancock a day or so before; and as they were regular cavalry boots and
                    worth, with us at least, $150 to $200 in Confederate money, it nearly broke my
                    heart to part with them. But the occasion was pressing, and they were soon
                    exchanged for a very sorry-looking pair. My hat, which was also a recent
                    Maryland acquisition, with a martial black plume, was appropriated by trooper
                    No. 2. My pockets were carefully investigated, but that part of the raid was a
                    complete failure. I had myself paid the same compliment to my guests when the
                    situation was reversed.</p>
                <p>"And how was it that the burners of Chambersburg were thus ignominiously routed,
                    scattered, and captured by a foe whom I have said they despised? The answer is a
                    simple one. It was through the carelessness of our commanding officer, and was
                    inexcusable. It happened in this way, and I am again in position to give the
                    exact facts: When we camped in the little valley, a detail was called on for
                    picket duty. That duty fell to the lot of Lieut. Samuel G. Bonn, of my company.
                    No truer man or more charming gentleman ever wore a saber. After the war he
                    settled in Macon, Ga., became a prosperous merchant, and died some years ago. He
                    went out on the picket post with about ten men some two or three miles from our
                    camp. This was the only guard between Averill and our sleeping men, and it must
                    be remembered that when this little band went on the outpost they were worn out
                    with the fatigue of the nearly incessant marching for the four or five previous
                    days and nights. So wearied were the men that after their first night's duty
                    Lieutenant Bonn sent word back to camp and begged to be relieved; stating that
                    his men were absolutely unfit for duty. I take it for granted this message was
                    sent to headquarters; but whether it was or not, it was an unjustifiable piece
                    of cruelty to keep those wearied men on duty. His appeal was unheeded. He told
                    me after the surprise was over that the men on the outpost actually went to
                    sleep upon their horses, and that in addition to all this no provision was made
                    for their rations.</p>
                <p>"While in this condition just before the dawn of day they heard the welcome sound
                    of what they supposed was the relief picket coming from our camp, and soon they
                    welcomed twenty or thirty troopers in gray ( ?) in their midst. Their rejoicing
                    was short-lived, for as their supposed friends surrounded them they quickly drew
                    their revolvers, and in an instant our men were prisoners. To run down the
                    outpost of two men was the work of a moment, and then there was nothing between
                    Averill and the men who burned Chambersburg but a few moments of darkness and a
                    couple of miles of dusty road. These men in gray were what in those days were
                    known as `Jesse Scouts.' They were familiar with the country, knew the little
                    mountain roads, and had clothed themselves in the Confederate gray. They slipped
                    in between our main body and the picket post and then played the part of the
                    'relief.'</p>
                <p>"As we were captured, we were gathered together in a circle, and soon poor Bonn
                    and his pickets were brought in looking unhappy and dejected. He felt keenly the
                    responsibility of his position, but after his story was told no one ever
                    attached any blame to him. About five hundred of our brigade were captured and
                    taken to Camp Chase, Ohio, where for eight long, miserable, weary months we
                    bewailed the day that Chambersburg was founded, builded, and burned."</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
