<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0005"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0005">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Death of Gen. Robt. E. Lee," by
                    Unknown, October 25, 1870</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county death of gen robt e lee, by unknown october 25 1870</title>
        <author>Unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 5.1  </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0005</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498522</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Death of Gen. Robt. E. Lee," by Unknown, October
                            25, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county death of gen robt e lee, by unknown october 25 1870</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Public Opinion, Oct 25, 1870, p.
                            2, c. 2</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va. (microforms)</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-10-25">1870-10-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Military Authority, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-03-21">2006-03-21</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0005T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>An obituary for Robert E. Lee</p>
            </div1>
            
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>A late telegraphic dispatch announces the death of <abbr expan="General"
                        >Gen.</abbr><abbr expan="Robert">Robt.</abbr> E. Lee, at his residence in
                    Lexington Virginia. An exchange, speaking of his death, appends the following
                    brief biography of the distinguished Virginian;</p>
                <p>Robert Edmund Lee was the son of Henry Lee, a distinguished American general,
                    once governor of Virginia, and an author of some eminence. He was born in
                    Virginia about 1810, and consequently was sixty years old at his death. Like his
                    long line of ancestors, <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Lee had enjoyed largely
                    the honors and emoluments disbursed by the United States government. He entered
                    West Point as a cadet in 1825, graduating in 1829, and entering the service as a
                    brevet second lieutenant of engineers. He was appointed assistant astronomer for
                    fixing the boundary between Ohio and Michigan in 1835, and was promoted to first
                    lieutenant in 1836, and to captain in 1838. In the war with Mexico he served as
                    chief engineer of the army; commanded by Brigadier General Wool, and was
                    breveted major for gallant and meritorious conduct in the battles of Contreras
                    and Cherubusco, August 20th, 1847, and was made colonel for like gallant conduct
                    at Chapultepec, September 13, 1847, in which he was wounded. He was appointed to
                    the superintendency of West Point September 1, 1852, and held the postion to
                    March 1855. On retiring from this post, he was appointed lieutenant colonel of
                    2d cavalry, the same month. We now come to the sad crisis in his otherwise
                    brilliant career. Upon the breaking out of rebellion, he resigned his commission
                    in the service of his country, and accepted the position of the commander of the
                    miltary and naval forces of Virginia, and when that state joined the
                    confederacy, he was appointed to the rank of general, and selected as <orig
                        reg="commander-in-chief">commander in chief</orig> by Jefferson Davis. He
                    was in immediate command of the forces in and around Richmond, and throughout
                    Northern Virginia for the most part during the war; and the success of the
                    confederate forces on the sanguinary battlefields of the peninsula,
                    Fredericksburg and Bull Run, compel a recognition of his rare military ability,
                    in spite of the disastrous repulses suffered by his troops at Antietam and
                    Gettysburg. Early in life he married the adopted grand-daughter and heiress of
                    Washington, by whom he had five sons, all of whom joined the confederate
                    service. For some five years General Lee has been president of the college at
                    Lexington, Virginia.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
