<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0056"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0056">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Border War," by Unknown, 1869</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county border war, by unknown 1869</title>
        <author>Unknown</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 28.5 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0056</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498568</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Border War," by Unknown, 1869</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county border war, by unknown 1869</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>5 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: The Rebellion Record: A Diary of
                            American Events, Edited by Frank Moore, New York: D. Van Nostrand,
                            Publisher, 1869, Pages 38-43</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1869">1869</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Home Front, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-03-20">2006-03-20</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0056T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This poem recollecting/imagining the war in Chambersburg is more bitter and
                    unhappy than many recollections in later years. It begins by describing the
                    original burning of Chambersburg in the French and Indian War.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">AS SEEN AND EXPERIENCED BY THE INHABITANTS OF <orig
                            reg="CHAMBERSBURG">CHAMBERSBURGH</orig>, PA.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>I.<lb/> A wandering hunter spied the spot,<lb/> Where Falling Spring, a limpid
                    stream,<lb/> Which glides on its course like a fairy dream,<lb/> A moment's joy
                    and then forgot,<lb/> Rolls laughing over its rocky bed;<lb/> A moment pure and
                    a moment free,<lb/> A lagging moment forever sped,<lb/> Then hurried onward
                    toward the sea.<lb/> Swept off, the victim of wild intrigue,<lb/> 'Twixt the
                    ripples and waves of the Conococheague.</p>
                <p>On that spot now rests a quiet town,<lb/> Called after a man attracted there<lb/>
                    By the hunter's tale, bewitching fair,<lb/> Of the water-fall which tumbles
                        down<lb/><pb n="39"/> In foaming spray o'er its rough-hewn stair;<lb/> The
                    spot I have learned to love so well,<lb/> Where fancy can revel without
                    restraint,<lb/> And her creations are wont to dwell,<lb/> And fill the mind with
                    pictures quaint;<lb/> And there I muse on a thousand things,<lb/> Which come on
                    Imagination's wings,<lb/> And the well-known legends fondly trace,<lb/> That are
                    told of the Indian-haunted place.</p>
                <p>'Twas on this spot stood free and wild,<lb/> The Shawanese and the Delaware
                    savage,<lb/> Ere Indian warrior taught his child<lb/> To scalp and murder, burn
                    and ravage.<lb/> And as I stood by the stream one day,<lb/> A thousands visions
                    flitting o'er me,<lb/> I thought of times long passed away,<lb/> And buried
                        <orig reg="chieftains">chieftans</orig> rose before me;<lb/> But vain are
                    the dreams we would fain recall,<lb/> For oblivion's mantle is over them all.</p>
                <p>And then I thought of the old-time fort,<lb/> With its blunderbuss and its swivel
                    gun,<lb/> Its cracking fire-arms' loud report,<lb/> And the name is bold
                    defender won;<lb/> How the savage ventured not too near<lb/> Its stockade sides,
                    from a wholesome fear<lb/> Of the bull-dogs laid at rest within,<lb/> But oping
                    their mouths with a ghastly grin:<lb/> And how when the governor's mandate
                    came,<lb/> "Forthwith to deliver up the same,"<lb/> Old Colonel Chambers
                    bristled with pride,<lb/> And declared that "the guns should stay by his
                    side,<lb/> For his guns had stood by him, and he<lb/> Would stand by his guns,
                    as they should see."<lb/> Then followed visions of trouble and strife,<lb/> Of
                    the tomahawk and the scalping-knife,<lb/> The war-whoop wild and the scene of
                    slaughter,<lb/> And of human blood in the limpid water.</p>
                <p>And then from the buried past we fly<lb/> To the living present which vividly
                    seems<lb/> The realization of mystic dreams<lb/> That are wont to fleck our
                    dream-land's sky.<lb/> From the time on freedom's natal day,<lb/> When Craighead
                    urged the youth away,<lb/> And our patriot sires, a martial band,<lb/> Shoulder
                    to shoulder and hand to hand,<lb/> Marched forth to consecrate the land<lb/> At
                    liberty's shrine and on freedom's altar;<lb/> Up to the day when marched the
                    son<lb/> To end the work the sire begun,<lb/> And not a man was known to
                    falter.<lb/> From the fields where Steele and Chambers fought,<lb/> At the
                    nation's first baptismal,<lb/> To the gory spot where Easton wrought<lb/> And
                    died 'midst the deep swamps dismal;<lb/> And from where our patriot fathers
                    bled,<lb/> And their comrades moaning, "dead, dead, dead,"<lb/> Consigned them
                    to God's own keeping,<lb/> To the far-off hillside's thorn-bush shade<lb/> Where
                    the gallant Kerns to rest is laid,<lb/> As one who is gently sleeping.</p>
                <p>The past, the present, the future, all<lb/> We have known in life or loved in
                    story;<lb/> The dead the living, the great, the small,<lb/> Obscurity's son and
                    the child of glory<lb/> In vision arise before our eyes,<lb/> And troop through
                    brain in wild disorder,<lb/> And we look in the stream with strange
                    surprise,<lb/> When we recollect we're on the "border."</p>
                <p>II.<lb/> And thus again as I lay by the stream<lb/> Which murmuring rolls its
                    waters along,<lb/> And drips o'er the Falls in rippling song,<lb/> My fancies
                    were shaped and this my dream,<lb/> Minerva-like, sprang out of my brain.<lb/>
                    And bore away the triumphal car<lb/> Of terrible, glorious "border war;"<lb/>
                    While rose to my ears a swelling strain,<lb/> Which seemed like the voices of
                    heroes slain,<lb/> And this was the burden of what they were singing,<lb/> Its
                    cadence wild with the waters ringing.</p>
                <p>Away to the border, away,<lb/> Where your brethren are calling.<lb/> Away and
                    take part in the fray,<lb/> Where your children are falling.<lb/> Fall in, men,
                    fall in, and forward in order,<lb/> Do you not hear the cry coming up from the
                    border?</p>
                <p>Away to the border, away,<lb/> Where stout hearts are contending.<lb/> Away, and
                    take part in the fray,<lb/> Your own hearth-stones defending.<lb/> Fall in, men,
                    fall in, and forward in order,<lb/> The foe's at your doors almost, his foot on
                    the border.</p>
                <p>Away, to the border away,<lb/> Where brave men are dying.<lb/> Away, and take
                    part in the fray,<lb/> Where your kinsmen are lying.<lb/> Fall in, men, fall in,
                    and forward in order,<lb/> The blood of the slain is calling, "Come to the
                    border."</p>
                <p>III.<lb/> Then quickly before my astonished eyes-<lb/> For dreams are like clouds
                    in summer skies-<lb/> Passed visions of men in warrior's guise,<lb/> Of men who
                    were going to battle:<lb/> And mixed and mingled with my dream,<lb/> Was
                    saber-thrust and bayonet-dream,<lb/> And the fierce artillery's rattle;<lb/>
                    There was the Home Guard's steady line,<lb/> The "State Militia's" martial
                    front,<lb/> The "Anderson Troop," in clothes so fine,<lb/> And men who had borne
                    the battle's brunt.</p>
                <p>The Home Guards marched like men who knew<lb/> Their dinners were safely cooking
                    behind them,<lb/> And like men who felt quite conscious, too,<lb/> Of where the
                    dinner hour would find them;<lb/> And I marched along with my gun by my
                    side,<lb/> And I praised my captain so kind and clever,<lb/> Who looked at "the
                    boys" with a soldier's pride,<lb/> And called time, RIGHT, RIGHT, whenever<lb/>
                    He meant the left foot<lb/> On the earth should be put;<lb/> But hurrah for our
                    captain forever.</p>
                <p>I can never forget, nor could I desire<lb/> That a scene like that which is
                    certainly worth<lb/> A life-long pilgrimage here on this earth<lb/> From my
                    memory should ever expire.<lb/> When our sergeant led out our squad in the
                    night,<lb/> Our homes to defend, for our hearth-stones to fight,<lb/> And
                    instructed us thus: "If the foe comes don't fire,<lb/> For you see if you
                    should, and a rebel 'bites dirt,'<lb/> It would end our organizations;<lb/> For
                    you know that in case there were 'somebody hurt,'<lb/> 'Twould conflict with the
                    regulations."<lb/> Then behind a stone fence we were placed where we slept<lb/>
                    Till we heard the approaching relief,<lb/><pb n="40"/> When we marched back to
                    camp, and like soldiers we stept,<lb/> Only stopping to drink to our chief,<lb/>
                    The provost, who'd shut up the bars, though by stealth<lb/> We still had enough
                    to drink to his death.</p>
                <p>The provost (I dreamed) I could never forget,<lb/> And his aids I would always
                    remember,<lb/> How from morning till night they were sorely beset<lb/> In that
                    terrible month of September;<lb/> When the foe in Middletown Valley was
                    seen,<lb/> As the sun went down in the west,<lb/> And at dark had advanced
                    already between<lb/> Greencastle and Marion at least.</p>
                <p>But the provost (I dreamed) was a man who would have<lb/> His will and his way in
                    his station,<lb/> And to show that the town he would certainly save,<lb/> He
                    issued a strict proclamation:<lb/> "No citizen armed for the common <orig
                        reg="defense">defence</orig>,"<lb/> His bitters could get of a morning;<lb/>
                    But the citizen-soldiers scorned abstinence,<lb/> As their mode of attack was by
                    horning.<lb/> "In case the foe approaches the town,"<lb/> The command was,
                    "Destroy all the brandy,"<lb/> But it did not say how, so my friend Mr.
                    Brown,<lb/> Thought to drink it were far the most handy;<lb/> "And guards will
                    be placed," it was thus ran the text,<lb/> "At every approach to the
                    Borough."<lb/> So away trooped a crowd, exceeding perplexed<lb/> Lest they
                    should bear arms on the morrow.</p>
                <p>I can never forget what the Guards have achieved,<lb/> And how closely they
                    looked at the "passes"<lb/> Of honest old farmers who "spies" were
                    believed,<lb/> While they kissed and passed out all the lasses.<lb/> Then the
                    "Anderson Troop" came riding along,<lb/> On horses impressed from the
                    farmers;<lb/> There clothes were new and their <orig reg="sabers">sabres</orig>
                    were strong,<lb/> So they thought themselves "perfect charmers."<lb/> And I
                    looked at their steeds when I saw the mark,<lb/> Uncle Sam puts on all of his
                    forces;<lb/> And I "laughed in my sleeve," as cried out some gay lark,<lb/>
                    "They've been branding borrowed horses."</p>
                <p>These "Anderson fellows" had drilled for a while,<lb/> And moreover were splendid
                    blowers;<lb/> So with <orig reg="sabers">sabres</orig> like scythes they came in
                    style,<lb/> To show rebels some excellent mowers.<lb/> And I saw in my dream, I
                    can't vouch for the truth,<lb/> That with dauntless and terrible blows<lb/> They
                    mowed forty thousand rebs down, forsooth,<lb/> When at least thirty miles from
                    their foes.</p>
                <p>Thus ended this part of my dream, when behold,<lb/> As the danger was past and as
                    bloodshed was over,<lb/> The "State Militia," in numbers untold,<lb/> The "War
                    on the Border" began to discover.<lb/> So away they marched with but little
                    persuasion,<lb/> To protect "the line" from threatened invasion.</p>
                <p>Unluckily for the "Militia," their fate,<lb/> 'Twas to be right in time to be too
                    late;<lb/> Unless they meant not to fight where my rhyme<lb/> Will bring them
                    just in the nick of time.</p>
                <p>Thus peace again reigned, not so much, I suppose,<lb/> That the rebels were
                    fearful we'd beat 'em,<lb/> As from a deep-seated conviction that rose<lb/> In
                    their minds on the banks of Antietam.</p>
                <p>IV.<lb/> The quiet town in its still repose,<lb/> Not a whisper heard from the
                    whispering trees,<lb/> Not a rumor borne on the passing breeze,<lb/> But little
                    recked of the coming foes.</p>
                <p>The clouds were lowering, and pattering rain<lb/> Began to plash on the
                    window-pane,<lb/> And darkness to veil all scenes from the light,<lb/>
                    O'ercasting the earth with the mantle of night.</p>
                <p>An anxious horseman with panting steed,<lb/> Rode into the town at his utmost
                    speed,<lb/> With the word that "the rebels were coming!"<lb/> Bells rang and
                    drums beat in that hour of need,<lb/> But all smiled at the ringing and
                    drumming.<lb/> 'Twere absurd, men argued, that here, so far<lb/> From the army
                    that lay on the river away,<lb/> The rebels should come in a single day,<lb/>
                    With all the paraphernalia of war.<lb/> Yet while they argued, the guns of the
                    foe<lb/> Oped their mouths with a grin on the town below.</p>
                <p>"They're here, they're here!" was borne on the air,<lb/> Through street and
                    alley, "The rebels are here;<lb/> Don't you see them down in the Diamond
                    there?<lb/> I heard their trumpet-tones calling clear."</p>
                <p>And I walked the streets, and I felt the pain<lb/> Of "surrender" thrill me
                    through every vein<lb/> When I heard a heroic woman declare,<lb/> "The dirty
                    rebels, they won't fight fair,<lb/> But come when they know we can't beat
                    them,<lb/> Instead of giving us time to prepare,<lb/> As we do with them ere we
                    meet them."</p>
                <p>Then into the town incessant poured<lb/> The hateful stream of the rebel
                    horde;<lb/> "They had now just come," they deigned to say,<lb/> "A hasty visit
                    this place to pay;"<lb/> And kindly promised for hurry this once,<lb/> To come
                    again and stay for months.<lb/> We told them no doubt 'twas well designed,<lb/>
                    But still we were sure they were quite too kind;<lb/> And assured them one thing
                    was very clear,<lb/> We were not at all fond of "butternuts" here.</p>
                <p>And General Stuart, the rebel chief,<lb/> Whom the farmers call "the rebel
                    horse-thief,"<lb/> Who captured "the city without delay,"<lb/> (Or "quiet
                    village," as Harpers say,)<lb/> Inquired next morning with pride: "If his
                    men<lb/> Were bad as was represented."<lb/> "But the devil ne'er," he was
                    answered then,<lb/> "Was black as he was painted."</p>
                <p>But up and away with the early morn<lb/> Were these defiant rebels borne,<lb/> As
                    fast as our horses could carry them.<lb/> As the flame and smoke to heaven
                    arose,<lb/> We declared our purpose to follow our foes,<lb/> To strike them
                    hard, and as to their blows,<lb/> We swore long and loud we would parry them.</p>
                <p>So we shouldered our guns and went out to see<lb/> Where the infernal rebels
                    might be,<lb/> But the devil himself couldn't find them.<lb/> For "over the
                    river and far away,"<lb/> They had gone, as they hadn't "the time to stay,"<lb/>
                    Leaving "flaming regrets" behind them.</p>
                <pb n="41"/>
                <p>V.<lb/> The autumn bleak and the winter cold<lb/> Passed slowly by, while afar
                    off rolled<lb/> War's tide and train if desolation.<lb/> On the Rappahannock's
                    blood-stained shore,<lb/> Where the Yazoo's darksome waters pour,<lb/> Or Stone
                    River's waves are mingled with gore,<lb/> Stood the bulwarks of the nation.</p>
                <p>Our fathers, brothers, sons were there,<lb/> While a sister's sigh or a mother's
                    prayer,<lb/> Went up to heaven, "O Father, spare!"<lb/> The rifle-flash and
                    bayonet-thrust,<lb/> The ranks of men, the columns of dust,<lb/> The musketry
                    crash, the cannon's roar,<lb/> And all the ominous sounds of war,<lb/> Was the
                    only answer the lightning brought,<lb/> From were contending thousands fought.</p>
                <p>The only answer-Ah! No, the rod<lb/> Upraised to punish a nation for sin,<lb/> Is
                    felt in the cry, "My son, O God!"<lb/> At the one little name in the
                    bulletin;<lb/> And this is answer enough for her,<lb/> Whose hopes and all that
                    she loved on earth,<lb/> Are borne to a soldier's sepulcher,<lb/> And buried
                    afar from the place of his birth;<lb/> Or brought in sorrow and laid to
                    sleep,<lb/> Where its vigils affection may silently keep.</p>
                <p>The dreadful sounds of WAR, WAR, WAR,<lb/> Still smote on the ear, yet while we
                    bore<lb/> Our loved ones home and mournfully laid<lb/> Their bodies at rest in
                    the earth at our feet,<lb/> Mourned over their graves and solemnly played<lb/>
                    Funereal dirges for heroes meet;<lb/> Men black as Erebus sprung forth,<lb/> And
                    I saw them spring at their country's call,<lb/> Raised up the banner of the
                    North,<lb/> And placed it high on Wagner's wall.</p>
                <p>From the dens where burrow a subject race,<lb/> Methought I saw them face to
                    face<lb/> With the monster Death on Wagner's towers,<lb/> Exclaiming: "THE FORT
                    IT MUST BE OURS."<lb/> And I turned and pointed where heroes lay,<lb/> And
                    pronounced a benediction of sorrow:<lb/> "Sleep sweetly, brave men, for ye this
                    day<lb/> Have gained for your children a glorious to-morrow."</p>
                <p>VI.<lb/> But again the rumor is borne on the breeze,<lb/> (We often before had
                    rumors like these,)<lb/> That Lee is moving, intent on invasion.<lb/> But we
                    heeded it not until it was clear<lb/> That Jenkins had come unpleasantly
                    near,<lb/> And Lee himself would surely be here<lb/> Before his head had many
                    more days on.<lb/> Then away the "prominent citizens" hurried,<lb/> Excited,
                    frightened, flustered, flurried,<lb/> In wagons, carriages, sulkies, carts,<lb/>
                    On horseback, "on foot," by all manner of arts<lb/> And devices;<lb/> And all
                    kinds of people-Smith, Jones,<lb/> Roberts, Robinson, Brown, and Bones,<lb/> And
                    the Rices.</p>
                <p>While away in advance of the headlong race,<lb/> Was a carriage that looked like
                    R-n's,<lb/> Which seemed "like he gwine to leab de place,"<lb/> Through fear of
                    the mighty Jenkins.</p>
                <p>'Mid shriek, and yell, and cry, and shout,<lb/> And peals of wicked
                    laughter,<lb/> On, hurried on, the rabble rout,<lb/> With Milroy's wagons
                    after.<lb/> Pell-mell,<lb/> Helter-skelter,<lb/> Hurry-skurry,<lb/> Toss and
                    tumble,<lb/> Roll and rumble,<lb/> And dust to make us blind, most;<lb/> Thus
                    Milroy's trains<lb/> Came over plains,<lb/> And rills and ridges,<lb/> Brooks
                    and bridges,<lb/> Let worst be worst,<lb/> The best man first,<lb/> And devil
                    take the hindmost.<lb/> And sure enough, when all had gone,<lb/> And night put
                    her sable garments on,<lb/> Came Jenkins, the guerrilla chief,<lb/> And arrant
                    traitor, and braggart, and thief,<lb/> To pay us that long-threatened
                    visit.<lb/> His rebs were dirty as dirt could make 'em.<lb/> And Jenkins himself
                    may have been a sachem,<lb/> A man or gorilla, a monkey or fairy,<lb/> Or
                    p'rhaps the famous "What is it?"<lb/> Which usually goes with "<orig
                        reg="traveling">travelling</orig> shows."<lb/> But whatever he was, no one I
                    suppose,<lb/> Will deny he was wretchedly dirty and hairy.</p>
                <p>Now Jenkins put up at the best hotel,<lb/> And as every thing looked uncommonly
                    well,<lb/> He grew quite communicative;<lb/> No foe on his front, no foe on his
                    rear,<lb/> Though he found on his flanks two glasses of beer,<lb/> He soon threw
                    them off like a "native."</p>
                <p>'Tis wondrous to tell how he soon sought his way,<lb/> From the house with the
                    sign of the Eagle,<lb/> A bird which he found he could ne'er lead astray,<lb/>
                    However he tried to inveigle,<lb/> To that spot on the Spring whose waters are
                    clear,<lb/> Transparent and lucid as lager or beer,<lb/> Where our good friends
                    the Dutch delight overmuch,<lb/> To hear their mugs jingle and "smile" at the
                    touch,<lb/> While they fight o'er the battles "mit Sigel."</p>
                <p>"Dear Harmon," says Jenkins, "I'm glad to be here,<lb/> And to know you's a great
                    delight, sir,<lb/> I confess I'm remarkably fond of your beer,<lb/> And relish
                    your 'kase' and your 'Sweitzer.'<lb/> Your people shall all be treated as
                    well<lb/> As I this day have been 'treated;'<lb/> I'll see they are paid for all
                    that they sell,<lb/> And will suffer no one to be cheated;<lb/> But then they
                    must all be content to receive<lb/> Such money as we are able to give."</p>
                <p>Impressed, no doubt, with this honest feeling,<lb/> (For Jenkins was morally
                    hostile to stealing,)<lb/> He ordered all business men open their doors,<lb/>
                    And he would send officers round to their stores,<lb/> And these, he assured
                    them, "would carefully make<lb/> A correct catalogue of their stock;<lb/> Such
                    things as they wanted were all they would take,<lb/> And the balance erase from
                    the book;<lb/><pb n="42"/> Except whatever 'the men' might find<lb/> To tickle
                    the fancy or please the mind."<lb/> Thus pleasantly chatting, when all was "took
                    down,"<lb/> He looked at the bills and bought out the town.</p>
                <p>Still Jenkins had terrible griefs to bear,<lb/> And as Jenkinses never were known
                    to swear,<lb/> He affirmed: "He'd be d-d if he'd stand 'em."<lb/> And so he
                    launched forth in a speech at the rate<lb/> Of Phoebus's horses when Phaeton
                    sate<lb/> On the box and drove 'em tandem.</p>
                <p>"In a peaceable way he had entered the town,<lb/> Yet we had a hostile spirit
                    shown;"<lb/> If he had said "horse steal" to me it appears,<lb/> The kettle had
                    had the pot by the ears-<lb/> "Had stolen his horses and tried to shoot
                    down<lb/> His men in a charge inoffensively made,<lb/> Which greatly displeased
                    his entire brigade;<lb/> Who swore that unless we paid all their losses,<lb/> Or
                    begging their pardon returned them their 'hosses.'<lb/> The d-d little town
                    should in ashes be laid.<lb/> He felt for his men, he was bound to confess
                    it,<lb/> And whatever their wrong was compelled to redress it,<lb/> And to
                    settle the matter desired to call<lb/> Our worthy Town Fathers together."<lb/>
                    Such was the substance of what he "let fall"-<lb/> From the "change in the wind"
                    we augured a "squall,"<lb/> And not wishing a "change in the weather,"<lb/>
                    Concluded to send our Burgess right down,<lb/> With the onerous duty of "saving
                    the town,"<lb/> Who managed the business he found to be down,<lb/> In a mode
                    that "did credit" in more ways than one,<lb/> To our ancient and goodly
                    Borough;<lb/> To the knowledge of these if you wish to explain-<lb/> Now,
                    gentlemen, please don't become so profane,<lb/> You all shall be paid-to-morrow.</p>
                <p>Now Jenkins determined to leave us awhile,<lb/> But first though it best to
                    disarm us.<lb/> Believing perhaps our power might spoil,<lb/> Or that pistols
                    and guns might harm us.<lb/> And hence he issued an order requiring<lb/> All
                    persons within the precincts of the town,<lb/> All rights being forfeited by
                    them by firing<lb/> (And oh! how we trembled at Jenkins's frown)<lb/> Upon the
                    benignant confederate forces,<lb/> And wickedly stealing the best of their
                    horses,<lb/> At once to deliver all arms and munitions<lb/> To officers named to
                    make proper disposal,<lb/> On pain of reprisal for any omissions,<lb/> And
                    punishment dire for every refusal.</p>
                <p>But whether compliance was honestly made,<lb/> Or a feigned respect to the order
                    was paid,<lb/> We all were swift his commands to obey,<lb/> And have our names
                    on his books "put down,"<lb/> 'Twas really a laughable farce to play,<lb/>
                    Though done, of course, "to preserve the town."</p>
                <p>Such a motley collection of arms I swear,<lb/> Has never before been exhibited
                    here.<lb/> There were swords without hilts and guns without locks,<lb/> Stocks
                    without barrels and barrels without stocks;<lb/> Pistols a big as your finger,
                    and e'en<lb/> A two-ounce vial of powder was seen.<lb/> And I stood and looked
                    on as my friends passed by,<lb/> And to whate'er they carried I gave "half an
                    eye."<lb/> "Hollo, dear N-, what is that you have there?"<lb/> "Oh! nothing-or
                    only a trifle."<lb/> I caught a slight glimpse, and it was, I declare,<lb/> A
                    telescopic rifle.<lb/> And then friend F- came along and got booked<lb/> For a
                    load that would break down a mason;<lb/> Five muskets-two <orig reg="sabers"
                        >sabres</orig>-astonished I looked<lb/> For howitzer, cannon, and caisson.</p>
                <p>VII.<lb/> But Jenkins now returns again,<lb/> And Lee and his army following
                    them,<lb/> Grief, terror, and desolation<lb/> Throughout our lovely valley
                    fling,<lb/> And nearer, nearer, nearer bring<lb/> Destruction to the nation.</p>
                <p>The first to come over the roads was Rhodes,<lb/> And then brigade, division, and
                    corps<lb/> Into the town with clatter and roar,<lb/> In one unceasing current
                    pour;<lb/> Divisions almost half a score:<lb/> Johnson's, Anderson's, Picket's,
                    and Hood's,<lb/> On, and on, and onward still,<lb/> McLaw's, and Pender's, and
                    Heath's, until<lb/> The corps of Ewell and A.P. Hill,<lb/> And the "Bull-dog"
                    Longstreet, all were found<lb/> Encamped throughout the neighborhood round,</p>
                <p>These rebels were flushed with insolent pride,<lb/> Believing an irresistible
                    tide<lb/> Like the waves of a deep-flowing river,<lb/> Was sweeping the nation
                    far and wide,<lb/> Engulfing us 'neat it forever.<lb/> "We're back in the Union
                    again," they cried<lb/> And endless their boasting and vaunting;<lb/> "You'll in
                    it remain," was all we replied,<lb/> Though endless their gibes and their
                    taunting.</p>
                <p>While Hood's division was passing through,<lb/> A lady sporting the "Red, White,
                    and Blue,"<lb/> From a bosom whence traitor ne'r won it,<lb/> Was hailed by an
                    insolent reb, who cried,<lb/> As he our own beloved emblem spied,<lb/> "A
                    breastwork, lady, please bear in mind,<lb/> Hood's boys delight to storm, when
                    they find<lb/> The Yankee colors on it."</p>
                <p>These rebs were an ignorant set, to be sure,<lb/> Nor was their language always
                    pure;<lb/> For reading, and writing, and such little arts,<lb/> Are not esteemed
                    "essential parts,"<lb/> Among our Southern cousins;<lb/> And one of them asked,
                    in a drawling tone,<lb/> A dirty, lousy son of a gun,<lb/> "What fur do yo'ns
                    fight us'ns?"</p>
                <p>A lady, Blackwood says and knows,<lb/> Cried out as the rebs passed by,<lb/> "To
                    the Red Sea Pharaoh's army goes,"<lb/> But things since veered awry.<lb/> For
                    when old Pharaoh led before,<lb/> His army to the Red Sea's shore,<lb/> Moses
                    was passing through;<lb/> But this time "Moses" might be seen<lb/> On Pharaoh's
                    side, sufficiently "green,"<lb/> To enter the Red Sea too.</p>
                <p>Now Moses (I dreamed) went round to see<lb/> That all our merchandise might
                    be<lb/> (In Blackwood find the text)<lb/><pb n="43"/> Carefully packed and
                    marked "supplies,"<lb/> While we looked on with sad surprise,<lb/> To see our
                    goods "annexed."</p>
                <p>But I suddenly from my dreams awoke,<lb/> As a distant sound of thunder
                    broke<lb/> Upon my startled ear;<lb/> And I looked around, but the foe was
                    gone,<lb/> My dream of "Border War" was done;<lb/> While the Falling Spring went
                    singing on,<lb/> O'er the Falls in accents clear.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
