<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0017"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0017">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Lee Defeated at Gettysburg," by A.
                    K. McClure, 1905</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county lee defeated at gettysburg, by a k mcclure 1905</title>
        <author>McClure, A. K.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 24.4 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0017</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498534</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Lee Defeated at Gettysburg," by A. K. McClure, 1905</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county lee defeated at gettysburg, by a k mcclure 1905</title>
            <author>A. K. McClure</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>12 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Old Time Notes of Pennsylvania,
                            Vol. II, Ch. LXI, p. 96-107</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Battle Description, Church/Religious Activity,
                        Death/Casualties, Home Front, Medicine/Hospitals, Military Authority,
                        Military Strategy, Patriotism, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-04-25">2006-04-25</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0017T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>McClure recounts locals of Chambersburg passing information to the Union, the
                    battle of Gettysburg through the eyes of those waiting for news in Washington
                    and elsewhere, and discusses how McClure had to go through a great deal of
                    effort to secure a Christian burial for a Confederate soldier.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>General Lee and His Leading Lieutenants in Chambersburg-Personal Description of
                    General Lee-Why Lee Moved to Gettysburg-Remarkable Feats of Volunteer
                    Scouts-Stephen W. Pomeroy Gave the First Word of Lee's Movement to Gettysburg-A
                    Week of Appalling Anxiety at Harrisburg and Throughout the State-Lee's Retreat
                    from Franklin County-Intense Passions That Denied Burial to a Confederate
                    Soldier.</p>
                <p>ON MONDAY, June 29, 1863, General Lee, with the largest Confederate army that
                    ever engaged in battle, had his entire command within the limits of
                    Pennsylvania, with his headquarters at Chambersburg, and General Meade, who had
                    just been assigned to the command of the Army of the Potomac, had his somewhat
                    larger force on the line north and south in Maryland and Pennsylvania, with his
                    head quarters at Frederick City, ready to concentrate against Lee whether he
                    moved eastward by the line of the Susquehanna or on the more direct line to
                    Baltimore and Washington. Lee himself, with his staff, entered Chambersburg on
                    the 26th, accompanied by General A. P. Hill. When they reached the center square
                    of the town Lee and Hill, mounted on their horses, conferred alone for some
                    time, and they were watched with great interest by the citizens, who were
                    intensely anxious to ascertain the line upon which Lee would advance. After the
                    consultation it was with a measurable sense of relief that they saw Lee turn
                    eastward on the Gettysburg pike. He proceeded to the little grove known then as
                    Shetter's Woods, just outside of the borough, where he made his headquarters,
                        <pb n="97"/> and remained there until he started to Gettysburg on the 31st
                    of June.</p>
                <p>The most careful and dispassionate observer among the people of Chambersburg of
                    the movements of Lee's army was Mr. Jacob Hoke, a prominent merchant, and his
                    "History of the Great Invasion of 1863," a volume of over 600 pages, is the most
                    complete and accurate in all details of the Gettysburg campaign that has ever
                    been presented. He witnessed the entrance of Lee and Hill into the town, and
                    thus describes Lee on page 167 of his admirable work: "General Lee, as he sat on
                    his horse that day in the public square of Chambersburg, looked every inch a
                    soldier. He was at that time about fifty-two years of age, stoutly built, medium
                    height, hair strongly mixed with gray, and a rough gray beard. He wore the usual
                    Confederate gray, with some little ornamentation about the collar of his coat.
                    His hat was a soft black without ornamentation other than a military cord around
                    the crown. His whole appearance indicated dignity, composure and disregard for
                    the gaudy trappings of war and the honor attaching to his high station."</p>
                <p>Lee's army was then located as follows: Of Ewell's corps, <orig reg="Early's"
                        >Earley's</orig> division was at York, Rhodes' division at Carlisle,
                    Johnson's around Shippensburg and Jenkins' cavalry was at Mechanicsburg, less
                    than ten miles from the State Capital. Of Hill's corps, Heth's division was at
                    Cashtown, with Pender's and Anderson's between Fayetteville and Greenwood, both
                    in Franklin County and west of the South Mountain. Of Longstreet's corps, McLaws
                    and Hood were in the neighborhood of Fayetteville, Pickett's division was near
                    Chambersburg to cover the rear of the advancing army; Imboden's cavalry was at
                    Mercersburg and Stuart's cavalry was in the neighborhood of Union Mills,
                    Maryland, north of Westminster. Lee was greatly em-<pb n="98"/>barrassed for two
                    days at Chambersburg in deciding upon what line he should move, as he had no
                    knowledge of the movements of the Union army. Stuart, who should have been
                    between Lee and the Union army, and giving information to Lee of its movements,
                    was driven from his course by the Union cavalry in Maryland and Pennsylvania,
                    and it was not until Sunday night, June 28, that a scout reached Lee's
                    headquarters and gave him the first information that the Union army had crossed
                    the Potomac and was concentrated, with Frederick as its center, ready to unite
                    against Lee whether he should march by the Susquehanna or the line of the
                    Potomac.</p>
                <p>This information quickly decided Lee to move to Gettysburg, and orders were sent
                    by swift messengers, as all telegraphic communication was interrupted, to <orig
                        reg="Early">Earley</orig> and Rhodes and all the other outposts to
                    concentrate as speedily as possible at Gettysburg. The celerity with which
                    Hooker had moved his army across the Potomac on a line that always gave the
                    fullest protection to the Capital, and compelled Lee to cross the Potomac west
                    of the Blue Ridge, decided Gettysburg as the great battlefield of the war. Had
                    Lee crossed the Potomac east of the Blue Ridge, as he originally intended, or
                    had he been advised of Hooker's crossing the Potomac two days earlier, his army
                    would have been far east of Gettysburg by the time that the battle was fought,
                    and he would have escaped the fatal necessity of fighting the Army of the
                    Potomac in probably the strongest natural position it could have found between
                    Williamsport and Washington. The only opposition that Lee's advance met with in
                    the Cumberland Valley was an occasional feeble skirmish with the undisciplined
                    militia commanded by General Knipe, of Harrisburg, who, being unable to give
                    battle to the overwhelming numbers of the enemy that always <pb n="99"/>
                    confronted him, discreetly retired down the valley until he landed in
                    Harrisburg.</p>
                <p>Such was the attitude of the two opposing armies immediately before the battle of
                    Gettysburg began. The entire Cumberland Valley was isolated from Harrisburg, as
                    all communication by railway or telegraph was broken up, and every highway in
                    the valley was covered by Lee's troops. My experience in entertaining the
                    Confederate officers in 1862, who had orders to take me as a prisoner to
                    Richmond, but who waived their knowledge of my personality because of the
                    hospitality they requested and received, taught me that it would not be discreet
                    for me to remain at home to entertain our Southern guests. I went to Harrisburg
                    on the last train that passed through the Cumberland Valley before the battle,
                    and remained there until Lee's retreat from the great struggle that inexorably
                    pronounced the doom of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>The more active men of Chambersburg well knew how important it was for
                    information to reach Harrisburg of the movements of Lee's army, and scouts were
                    sent out every day and night when any movement of importance was made. It is
                    marvelous how quickly the young men of the town and neighborhood developed into
                    the most daring and skillful scouts. The most prominent of them were Shearer
                    Houser, Benjamin S. Huber, J. Porter Brown, Anthony Hollar, Sellers Montgomery,
                    T. J. Grimeson, Stephen W. Pomeroy and Mr. Kinney. The only way that they could
                    reach Harrisburg was by getting out on the northwest toward Strasburg, and by
                    climbing several spurs of the mountains into Tuscarora or Sherman's Valley, and
                    reach the Pennsylvania Railroad at Newport, in Perry County, or Port Royal, in
                    Juniata County. When the concentration toward Gettysburg began scouts were sent
                    out generally with information written out by Judge <pb n="100"/> Kimmell on
                    tissue paper either sewed in their garments or carried in a pocket where they
                    could be promptly fingered into a little ball and swallowed in case of capture.</p>
                <p>The movement of the infantry toward Gettysburg was sent out at once, but was not
                    regarded as decisive of Lee crossing the mountain to Gettysburg until on the
                    night of the 29th, when the wagon train of the army was hurried through
                    Chambersburg on the way to Gettysburg. It was then accepted as conclusive that
                    the battle center of the campaign was to be transferred from the Cumberland
                    Valley to the line between the South Mountain and the Potomac, and it was
                    considered of the utmost importance to have the information sent speedily to
                    Harrisburg, as the only way to reach the Union commander. Among the young men
                    who happened to be in the town was Stephen W. Pomeroy, of Strasburg, whose
                    father had been an associate judge with Kimmell on the bench, and Kimmell knew
                    that he would be one of the safest who could be trusted with such a mission.
                    Kimmell prepared a <orig reg="dispatch">despatch</orig> without date or
                    signature, briefly telling of Lee's movements, and the certainty of his
                    concentration on the Potomac line. This <orig reg="dispatch">despatch</orig> was
                    carefully sewed inside the lining of the buckle-strap of Pomeroy's pants, and he
                    was hurried off on his important mission. He went on foot to his father's home
                    in Strasburg, where he managed to find a horse, and hurried across the mountain
                    spurs into Path Valley and to Concord at the head of the valley where the
                    mountain gap opens into Tuscarora Valley. He secured a fresh horse there, and
                    rode rapidly down the Tuscarora Valley, exchanged horses again with an
                    acquaintance near Bealtown, and he reached Port Royal on the Pennsylvania
                    Railroad, between two and three o'clock in the morning, after having walked
                    nearly twenty miles at a rapid gait and ridden <pb n="101"/> over forty miles.
                    He walked up to the telegraph operator and delivered his <orig reg="dispatch"
                        >despatch</orig>, but he was in such an exhausted condition that he did not
                    think of the necessity of signing it, or indicating in some way from whom it
                    came.</p>
                <p>I was one of the most anxious party in the Governor's room at Harrisburg waiting
                    for some information of the movement of Lee's army, and not knowing at what hour
                    Lee would swoop upon Harrisburg and hoist the Confederate flag over the Capitol.
                    For three days we had no information, excepting that furnished by scouts, and
                    while it was at times important, all of the reports received up to that time
                    gave no information as to Lee's purpose to deliver battle in the Cumberland
                    Valley or south of the South Mountain. There had been no sleep, except broken
                    naps forced by exhaustion, and not one of the Governor's circle had been in bed
                    for three nights. The whole State was simply paralyzed by the appalling
                    situation, and one of the aggravating features of it was that no information
                    could be obtained of Lee's movements or purposes. Colonel Scott was present, but
                    rarely left the little room in which was the telegraph battery. About three
                    o'clock in the morning of the 1st of July, Scott brought into the Executive
                    chamber an unsigned <orig reg="dispatch">despatch</orig> dated at Port Royal,
                    telling that Lee's entire army was marching toward Gettysburg, and that the
                    wagon trains rapidly followed, to which the operator had added that the
                    messenger had left Chambersburg the day before and reached Port Royal through
                    Path and Tuscarora Valleys, but no information was given as to his identity.</p>
                <p>The operator at Port Royal closed his office immediately upon sending the <orig
                        reg="dispatch">despatch</orig>, and all efforts to get him for further
                    explanation failed. General Couch, who was present, finding that in no way could
                    the <pb n="102"/> account be verified by reaching the messenger, at once crossed
                    the river and advanced a strong picket force toward Carlisle, and early in the
                    forenoon he discovered that Rhodes had withdrawn from Carlisle, and moved
                    directly toward Gettysburg, and he at once advanced his force up the valley that
                    was then entirely free from the enemy and re-established telegraph and railroad
                    communication. As soon as the unsigned <orig reg="dispatch">despatch</orig> was
                    received, it was repeated to Washington, and General Meade received it probably
                    within less than an hour after it reached Harrisburg. It was the information
                    given by this <orig reg="dispatch">despatch</orig> that prompted General Meade
                    to order Reynolds to make his <orig reg="reconnaissance">reconoissance</orig> in
                    force to Gettysburg, resulting in the first day's battle disastrous to the Union
                    army, and the death of Reynolds.</p>
                <p>Events of overwhelming moment multiplied so rapidly upon the worn-out men at
                    Harrisburg that the question of the author of the <orig reg="dispatch"
                    >despatch</orig> giving the important information was forgotten, and it was not
                    until twenty years later that Governor Curtin, or any of those about him at the
                    time, discovered who the messenger was. The Presbyterian synod was meeting in
                    Bellefonte, and Governor Curtin was entertaining several of the ministers. At
                    the breakfast table one morning the Governor mentioned the remarkable
                    circumstance of the important information received about Lee's movement to
                    Gettysburg, and that he had never been able to learn who the scout was who
                    brought the message. One of his guests, <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr>
                    Stephen W. Pomeroy, a member of the synod, then told them for the first time
                    that he was the scout, and at Curtin's request wrote out for him a detailed
                    account of his journey.</p>
                <p>News from the battlefield was awaited with the wildest interest, but none came
                    until the morning of the second day, when the information of the death of
                        Rey-<pb n="103"/>nolds and the overwhelming defeat of the two corps engaged,
                    with the capture of some 4,000 prisoners, reached the North through Baltimore,
                    and the first authentic account of the battle was brought by Major Rosengarten
                    and Captain Riddle, of Reynolds' staff, who brought the body of their fallen
                    chieftain to sleep with his kindred. During all of the second of July many
                    bloody conflicts occurred on the Gettysburg field, and there was continued
                    uncertainty and fearful apprehension as to the final issue of the conflict.
                    General Meade had communication with Washington so that any important event
                    could be ascertained. The most hopeful view that could be taken of the reports
                    of the second day's conflict was that it was without special advantage to either
                    side, and all of the night of the second, and the morning and day of the third
                    passed with the most painful uncertainty prevailing at Harrisburg. Wayne
                    MacVeagh was among the men who gave anxious days and sleepless nights to the
                    occasion, and he spent most of his time close to the tick of the telegraph.
                    About five or six o'clock in the afternoon he rushed into the Governor's
                    chamber, and with a wildly tremulous voice read out Meade's <orig reg="dispatch"
                        >despatch</orig> announcing the repulse of Pickett's charge. All knew that
                    such a charge was the last desperate effort of Lee to win at Gettysburg, and
                    that his defeat was almost absolutely assured. It was the first moment of relief
                    or anything approaching repose the worn-out men at the Capitol had been able to
                    welcome for fully a week. Some immediately sought their beds for rest, while
                    within half an hour there were many sleepers in the chairs and on the sofas of
                    the Capitol rooms. Curtin, because of his feeble condition, was forced home to
                    take his bed and remain there several days with the assurance that he would be
                    notified of any new peril that arose.</p>
                <pb n="104"/>
                <p>The following morning, the natal day of the Republic, the sun arose to spread its
                    refulgence over a cloudless sky, and the first news received from the
                    battlefield was that Lee's trains were retreating toward the Potomac, and later
                    came the message from Grant telling of the surrender of Vicksburg. The people of
                    Pennsylvania not only felt that they had been rescued from invasion and the
                    desolation of war upon their own soil, but they knew that the military power of
                    the Confederacy was broken, and the dark cloud of uncertainty verging on
                    despair, that hung over the great State for nearly a fortnight, speedily gave
                    way to the strengthened conviction and delightful hope that the Union could be
                    restored by the valor of our arms.</p>
                <p>The sudden change made by the report of Lee's defeat and the capture of Vicksburg
                    was visible on every face, old and young. The terrible strain was ended, the
                    invasion was repulsed, and the many thousands of people in the Cumberland
                    Valley, scattered all through the interior and eastern part of the State, with
                    their stock and other valuables, began a general movement homeward. Many of the
                    farmers had left their golden wheat fields ready for the reaper, but fortunately
                    the Confederates expected to occupy the valley and harvest it, and no
                    destruction of the grain fields was permitted. Most of the crops were thus
                    saved, and in a few weeks industrial operations in the shops and valleys were
                    very generally resumed. General Couch moved his forces forward through the
                    Cumberland Valley and rapidly repaired the railway and telegraph lines, and by
                    the 10th of July he established his headquarters at Chambersburg. A large
                    portion of Milroy's command had scattered off through the mountains in squads of
                    half a dozen or more, and in the general demoralization foraged upon the country
                    recklessly and often destructively. It required nearly two weeks to get them
                        re-<pb n="105"/>united. They were scattered along the Juniata Valley and in
                    the mountains as far west as Altoona. Most of the people as they returned to
                    their homes were amazed to find their property in comparatively well-preserved
                    condition, as Lee's orders against the wanton destruction of property were
                    scrupulously enforced by the infantry.</p>
                <p>The last echo of Lee's army in the Cumberland Valley came from his immense train
                    nearly twenty miles long, that left Lee at Gettysburg on the 4th and led the
                    advance of the retreat. To escape the dashes of the Union cavalry, this immense
                    train recrossed the South Mountain and turned southward at Greenwood to the
                    Potomac along the unfrequented road on the mountain base, and where only the two
                    small villages of New Guilford and New Franklin witnessed it. The wagons of this
                    train were largely filled with the severely wounded, and accompanying it were
                    all the wounded who were able to travel on foot. This train was thirty-four
                    hours in passing a given point, and General Imboden, who had charge of it, and
                    whose cavalry command protected it, stated in an article contributed to the
                    Annals of the War that when compactly in line the train was seventeen miles in
                    length. The number of wounded in the wagons and walking was not less than 10,000
                    or 12,000, and many of those who attempted to walk with the train fell by the
                    wayside. These were gathered up and brought to Chambersburg, where a Confederate
                    hospital was improvised, but the intense passions inspired by civil war made the
                    people of even so intelligent and Christianlike a community as those of
                    Chambersburg at first withhold kind ministrations to the wounded of the enemy.
                        <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> Senseny, my own family physician, was in
                    charge of this hospital, and in the multiplicity of cares that crowded upon my
                    return to Chambersburg I had given no attention to it.</p>
                <pb n="106"/>
                <p>After these wounded Confederates had been in Chambersburg for a week <abbr
                        expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> Senseny called upon me, and made a personal appeal
                    to inaugurate a movement to give much-needed relief to many of the suffering. It
                    would not have been discreet for any other than a pronounced loyal citizen to
                    take the first step toward relief for these sufferers, but my attitude was not
                    one that could be questioned, and Mrs. McClure at once went with the doctor and
                    visited all of the sufferers personally. That movement made an open door for
                    all, and thereafter they had even more generous ministration than most of them
                    could have obtained at home. A message was brought to me by <abbr expan="Doctor"
                        >Dr.</abbr> Senseny from Colonel Carter, I believe a native of Tennessee,
                    but then a resident of Texas, who had no hope of recovery, and had appealed to
                    the doctor to bring him some one who would give him the assurance of Christian
                    burial. I called at once and found the sufferer, an unusually bright and
                    handsome man, calmly watching the rapid approach of death. With beseeching eyes
                    that would have melted the sternest enemy, he begged of me to give him the
                    assurance that his body would receive Christian burial, and when he was told
                    that I would personally execute his request, he reached out his trembling hand
                    and gave most grateful acknowledgment. A few days thereafter he died, and I at
                    once applied to the authorities of the Presbyterian church, of whose
                    congregation I was a member, for permission to bury him in the cemetery, but it
                    was promptly refused. A new cemetery company had been organized a short time
                    before, of which I was an officer, and I applied to that company to sell me a
                    lot for the burial of the Confederate soldier, but that was refused. I then
                    announced that I would set apart a lot on the corner of my farm on the public
                    highway, and dedicate it by deed as the resting place of Colonel Carter. The
                    incident <pb n="107"/> caused very general discussion, and finally several
                    prominent members of the Methodist church decided that it was un-Christian to
                    refuse burial to a fallen foe, and they permitted his body to be interred in
                    their cemetery. Such were the appalling estrangements caused by civil war that a
                    community noted for its intelligence and Christian character hesitated to give
                    even decent sepulture to one who had fallen in the battle as conscientious in
                    his convictions as were the brave boys who vanquished him in the conflict.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
