<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0009"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0009">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin: "Chapter XXXVI. The Preliminary Battle of
                    1860.," by Alexander K. McClure, 1905</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin chapter xxxvi the preliminary battle of 1860 , by alexander k mcclure 1905</title>
        <author>McClure, Alexander</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 29 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0009</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498526</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin: "Chapter XXXVI. The Preliminary Battle of 1860.," by
                            Alexander K. McClure, 1905</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin chapter xxxvi the preliminary battle of 1860 , by alexander k mcclure 1905</title>
            <author>Alexander K. McClure</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>15 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Alexander K. McClure, Old Time
                            Notes of Pennsylvania, 1905, pages 384-398.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy</term>
                    <term>State Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0009T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this work, Alexander McClure details the history Andrew Curtin's nomination
                    for governor in 1860 by following the heated relationship between Andrew Curtin
                    and Simon Cameron.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>THE year 1860 came upon us pregnant with the most momentous events of the
                    century. It dated the second great political revolution, and the third distinct
                    epoch, in the history of the Republic. The Federal party came into power with
                    Washington, and ruled during the twelve years of the two terms of Washington and
                    one of the elder Adams, when Jefferson won the first substantial revolution in
                    the politics of the nation. Jefferson's battle was against the illiberal Federal
                    views, which demanded a government of centralized power, while Jefferson battled
                    for government of the people. The policy established by the Jefferson revolution
                    ruled the country for sixty years. All of the Presidents during that time were
                    not distinctly Democratic, as Adams, who was elected by the House in 1825,
                    although nominated as a member of the then existing Republican party that later
                    became the Democratic party, was drifting away from his old political
                    affiliations and made an entirely independent administration. The two Whig
                    Presidents -- Harrison, elected in 1840, and Taylor, in 1848 -- brought no
                    material reversal of the general Democratic policy established by Jefferson in
                        <pb n="385"/> 1800, that gave us the acquisition of Louisiana and all our
                    Pacific and Southern extension of territory; but 1860 brought a revolution that
                    ended the Democratic party as a ruling power of the nation. Two Democratic
                    Presidents have been elected since 1860, but, even with the strong personality
                    of Cleveland in the Executive chair during two terms, no permanent change was
                    made in the policy of the government.</p>
                <p>A decided political revolution was generally expected in 1860, but none then
                    dreamed that it would mean anything more than merely halting the extension of
                    the slave power, and liberalizing the policy of the government in the support of
                    free industries against the slave labor of the South. Had it been generally
                    believed in 1860 that the election of Lincoln would bring the bloodiest civil
                    war of modern times, and the sudden and complete overthrow of slavery at the
                    point of the bayonet, it is doubtful whether the popular vote of the country
                    would have invited such an appalling entertainment. The sectional feeling was
                    greatly intensified by the earnest and constantly growing agitation that began
                    with the repeal of the Missouri Compromise in 1854 and had continued to convulse
                    the country by the desperate struggles over Kansas, with the battle for a free
                    State then unsettled. The North believed that the South was more bombastic than
                    earnest in the threat of provoking civil war for the protection of slavery, and
                    the South believed that the Northern people were mere money-getters, ready to
                    yield anything rather than accept fratricidal conflict.</p>
                <p>Had the North and the South justly understood each other, as they should have
                    done when remembering the common heroism exhibited by Northern and Southern
                    soldiers on every battlefield, there would have been no civil war. It was common
                    in those <pb n="386"/> days to hear demagogues on the stump in the North declare
                    that, in the event of secession, the women of the North would sweep away the
                    bombastic South with their brooms, and like demagogues of the South told how, in
                    the event of civil war, they would march to Boston and command their obedient
                    slaves on Bunker Hill. How it was possible for the bravest and noblest people of
                    the world thus to misunderstand each other merely because of irritating
                    sectional divisions, must be incomprehensible to any intelligent student of the
                    present day. The people of the North and the South were of the same blood; they
                    had the same proud traditions; their heroism and their grandeur in field and
                    forum had been established side by side in every triumph, and only the madness
                    of the fiercest passion could have made either section assume that cowardice
                    could be an attribute of the American people, North or South. The most fearful
                    atonement was made for this strange misunderstanding of each other, and there is
                    nothing in Grecian or Roman story that equals the heroism of the soldiers of the
                    blue and the gray in four years of bloodiest conflict.</p>
                <p>The second victory of the opposition to democracy in Pennsylvania was achieved in
                    the fall of 1859, and it was notice to all that Pennsylvania was debatable
                    ground for the great battle of 1860, with chances largely in favor of another
                    defeat for the Democracy. So earnest were the people in forcing the unity of
                    political action by the various elements which were not in hearty sympathy with
                    each other, that the leaders who were ambitious for promotion by the success of
                    the new organization were compelled to avoid disturbing the unity of the
                    opposition forces by individual ambition, but as soon as the election of 1859
                    had reached a decided opposition victory, a host of candidates were suddenly
                    sprung upon the <pb n="387"/> new People's party for the office of Governor and
                    United States Senator.</p>
                <p>Curtin and Cameron had become implacably estranged in their desperate contest for
                    the Senatorship in 1855, and from that time until the close of their political
                    careers they never met or exchanged the ordinary courtesies of life except on
                    ceremonial occasions. They became intensely embittered against each other in the
                    three months' struggle for the Senatorship five years before, and
                    reconciliation, or even the restoration of the ordinary civilities of life, was
                    made impossible by a personal reproach put upon Curtin by Cameron when he had
                    several of his political friends about him in a convivial mood, during the heat
                    of the Senatorial struggle. The only time that I ever knew Curtin and Cameron to
                    meet in conference was the morning after Sumter had surrendered, when Curtin
                    with myself, as chairman of the military committee of the senate, was summoned
                    hastily to Washington to confer with the President, the Secretary of War and
                    General Scott as to the action necessary for Pennsylvania to take to meet the
                    civil war that had been forced upon us.</p>
                <p>In the raising and furnishing of troops in Pennsylvania many serious differences
                    arose between Governor Curtin and Secretary Cameron, as both were probably
                    inclined to judge the actions of each other harshly. When such disputes became
                    serious, Lincoln invariably summoned me to Washington to confer with Cameron and
                    himself on the subject, and in every instance the difficulties were adjusted and
                    accepted by both Cameron and Curtin. My relations with Cameron were always
                    personally pleasant, and while he was very earnestly opposed to me politically
                    as a close and ardent friend of Curtin, he had confidence that I would always
                    fulfill any obligations which I <pb n="3883"/> assumed. Cameron embarrassed
                    Curtin very seriously on several occasions by giving special authority to
                    favorites to raise regiments in Pennsylvania. Armed with the authority of the
                    War Department, with all necessary expenses paid, the prospective colonel would
                    locate in Philadelphia, or some section of the State, to raise a regiment, and
                    as a rule they did not make much progress. Indeed, some of them were not in
                    haste to fill their regiment and get into the field, as they were enjoying a
                    good time and were well paid while on recruiting duty. A number of such embryo
                    regiments were located in different parts of Pennsylvania when a requisition was
                    made upon the State for additional troops, and Curtin, always prompt in response
                    to the call of the government, at once declared his purpose to consolidate the
                    various embryo regiments, appoint the officers and make them part of the quota.</p>
                <p>In this Curtin was entirely warranted by the Constitution and the laws, as his
                    right was absolute to appoint the officers of regiments. He communicated with
                    the Secretary of War, officially announcing his right and his duty and asking
                    the Secretary to issue his order to the recruiting colonels he had authorized,
                    to consolidate their regiments under the direction of the Governor, but Cameron
                    promptly and positively refused. Curtin and Attorney General Meredith went over
                    the case very carefully, resulting in Meredith drawing an order to be signed by
                    the Secretary of War, directing the consolidation of the regiments under the
                    authority of the Governor, and I was requested to take the order to Cameron,
                    then visiting his home at Lochiel, and explain why his signature was a
                    necessity. Assuming that he would promptly refuse to sign the order, Mr.
                    Meredith prepared for Curtin a letter to the President, stating the <pb n="389"
                    /> Governor's right under the Constitution and the laws of the State, and
                    demanding that they should be respected by the National government, as it was
                    the only way in which he could be relieved of painful embarrassment and grave
                    obstacles in filling the quota of the State. My instructions were to present the
                    order to Cameron at his home, and if he refused to sign it to take a train that
                    night to Washington and present the letter and order to the President.</p>
                <p>I reached Cameron's home in the evening some time after dark, and, as usual, was
                    received with courtesy. I presented the order to him, and before he had time to
                    read it, I explained the Governor's rights, which Cameron doubtless knew, and
                    urged him to harmonize the effort to fill our quota by signing the order. He
                    read it carefully and deliberated for some time, when he finally answered that
                    he would refuse to sign the order. He insisted that he was trying to aid the
                    Governor in furnishing troops from Pennsylvania, and that to sign the order
                    would be to confess that he had exceeded his authority in a manner injurious to
                    the service, by granting permission to various persons to organize regiments. He
                    gave his answer very courteously and expressed his regret that there should be
                    any difficulty between the State Executive and the War Department in such a
                    crisis.</p>
                <p>I took the order, placed it in my pocket, and, while putting on my overcoat, I
                    remarked that I regretted his refusal to sign the paper, not only because it
                    opened an unpleasant issue between him and the Governor, but because I was
                    compelled to proceed to Washington that night to deliver the order and a letter
                    in my possession to the President, explaining the situation and demanding the
                    revocation of the Secretary's order as a matter of right to the Governor.</p>
                <p>Cameron evidently knew that a letter from Curtin <pb n="390"/> to Lincoln
                    defining the Governor's rights and duties which were absolutely undisputed could
                    have but one result. He asked me to sit down and talk the matter over. We had a
                    very earnest, frank, but always kind and courteous discussion of the question
                    for some time. I told Cameron that the President could do no less than direct
                    him to issue the order, and it would make public a political scandal that would
                    weaken the power of the State in furnishing troops, and I appealed to him not
                    only for his own sake, but for the interests of the State, to end the dispute
                    there by signing the order. He asked me to give it to him again, and when I did
                    so he signed it promptly without any exhibition of unkindness toward Curtin or
                    any others, and handed it back to me. This act of Cameron removed a multitude of
                    troubles which had grown up in the State in organizing and furnishing troops.
                    The dispute between the Governor and the Secretary of War had been wisely
                    withheld from the public, and the order of the Secretary directing the
                    consolidation of the various embryo regiments was made public by the Governor as
                    though it were the voluntary act of the War Department, and thereafter no
                    attempt was made to encroach upon the prerogatives of the State Executive.</p>
                <p>Curtin was the logical candidate for Governor of the opposition that was united
                    under the People's party flag. He was known as altogether the most effective
                    popular campaigner in the State, and he had exhibited great administrative
                    ability as secretary of the commonwealth under Pollock, especially in the
                    advancement of our free school system. He was a man of the most genial and
                    fascinating manners, and was the special favorite of the younger element of the
                    party. Cameron was intensely hostile to him, and saw that unless he played a
                    bold hand with reasonable <pb n="391"/> success, Curtin would be nominated and
                    elected as Governor and be strongly entrenched in the citadel of power of the
                    new political organization. While, as a rule, the followers of Cameron and
                    Curtin shared the prejudices of the chiefs, there were a number of men, and some
                    of them quite prominent in political power, who supported Curtin for Governor as
                    the most available of the candidates presented, but who were personally and
                    politically friendly to Cameron as well. They were ready to serve Cameron in any
                    movement for his own advancement, but unwilling to desert Curtin in doing so.</p>
                <p>Cameron was one of the most sagacious political leaders of his day, and was
                    heroic in effort when he had decided upon his plan of operation. He knew that he
                    could not be nominated for President, as in the political conditions then
                    existing he was simply an impossible candidate, but as he would be without a
                    competitor for the Presidency in Pennsylvania, he decided to make an aggressive
                    battle ostensibly for the Presidential nomination. He was formally announced as
                    a candidate for the Presidency by his friends, and a very active campaign made
                    to secure his endorsement by the State convention that was to nominate a
                    candidate for Governor. It was a masterly movement on the part of Cameron,
                    regardless of its utter hopelessness. It gave him a strong position in which to
                    wield his power against the nomination of Curtin, and it would also give him
                    special prominence for cabinet or other National honors if the Republicans
                    elected the President. The Cameron campaign was pressed as Cameron always
                    pressed his battles, persistently and methodically, and some time before the
                    convention met it was generally conceded that Cameron would receive a decided
                    majority in the convention for president, and that Curtin would be <pb n="392"/>
                    nominated for Governor. In point of fact, in a convention of 133 members,
                    Cameron had about eighty who were ready to support him for President, and Curtin
                    had about a like number who were ready to support him for Governor, and yet
                    Cameron and Curtin both played to the limit in hostility to each other.</p>
                <p>There were two prominent competitors of Curtin in the contest for Governor. They
                    were John Covode, of Westmoreland, and David Taggart, of Northumberland. Cameron
                    shrewdly planned to divide the party as much as possible by multiplying
                    candidates for Governor, and Covode and Taggart were regarded as the two men,
                    one of whom would ultimately be chosen, on whom to unite the opposition to
                    Curtin. Thomas M. Howe, a highly respected Congressman from Allegheny, was
                    brought into the field to divert the strength of Curtin, as was Levi Kline, of
                    Lebanon, but the man upon whom Cameron intended ultimately to unite the
                    opposition forces was Covode, and he was altogether the strongest of the
                    opposing candidates.</p>
                <p>Covode attained great distinction as a political leader. He was a man of rare
                    sagacity, strong natural intellectual force, with little culture and rather
                    inclined to take pride in his crude ways and expressions. He was elected to
                    Congress in the Westmoreland Democratic district by the Know Nothing whirl of
                    1854, and early became a very aggressive leader in opposition to the slave power
                    that was seeking to force slavery into Kansas and Nebraska; was elected to his
                    fourth consecutive term in the popular branch of Congress, and he was chairman
                    of the committee that went to Kansas and investigated the efforts that had been
                    made to overthrow the rule of the bona fide residents. He was an expert in
                    knowing how to develop all the bad political phases of the movement against free
                    Kansas, and with a man of Repre-<pb n="393"/>sentative Howard's ability and
                    accomplishments to write a report, Covode's presentation of the wrongs of Kansas
                    became the political text-book of the Republican party. He was a man of tireless
                    energy, clean personal record, a master student of human nature and was one of
                    the most skillful of all our prominent men in managing a campaign for himself.
                    He retired from Congress in 1863, but did not abate his interest in politics. He
                    was sent south by President Johnson in 1865 to aid in Johnson's reconstruction,
                    but Covode soon rebelled against it and retired. He was renominated for Congress
                    in 1868 and was elected, and in 1870 made his final political battle for
                    Congress against Henry D. Foster, the ablest Democrat of the district, and was
                    successful.</p>
                <p>Covode was a man of liberal means, a most tireless worker, personally popular,
                    and Cameron confidently counted upon his ability to give Covode sufficient
                    support in the State convention to nominate him for Governor. Taggart had been
                    elected to the State senate in 1854 in the Northumberland and Dauphin district,
                    but bitterly opposed Cameron's election to the Senate in 1855. Cameron resented
                    this opposition of his own immediate senator by severely retaliating upon
                    Taggart and his family, taking from them the control of the Northumberland Bank
                    that gave a livelihood to Taggart's father and increased his own revenues as
                    attorney for the bank.</p>
                <p>A few years later Taggart decided that Cameron was a dangerous enemy, and they
                    reconciled their differences upon terms which Taggart confidently believed would
                    bring Cameron to his support for Governor. He did not assume that Cameron was
                    pledged to support him, but he did not doubt that he would be the Cameron
                    candidate in the end. He lacked the strength and some important personal <pb
                        n="394"/> qualities possessed by Covode, and Cameron in the end logically
                    concentrated his strength in the strongest candidate, and had Cameron not been
                    caught bar Cumin's friends in the convention in a position much like that of
                    Hooker's bull, who was fast on the fence and could neither hock in front nor
                    kick behind, it is quite possible that Covode would have been nominated.</p>
                <p>There were fully eighty men in the convention who were positively pledged or
                    instructed for Curtin and sixty-seven were a majority, but by the time the
                    convention met the friends of Curtin discovered that half a dozen or more of the
                    men positively pledged to support him had been switched off to Covode, and among
                    them Colonel Gehr, my fellow-delegate from Franklin, who was one of the very few
                    known Cameron men in that section, and whose election I had aided to accomplish
                    simply to demonstrate that Cameron's friends would not be <orig reg="ostracized"
                        >ostracised</orig>. He was sincerely for Curtin and positively pledged to
                    him, but I learned the night before the convention met that he was pledged to
                    support Covode, as were McConkey, of York, and Haines, of Perry, two additional
                    Cameron delegates, who were pledged to Curtin and elected for the same reason
                    that had given me a Cameron associate from Franklin. Nearly the whole of the
                    night before the meeting of the convention was devoted by Curtin's friends to
                    getting his stragglers into line, but when the convention met the next day we
                    were in grave doubt as to our ability to hold a majority for Curtin.</p>
                <p>Fortunately Cameron pressed his nomination for the Presidency as the first duty
                    of the body. It was an unusually able assembly with Governor Pollock in the
                    chair, and such able anti-Cameron representatives as Tom Marshall, of Allegheny,
                    and District <pb n="395"/> Attorney Mann, of Philadelphia, while Schofield, of
                    Warren, a man of unusual ability, championed the Cameron cause and stood with
                    heroic fidelity in support of Curtin. A resolution was offered nominating
                    General Cameron for the Presidency, and instructing the delegates-at-large to
                    support him in the national convention. No other name was presented, and the
                    delegates were compelled to vote directly for or against conferring the honor
                    upon Cameron. Protracted and somewhat acrimonious debate was had upon the
                    resolution, in which Tom Marshall, one of the ablest and most fearless of the
                    Western Republicans, denounced Cameron unsparingly as a Presidential candidate,
                    and declared that he could go out any dark night and grab fifty men who were
                    better fitted for the position than Cameron.</p>
                <p>Schofield ably supported Cameron, and sought to pour oil on the troubled waters,
                    while Senator Mumma, who represented Cameron's home county, took the laboring
                    oar of managing the Cameron side and defended his cause with great earnestness.
                    When the vote was finally taken, forty-four of us voted squarely against the
                    adoption of the resolution, and about eighty voted for Cameron, with a few who
                    did not respond.</p>
                <p>Cameron shrewdly sought to temper the opposition somewhat by proposing David
                    Wilmot and Thaddeus Stevens, neither of whom was for Cameron, as two of the four
                    delegates-at-large. He relied upon them obeying their instructions, which they
                    did, but neither attempted to advance Cameron's nomination at Chicago. The
                    question then arose as to how the district delegates should be chosen. As
                    Cameron was weak with the Republican people in the State, I made a blind stroke
                    to call him to a halt on the Curtin issue by offering a resolution providing
                    that the district <pb n="396"/> delegates should be chosen by the people of
                    their respective districts and not by the convention, and to my surprise, after
                    I had spoken briefly in support of the motion, Mumma followed with a motion to
                    adjourn until the next morning. Although coming from a Cameron leader, I was
                    very glad to accept it, and the convention adjourned, neither side knowing
                    precisely where it stood, and the Curtin men did not know how weak the Cameron
                    men were on the question of selecting a Cameron delegation by the convention.</p>
                <p>Very early in the evening Alexander Cummings, then editor of the Philadelphia
                    "Evening Bulletin," and ex-Senator Haldeman, of York, both very earnest Cameron
                    men, sent for me to meet them in a private room in the same hotel where I was
                    staying. I joined them at once, and they informed me that they had come to
                    effect a compromise on the question of electing the district delegates to the
                    National convention. I asked them why they did not defeat my resolution that was
                    still pending before the convention, and they frankly informed me that they had
                    not done so because they had not votes enough. They said:--</p>
                <p>"You want Curtin for Governor, we want Cameron for President, and we are here,
                    with the knowledge and by the advice of Cameron himself, to adjust the
                    difficulty on the basis of giving Curtin the nomination for Governor."</p>
                <p>I told them that as they had come from Cameron I certainly must confer with
                    Curtin before I could propose to accept any definite proposition, and we
                    adjourned for an hour. I immediately hastened to Cumin's room, locked the door,
                    told him of the situation and asked him to go over the list of delegates and
                    ascertain how many men we had who could be relied upon under all circumstances
                    to support him. We found the names of sixty-five on the list who <pb n="397"/>
                    could be relied upon to stand by Curtin, and I proposed that the negotiations
                    with Cameron's representatives should require them to return to us ten delegates
                    who had been elected for Curtin, but who had been taken from us by Cameron. I
                    suggested to Curtin, as a compromise proposition, that I should agree to modify
                    my resolution to authorize the delegates in the convention from any
                    congressional district to decide for themselves whether they would name
                    delegates to be chosen by the convention, or whether they would refer the choice
                    of district delegates back to the people, to which Curtin agreed.</p>
                <p>I met Cummings and Hallman soon thereafter and gave them my ultimatum, viz.,
                    first, that they should return to Curtin ten delegates originally chosen for
                    him, each of whom I named, who must come to Curtin personally and pledge their
                    support to him, and that if that were done at once I would move to modify my
                    resolution as Curtin had agreed to it. I named among the delegates to be
                    returned to Curtin my own associate and others, who, like him, had been honestly
                    committed to Curtin, but were taken from him by the power of Cameron. They were
                    quite willing to give us the ten delegates or even more, as they meant the
                    adjustment to involve the nomination of Curtin, but begged to be excused from
                    compelling the men they had taken from us to return to their allegiance to
                    Curtin. I peremptorily refused, and they finally assented, and every one of the
                    delegates named came in person and pledged himself to Curtin before midnight.</p>
                <p>They accepted the other proposition very willingly as to the district delegates,
                    but insisted that I should give the example of electing the delegates from my
                    own district. It would have been difficult then to find two men in my district
                    fitted for the position of <pb n="398"/> National delegate who were friendly to
                    Cameron, but I finally agreed to elect delegates and to send two men of high
                    position, neither of whom was friendly to Cameron, but whom I pledged to vote
                    with the delegation.</p>
                <p>It is quite possible that Curtin might have been defeated, but for this halt in
                    the Cameron <orig reg="program">programme </orig>that enabled Curtin's friends
                    to make reprisals. When the convention met the next morning Judge Hale, of
                    Bellefonte, Curtin's immediate representative, offered a compromise resolution
                    as an amendment to mine, as had been arranged, and it was promptly accepted by
                    Mr. Mumma and myself and unanimously adopted. Curtin's nomination followed on
                    the second ballot when he received seventy-four votes to twenty-seven for
                    Covode, sixteen for Taggart, ten for Howe and a dozen scattering. Such is the
                    story of the inner history of Cumin's nomination for Governor.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
