<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0046"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0046">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "The War Between the States, its
                    Causes, Character, Conduct and Results," by A. H. Stephens, August 16, 1870</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county the war between the states, its causes character conduct and results by a h stephens august 16 1870</title>
        <author>A. H. Stephens</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 6.5 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0046</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498558</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "The War Between the States, its Causes, Character,
                            Conduct and Results," by A. H. Stephens, August 16, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county the war between the states, its causes character conduct and results by a h stephens august 16 1870</title>
            <author>A. H. Stephens</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Public Opinion, August 16, 1870,
                            p. 2 col. 6</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va. (microforms)</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-08-16">1870-08-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Reunification</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-21">2006-02-21</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0046T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This article is a book review for a new volume in (former vice president of the
                    Confederacy) Alexander H. Stephen's history of the Confederacy and Civil War.
                    The reviewer glows with praise for the work, claiming that it is informative and
                    free from sectionalism.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Three years ago the announcement by the National Publishing Company, of
                    Philadelphia of the speedy publication of this great work, created a profound
                    sensation throughout the country. The press of both sections hailed the
                    appearance of the book with delight, for it was admitted by all that the task of
                    transmitting to prosperity the Southern version of the history of our great
                    civil war could not have been confided to an abler pen than that of Mr.
                    Stephens, the greatest living statesman of the South. The colleague and friend
                    of Clay, Calhoun and Webster, he is a connecting link between the present and
                    the glorious past, and as Vice-President of the late Southern Confederacy, he is
                    peculiarly fitted for the task, by his opportunities of knowing the most secret
                    details of the history of the War. Above all, his high character as a man which
                    has always won him the respect of his political enemies, enables us to rely upon
                    his statements with an absolute certainty. In the first volume of his work, Mr.
                    Stephens confined himself exclusively to the <hi rend="underline">cause</hi>
                    of the War, reserving the narrative of the actual struggle for the second and
                    concluding volume. The success of the former volume was extraordinary, reaching
                    a sale of over 60,000 copies.</p>
                <p>If then that portion of the work which of necessity was the <orig reg="driest"
                        >dryest</orig>-if any part of this magnificent production can be called
                    dry-has met with such a wonderful and rapid sale that we are not warranted in
                    predicting for the second, in which the thrilling story of the most terrible and
                    destructive war of modern times, is told with all the fascination of romance and
                    all the <orig reg="sublime">sublimity</orig> of truth. Mr. Stephens slights no
                    feature of the War, and his work reveals a particularly interesting and
                    fascinating portion of its history, which has never been made public until
                    now.-He goes to the bottom of the secession movement, and gives the confidential
                    history of the Convention which formed the Confederacy. The vexed question of
                    the non-exchange of prisoners of war has much new light shed upon it, and this
                    alone ought to commend the book to every one who saw the inside of a Northern or
                    Southern prison.</p>
                <p>What will strike the practiced reader most favorably however, is the fact that
                    Mr. Stephen's narrative is free from bitterness and sectional feeling. He writes
                    with that calm dignity which is always the historian's most effective weapon,
                    weighing facts according to their merits, and arriving at conclusions with a
                    clearness of judgment which is, to say the least, remarkable in one who was
                    himself so important an actor in the events narrated.-It is this fact which will
                    make his book so welcome to those who are seeking substantial information upon
                    the subjects treated of, and who prefer clear and straight-forward statements of
                        <hi rend="underline">what was done</hi>, to fine theories as to <hi
                        rend="underline">what might have been</hi> accomplished. Having been
                    compelled by ill health, since the war, to remain almost entirely in the privacy
                    of his home, and to take no part in the questions of the day, Mr. Stephens has
                    been enabled to look back over his long and honorable career with the calmness
                    of one whose record is completed, and to produce, as his most valuable service
                    to the country, the magnificent history which lies before us. The book is sold
                    by subscription only, and agents are wanted in every country.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
