<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0066"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0066">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "The Burning of Chambersburg," by ,
                    August 2, 1870</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county the burning of chambersburg, by august 2 1870</title>
        <author/>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes">6 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0066</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498576</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "The Burning of Chambersburg," by Unknown, August 2,
                            1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county the burning of chambersburg, by unknown august 2 1870</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Public Opinion, Chambersburg, PA,
                            August 2, 1870</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville Va. (microforms)</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-08-02">1870-08-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Economy, Home Front, Military Authority</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-10-11">2005-10-11</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0066T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Marking the sixth anniverary of the burning of Chambersburg, the Franklin
                    newspaper included a detailed, still angry, first-person account of the burning.
                    Thus there was still bitterness, part of the legacy of the wartime burning.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>On Saturday last, the 30th of July, was the sixth anniverary of the burning of
                    Chambersburg at the hands of the rebel incendiary, M'Causland, and his horde. On
                    the morning of that day, just six years ago, twenty-six hundred rebel veterans
                    (cavalry) occupied the <orig reg="outposts">out-posts</orig> of Chambersburg, in
                    supporting distance of the four or five hundred delegated and commanded to apply
                    the torch. Promiscuous plundering was indulged in by the soldiery from the hour
                    of the possession of the place until the command was given for applying the
                    torch. We were one of a party of eight--T. B. Kennedy, <abbr expan="William"
                    >Wm.</abbr> M'Lellan, J. M'D. Sharpe, <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> J. C.
                    Richards, W. H. McDowell, W. S. Everett and E. G. Etter, who were ordered under
                    arrest, and held for the raising of five hundred thousand dollars in greenbacks,
                    or one hundred thousand dollars in gold, failing to do which in fifteen minutes,
                    we were to be taken to Richmond and the town burned. <abbr expan="Doctor"
                    >Dr.</abbr> Richards informed the rebel general that it was out of the question
                    to comply with the demand, when the general (Gilmore) said that we could
                    "consider ourselves released for the present but to report again to <orig
                        reg="headquarters">head-quarters</orig> in twenty minutes." The party didn't
                    report. The enemy were stationed and appropriated over the town with torch in
                    hand, ready for the order to burn, <orig reg="which">whish</orig> was now given.
                    In fifteen minutes smoke might be seen arising from buildings in every
                    direction, and in half an hour the heart of the town was one body of flames.</p>
                <p>We shall not attempt a picture of the horrid scenes that followed. All here are
                    familiar with these heart-sickening details. As a summary of what was done, we
                    give the following from Dr. Schneck's history of the "Burning of Chambersburg."
                    "Residences and places of business consumed, 278; various other buildings, 271;
                    total number of buildings consumed, 549. In a few hours,<pb n="2"/> the major
                    portion of Chambersburg, its chief wealth and business, its capital and
                    elegance, were devoured by a barbarous foe; three millions of property
                    sacrificed; three thousand beings homeless and many of them penniless; and all
                    without so much as a <orig reg="pretense">pretence</orig> that the citizens of
                    the doomed town, or any of them had violated any accepted rule of civilized
                    warfare. Such is the deliberate, voluntary record made by <abbr expan="General"
                        >Gen.</abbr><orig reg="Early">Earley</orig>, a corps commander in the
                    insurgent army."</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
