<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0059"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0059">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Legend of the Late Civil War," by
                    C. C. Kauffman, March 1914</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county legend of the late civil war, by c c kauffman march 1914</title>
        <author>Kauffman, C. C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 14.9 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0059</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498569</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Legend of the Late Civil War," by C. C. Kauffman,
                            March 1914</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county legend of the late civil war, by c c kauffman march 1914</title>
            <author>C. C. Kauffman</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kauffman's Progressive News,
                            Greencastle Press, 2:23 &amp; 24, February 27, 1914 and March 6,
                            1914</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1914-02-27">1914-02-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Economy, Family, Patriotism, Race Relations, Slavery,
                        Veterans, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-09-19">2005-09-19</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>proofed</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0059T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>The author describes a run-in with a hermit who tells a story of his birth in
                    Pennsylvania, then move to the South, where he got involved in slavery and
                    joined the Confederate Army. At the end of a battle, the hermit found his
                    brother, captain of the Union troops, dead.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>It was one bright and beautiful morning in May, and all nature seemed to be doing
                    her best. Not a cloud floated in the archway of Heaven and the sun was shining
                    in all the splendor of his brightness. A gentle breeze was blowing from the
                    Sunny South interlaid with the jessamine and orange. The trees were shooting
                    their foliage and proudly looked down upon the velvet green meadows as they lay
                    stretching themselves out in the distance. Ever and anon could be heard the
                    clear notes of the birds as they sand in the dizzy <orig reg="height"
                    >heighth</orig> above and made merry in the grove beyond. The ox lay bathing in
                    the sun and the lambs skipped each other in play, while the swallow's swift
                    course was over the meadow and along the winding stream. Spring had come and
                    nature had dressed the world in all the grandeur and splendor of her beauty.
                    There was not a valley, mountain or stream that did not seem to be conscious of
                    the fact, and as the mountain daisy nodded to the <orig reg="lily-of-the-valley"
                        >lilly-of-the-valley</orig>, the rippling stream rolled onward to the sea. I
                    was <orig reg="nonplussed">nonpulsed</orig>, not knowing in what direction to
                    take my course, for on every hand there was a lesson to be learned and a
                    principle to be understood.</p>
                <p>A love of nature and an inquisitive mind soon had me far beyond the limits of my
                    native town, wandering where the aborigines loved to sail their birch canoe and
                    rove undisputed lords of a country not yet in question. I paused for a moment on
                    a high bluff that overlooked the surrounding country, and there under the
                    branches of a wide spreading tree I watched the merry pranks of a little
                    squirrel as it mounted high in the tops of the trees and then to the ground. It
                    seemed to be unconscious of either present or approaching danger as it lay flat
                    on a limb not far distant from where I was standing. The temptation and
                    opportunity to do it harm was so great that I picked up a small missile that lay
                    at my feet and was in the act of hurling it at the little squirrel when
                    something said, "Live and let live". It came with such force and so impressed
                    itself on my mind that my arm fell to my side and the stone to the ground. It
                    was a jewel memorized when a boy and placed away upon the tablets of my memory
                    to be used when an occasion like this required it. Safety was not with me alone,
                    for when I cast my eyes to the ground, I saw a large snake with head erect
                    moving in the direction of the tree, but my curiosity was not aroused to know
                    the mission of one who had practiced it the first deceit on the human family, so
                    I continued my journey along the historic banks of the Conococheague, for I had
                    knowledge of a hermit that lived in a cave in the hills and was frequently seen
                    when pressed by hunger going to and from the cavern.</p>
                <p>My walk was a pleasant one, for it brought me in contact with the wild flowers
                    and the many pretty things as revealed by the hand of God. It was past the hour
                    of noon, for the sun was far in the West, when I came to the Conoco Hills, where
                    the hermit lived. A strange feeling of fear and fancy stole over me as I entered
                    a deep ravine on either side of which rose great and lofty hills, for fear that
                    I would meet the object of my search. I passed out of the ravine and was
                    standing on a small sand bar that jutted out into the creek, when a large owl,
                    hid away in the tops of the trees, gave an unmercifully loud screech, that under
                    the circumstances set me quaking with fear, and before I could gather myself and
                    thoughts together the hermit appeared but a short distance away along the waters
                    edge. He was either unconscious or unmindful of my presence, and I had a good
                    view of him as he stood gazing intently into the water. He was tall and gaunt
                    with long arms and legs. His eyes were deep set and he had an old fashioned
                    Roman nose with high cheek bones and long pointing chin. His hair was long and
                    silvered with gray, so that it fell over his shoulders and came down to his
                    waist. His beard was long and <orig reg="straggly">stragly</orig> and he
                    reminded me very much of Rip Van Winkle. I must have his attention with the
                    least possible disturbance or my mission will be in vain. I was waiting an
                    opportunity when he looked up and saw me and started up the hill, but before he
                    had gone far his feet slipped and he fell some ten or twelve feet to the bank
                    below, striking his head on a large rock, and lay unconscious. I hurried to his
                    assistance and bathed his head with water from the creek. It was some minutes
                    before he showed signs of life and when he did he opened his eyes and looked at
                    me in a wild bewildered kind of way. I was very kind and offered to assist him
                    in sitting up, but he refused and would not talk. He made the second effort but
                    failed, and then realized that he must have my assistance, which I again offered
                    him, and he accepted. He pointed to the hillside and then for the first time
                    spoke, asking me to assist him to his cave in the hill.</p>
                <p>To Be Continued</p>
                <pb n="5"/>
                <p>Continued from last week.</p>
                <p>I took his arm and we made our way as best we could from rock to rock and from
                    peak to peak until we came to the entrance of the cave. Here he sat down
                    exhausted from the effort, saying that my kindness was worthy of something and
                    that if I would abide with him a few hours he would confide in me the story of
                    his life. He felt that he was nearing the end of life's journey and was
                    tottering on the way and that he would soon lay down by the wayside and
                    surrender that which was not his own for a new life and a new work. It was his
                    intention to die retaining the secret, but he would tell it to me.</p>
                <p>We entered the cave, which was well kept but damp, and which had appearance of
                    long use and of a routine daily life. I watched him closely and he had the
                    bearing and manner of a once high-toned, dignified gentleman and showed every
                    evidence of a finely cultured mind up to July, 1863, after which time it was
                    blank. We seated ourselves around the dying embers of a fire on the floor of the
                    cave, the smoke from which curled to the top and was lost in the darkness. As we
                    sat gazing into the fire he seemed to be meditating on the past, and the
                    grave-like silence remained unbroken for some minutes, when he said:</p>
                <p>"I am a Pennsylvanian by birth and when quite young left my home in the North to
                    find a new one in the South. A younger brother followed my example, he going
                    North and locating in Massachusetts. We kept up an occasional correspondence
                    until the breaking out of the late Civil War, when I received his last letter,
                    stating that he had enlisted in a Massachusetts regiment and was coming South. I
                    had heard and read so much about Southern chivalry and the field of honor, that
                    I felt a delicacy in going South for the reason that I entertained views
                    radically different from <orig reg="theirs">their</orig> and was firmly set in
                    my opinion of emancipation. This feeling was only momentary, however, after
                    traveling through the principal part of the South, I learned to love and admire
                    the people and was not long in locating. The first year rolled around without
                    having anything to do, and finally I became overseer on a large cotton
                    plantation in Alabama. My associations were with the professional and business
                    men of the community, and it afforded me the opportunity of improving a much
                    neglected want, and ere long my conscientious scruples on emancipation, like the
                    snow flake melted under the sun's gentle ray. By industry and economy I
                    accumulated some wealth which I invested in the slave traffic, which was very
                    lucrative, and in the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> ouree of time returned me a handsome income. I had
                    become a full fledged Southerner in every particular and my confidence in the
                    people and their cause grew as my investments in the slave traffic became
                    heavier. The owner of the cotton plantation over which I had charge became
                    financially embarrassed and disposed of his slaves, which I purchased and turned
                    back upon the plantation at a handsome rental.</p>
                <p>"A young lieutenant of the regular army stationed at Charleston, <abbr
                        expan="South Carolina">S. C.</abbr>, was paying attention to my employer's
                    youngest daughter, Elvira. He was very attentive and his visits were quite
                    frequent, but in the course of time I noticed a falling <orig reg="off"
                    >og</orig> in his social calls and a decided coldness toward myself. I asked
                    Elvira the cause of this and she said that he wanted to press a marriage
                    engagement which she refused. He accused me of being the cause, saying that he
                    knew of the financial relation between myself and her father, and that I owned
                    the daughter as well as the property. I said I will refute this charge, but
                    would be only be too happy to call Elvira my own. She said 'your wish shall be
                    granted.' In the course of a week or ten days and the young lieutenant made a
                    social call and Elvira acquainted him with the facts in the case. He left
                    swearing vengeance, and that evening when I was driving with Elvira into the
                    city I met the lieutenant on his way out. As his carriage neared mine and he saw
                    Elvira at my side he peremptorily and without ceremony said: 'George Thomas, I
                    challenge you to a mortal combat on the field of honor, you to select the place,
                    time and weapons.' Quick as thought I replied, 'I will meet you in the Dismal
                    Swamps of Virginia, March 12, at 9 o'clock a.m., with pistols at twenty paces.'
                    The rest of the details were <orig reg="arranged">atranged</orig> by our
                    seconds, and on the morning of the 12th, as I drove into the swamp, I saw the
                    lieutenant and his friends clearing away a place for the fight. My second and
                    myself helped in completing the arrangements and at 9 o'clock a. m. they had us
                    twenty paces distant, back to back, with pistols in hand. The command to fire
                    was given and both pistols rang out loud and clear. I felt a stinging sensation
                    in my left side and as I raised my hand to the wound I saw the lieutenant reel
                    and fall. The doctor hurried to his side but he was dead. The ball had entered
                    his left breast directly the heart. My wound needed little attention, which was
                    given when I entered my <orig reg="carriage">car-carrlage</orig> and hurried
                    away. The news was flashed all over the South, and when Elvira heard it, for
                    fear of my safety, she fell into a stupor and before I could reach her side was
                    dead.</p>
                <p>The excitement of the duel had hardly died away until Beauregard fired on Fort
                    Sumpter, when I enlisted in an Alabama regiment in defense of my rights and
                    property. I went all through the war up to 1863, when Lincoln issued his
                    emancipation proclamation, which left me without a dollar in the world. My
                    grievance now was greater than ever and I was only too glad to learn of Lee's
                    intended invasion. I had not only to wait, for the opportunity soon presented
                    itself, and as we drew up our line of battle at Gettysburg I felt that victory
                    would soon perch upon our banners.</p>
                <p>"I was in the thickest of the fight on the first, second and third. On the
                    evening of the third, just as the sun was setting in the West, a Massachusetts
                    regiment came out of the woods and charged our regiment on the Baltimore pike.
                    It was lead by a brave young captain, and as he came to the pike, he was struck
                    by a piece of shell and fell mortally wounded. The regiment became demoralized
                    and fell back into the woods. That night I was detailed one of three to bring
                    water from a nearby spring. When we came to the pike where the captain fell I
                    asked a wounded soldier that lay by his side if the captain was dead. Yes, said
                    he, 'and a braver boy never wore the blue than Will Thomas.' 'Will Thomas,' said
                    I, and as I turned him over the moon shown full in his face and I was satisfied
                    that it was my brother. That night I buried him with dead and dying heroes all
                    around him, and as the first gray dawn streaked the Western sky I heard the
                    retreating forces of Lee's mighty army. As we were falling back into Virginia
                    and before we crossed the Potomac I wandered from the army and found my way here
                    to the cave in the Conoco Hills. A few more parting words and George Thomas, the
                    hermit, and I parted forever.</p>
                <p>The End</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
