<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0036"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0036">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Recollections of Lee's Invasion,"
                    by John W. P. Reid, April 11, 1919</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county recollections of lees invasion, by john w p reid april 11 1919</title>
        <author>Reid, John W. P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 19.4 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0036</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498548</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Recollections of Lee's Invasion," by John W. P.
                            Reid, April 11, 1919</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county recollections of lees invasion, by john w p reid april 11 1919</title>
            <author>John W. P. Reid</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kauffman's Progressive News,
                            4/11/19</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1919-04-11">1919-04-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Home Front, Military Authority, Military Strategy,
                        Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement, Veterans</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-03-20">2006-03-20</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0036T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Reid gives his account of life in Greencastle during Lee's invasion.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Mr. John W. P. Reid Gives an Interesting Account of the Trials and Troubles of
                    the People of Greencastle June and July 1863</p>
                <p>Rebel Commander Told William Allison He Would Shell Greencastle if Prisoner Was
                    Not Returned in 24 Hours as Citizens Showed Little Sense.</p>
                <p>Zanesville, Ohio<lb/> April 5, 1919</p>
                <p>Mr. Editor:-Today I received your issue of yesterday and notice that you have
                    promised your patrons my recollection of events transpiring at Greencastle,
                        <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr>, during Lee's Invasion-his advance and
                    retreat. As you may have correspondence which should be given place, I will
                    divide my reminiscence in two parts, viz, happenings up to July 4th, 1863, first
                    part, 2nd, from 4th of July (morning 4:30 A. M.) to departure, in retreat of his
                    forces which passed <orig reg="through">thru</orig> Greencastle, going towards
                    Potomac river on Williamsport Pike.</p>
                <p>Company K. 126 <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr><abbr expan="Volunteers"
                        >Vols.</abbr> was discharged with <abbr expan="Regiment">Reg.</abbr> at
                    Harrisburg, <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> May 20th, 1863. The two
                    Juniata Companies (F &amp; I) went to Mifflintown the remaining 8 companies
                    came to Chambersburg, where we were received in grand style, plenty to eat,
                    several placards bearing the words "Brave men of the 126. <abbr
                        expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr> J. G. Rowe, disabled by wound received was
                    unable to take part in Parade, therefore commanded of second platoon devolved on
                    me. I pointed to placed, saying to <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> A. R.
                    Davison, none of Chancellorsville Skulkers shall march in my platoon," so his
                    platoon numbered more than mine. This class of soldiers throughout the Regiment
                    had declared that when mustered out they would attend" to me when detailed as
                    Field <abbr expan="Regiment">Reg.</abbr><abbr expan="Quartermaster">Q. M.</abbr>
                    at Chancellorsville battlefield. I asked each company Commissary when he came to
                    draw company rations, how many of your company were in the battle-draw (rations
                    for them) those not in the fight will do without, no intention of starving them,
                    but wishing to impress upon them the necessity of doing their duty; this class
                    claimed that as May 2nd was 9 <abbr expan="months">mos.</abbr>, it was not their
                    duty, or rather they were not compelled to go into battle after 9 months, for
                    which they had enlisted and expired (of course they received rations on the next
                    draw) I claimed that until mustered out, we must fight. Readers of this
                    communication can decide for themselves, whether I was just or not.</p>
                <p>Milroy's army was driven out of Winchester, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>,
                    June 15th 1863-part skeddling towards Washington, part to Hancock, the remaining
                    part came through Greencastle, I boarded with James Hause, <abbr expan="West"
                    >W.</abbr> Baltimore <abbr expan="Street">St</abbr>, as I had done for many
                    years. Had no set time for retiring nor rising 11 o'clock P. M. to 12 M. would
                    do-rise 7 A. M. to A. M.</p>
                <p>When I came to Diamond, June 16, 1863 about 8 A. M, I saw a <orig reg="group"
                        >groupe</orig> of citizens on Newcomer's corner lot where bank now is was
                    vacant. When I arrived within talking distance, I of course asked "what is
                    up"-at this time several U. S. wagons were in sight coming down <abbr
                        expan="East">E.</abbr> Baltimore, crossing from it to <abbr expan="North"
                    >N.</abbr> Carlisle <abbr expan="Street">St.</abbr>, diagonally, didn't come to
                    Railroad-a box or two fell out-no stop to replace it in wagon-teamster <orig
                        reg="driving">dirving</orig> as if Rebels were right after him: now back to
                    time I asked what was was up, I was told Rebels were coming. Jim Null had his
                    shotgun, some others had guns and others were to take stock, horses, wagons,
                    etc, to "Fulling Mill Hill," and there await Rebels if they came, defend
                    property, etc., the several parties with horses, wagons, etc., departed for
                        <orig reg="Rendezvous">Rendevous</orig>. Army wagons had all passed out of
                    sight on road to Harrisburg. All quiet for about 30 minutes then came in via
                    Hagerstown road <abbr expan="East">E.</abbr> Baltimore <abbr expan="Street"
                    >St.</abbr> and stopped, the advance down as far as alley. While Boyd's <orig
                        reg="cavalry">calvary</orig> were resting along street I was standing on
                    porch at Hollar Hotel. Across Diamond at Irwin's store I saw a Copperhead (whose
                    name I will not state it might insult his friend) <orig reg="strike"
                    >stike</orig> a union man smaller than <orig reg="himself">htmself</orig>,
                    yelled wait till I get there, copperhead ran up to <abbr expan="Doctor"
                    >Dr.</abbr> Hammils (a dentist) at corner of alley-he had time to tell the
                    soldiers something derogatory of me, so when I reached the soldiers they barred
                    my way, this lead to an altercation, down rode the <abbr expan="Captain"
                    >Capt.</abbr> with a squad of his command with drawn sabers, Boyd in commanding
                    tone demanded to know what I was doing there raising a disturbance, I told him
                    minding my own business as he should do. He ordered me to go back home, I
                    replied I went home when I pleased not at the beck of any man, I was not now a
                    soldier, he said I suppose you never were. I had been in bigger fights than he
                    had, naming charge at Fredericksburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">V</abbr> and stated
                    I had been in the battle of Chancel-<pb n="2"/>lorsvil'e, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va.</abbr>, we were probably engaged in altercation 15 minutes when brother
                    William begged me to go away, that I might be hurt; looking at Boyd, I told him
                    he would run as soon as he saw the rebels, as that was the way Cavalry fought, I
                    said I go home for dinner and not because you ordered me to go. After dinner
                    John Donaldson and I were at Zieglers store sitting on door-step facing <abbr
                        expan="North">N.</abbr> Carlisle Street when Boyd came around corner,
                    recognized me and said "I told you to go home and stay <orig reg="there"
                    >therere</orig>, yes, and I told you I would not obey; Donaldson got up and
                    started away. I said I would go where and when I pleased, just then a squad of
                    Cavalry from Chambersburg, alighted at hotel the <abbr expan="Lieutenant"
                    >Lt.</abbr> in command I knew so I went up to the hotel shook hands with him,
                    Boyd calling <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr> to him commenced <orig
                        reg="talking">taking</orig> with him, as it was not my business to hear
                    conversation I went away-never saw Boyd afterwards but he <orig reg="sent"
                    >sen)</orig> word to me to recruit a company <orig reg="for">or</orig> his <abbr
                        expan="Regiment">Reg.</abbr> (21st <abbr expan="Pennsylvania"
                        >Pa.</abbr><abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> So ended our altercation-the
                    soldier wounded in skirmish when <orig reg="Rhiel">Rheil</orig> was killed and
                    was taken care of at Ilginfritz's wounded was to be 1st <abbr expan="Lieutenant"
                        >Lt.</abbr> as he understood cavalry drill and was to bring back with him at
                    least 15 recruits, he was so long returning that I became disgusted and took a
                    trip to New Martinsville, <abbr expan="West Virginia">W. Va.</abbr>, where my
                    sister Margaret resided. After supper and before sun down, <orig reg="Boyd's"
                        >Boy'd</orig> pickets on <orig reg="Hagerstown">Hrgerstown</orig> road came
                    pell mell down <abbr expan="East">E.</abbr> Baltimore and made toward
                    Chambersburg-I ran down <abbr expan="South">S.</abbr> Carlisle Street, reached
                    the hill at Yous, near Negro Church, from there could see the dust rising on
                    Hagerstown road and in a few minutes Imboden's rebel Mounted <abbr
                        expan="Infantry">Inft.</abbr> dashed <orig reg="through">thru</orig> the
                    streets, taking Chambersburg <orig reg="road">roar</orig>, on which road near
                    Fleming's the skirmish took place and Rhiel was killed, I was in Southern part
                    of <abbr expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> then went up to the Miss Eby's; nearly
                    opposite where James Null lived. Soon after I arrived and was sitting on the
                    porch a rebel came up to porch demanded an ax. I told him I did not reside at
                    house, knew nothing about where ax was kept, axes were found and a few minutes
                    telegraph poles were cut down and at Water Station set on fire, thus ended the
                    day. Upon the third day thereafter about 2 p.m. rebels returned, rode down to
                    Diamond, 30 or 40 countermarched and turned corner to left H Strickler where
                    detail was going was a matter of conjecture to us in center of <abbr
                        expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr>; but in about an hour rebs returned in
                    possession some teams I remember <abbr expan="Charles">Chas.</abbr> Stines horse
                    and butcher wagon was part of the loot, Rebs left town, going towards
                    Hagerstown-for a couple of days no Rebs came into town. The <abbr
                        expan="Cumberland Valley Railroad">C.V.R.</abbr> sent a Hand Car with crew
                    to repair Telegraph line were at work near Ziegler's store, many others with
                    myself were looking on, when a boy said to me horses &amp; rebels are up
                    near Hartman's pump I hurried to look up street, by that time, horses at a walk
                    were at alley, I ran to Hand Car jumped in yelled to hands rebels were just a
                    little distance up <abbr expan="East">E</abbr> Baltimore Street, one of the
                    hands who did not know me seized the piece of wood used to break the car, so I
                    stepped out, track hands jumped in, moved slowly towards Chambersburg, Rebels
                    stopped the car opposite Clippinger's. We couldn't hear what was said but the
                    hands moved the car South and left it at the warehouse on the South Carlisle
                    Street. When I came up street after dinner, four parties whose names I have
                    forgotten asked me to go with them to Chambersburg in car and come back in it. I
                    jumped in we started after a mile or two, we all wished we were back in <abbr
                        expan="Greencastle.">G.</abbr> When out near Hade's, we overtook one of the
                    hands who was walking on Railroad, he asked to get in, we consented if he would
                    help run car, he agreed. When we arrived in <abbr expan="Chambersburg."
                    >C.</abbr> we left car on track at street crossing went down street to Diamond.
                    In our absence car was taken by some one and delivered to railroad, then we
                    could walk to <abbr expan="Greencastle.">G.</abbr><abbr expan="Governor"
                        >Gov.</abbr><orig reg="Curtin">Curtain</orig> was at Franklin hotel, I was
                    introduced to him and told him what had <orig reg="occurred">occured</orig> in
                    the forenoon at <abbr expan="Greencastle.">G.</abbr> I decided to remain
                    overnight in <abbr expan="Chambersburg.">C.</abbr><abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col.</abbr> Rowe was in Chambersburg. Sometime in afternoon, Courthouse bell
                    was rung-town meeting called at which it was determined to ask the citizens to
                    volunteer for defence of town- before night probably two hundred or three
                    hundred had volunteered and <orig reg="on command">uncommand</orig> of <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Rowe marched out beyond suburbs, how far I do
                    not know as I was not a volunteer. It rained that night, after daylight the
                    command return to town and more bedraggled set of men I never saw-clothes
                    hanging to their bodies-surely a nondescript aggregation - armed with shot guns,
                    old muskets, etc.</p>
                <p>The day after we run the hand car to <abbr expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> after
                    dinner I started afoot for <abbr expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr>, arriving there
                    about supper time, as I was passing the hotel where the Shirey hotel is now
                    Daniel Hawbaker, town Constable, hailed me, wished me to help as guard of two
                    parties arrested during my absence in <abbr expan="Chambersburg">C.</abbr>, I
                    declined. He asserted they were rebels. The next afternoon I was in Rhoadarmer's
                    barber shop, cry was shouted "Rebels in town" we rushed to the street and
                    opposite Ziegler's store where bank now is we saw two men climb upon horse
                    behind the rider, then start for hotel. When Hawbacker saw his prisoners mount
                    behind the riders, he ran through hall of hotel out into alley, knowing the way
                    he succeeded in crossing Chambersburg road, by keeping the fields, rebs, on
                    horseback had to go by Shook's he reached Rankin's Mill in time to hide under
                    water of waste-way the rebs, failed to find his place of refuge and when they
                    returned to <abbr expan="Greencastle">G</abbr>, Hawbacker went toward Campbell's
                    town and remained away during Invasion. When the Fulling Mill defenders saw the
                    Rebels coming toward hill they never thought of fighting, the ones on horseback
                    escaped, the horses hitched to vehicles were nearly all captured. The amusing
                    incident was as follows, viz: James Null and Charles Stine made for the
                    Conococheague, striking same near the dam 1 1/2 miles above bridge. Null on
                    reaching creek sat down to take off his shoes so he could wade through and over
                    the water on the riffles, called to Stine came below dam Stine replied by <orig
                        reg="saying">saving</orig> "No time for riffles now Jim" and plunged into
                    the water, Charlie was over 6 ft. in height, so water did not reach his neck.
                    For months after it Charlie was discussing some matter some one would yell "No
                    time for Riffles now Jim." M. D Reymer wrote in rhyme these two incidents, as
                    well as other events.</p>
                <p>One afternoon M. D. Reymer and myself were on our way to first Dam where we
                    bathed and swam, almost daily. Saw a confederate searching negro quarters for
                    run-away slaves, could identify them by their talk. We stopped to see his luck,
                    noticing our stopping he said for what are you looking? We replied, "to see your
                    luck." He ordered us to move on. We replied, when satisfied.</p>
                <p>One afternoon coming from Dam on arriving at Diamond, saw a crowd at Paulings
                    hotel (called Bulls Eye from shape of sign) I hurried up to hotel, asked what
                    was up. There was a one horse wagon and a Rebel under arrest. On hearing my
                    inquiring one of the participants in the arrest said "It is none of your
                    business," we are taxpayers. I replied <orig reg="I">1</orig> don't pay any
                    taxes in <abbr expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> if I did no arrest would be made.
                    The Reb was sent to Waynesboro, the citizens of <abbr expan="Waynesboro"
                    >W.</abbr> sent him up to hotel on mountain. A few days thereafter orders came
                    from <orig reg="confederate">confiderate</orig> command to produce arrested man
                    or <abbr expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> would be shelled.</p>
                <p>Council was hastily called together resolution passed to find and return
                    prisoner. Only one blind horse and a one horse wagon without springs could be
                    found and started for Waynesboro. On arriving at <abbr expan="Waynesboro"
                    >W.</abbr> driver was told prisoner had been sent to mountain. Finally prisoner
                    was found returned to <abbr expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> and delivered to Rebel
                    commander. The general made his <orig reg="headquarters">headbuarters</orig> at
                    my brother-in-law William Allison, who told me commander said <abbr
                        expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> was an abolition hole, if prisoner not
                    returned in time even (24 hours) he would delight to shell <abbr
                        expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> as we the Taxpayers showed little sense for
                    men of families.</p>
                <p>On another occasion Rebels demanded powder, balls, etc., and vegetables or
                    whatever an army could use. <abbr expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> had no powder
                    and balls in other words munition. The vegetables were delivered on pavement at
                    Hollar hotel, As <orig reg="I">1</orig> was at Rowe's store corner, Mr. Miller
                    whose son was struck by lightning spring of 1862, came alone carrying a fine
                    saddle and bridle bought for his son deceased. I asked him where he was going
                    with saddle and bridle, he said to Hollar hotel to deliver to Rebels
                    requisition. I said, Mr. Miller have you got an ordinary saddle and bridle this
                    one is too good to give to the Johnnies. He replied <orig reg="I">1</orig> have
                    an old one, but if rebels made search and found this new saddle they might burn
                    my property. He gave the new saddle and bridle, The Town Council owing to orders
                    it had given was joculary named Onion Council, much to the disgust of several of
                    the councilmen.</p>
                <p>The foregoing about completes my remembrance of events of public interest up to
                    July 4th 1863. The next communication will relate <abbr expan="Captain"
                    >Capt.</abbr> Dahlgreen's attack, capture, disposition of prisoners (33)
                    captured by Milroy's <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cavl.</abbr> of Wagontrain at
                    Cearfosses <orig reg="tavern">taverin</orig> of 7 miles from <abbr
                        expan="Greencastle">G.</abbr> on Williamsport Pike.</p>
                <p>John W. H. Reid<lb/> 1107 Lexington <abbr expan="Avenue">Ave</abbr><lb/>
                    Zanesville, Ohio</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
