<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FM0021"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="FM0021">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: "Reminiscences of the Underground
                    Railroad," by Horace G. Kauffman, April 28, 1915</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county reminiscences of the underground railroad, by horace g kauffman april 28 1915</title>
        <author>Kauffman, Horace G.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8.8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FM0021</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2005">2005</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498538</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: "Reminiscences of the Underground Railroad," by
                            Horace G. Kauffman, April 28, 1915</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county reminiscences of the underground railroad, by horace g kauffman april 28 1915</title>
            <author>Horace G. Kauffman</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kauffman's Progressive News,
                            5/7/15</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from [unknown]</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1915-04-28">1915-04-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Race Relations, Slavery</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-12-15">2005-12-15</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FM0021T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kauffman recounts his understanding of his father's involvement in the
                    Underground Railroad and his memories of having an abolitionist Republican
                    father in the antebellum era.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="article" id="d5">
                <p>Oregon, Illinois, April 28, 1915.</p>
                <p>To the Editor:-I have read with interest the reminiscences of a late contributor
                    to the NEWS, wherein our father, the late John Kauffman, is referred to as
                    having been an agent on the Underground Railroad in the years immediately
                    preceding and during the Civil War, and wherein in particular it is stated that
                    on one occasion a fugitive slave came at two o'clock in the morning to the house
                    of this agent, who upon being awakened received the runaway into his home and
                    having sheltered and fed him in the secretive way necessary in those times of
                    peril to fleeing bondmen, when every public officer was expected to enact the
                    role of detective in aid of southern slaveholders, followed such material aid
                    with full and explicit directions to the next station of the famous subway which
                    extended from Mason and Dixon's Line to Canada. I am, induced to give an item
                    from recollections of my own of that period of sectional bitterness, political
                    upheaval and fratricidal war, when even as a lad of tender years I had
                    experiences which are as well remembered after the lapse of half a century as if
                    they had occurred only a few days ago.</p>
                <p>Greencastle was the first station on the Underground Railroad in that
                    neighborhood in a free state, being but four miles north of the historic
                    boundary between the North and the South-"that crimson scar of honor across the
                    brow of our country which divides the land of cold bread from that of hot <orig
                        reg="biscuit">buscuit</orig>." The town was for that reason a place of
                    importance and inspiration to the fugitives. Hope rose within them as they found
                    themselves in the coveted North, nor did Greencastle disappoint them. The
                    sentiments of a Randolph, a Calhoun, or a Toombs, however they grew and
                    flourished in the Halls of Congress, ninety miles away, fell upon stony ground
                    for the most part in the district represented at Washington by the great
                    commoner, Thaddeus Stevens. And why should not the Cumberland Valley have been
                    known for its abolitionists-its people the descendants of colonists from two of
                    the most liberty-loving countries of Europe, Scotland and Switzerland?
                    Greencastle's roll of honor, inscribed here from memory, includes the names of
                    Major John Rowe, George W. Zeigler, William Ward, John Wilhelm, Thomas Pauling,
                    John Kauffman, William Ward, in 1859, acted as guide from Greencastle to Harpers
                    Ferry for John Brown of Ossowatomine, when that brave, though mistaken, champion
                    of the slaves rested in Greencastle on his way south with his pasty and their
                    wagons.</p>
                <p>To act as an agent of the Underground Railroad was to risk one's peace and
                    safety, since giving aid to runaway slaves was in violation of the Fugitive
                    Slave Law, of 1850. This enactment was never respected by the more radical of
                    the Abolitionists, who chose conscience as their guide, and which they continued
                    to follow even when in his first inaugural address the enforcement of the
                    obnoxious law was recommended by Mr. Lincoln-the recommendation which drew upon
                    Mr. Lincoln from Wendell Phillips the famous words of opprobrium, "the
                    slave-hound of Illinois."</p>
                <p>Certainly, government and righteousness were in a tangle when the burden bearer
                    of a region's industry in order to get wages for his toil and the boon of
                    liberty for himself and his children were compelled to flee from the Stars and
                    Stripes, proud emblem of the new Republic, to the superior protection and
                    guaranty of that ensign of Monarchy, the banner of St. George; to do which it
                    became necessary to run the gauntlet of arrest by the ever watchful officers of
                    the law and the friends of vested interests through several hundred miles of
                    territory, and to depend chiefly upon the friendly, secret aid of the few ardent
                    lovers of Freedom who were willing to risk the suspicion and enmity of their
                    fellows, as well as criminal prosecution itself.</p>
                <p>Political feeling was intense and bitter. In 1854, father left the Whigs and
                    joined the newly-organized Republican party, opposed to the extension of
                    slavery. He was also an Abolitionist. He became therefore, in the vernacular of
                    the day, a "black-Republican", in favor of "nigger equality," and had put to him
                    that clinching question believed to triumphantly dispose of any abolitionist's
                    argument, to-wit, "Do you want your daughter to marry a nigger"?</p>
                <p>My first recollection of politics is in that connection, and pertains to an
                    incident which occurred in 1862, when I was seven years of age. Father had
                    bought the goods for a suit of clothes for me, and took me with him to a tailor
                    to have my measure taken preparatory to cutting out the pattern. The tailor in
                    this instance was a pro-slavery Democrat, jocular, hardshell and complacent, to
                    whom the agitation of the question of abolishing slavery was most objectionable
                    in that it aimed to destroy an existing legal institution of long standing
                    upheld by a majority of the party of his political faith. He had heard father
                    denounce "the league with death and covenant with hell", while not sparing
                    pro-slavery leaders, including President Buchanan. As he stood behind me and
                    drew the measuring tape from my shoulder to my wrist, he took a lock of my hair
                    between his thumb and finger and pulling it gently, said, "Do you know that your
                    hair is getting kinky?" Instantly, I was aflame, of course. I answered, "My hair
                    is a bit curly, but it is not kinky, and it will never be, either."</p>
                <p>The pro-slavery joker laughed, enjoying my ire, but he was unintentionally
                    assisting then and there in the making of another Republican and Abolitionist.
                    He himself was joined to his idols, even the convulsion of war passing over him
                    without clearing his mental atmosphere.</p>
                <p>Horace G. Kauffman.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
