<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.09.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/30.05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-08">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.08.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Teachers and Teaching--No. 1</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"W. T. P." from Sweet Briar Manse writes to the Spectator to inform readers
                    that an association is being formed aimed at professionalizing teaching as a
                    career.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>All hail to this great Company, which has just come into existence from the
                        chrysalis state of the old Va. Central Rail Road Company, which has already
                        so greatly enriched this whole region. The earnest wishes of the people of
                        Virginia seem about to be realized. -- Col. Fontaine, with an energy and
                        perseverance which must make his name forever honorable in the history of
                        his State, has gone forward, over seemingly insurmountable difficulties, and
                        succeeded in taking steps which must soon obtain for us the connection
                        between the Western and Eastern waters over this route which presents
                        advantages over any other in country, a consummation most devoutly prayed
                        for by all the great men of Virginia from Washington to this time.</p>
                    <p>We are glad to know that Col. F. will hereafter be aided by Hon. Samuel Price
                        as one of his directors. Mr. Price was elected a member of the Board of
                        Directors upon the unanimous recommendation of the Commissioners of the
                        State of West Va., who knew him well, and who knew, from his long and
                        valuable services in public life heretofore, and from his well known
                        integrity and business capacity, that he would be a most efficient coadjutor
                        for Col.. Fontaine and a most reliable agent for the interests of the States
                        of Va. and West Va.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the creation of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad, and the
                    appointment of their Board of Directors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Contract Consumated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The commissioners of Virginia and West Virginia have contracted with the
                    Virginia Central Railroad Company for constructing the Covington and Ohio
                    Railroad that will extend the Virginia Central to the Ohio River. Capt. C. R.
                    Mason played a role by subscribing large amounts of stock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mr. Pendleton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pendleton</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Pendleton has declared his support for Horatio Seymour. "He says
                    that not one decent white man in a thousand in Virginia will support Grant. In
                    fact, Mr. P. knows of but three Radicals in the State who are 'worthy of the
                    notice of any gentleman.' He adds that that 'diminutive and contemptible
                    faction' styled scalawags are 'in all respects immeasurably meaner and more
                    degraded than either the emancipated slaves or their inferiors the
                    'carpet-baggers.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Gen. Rosecrans and Gen. R. E. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The conference of Gen. Rosecrans with Gen. R. E. Lee and other distinguished
                        Southern men at the White Sulphur Springs has excited interest in all parts
                        of the country, and the public have manifested a feverish anxiety to learn
                        the character of the correspondence which took place between the parties.
                        The letter of Gen. Rosecrans is long, and we have not the space to publish
                        it in this issue, but we give below the reply of Gen. Lee and others which
                        will enable the reader to learn the substance of it. The whole people of the
                        South, with possibly the exception of mangy scallawags diseased with the
                        leprosy of Radicalism, will heartily endorse the able and patriotic letter
                        of Gen. Lee and the other distinguished men whose signatures are attached
                        thereto. The National <emph rend="italic">Intelligencer</emph> denominates
                        it a "masterly letter," and says "it is a calm, judicious, pacific, earnest
                        and eminently paper." Here it is:</p>
                    <p>WHITE SULPHUR SPRINGS</p>
                    <p>WEST VA., August 26, 1868.</p>
                    <p>GENERAL -- I have had the honor to receive your letter of this date, and in
                        accordance with your suggestions I have conferred with a number of gentlemen
                        from the South in whose judgment I have confided, and who are well
                        acquainted with the public sentiment of their respective States. They have
                        kindly consented to unite with me in replying to your communication, and
                        their names will be found with my own appended to this answer. With this
                        explanation, we proceed to give you a candid statement of what we believe to
                        be the sentiment of the Southern people in regard to the subject to which
                        you refer.</p>
                    <p>Whatever opinions may have prevailed in the past in regard to African
                        slavery, or the right of a State to secede from the Union, we believe we
                        express the almost unanimous judgment of the Southern people when we declare
                        that they consider that those questions were decided by the war, and that it
                        is their intention in good faith to abide by that decision. At the close of
                        the war, the Southern people laid down their arms and sought to resume their
                        former relations with the United States Government.-- Through their State
                        Conventions they abolished slavery and annulled their ordinances of
                        secession, and they returned to their peaceful pursuits with a sincere
                        purpose to fulfill all their duties under the Constitution of the United
                        States, which they had sworn to protect. If their action in these
                        particulars had been met in a spirit of frankness and cordiality, we believe
                        that ere this old irritations would have passed away, and the wounds
                        inflicted by the war would have been in a great measure healed. As far as we
                        are advised, the people of the South entertain no unfriendly feeling towards
                        the government of the United States, but they complain that their rights
                        under the Constitution are withheld from them in the administration thereof.</p>
                    <p>The idea that the Southern people are hostile to the negroes, and would
                        oppress them if it were in their power to do so, is entirely unfounded. They
                        have grown up in our midst, and we have been accustomed from childhood to
                        look upon them with kindness. The change in the relations of the two races
                        has brought no change in our feeling towards them. They still constitute the
                        important part of our laboring population. Without their labor, the lands of
                        the South would be comparatively unproductive. Without the employment which
                        Southern agriculture provides they would be destitute of the means of
                        subsistence, and become paupers, dependent on public bounty. Self-interest,
                        even if there were no higher motive, would therefore prompt the whites of
                        the South to extend to the negroes care and protection.</p>
                    <p>The important fact that the two races are, under existing circumstances,
                        necessary to each other is gradually becoming apparent to both, and we
                        believe that but for the influences exerted to stir up the passions of the
                        negroes that the two races would soon adjust themselves on a basis of mutual
                        kindness and advantage.</p>
                    <p>It is true that the people of the South, together with the people of the
                        North and West, are, for obvious reasons, opposed to any system of laws
                        which will place the political power of the country in the hands of the
                        negro race. But this opposition springs from no feelings of enmity, but from
                        a deep seated conviction that at present the negroes have neither the
                        intelligence nor other qualifications which are necessary to make them safe
                        depositories of political power. They would inevitably become the victims of
                        demagogues, who for selfish purposes would mislead them, to the serious
                        injury of the public.</p>
                    <p>The great want of the South is peace. The people earnestly desire tranquility
                        and the restoration of the Union. They deprecate disorder and excitement as
                        the most serious obstacle to their prosperity. They ask a restoration of
                        their rights under the Constitution. They desire relief from oppressive
                        misrule. Above all, they would appeal to their countrymen for the
                        re-establishment in the Southern States of that which has justly been the
                        right of every American -- the right of self-government. Establish these on
                        a firm basis, and we can safely promise on behalf of the Southern people
                        that they will faithfully obey the Constitution and laws of the United
                        States, treat the negro with kindness and humanity, and fulfill every duty
                        incumbent on peaceful citizens loyal to the Constitution of the country.</p>
                    <p>We believe the above contains a succinct reply to the general topics embraced
                        in your letter, and we venture to say on behalf of the Southern people and
                        of the officers and soldiers of the late Confederate army, that they will
                        concur in all the sentiments which we have expressed.</p>
                    <p>Appreciating the patriotic motives which have prompted your letter, and
                        reciprocating your expressions of kind regard, we have the honor to be,</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully and truly,</p>
                    <p>R. E. Lee, of Va.,<lb/>W. J. Green, N.C.,<lb/>G. T. Beauregard,
                        La.,<lb/>Lewis E. Harvie, Va.<lb/>Alex. H. Stephens, Ga.,<lb/>P. V. Daniel
                        Jr., Va.<lb/>C. M. Conrad, La.,<lb/>W.T. Sutherlin, Va.<lb/>Linton Stephens,
                        Ga.,<lb/>A. B. James, La.,<lb/>A. T. Caperton, W. Va.,<lb/>T. Beauregard,
                        Texas,<lb/>John Echols, Va.,<lb/>M. O. H. Norton, La.,<lb/>F. S. Stockdale,
                        Texas,<lb/>T. P. Branch, Ga.,<lb/>Jos. R. Anderson, Va.,<lb/>Jeremiah
                        Morton, Va.<lb/>W. T. Turner, W. Va.,<lb/>John B. Baldwin, Va.<lb/>C. H.
                        Suber, S. C., Geo. W. Bolling, Va.<lb/>E. Fontaine, Va.,<lb/>Theo. Flourney,
                        Va.,<lb/>John Letcher, V.,<lb/>James Lyons, Va.<lb/>B. C. Adams, Miss.,</p>
                    <p>To Gen. W. S. Rosecrans, Minister to <sic>Mexiao</sic>.</p>
                    <p>White Springs, Va.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter, signed by a number of former Confederate leaders, including Gen.
                    R. E. Lee, expressing the South's desire for reunification and restoration.
                    Acknowledges the South's opposition to black suffrage, but claims this is
                    similar to sentiments in the North and West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ransom</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hon. A. H. H. Stuart and Thomas D. Ransom have formed a partnership to
                    practice law in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Child Pianist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Little Willie Coffman, a blind boy only 33 months old, played piano at
                    White Sulphur Springs and will perform in Staunton on Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Bryan's Menagerie and Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bryan's Circus and Menagerie is coming to Staunton. The show has 20 cages
                    of "wild beasts" and has received great reviews.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of the Board of Directors of the Western Lunatic Asylum mourned
                    the loss of their colleague John Newton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Vote on the R. R. Subscription</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is a full and correct statement of the vote of Augusta county,
                        taken on the 27th ult. on the question of subscribing $300,000 to the
                        Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>White For</cell>
                            <cell>Negro For</cell>
                            <cell>Total For</cell>
                            <cell>W Against</cell>
                            <cell>N Against</cell>
                            <cell>T Against</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Court House,</cell>
                            <cell>38</cell>
                            <cell>147</cell>
                            <cell>536</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Union Hall,</cell>
                            <cell>79</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>83</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Middlebrook,</cell>
                            <cell>29</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                            <cell>43</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>43</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Craigsville,</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                            <cell>38</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Newport,</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenville,</cell>
                            <cell>44</cell>
                            <cell>22</cell>
                            <cell>66</cell>
                            <cell>89</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell>90</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Stuart's Draft</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>No Poll Opened</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Midway,</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>19</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>19</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Waynesboro',</cell>
                            <cell>106</cell>
                            <cell>37</cell>
                            <cell>143</cell>
                            <cell>137</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>137</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fisherville,</cell>
                            <cell>31</cell>
                            <cell>15</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Hope,</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                            <cell>15</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Meridian</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>52</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>58</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Sidney,</cell>
                            <cell>18</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>180</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>184</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Spring Hill,</cell>
                            <cell>44</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Parnassus,</cell>
                            <cell>21</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>21</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Churchville,</cell>
                            <cell>22</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>22</cell>
                            <cell>34</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>34</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Deerfield,</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total,</cell>
                            <cell>925</cell>
                            <cell>284</cell>
                            <cell>1209</cell>
                            <cell>1077</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                            <cell>1101</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Majority of whole vote for subscription, 108.</p>
                    <p>Majority of white vote against subscription, 152.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of the Vote On the Railroad subscription, divided by county and
                    race.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
