<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.11.10">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/02/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-11-10">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">10</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.11.10.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.11.10.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our People Calm and Serene</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Though the Presidential election has not resulted in accordance with the
                        wishes of our people, they are not foolishly wading in the "slough of
                        despond," nor are they the helpless victims of "<emph rend="italic">blue
                            devils,</emph>" but, in the language of Bill Arp, they are "cam and
                        sereen," exercising philosophic composure, if not christian resignation. The
                        result has not taken them by surprise, for they saw that the Democratic
                        party suffered itself to become "demoralized" when it felt the strength of
                        the hosts of Radicalism in the "reconnoisance" which took place in October.
                        Since they witnessed the evidence of that demoralization, they could
                        entertain little, if any, hope of success in the general engagement, on the
                        3rd of November.</p>
                    <p>They were, therefore, somewhat prepared for the reception of the sad news
                        that the Democratic legions had been routed, "horse, food, and dragoons."
                        Our people are too sensible to spend time in vainly fretting over spilt
                        milk.-- They know that that would be as unwise as unmanly, and they are too
                        sensible to act the part of fools, and too manly to act the part of
                        children.</p>
                    <p>The majority of our people, we are sure, have sufficient spirit and good
                        sense to comport themselves with becoming propriety, and to act the part of
                        men, even though there were not a ray of hope to cheer them, and they were
                        convinced that their liberties were, for all time, to be ruthlessly trampled
                        upon by the Radical party. But such, fortunately, is not the case. There is
                        good ground for the hope that the ultra Radical policy will not be carried
                        into effect. The President elect is not a Radical. If not a Democrat, as he
                        was before the war, he is a conservative Republican. Though he accepted the
                        nomination of the Chicago Convention, (as he would have done that of the New
                        York Convention if it had been tendered him) he has not committed himself in
                        any way to the policy of the Radical party. He was not, as he very well
                        knows, the choice of the Radicals. He knows, too, that they nominated him,
                        because they were satisfied, from the elections in October 1867, that any
                            <emph rend="italic">representative</emph> man of the Radical party would
                        certainly be defeated.</p>
                    <p>He knows, furthermore, that he owes his election the thousands of Democrats
                        and Conservative Republicans who, whilst being opposed to the Radical party
                        and the policy they advocate, voted for him, though a candidate of that
                        party, because they believed that his administration would be conservative,
                        and that his policy as President would accord with his well-known moderate
                        and conservative sentiments as evinced heretofore both by his expressions
                        and conduct. He has studiously, persistently, and consistently, so far as
                        the public know, refused to commit himself to the policy of the Radical
                        party. This is an important and significant fact. He is free from the
                        trammels of committal, and can act the part of a wise, moderate, and
                        conservative President without violating any pledge. He occupies a most
                        favorable position to do justice to all sections of the country, and to win
                        a name for wisdom and statesmanship which would eclipse all the honors won
                        by his sword.</p>
                    <p>We admonish our people to be of good cheer. There is, as yet, no reason to
                        despair. There may be a good time coming. At any rate it is best to think
                        so.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The people of Augusta are optimistic and happy, despite the election of
                    President Grant. Asserts that Grant is not a Radical, and that his policies may
                    in fact be quite conservative.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Election of Grant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Presidential election has resulted in the choice of Gen. Grant. Some may
                        think that in this result the Radicals have secured a triumph, but this is
                        an error. Gen. Grant is not the Representative of the Radicals, though he
                        received their votes. The Radicals did not like Grant and did not wish to
                        have him as their candidate, but they felt assured that any Radical would be
                        defeated, and were afraid to nominate one, hence they agreed to nominate
                        Grant. The Democrats are proverbially smart in the management of election
                        campaigns, and in the one which has just closed they exhibit more smartness
                        than usual and played the surest of all games. It was like that of heads I
                        win and tails you lose, for they were destined to win however the election
                        might result.</p>
                    <p>In this election the Democrats practised towards the Radicals that kind of
                        liberality which the white man proffered the Indian when he told him: "You
                        may take the buzzard and I will take the turkey, or I will take the turkey
                        and you may take the buzzard."</p>
                    <p>The Democrats had a candidate, for the Presidency upon each ticket. The
                        Radicals elected one of them. Grant has been a life long Democrat, and has
                        studiously avoided any committal to the policy of the Radicals. The Radicals
                        supposed that he kept his mouth shut because he had nothing to say, and
                        flattered themselves that he would make a fine catspaw for the Radical
                        monkey to use. But Grant knew what he was about. He knew how to get the
                        votes of the Radicals without committing himself to their policy in any way,
                        and he succeeded. The Radicals have elected a Democrat for President. When
                        they discover the strategy which has been so successfully practised upon
                        them, they will knash their teeth, and curse the deep policy of the man who
                        said he had "no policy," and for whose election they labored earnestly,
                        spent their money lavishly and voted early, late and often. The Democrats in
                        this election successfully flanked the Radicals. The Radicals will not fully
                        appreciate this fact till about six months after Grant shall be inaugurated
                        as President. Then they will see how they were fooled. They will howl in the
                        agony of their chagrin and disappointment and the Democrats will laugh at
                        their calamity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that Grant is not a representative for the Radicals, and is in fact
                    a Conservative. Thus, his election was a victory for the Democrats, as the
                    Radicals will come to realize after his inauguration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Petersburg <emph rend="italic">Express</emph> asks that the young men
                        whether they have brought back into civil life the energy that characterized
                        them in the camp and on the battle field, or are they sinking listlessly
                        into habits of inactivity and ease.</p>
                    <p>Have they awakened to the new order of things -- the new life before them
                        that demands the exercise of their utmost energies, or are they dreamily
                        feeling around for soft places where they can doze away their lives in
                        comparative idleness.</p>
                    <p>Many, we know, have gone earnestly to work and are reaping for themselves and
                        those dependent upon them the rich fruits which are the inevitable results
                        of industrious labor.</p>
                    <p>But are there not many others who are living upon inadequate salaries, or
                        under the idea of finding no employment suited to their taste, are doing
                        absolutely nothing.</p>
                    <p>It may be true that they can find nothing that suits them -- but can they not
                        suit themselves to something that will amply compensate them for the
                        sacrifices they make.</p>
                    <p>Do young men consider in wasting their time they are throwing away the
                        fortune and its comforts that is within their reach? We know that in a
                        country like ours no young man with health and strength need be without
                        employment, or dependent upon his friends.</p>
                    <p>Look to the cry for labor that goes up from day to day all over the South.
                        Look at the broad fields that are turning to waste for want of development,
                        and the timbers that stand in our forests inviting to be felled.</p>
                    <p>Young men look around you -- ponder the situation. You have made many noble
                        sacrifices, therefore, make them again. Go to work and bring back to our
                        shattered old State the days of prosperity and comfort.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Petersburg Express urges the young men of the South to labor in civil
                    life with the same energy they fought with in the Civil War.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Now that the struggle is over, says the Baltimore <emph rend="italic"
                        >Gazette</emph>, it becomes the Democratic party to endeavor to hope for the
                        best. Let it even try to believe beforehand that it may be mistaken in its
                        estimate of the character and aims of its antagonists. This is their country
                        as well as ours, and now that they are in the secure possession of absolute
                        power it may be that they will yet hesitate before they utterly and
                        irrevocably consign ten States, with their millions of inhabitants, to
                        humiliation, ruin and despair. While we cannot without further experience
                        alter one single opinion that we have honestly formed and uttered, we do not
                        hesitate to say that the party in whose defeat we share should await with
                        calmness the advent of General Grant's administration and judge it with
                        perfect candor. Nothing can be done by now to avert any impending peril that
                        may await the country, and in this hour of distress and danger the party
                        which has gone down in the struggle for constitutional liberty can only
                        stand aside, prepared to make one more manly effort against further
                        revolution, should time and occasion call for it. General Grant has now an
                        opportunity before him such as is accorded to but few men in the lives of
                        nations. If he is the man of comprehensive intellect and patriotic impulses
                        that his friends assert him to be he can quickly sweep away the
                        embarrassments which now surround the country, and restore her again to her
                        olden prosperity. It behooves the Democratic party to hold fast to this last
                        hope. With General Grant it rests to restore or to overthrow forever our
                        time honored Republic. The Democratic party should cease to judge him
                        further for the present and look with anxious solicitude for the first
                        indications of his capacity and his intention to save the country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Baltimore Gazette asks the Democratic party to remain hopeful. General
                    Grant, they claim, may act in a conservative manner, and should not be judged
                    before he enters office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This glorious old Commonwealth, says the Richmond <emph rend="italic"
                            >Enquirer</emph>, was never intended by God and nature to become the
                        mean prey of unprincipled adventurers, and by the aid of her own true sons
                        she never will. Our adversaries dare not yet discard the <emph rend="italic"
                            >forms</emph> of Republican government, and by the proper use of the
                        means we have in our power we shall still make these forms avail us for
                        salvation, at least until the whole country is caught up in the tide of the
                        coming revolution. We shall soon find our mettle, our determination, and our
                        endurance tested in a fiercer fire than ever, unless we do not read aright
                        the signs of the times.</p>
                    <p>Of the immediate future, which is big with events only a little less in
                        importance than those which will succeed them, we need hazard no
                        predictions. The whole country will listen with ears erect for the earliest
                        outgivings of the purposes of the President elect. In the hands of the men
                        who put him forward, we fear that it is hardly probable that he will
                        manifest any disposition to deal with the down trodden South in the spirit
                        of true patriotism and elevated statesmanship. Still we have many notable
                        examples where the possession of power has developed a new born
                        conservatism, and we can but hope that this may be the outcome of General
                        Grant's "policy," or rather his lack of such a thing. If it turns out so, we
                        shall rejoice in the fact, and take it for a sign that the God of Nations
                        has not yet directed his angel to enter upon the record of time the Last
                        Days of the American Republic.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Enquirer claims that the Radical's inability to fully discard
                    democratic institutions, as well as the Providence of God, will sustain
                    Virginia. Asks Virginians to hope that Grant will prove to be a reasonable
                    President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph> says that as Gen. Grant
                        was instrumental in bringing the war for the Union to a termination, he may
                        seek to round off what he would doubtless desire to have in the future: a
                        great historic character, by bringing the Radical war on the Constitution
                        and the South, to an end, with the restoration of an enduring peace on the
                        basis of a fraternal Union. He will be able to accomplish more in this
                        regard, than any other man that could have been invested with the Executive
                        functions of the Government; and if he will repudiate the counsels of the
                        extreme, malignant Radicals, we shall have a near prospect of peace and
                        returning prosperity to the whole country. We are not without hope that such
                        may be the result of Grant's administration; and no sound policy would
                        suggest the propriety of making no factious war upon him, in advance. For
                        ourselves we may say, that, while we think as badly of the Radical party as
                        Christian charity would permit, we regard him as being a great deal better
                        than the majority of those who availed themselves to his popularity to
                        appropriate him as their candidate. We shall, therefore, endeavor to judge
                        him fairly, by his official acts, awarding our humble meed of praise
                        whenever it may appear to be deserved. "Let us have peace."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Lynchburg Virginian claims hopes that Grant will seek to secure his
                    place in history by ending the "Radical war on the Constitution and the South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Let us remember, says the Norfolk <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph>, that
                        we have, as Virginians, a great future before us, if we are true to
                        ourselves;</p>
                    <p>And in what does this consist?</p>
                    <p>It consists in standing together as white men, bent and determined on doing
                        justice to all members of our society, but above all, determined to be true
                        to our race and traditions. Let us maintain the plain proposition that negro
                        suffrage is not a wise or wholesome thing for us, or for the negroes; and
                        rather go down, as the Cumberland did, with our flags flying, than basely to
                        surrender and submit to loss of honor and material property both at once. If
                        true to ourselves, the election cannot deprive us of a future rich, at
                        least, in material results.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Norfolk Virginian claims that Virginians will have a bright future so
                    long as they remain true to their principles, including their opposition to
                    universal suffrage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As indicated in our allusion last week, to the Augusta Fair, held near
                        Staunton, this last public movement of our neighbors was a most triumphant
                        success. The exhibition of articles was larger than had been expected from
                        the shortness of the time given for them to be brought in. The attendance of
                        citizens and strangers was unusually large, especially on the second day of
                        the Fair, when the scene presented was exhilarating in the extreme. We have
                        seen nothing grander since the war. The handsome natural amphitheater was
                        crowned with intelligent and high spirited men and beautiful women, the
                        surrounding country having poured out its jewels for this great occasion.
                        And then, as if to complete the perfection of this enchanting vision,
                        Virginia's great son, Gen. R. E. Lee, was there, not in all "the pomp and
                        circumstance of glorious war," but in a presence becoming his quiet,
                        unassuming dignity and ease. He was dressed in his plain grey clothes, with
                        his cavalry boots, and mounted upon his grey charger, the same noble animal
                        that had borne his master in many a fearful conflict in the eventful period
                        of the past. To us the sight was almost bewildering. It seemed as if the
                        South had achieved at last a triumph, a great civic triumph -- a triumph of
                        the arts of peace.</p>
                    <p>* * * * * * *</p>
                    <p>It was a grand demonstration -- an exhibit of many of the best implements of
                        agriculture, of seeds and trees, and shrubbery, of fowls, of every species
                        of beautiful needle work, of all kinds of domestic animals; but especially
                        an exhibit of some of the finest and best specimens of the human race of
                        both sexes to be found in the world. At least such is our deliberate
                        judgment. --<emph rend="italic">Rockingham Register</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article from the Rockingham Register talking about the successes of the
                    Augusta County Fair. General Lee was also present at the event.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Liberian Paradise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article endorsing emigration to Liberia for African Americans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.11.10.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nightly meetings led by the Rev. John L. Clarke have been held in
                    Staunton's Methodist Church for the past week. "Considerable interest has been
                    manifested, and there have been five or six professions of conversion, with
                    others anxiously seeking the 'pearl of great price.'" The meetings will continue
                    into next week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum will discuss questions of conscience and government at
                    their upcoming meetings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"J." writes to the Spectator complaining that those who attend Staunton's
                    Union Prayer Meetings are not religious people. He suggests that this may be due
                    to the non-sectarian nature of the meetings, and calls it "a sad commentary upon
                    the religion of our town."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Valley R. R. Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday night last, a meeting was held in the Court-House to discuss the
                        question of subscription by the town of Staunton to the sum of $100,000 to
                        the stock of the Valley R. R. Company.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. B. Christian, Mayor N. K. Trout was called to the chair,
                        and Jno. B. Evans, Esq., appointed Secretary.</p>
                    <p>The meeting was then addressed by Col. M. G. Harman, the President of the
                        Valley R. R. Company. He earnestly urged the propriety of the subscription,
                        and gave the assurance that the road would be put under contract within a
                        few months after the sum of $1,000,000 should be subscribed by the counties
                        and towns along the line of the proposed road, and expressed the belief that
                        that amount would be subscribed.</p>
                    <p>Judge H. W. Sheffey followed Col. Harman with a speech characterized by
                        sound, practical views. He said that there would be, in a short time, a
                        tendency to immigration into the South, and particularly into this fertile
                        Valley.</p>
                    <p>There are times, said he, when people were called upon to decide, and that
                        promptly, whether they would be great and successful, or stand back and be
                        beggars. The present is such a time with the people of Staunton. This is not
                        the time to be alarmed at taxes.</p>
                    <p>Years ago, the old fogies of Staunton were startled when it was proposed to
                        establish a water works. They feared the taxes could not be paid, and that
                        the town would be rendered bankrupt. Now Staunton has eight miles of water
                        pipe, and it has increased both the value of property and the population of
                        the town.</p>
                    <p>He said there were two things which the citizens of this county were wont to
                        do successfully: 1st. To choose the best men to represent them in the
                        Legislative Halls. 2nd. To do boldly what they were called upon to do. --
                        This was a time for the citizens of Staunton to act boldly, if they wished
                        to win the distinction of being the city of the Valley.</p>
                    <p>One thing is certain, and that is that the Valley R. R. will tap the
                        Covington &amp; Ohio R. R., and it will depend upon the action of the
                        citizens of Staunton whether it will thus tap that great line of trade and
                        travel at this place or not. If Staunton shall subscribe the proposed amount
                        it will be made a point on the Valley R. R., -- if she does not, that road
                        may tap the Covington &amp; Ohio R. R. at some other point. The interest
                        on the $100,000 at 6 per cent would only be 40 cents on the $100 value of
                        property in the town at its present valuation, but the population and the
                        value of property in town is destined to a great increase, and the tax thus
                        rendered less burdensome.</p>
                    <p>In November 1846, a meeting was held here to secure the extension of what was
                        then known as the Louisa R. R. from Gordonsville to Staunton. Rockingham
                        county tried hard to make Swift Run Gap a point on the Road.-- The President
                        of the R. R. hesitated, rather than leaning in favor of that route, with
                        Harrisonburg as a contemplated point on the Road. -- After an anxious
                        consultation with Col. Crozet one night, Judge Sheffey, (then one of the
                        Representatives of this county,) the next day offered an amendment to the
                        bill providing that the route should be in the direction of Covington and to
                        cross the Blue Ridge where the distance and cost would be least. The bill
                        thus amended was passed, and the Road secured to Staunton.</p>
                    <p>Staunton, said Judge Sheffey, cannot <emph rend="italic">afford</emph> to
                        fail to vote the proposed subscription of $100,000.</p>
                    <p>Suppose the Valley R. R. should cross the Covington &amp; Ohio R. R. at
                        the toll gate four miles from Staunton. The scream of the whistle then would
                        make the oldest fogey in Staunton grunt. Then they would regret that they
                        had not voted the tax. Should this be made a point of intersection of the
                        Valley and Covington &amp; Ohio Railroads, Staunton will become a place
                        of wealth and population not now ever dreamed of by the most hopeful.</p>
                    <p>The building of the Road through this county would necessitate an expenditure
                        within the county of more than a million dollars. All will be benefitted by
                        the expenditure.</p>
                    <p>By the construction of this Road through the county, its citizens would make
                        four times the amount of the tax in a mere business point of view. He dated
                        the prosperity of Staunton from the building of the McAdamzied Road in the
                        Valley. He concluded by the expression of the hope that this people would
                        work out a noble destiny.</p>
                    <p>Dr. C. R. Harris, being called upon, addressed the meeting briefly. He said
                        this was not the first time he had spoken in advocacy of Railroads -- that
                        when he had the honor to represent Augusta in the Senate of Va., he had
                        spoken in favor of the great line of Railroad which passes through this
                        place. Also in the Staunton Lyceum when the vote was very gratifying to him.</p>
                    <p>He maintained earnestly that the prosperity and life of Staunton depended
                        upon voting the proposed subscription. He said if Staunton did not vote the
                        subscription, that if it did not die it would, like the Yankee butcher's
                        calf, "<emph rend="italic">kinder gin cout.</emph>" His remarks were greeted
                        with applause.</p>
                    <p>At this stage of the meeting Col. Harman moved that the vote of the meeting
                        be taken upon the question of subscription. The vote was taken, and resulted
                        unanimously in favor of it.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. Harman, the chair appointed a committee of ten to canvass
                        the town in favor of the proposed subscription of $100,000.</p>
                    <p>The chair appointed the following to constitute the canvassing committee of
                        ten: Robt. G. Bickle, Dr. C. R. Harris, R. Mauzy, Jno. B. Evans, J. C.
                        Marquis, Jed Hotchkiss, Wm. P Tams, H. M. Bell, Wm. A. Burke and Bolivar
                        Christian.</p>
                    <p>Prof. Jed Hotchkiss made a few remarks, in which he said that there was in
                        two deposits of iron in the country -- one in the Eastern and the other in
                        the Western part of the county -- a sufficiency of that valuable metal to
                        last hundreds of years -- that the working of this iron would bring here the
                        coal of the West, and that these two minerals would add greatly to the
                        population and wealth of our county.</p>
                    <p>Maj. Jno. B. Watts, in response to a call, arose, and, with that easy manner
                        and calm dignity, which so distinguishes him, with the skill of the master
                        builder, placed the graceful and finishing cap upon the column of discussion
                        reared by the other speakers.</p>
                    <p>For some time, he enchained the rapt attention of the audience, and by his
                        lucid statement of facts, logical arguments, and stirring eloquence elicited
                        frequent and rapturous applause from the delighted auditors. Any effort to
                        report this great speech would be doing manifest injustice to the eloquent
                        speaker -- hence we merely allude to its character in general terms.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held at the Court-House in support of the Valley Rail Road
                    project. Several speakers offered arguments in favor of the subscription of
                    $100,000 to the stock of the Company, and explained why the Railroad would be a
                    profitable venture for Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>General Grant's Policy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints rumors that General Grant is not a radical and plans to
                    lead a policy of reconciliation toward the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Almarode</ln>
                        <fn>George D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesell</ln>
                        <fn>Susan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George D. Almarode and Miss Susan J. Whitesell, both of Augusta, were
                    married in Staunton on November 5th by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Delila</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Johnson and Miss Delila Allen, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 29th by the Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adair</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William A. Beard and Mrs. Rachel E. Adair were married at Fairfield on
                    October 27th by the Rev. Harvey Gilmore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echard</ln>
                        <fn>Silas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnside</ln>
                        <fn>Phebe C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bovey</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Silas C. Echard of Augusta and Miss Phebe C. Burnside of Rockingham were
                    married at the residence of Robert Cox in Taylor Springs, Rockingham County, on
                    October 20th by the Rev. Henry Bovey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wampler of Rockingham and Miss Catharine A. Miller, daughter of Samuel
                    Miller of Augusta, were married at the residence of the bride's father on
                    October 22nd by the Rev. Frederick Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marsh</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freeman</ln>
                        <fn>Willie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Marsh and Miss Willie A. Freeman, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Barterbrook on November 3rd by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Brown and Miss Lucy A. Riley, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 20th by the Rev. John L. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackwood</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackwood</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Maria Blackwood died near Greenville at the residence of her brother,
                    David Blackwood. "She had been for many years a consistent member of the
                    Presbyterian church, and has gone from earth to the better land; but her memory
                    and her virtues will be green and bright long after her body has perished in the
                    dust."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.11.10.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
