<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.10.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/01/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-10-27">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">27</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.10.27.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Progress of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the progress in constructing the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.10.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Western Lunatic Asylum" at Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To the humane and contemplative the Western Lunatic Asylum of this place
                        furnishes a subject of great interest. The visitor, with his preconceived
                        ideas that he is about to enter a Pandemonium on earth and expects his blood
                        to be frozen with horror on visiting the abode of hundreds of the insane, as
                        soon as he enters the gate and catches a view of the beautiful grounds
                        within the enclosure begins to feel emotions of admiration and pleasant
                        surprise, and to wonder if he has not mistaken the place, and entered upon
                        the beautifully ornamented grounds of a private gentleman blessed with vast
                        wealth and highly cultivated taste. He passes up the graveled walk, admiring
                        the variety, number and beauty of the flowers blooming on either hand, and
                        thinks of Milton's description of Paradise, instead of Dante's inferno as he
                        had previously expected. In this mood of revolutionized feelings he ascends
                        the steps and enters the Building which he finds well-arranged for the
                        purpose for which it was designed and is used, and kept in the neatest
                        style. He feels that the genius of Order reigns, and unconsciously looks for
                        the placard: "A place for everything, and everything in its place." He meets
                        with a polite reception, enters his name upon the register of visitors, and
                        is conducted through the various apartments of the spacious buildings. He
                        becomes strangely pleased with the place, and almost envies the occupants
                        their neat, orderly, peaceful, and comfortable home. At 3 o'clock P.M. on
                        Sabbath he revisits the Asylum, and attends divine service in the Chapel,
                        where, to his surprise, he finds the most quiet and best-behaved
                        congregation he ever saw, composed almost entirely of the patients of the
                        Asylum. At the conclusion of the services, he takes his departure, seemingly
                        with reluctance, his bosom filled with emotions of thankfulness that there
                        is in the State such an Asylum, so well conducted, for that unfortunate
                        class who have greater claims than any other upon the sympathies of mankind.</p>
                    <p>He makes the acquaintance of Dr. Francis T. Stribling, the distinguished
                        Superintendent and Physician of the Asylum -- is struck with his gentle,
                        polite and affable manners, and does not fail to observe the combined
                        firmness and kindness in his character which has enabled him to attain such
                        remarkable success in governing and attaching to him the patients under his
                        superintendence, whose obedience, confidence and affection he uniformly
                        secures. He becomes deeply interested in the history and management of that
                        beneficent institution. He reads the bound volumes of the reports containing
                        the information he desires, and becomes satisfied that to Dr. Stribling more
                        than to any one else is due the distinguished honor of impressing upon the
                        Asylum that marked character which has made it justly famous, as one of the
                        best managed institutions of the kind in this or any other country. He rids
                        himself of all the prejudices which he had before, in common with the
                        majority of the people, entertained in reference to sending friends to an
                        insane asylum. He learned that insanity was the result of physical disease
                        -- that no stigma attached to it any more than to a fever or headache --
                        that in the asylum patients were merely under the care of skillful
                        physicians, where they could be better treated and live more comfortably
                        than at home. He learned also the important fact that of those patients
                        whose friends were wise enough to send them to the asylum in the early stage
                        of the disease <emph rend="italic">nine out of ten</emph> were restored to
                        health and clothed in their right minds, whilst of those whose friends
                        unwisely kept them at home till the disease had assumed a chronic form, only
                            <emph rend="italic">one in ten</emph> was restored to health and sound
                        mind.</p>
                    <p>We would appeal to the friends of persons thus unfortunately afflicted not to
                        hesitate a moment about sending them to the asylum, and would impress it
                        upon them that it is their duty to secure their admission as soon as
                        possible after learning that their minds are diseased.</p>
                    <p>When we commenced this article it was with the view chiefly of mentioning
                        some interesting facts connected with the statistics of insanity, but having
                        written the above, we must, for want of space, postpone to another time what
                        we wish to say concerning them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Spectator describes the Western Lunatic Asylum as a beautiful, orderly,
                    and well-maintained institution, far more pleasant than its purpose might
                    suggest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Petersburg <emph rend="italic">Index</emph> says that politics are just
                        getting to be interesting. They mean something. They concern every man,
                        woman, and child in America, in all relations of life. They effect us in our
                        business, moral, religious and social life, and through the medium of
                        taxation and finance, have a most intimate connection with our purses.</p>
                    <p>Away with the silly cant, "let politics alone and go to work." There is no
                        antagonism between patriotism and industry, between diligence in business
                        and industry, between diligence in business and that fervor of the soul
                        which clings forever to the right, and inspires that generous public spirit,
                        and love of the common weal, which has been possessed by every man who
                        deserves to be remembered after death.</p>
                    <p>Happily the degrading advice to "let politics alone" is not practicable,
                        because politics will not let us alone. As well talk about letting a bull
                        dog alone whose venomous fangs have fastened upon your body and who is
                        tearing the flesh from your limbs. The sense of pain was given to us for the
                        preservation of our bodies.</p>
                    <p>A child who is insensible to the pain of a fall, or to the touch of fire,
                        would soon break his neck or burn his hand off.</p>
                    <p>The Republic which "lets politics alone" has lost its functions and
                        republican forms have become as useless to it as a pair of nine league boots
                        would be to a paralytic.</p>
                    <p>If we would enjoy the advantages of constitutional liberty, let us not haggle
                        about the price, be it eternal vigilance or eternal agitation. We need
                        patience, indeed, but it is the patience of activity, the patience of the
                        smith at the anvil who not only strikes when the iron is hot, but makes the
                        iron hot by striking.</p>
                    <p>Man is naturally an indolent animal. The tendency of patriotism and religion
                        in this country is to become emasculate. To put money in their purse and be
                        wafted to the skies "on heavenly beds of ease," is about the average
                        aspiration, and is considered to be the wise and correct thing. Our
                        patriotism needs an infusion of Spartan contempt for luxury and ease, and
                        our christianity needs the heroic self-sacrificing spirt of its found --
                        "Whosoever would save his life shall lose it."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Petersburg Index "says that politics are just getting to be
                    interesting," and encourages people to remain involved in the vital political
                    issues of the day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Petersburg Index</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The people of Virginia have borne too long and too bravely, to be overwhelmed
                        by another stroke of adverse fortune. Recurring to the last three years of a
                        varying but always bitter experience, there has been much to reward this
                        people for the constancy with which they have attested devotion to
                        principle. Spared the reproach of a mock admission to an enforced Union,
                        spared the rule of the debased and besotted, spared the turmoil and
                        bloodshed of contending races -- we can find much to encourage a
                        perseverance in stand-fastness, a persistence in calm self, and God,
                        reliance.</p>
                    <p>Much of that galling poverty, which added so greatly to our first seasons of
                        trial, has passed away. In the growth of great enterprises, the steady
                        development of remunerative trades, the general employment of long neglected
                        resources, the resuscitation of paralyzed energies, and in the consciousness
                        of strength which the unavailing assaults of our enemies have brought, we
                        learn that there is much which cannot be taken away from an earnest
                        determined life, and that the powers of endurance belonging to us are as
                        illimitable as the oppressors ingenuity of oppression.</p>
                    <p>Is our repulse, therefore, to bring panic, or our failure, surrender? We can
                        work with resolute wills, wait with watchful minds, stand by the right with
                        hearts anchored in faith; and trust to the end that neither the powers of
                        this world nor of darkness, can make slaves of a people who have sworn to
                        God in their souls, that as they have lived they will live Free and die
                        Free, as their Fathers did, or else be driven to that yoke by the sheer
                        brutal force which cannot chain the will or fetter the reason, and which can
                        enforce decrees only while it is strong, and those whom it drives are weak.</p>
                    <p>Hope for the best. Even continued radical supremacy, with Grant as its sword,
                        will find it difficult to enable a negro minority to rule Virginia's people.
                        We will obey the law, as in the past, stand by the terms of our capitulation
                        like men of honor. Perhaps in assumed power, these people may ape
                        generosity, and better afford to be lenient than cruel. Be that as it may,
                        we will hold fast to that which is good, submit where we must, resist where
                        we may, and never despair of vindication in the end.</p>
                    <p>Virginia's honor is as bright to-day, as when she gave to the young Republic
                        its first President. Be it ours to keep her shield untarnished, and her
                        faith inviolate. -- <emph rend="italic">Petersburg Index.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Petersburg Index writes of the trials that Virginia has recently faced,
                    and asks Virginians to remain hopeful and honorable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.10.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sports at the Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following sports will take place at the fair: Jumping matches, quoit
                    pitching, wheelbarrow race, Lady's Archery Club. Col. Bolivar Christian is in
                    charge of the department running the games.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Ned</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ned Fisher, of the Ballard House, Richmond, just received appointment as
                    clerk at the Virginia Hotel, Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Court day drew large crowds in the streets of Staunton. Most were excited
                    about the opening of the fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Friends of Temperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nowton</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The State Council of the Friends of Temperance met in Staunton's Odd
                    Fellows Hall, Mr. A. P. Abell presiding. An election of officers was held,
                    resulting in selection of George A. Bruce of Waynesborough as president and
                    James W. Nowton of Staunton a conductor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Lucinda E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Wilson of Indiana and Miss Lucinda E. Humphreys were married at the
                    residence of the bride's father near Greenville by the Rev. Mr. Murray on
                    October 8th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golladay</ln>
                        <fn>Rachael J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Calvin L. Black and Miss Rachael J. Golladay, both of Augusta, were married
                    on October 15th by the Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabbert</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabbert</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Sallie Gabbert died at the residence of her nephew, Wilson Gabbert,
                    near Arbor Hill, Augusta County, on October 18th. She was 104 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.10.27.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
