<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.02.25">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/18/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-02-25">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="02">Feburary</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.02.25.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Interesting Correspondence about Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>FLAT WOODS, FAYETTE CO.,<lb/> Pennsylvania, Feb 10, 1867</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Dr. Samuel I. Baird, Staunton, Va.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>DEAR SIR: -- Knowing your former identification with this part of the State
                        of Pennsylvania, and that you have been for some time residing in the State
                        of Virginia, and that your duties have given you unusual opportunities for
                        forming an correct judgement of the capacities of Virginia as an
                        Agricultural and Manufacturing region, and still more than that you must be
                        able to speak the temper and disposition of her people towards the citizens
                        of the Northern States, who might be induced to go to that State, have
                        determined to address to you this letter. I have no doubt that many of our
                        Pennsylvania people might be induced to go to Virginia to seek new homes and
                        more profitable pursuits, if they could be satisfied of the advantages,
                        which <emph rend="italic">I</emph> am satisfied Virginia now presents to men
                        of enterprise and integrity, and intelligence, who will go there and cast in
                        their lots with Virginians. A very general impression, however, prevails
                        that Northern men would not be kindly recieved there, and indeed many
                        apprehend that they would not be safe. I will thank you, my dear Sir, to
                        give me fully and candidly, your views and convictions upon these points.
                        Whether those views shall induce any of my friends to settle in Virginia or
                        not, they will, I am satisfied, tend to the formation of correct opinions,
                        and to the cultivation of kindly feeling towards our brethren, among whom
                        you live.</p>
                    <p>I write to you for the reasons which I have already given, and because I know
                        that you are permanently settled at Staunton, in the very heart of the
                        Shenandoah Valley.</p>
                    <p>I am very truly,</p>
                    <p>JAMES M. ABRAHAM.</p>
                    <p>Staunton, VA. Feb 18, 1868.</p>
                    <p>DEAR SIR: -- I cheerfully comply with your request for a statement of the
                        results of my observations in this State. The manner in which I was brought
                        into my present official position is, of itself, so significant, that I
                        venture to relate it.</p>
                    <p>I came into Virginia in November, 1865, under commission from the American
                        Bible Society, to labor for the supply of the Scriptures to the destitute of
                        all classes and colors, but with a special view to the necessities of the
                        colored population. When I reached Richmond, I found that, but a week
                        before, the Virginia Bible Society had resolved, after mature deliberation,
                        to resume its old relations to the American Bible Society, of which it was
                        one of the original founders, and an early and active auxiliary.</p>
                    <p>The significance of this fact is consequent upon the character and position
                        of the Managers of the Virginia Society. They were such men as the Rev. Drs.
                        Duncan, Edwards, and Dogment, (now Bishop,) of the Methodist Church;
                        Woodbridge and Minnigerode, of the Episcopal Chruch; and Moore, Hoge, and
                        Read, of the Presbyterian Church -- with equally eminent laymen, men than
                        whom no others are more worthy, or more fully enjoy the respect and
                        confidence of the people of Virginia. In the face of the opposing sentiments
                        of some individuals, not of the Board, who preferred to maintain an attitude
                        of reserve toward the North, these gentlemen, within six months of the end
                        of the war, spontaneously took the decisive step of resuming the old
                        relations of intimacy with the American Bible Society, and its friends in
                        the North.</p>
                    <p>Upon my arrival in Richmond, the Managers of the Virginia Society sought an
                        interview, in which the purposes and plans of the American Society were
                        fully unfolded, with respect especially to the distribution of the
                        Scriptures among the colored people. The Board immediately made proposals to
                        the Society in New York, which resulted in my being, at once, jointly
                        commissioned by the two societies to superintend this work in Virginia.
                        Under this commission, I have now been laboring for more than two years. I
                        have repeatedly traversed the entire extent of the State, from Winchester,
                        on the North, to Bristol, in the Southwest, and from the Western line to
                        Norfolk and the Eastern shore. I have had the fullest opportunity of
                        observation, in the freedom of the associations of travel; in the confidence
                        of the family circle; in the gatherings of literary festivals; and in the
                        deliberations of ecclesiastical bodies; and feel, therefore, some confidence
                        in the adequacy of the grounds of my conclusions.</p>
                    <p>I do not pretend much skill in judging the character of the soil, &amp;c.
                        I can only say, that I am continually impressed with the extent and variety
                        of the undeveloped resources of the country, Agricultural, Mineral, and
                        Manufacturing. Particularly have I been interested in the rich resources of
                        the Valley of Virginia, throughout its extent, the variety and beauty of its
                        scenery, the salubrity of its climate, the fertility of its soil, and its
                        adaptation to the production of corn and the cereals, and fruits, and to the
                        products of the dairy. Already the home of a cultivated and hospitable
                        population, it is destined, I am confident, to become, at no distant day,
                        one of the most populous and attractive regions on the continent.</p>
                    <p>At the other extremity of the State, Norfolk is the entrepot of an extensive
                        region, traversed by railroads and navigable rivers, with a soil eminently
                        adapted to that truck culture, by which New Jersey is enriched, whilst the
                        climate gives it several weeks advantage over that State, in the markets of
                        Washington, Baltimore, Philadelphia and New York, to all of which it has
                        easy access by water. It must soon become one of the wealthiest regions in
                        the country.</p>
                    <p>As to your suggestion of fears that Northern men would not be welcome or even
                        safe; it can but excite a smile among those who know the facts. I am
                        confident that there is not, in the land, at this time, a more thouroughly
                        law abiding people than those of Virginia. Since coming to the State, I have
                        met with many Northern men, visiting it for the purposes of business and of
                        pleasure -- men of every class, and every phase of politics. I have never
                        myself, for a moment, felt apprehensive of insult, even; much less, of
                        danger to life or limb, on sectional or political grounds; nor have I met
                        with, nor heard of the man who has. In fact, my observation corresponds with
                        a published remark of the Rev. Dr. Sears, the General Agent of the Peabody
                        Fund. "I hear much, from the Northern papers, about Southern excitement. I
                        see but very little of it. I find very little, except in the customs of the
                        people,to remind me that I am a Northern man." In fact, I saw, in the course
                        of a few days visit to the North, last Summer, a greater amount of political
                        excitement, than in all my residence and travels here. What the people here
                        are longing for, is the opportunity of rest and quiet, to enable them to
                        restore their dilapidated fortunes.</p>
                    <p>Men who should now come to Virginia, for the purpose of trading in politics,
                        or whilst cherishing feelings of hostility towards the people among whom
                        they are living, and I have met with such, would be perfectly safe from
                        personal violence; but would, undoubtedly, be "severely left alone." But
                        those who come, in the spirit of peace and fraternity, expecting to identify
                        themselves with the interests and seek the welfare of the people and the
                        State, will, I feel very sure, be recieved with a hearty welcome, and
                        cordial God-speed.</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully yours,</p>
                    <p>SAMUEL J. BAIRD.</p>
                    <p>JAMES M. ABRAHAM, Esq., Flat Wood's, <lb/> Fayette, Co., Pa.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A member of a Bible Society responds to a letter requesting his opinion
                    about the suitability of Virginia for Northern business. He claims that Virginia
                    is well suited to a variety of agricultural and manufacturing industries, and
                    that her people are welcoming to Northerners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.02.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Great Excitment in Washington. Stanton Removed and General Lorenzo Thomas
                    appointed in his place.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on Johnson's removal of Stanton and appointment of Lorenzo Thomas
                    as Secretary of War.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>What the Convention Should Do</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph> maintains that the wisest
                        thing the convention could do, would be to adopt the freehold basis of
                        suffrage. It says that "unqualified white suffrage is bad enough; but when
                        to that is added universal negro suffrage, we, of the South, must prepare
                        for the rule of demagogues and inferiour men in every department of the
                        government. With this depression of the standard of moral and intellectual
                        qualification for office, countless evils must be inflicted upon the State.</p>
                    <p>If the Convention should be waiting in wisdom to devise such a plan, then we
                        must be left to a conflict of the races at the ballot box, to extend,
                        perhaps, even further. It will be race against race, and no constitution,
                        recognizing universal negro suffrage, can possibly be adopted in Virginia,
                        unless it be secured through a further disfranchisement of the whites. And,
                        in that case, it would not exist long, for the influx of white population
                        from all quarters, would soon give such a preponderance of that element in
                        Virginia as to enable it to sweep away every vestige of negro suffrage. This
                        will be the result, inevitably, if Congress should now force upon this
                        unmixed evil.</p>
                    <p>We can hardly imagine that any thing we might propose would influence either
                        Congress or the Convention to reverse from their present course. The
                        interests of the Radical party overshadow, at this time, every consideration
                        of statesmanship, and the thought that is uppermost with their leaders, is
                        to secure, by any system of outrage, the sucess of their party at the next
                        Presidential election. In such a case, reason must fail and argument is
                        useless --They will play their game out, however desperate it may be, and we
                        can only look for the future to redress the wrongs of the present."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests a system of suffrage based on freeholding, and argues that a
                    system of unqualified suffrage would be untenable, as the white population will
                    never consent to it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Virus of Radicalism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gloats over the failure of the Register, a radical newspaper
                    published in Richmond. Still, that alone will not relieve the state's problems.
                    "The people who are now threatened with the horrors of Radicalism and negro
                    domination, and the loss of all liberty, appreciate the fact that this condition
                    of affairs in owing, not to the Radical journals, for they exerted no influence
                    on the mass of the white voters, but to the course of such as professed to be
                    Conservative, but advocated the policy of the Radicals in urging the
                    Conservatives to vote in favor of the Convention which is now assembled in the
                    Capital of Virginia and are tramping beneath 'gizzard-feet' every principle of
                    liberty."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The hopes of the friends of Liberty are now based upon what it is supposed
                        will be the action of the people in the Northern and Western States. The
                        South is helpless and can only suffer with heroic fortitude. The people of
                        the North are free, as yet, and should act without delay, if they wish to
                        remain so.</p>
                    <p>In the language of a contemporary, "we have been wondering for eighteen
                        months past how the Northern people have managed to keep so quiet in view of
                        what is passing before their eyes. They must know that the chains forged for
                        ten of the States will just as easily fit the limbs of the other twenty-six.
                        The power that is daringly adequate to strike down local government in the
                        great expanse of territory that reaches from the Potomac to the Rio Grande,
                        is certainly able to repeat it north of the Potomac and west of the Ohio.
                        The Northern people thus see and feel the gradual approach of an alarming
                        and despotic change in their form of government, and except in the protests
                        of the press and from the lips of public speakers, we witness no signs of
                        the spirit of resistance which the audacity of the attempt and the peril of
                        its success, would seem naturally to provoke.</p>
                    <p>The "Rump" seems to know the people it is dealing with, and it certainly has
                        reason to count heavily on its patient and stolid forbearance. They do stand
                        buffeting with wonderful fortitude. Perhaps the solution is that the people
                        rely on the ballot-box to arrest and correct the evils of "Rump" tyranny,
                        and prefer to wait for that peaceful method."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that the hope of liberty lies in the North and the West, and
                    questions why the people of the North have failed to check the tyranny of the
                    Radicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Feeling in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph> says that, "Outside of the
                        small circle of fanatics, there is no white man who does not feel and know
                        that he sins against nature when he seeks to build up negro supremacy, for
                        nothing less than that is the aim of Radicalism in the South. This moment,
                        if the Southern negroes were to proclaim that no white man shall receive
                        their votes for office, and were to set up for themselves, thus
                        extinguishing the hopes of the wretched white allies, there is not one of
                        the latter who would not instantly abandon politics. The adventurers who
                        have come here from other States in quest of office would pull up stakes and
                        vanish, and the native Radicals would hide themselves in their congenial
                        obscurity, cursing the negroes in their hearts. So long as the negroes are
                        content to be privates, and to make captains and lieutenants of their white
                        allies, so long will they have their countenance and co-operation, but no
                        longer.</p>
                    <p>The great body of the white people of Virginia are resolved that they will
                        not, by any voluntary agency, and from any consideration of personal gain,
                        assist in the establishment of negro suffrage. It exists now under the
                        reconstruction act, and will be made the corner-stone of the Constitution
                        now being framed, but they are not responsible for the one, and will not
                        assume responsibility for the other. According to the terms of the
                        reconstruction act as it now stands, the whites have the same right (those
                        not disfranchised) to vote against the ratification of the Constitution that
                        the blacks have to vote for it, and they have a majority in the State. They
                        are perfectly organized in all the <sic>countries</sic>, cities, and towns
                        of the State, and this complete organization cannot fail to tell decisively
                        upon the vote of ratification. It may be that this juggling Congress will
                        change the terms of the reconstruction act so as to dispense with a
                        ratifying vote, or in some other way so arrange as to frustrate all our
                        efforts to defeat the constitution. This it has not yet done, and there is
                        yet a field of action open to us. It is impossible to foretell what Congress
                        will or will not do. But we can determine as to what we will do. We are now
                        organized against negro suffrage and negro supremacy, and let us keep up
                        this organization. Our votes may be neutralized by fraud, but no fraud can
                        abate the strength of our organization or paralyze that influence which a
                        compact and well disciplined body of intelligent people must exert. Let us
                        hold ourselves in readiness to speak and act as a unified people at all
                        times, and on all occassions, against negro suffrage. It may be carried
                        against us, by foul means, but let us act as to keep our protest against it
                        before the public." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Southerners to organize to defeat any state Constitution that
                    includes "negro suffrage", and to organize in protest of such a Constitution,
                    should it be passed over their objections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.02.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Henry A. Wise will appear at the Court House to address the people of
                    Augusta on the importance of completing the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad. The
                    speech is part of a campaign to win the vote coming up in April.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Western Lunatic Asylum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Francis T. Stribling submitted the report of the Western Lunatic Asylum
                    for the current fiscal year. 437 patients were cared for in the past two years.
                    99 patients died or were discharged, 50 of whom were discharged as recovered.
                    The board requested $45,500 for the upcoming year. The paper praised the
                    institution's "excellent management." "'To minds diseased' it supplies the
                    remedy, and in many cases affects permanent cures. To all, it furnishes a good
                    home, and a quiet and comfortable retreat."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. George B. Taylor delivered a lecture before the Staunton Lyceum on
                    "The Thinker." The paper praises the high intellectual nature of the address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gladwell</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Emma N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David H. Gladwell and Miss Emma N. Martin of Augusta were married on
                    February 16th by the Rev. Thomas L. Preston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Folds</ln>
                        <fn>James J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bull</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James J. Folds and Miss Susan Bull were married at the residence of the
                    bride's father on February 18th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelly</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelly</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getzendanner</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob B. Cale and Margaret F. Shelly, both of Augusta, were married at the
                    house of the bride's father, Jacob Shelly, on February 20th by the Rev. H.
                    Getzendanner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Ruff, Sr., died on February 10th at the residence of his son-in-law
                    William Brown. He was 81 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.02.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
