<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.08.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/27/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-08-04">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.08.04.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.08.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Shall Virginia be Dumb?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have noticed the fact that the Electoral College Bill was passed over the
                        President's veto. By this bill the Radical Congress would exclude from the
                        Electoral College the electors from Virginia, Mississippi, and Texas -- it
                        would deny to these States any vote in the Presidential election. Shall the
                        voice of Virginia be thus stifled? Shall that State which did more than any
                        other to establish the Government of the United States have no voice in the
                        selection of its Chief Magistrate? Shall Virginians assent to such an
                        outrage? We answer no, NEVER. "The mother of States and Statesman" is not
                        dumb -- she can speak, she should speak, she will speak. She will cast her
                        vote at the Presidential election -- she will choose her electors -- she
                        will express her emphatic condemnation of Radicals and Radical Legislation
                        -- she will do her duty and leave the consequences with Providence. She is
                        chained, she is in the bonds of tyranny, she is pinned to the earth with
                        bayonets, but her spirit is unbroken, her fidelity top principle is
                        unimpaired; she is forbidden to speak, but, denying the authority which
                        issues the interdict, she <emph rend="italic">will</emph> speak, and that,
                        too, in a tone deserving of her character, expressive of devotion to liberty
                        and detestation of tyranny.</p>
                    <p>In thus speaking she complies strictly with letter and spirit of both the
                        Federal and State Constitutions. She stands upon solid ground -- she
                        exercises no doubtful right.</p>
                    <p>The Constitution of Virginia provides that, in the event the Governor shall
                        fail to appoint Commissioners of election, or if those appointed shall fail
                        to serve, any <emph rend="italic">two freeholders</emph>, taking the oath
                        required for the faithful discharge of their duties as such, may act. So
                        that, if <emph rend="italic">Gov.</emph> Wells -- so-called -- shall not
                        appoint commissioners, the Constitution provides that the election may be
                        held notwithstanding.</p>
                    <p>The Democratic Conservative party of this State will nominate and elect their
                        electors. If their votes shall not be counted in the electoral College, the
                        responsibility will rest with the party which excludes them.</p>
                    <p>If the vote of Virginia shall not be counted, it will not be because it was
                        not cast. The vote of Virginia will be cast, and will be cast in favor of
                        the election of Seymour and Blair electors. The voice of Virginia should be,
                        and will be heard.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that Virginia should cast its votes for President, even though the
                    Radical Congress has passed a law excluding Virginia from the Electoral College.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fortitude of Virginians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The fortitude of Virginians is still farther to be tested. If unauthorized
                        Radical legislation be regarded, which we hope, however, will not be the
                        case, they will be denied participation in the struggle which will decide
                        their political fate. Soldiers know that it is more difficult to remain
                        passive in the midst of a hot engagement than to take active part in it.
                        Such is the case with Virginians at this time. The drums beat, the bugle
                        sounds the charge, the conflict is joined, but Virginians must remain mere
                        spectators of the struggle, the result of which will decide whether they are
                        to be free men or the vassals of the worst tyrants that ever disgraced any
                        country. As the Petersburg <emph rend="italic">Index</emph> says, "there is
                        nothing so painful to an earnest, brave nature as to be placed in a
                        situation in which he is merely compelled to <emph rend="italic"
                        >wait</emph>; nothing is so trying as to stand with folded and fettered arms
                        and look on, while a struggle for life and death and all he loves and all he
                        reveres is going on before him. But remember they also serve the good cause
                        who only stand and wait.</p>
                    <p>But do not fall asleep at your post -- watch, also. The time is coming -- the
                        time is not distant, when every Virginian will take an active part in the
                        contest between the National Democracy and their opponents.</p>
                    <p>In November our allies will cut their way through to us.</p>
                    <p>The Radical party have attempted what it is impossible to do. It has
                        attempted to stifle the volition of eight millions of people, and to dragoon
                        them not only into tame and silent submission to their policy, but also into
                        a cheerful surrender of their opinions, and a hearty co-operation with the
                        party which maltreats, insults, and oppresses them.</p>
                    <p>It has lost the gold opportunity when it might have conciliated the hearts of
                        our people and won their affections by a manly, generous, and truly American
                        policy. But it was unequal to the occasion -- and it is left for the old
                        Democratic party to step forward to the front -- and lead off the march of a
                        free people to glory and to empire. It is already in motion -- it moves this
                        way -- and it will not be long before we will see the head of the columns of
                        the great army which has routed radicalism and comes at once a victor and a
                        deliverer."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the fortitude of Virginians, who must sit idle and wait for their
                    time to vote, while the Radicals impose unconstitutional and harmful laws upon
                    them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the complements of a northern doctor to Dr. F. T.
                    Stribling, superintendent of the Western Lunatic Asylum. "It is true that the
                    Western Lunatic Asylum of this place is not only one of the best in this
                    country, but one of the best in the world, and its high character and admirable
                    management are due to the talents, skill, humanity and assiduous, devoted
                    attention for a number of years."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Arms for the "Loyal"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The late military bill, intended to place an untold number of repeating
                        rifles in the hands of only the "loyal" citizens of the South, is well
                        calculated, says the Norfolk <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph>, to
                        disturb one's equanimity, even though passed over for the present.</p>
                    <p>But although it has been postponed, we can not disguise the fact that our
                        government is in the hands of wicked, unprincipled, and designing
                        politicians, whose object is power, and who will not shrink from any means
                        necessary to accomplish their fell designs.</p>
                    <p>Sumner, Stevens, Butler, and others, from the moment of their entry into the
                        councils of the nation, have superseded the people, their every gesture is a
                        command, and each movement a coup d'etat. They have placed themselves above
                        two branches of government, and the people now feel themselves confronted by
                        a power which menaces their freedom.</p>
                    <p>But our hope is, that the white men of the North, who according to the
                        instincts of nature, <emph rend="italic">ought</emph> to be our friends,
                        will not look with indifference on our present situation, in which their own
                        immediate interests are involved. -- The missile which strikes down the
                        South, will, on its rebound, pierce the heart of the North.</p>
                    <p>Our friends at the North must see, do see, the design of this infamous bill,
                        which we consider an insult to their understanding as well as a threat to
                        their liberties.</p>
                    <p>The bill goes over, as we have before said, and in the interval we should
                        protest as one man from the Potomac to the Rio Grand against its iniquities.
                        Do not delude yourselves with the false belief that the scheme is dead. For
                        the present it is only a frozen adder. The reassembling of Congress will
                        warm it into life.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial, quoting from the Norfolk Virginia, claiming that, even though
                    the bill intended to arm loyal militias throughout the South has been dropped
                    for the present, it should concern American citizens and show them the extent of
                    Radical tyranny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Horatio Seymour</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praise for Democratic presidential candidate Horatio Seymour's eloquence
                    and charisma.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Blair's Letter of Acceptance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises Frank Blair's letter accepting the Democratic
                    vice-presidential nomination. "It sweeps away, with a mailed hand and supreme
                    disdain, the flimsy pretexts by which the Radical conspirators would bind the
                    nation while they rivet its chains, and it tears the veil from their half
                    accomplished purpose, and reveals the whole plot in its naked and unblushing
                    deformity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Colored Democrats</head>
                <origin>Charleston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article takes as an "indication of a return to reason" the presence of
                    300 African Americans at a Democratic Ward Club procession in Charleston. "The
                    colored people, we think, begin to realize that their true interests lie with
                    those of the white people of the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports discontent in the North with the "useless, expensive, and
                    unnecessary" Freedmen's Bureau. "The Radicals have to bear the odium of the
                    continuance of an establishment for supplying the wants or demands of the
                    colored people, while no such 'favors' are extended to white men. That point
                    tells with the white men at the North who are taxed to support the 'Bureau.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Radical Attempt to Rekindle War</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals, feeling that they must be everywhere beaten at the polls,
                        intend, if possible, to stir up a new civil war at the South, and thus
                        prevent an election. -- <emph rend="italic">New York World.</emph></p>
                    <p>There can be no doubt that the policy so successfully tried before of "firing
                        the Northern heart" is the policy once more determined upon. The Radicals
                        would clap their hands joyfully over a general riot in the South, and to
                        this end are endeavoring to foment strife between the white and black race.
                        Such collisions would be heralded as the revival of rebellion and secession,
                        and would furnish the capital so much needed in the conduct of the Radical
                        campaign. The peace and good order that have prevailed in the Southern
                        States under all the circumstances of provocation and irritation under which
                        they have been kept have disappointed and alarmed the Radicals. They want to
                        see the public peace broken and are determined that it shall not be the
                        fault of Congress if it is not violated. The bill that lately passed the
                        Senate for arming the Southern negroes was passed with this view. The bill
                        that passed the House for degrading the military commanders and the
                        provisional governors into cyphers and making the convention mob the ruling
                        power in Virginia, Mississippi, and Texas, looked to the same end. -- <emph
                            rend="italic">Richmond Whig.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial from the Richmond Whig. Claims that Radicals wish to see war and
                    riots throughout the South, since that would help them at the polls. In
                    furtherance of this wish, they are passing bills intended to stir up racial
                    conflict in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.08.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The stockholders of Staunton's new Building Association will meet at the
                    Court House to discuss organization.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Firemen's Excursion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company, led by Capt. J. H. Walker, made an excursion to
                    Goshen in the company of "gay lads and merry lasses." The party of 200 arrived
                    at their destination "and spent the day in a most joyous and happy manner."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The stockholders of the Valley Railroad met and unanimously re-elected
                    their officers. N. K. Trout chaired the meeting and R. H. Catlett served as
                    secretary. M. G. Harman delivered a report detailing operations for the past
                    year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>W. J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Carrie Riley, infant daughter of W. J. D. and Caroline Riley of Staunton,
                    died on July 23rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph B. Scott died on July 20th in his Augusta County residence. He was
                    67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newham</ln>
                        <fn>J. Annis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newham</ln>
                        <fn>J. W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss J. Annis Newham died of consumption on July 27th at the Waynesboro
                    residence of her father, J. W. C. Newham. She was 22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary A. Bare died in Staunton on May 13th. She was 57 years old. "Her
                    sufferings during her protracted illness were very severe, but were borne with
                    unmurmuring patience and christian resignation to the will of God."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.08.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
