<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.09.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-22">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">22</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.22.01" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Taxation!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes the Republicans for the heavy taxation they have
                    levied while in office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Let Us Have Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Away down in the State of Maine, says the Lynchburg <emph rend="italic"
                            >Virginian</emph>, they seem to be imbued with Horace Greeley's idea of
                        the best means of making peace between the North and South. They justify the
                        wrongs and outrages that have been inflicted upon the white men of the South
                        by the party in power. They "speak good words" to us like Rehoboam did to
                        the people, when following the advice of rash and wicked counselors. They
                        say, in effect: "Those who have gone before us made your yoke heavy, and we
                        will add to your yoke: They chastised you with whips, but we will chastise
                        you with scorpions. Our little finger shall be heavier than their loins."
                        And having said this, they add: "Let us have peace!" Of course we shall have
                        peace, for nobody wants war. But what of that kindness and good will which
                        are the true basis of peace and concord? Can we feel these in our hearts
                        towards the men who thus declare that our punishment is just and they will
                        not lighten it? They act a brutal part towards us, in that they support the
                        authors of the greatest crimes upon civilization that have been committed in
                        any age or country where the spirit of Christianity prevailed. "What concord
                        hath Christ with Belial? Or what part hath he that believeth with an
                        infidel?" About as much, we answer, as it is possible for the Southern
                        people to have with those who would "shed the blood of war in peace" and
                        crush out the last remaining hopes of a ruined and almost despairing people.
                        We trust, however, that no Southern man will ever humble himself at the feet
                        of these people -- We have had enough of that, and now let them do their
                        worst.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Lynchburg Virginian argues that the South shall have peace because no
                    one wants war, but claims that the Radicals who campaign under the slogan "let
                    us have peace" have failed to generate the kindness and good will that form the
                    lasting basis for peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is well remarked in the last number of the Political Pamphlet, that a
                        prevailing error is, "to confound the resentment of the South towards a
                        political party, with hostility to the rightful authority of the government.
                        The two sentiments are widely separate; and yet how often do we see some
                        indignation which the South has exhibited on Radical rule, busily and
                        ingeniously misrepresented as an evidence of disloyalty, a sign of "rebel"
                        impatience and contumacy. The mistake is constantly made even by some
                        honest, but thoughtless people. It runs through the newspapers; it is the
                        familiar fallacy of the Republican party; and it has been imposed on the
                        popular mind with an effect dishonorable to its own intelligence and ruinous
                        to the South." And the misfortune is, that a long possession of power almost
                        unlimited, and authority without stint, even to a course of legislation
                        outside and irrespective to the Constitution, has emboldened the leaders to
                        impress upon many of their followers, the idea that Congress <emph
                            rend="italic">is</emph> the government, and that the Executive is its
                        creature, and the Judiciary subject to its orders. There are thousands of
                        Radicals who entertain this opinion, and who have no proper conception of
                        the Federal government as organized under the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>Two gentlemen from the North who went to South Carolina to speculate in
                        loyalty have been doing splendidly. One got elected delegate to the
                        Constitutional Convention and the other has got into jail for bigamy. The
                        Convention man has also been elected a member of the Legislature and stands
                        indicted for a criminal offence.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes those who would confuse disagreement with the Radical platform
                    with disloyalty, as well as those who believe that Congress represents the whole
                    government, with the other two branches subordinate to it. Also criticizes
                    Radicals for electing criminals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Wonderful Combination of Curative Waters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper extols the virtue of the waters at Variety Springs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls attention to "accounts of atrocities committed by colored
                    people in various portions of the country, either impelled by their own bad
                    passions, or incited by evil counsels. Some of the details are shocking,
                    involving murder, rapine, arson, outrages on females, etc."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harvey Risk has announced that he will take a census of Staunton if the
                    town furnishes him with the books and supplies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Allen and Mr. Johnson, nurserymen of Richmond, subscribed one $100
                    share of stock to the Augusta County Fair. They made their purchase through
                    William Burke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum will resume its meetings. The Rev. Mr. Long will open
                    the season by delivering a poem. The paper also lists the organization's
                    officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Memorial Dinner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Lady's Memorial Association will hold a dinner in the Town Hall. The
                    proceeds will go toward the costs of laying turf on the graves and graveling the
                    walks in the Soldier's Cemetery. The paper urges citizens to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Norfolk Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: -- Augusta is much more interested in the Commercial Convention,
                        or I ought to have said the Internal Improvement Convention, which meets in
                        Norfolk in Oct., than she was in the Democratic Convention which met in New
                        York. We are deeply concerned in pushing thro' to the Ohio, the Chesapeake
                        and Ohio Railroad, but far more that <emph rend="italic">greatest</emph> of
                        all schemes, the James River and Kanawha Canal. I will not take time to say
                        any thing on a subject about which all intelligent people are familiar. Maj.
                        Carrington, President of the Company, has lately put forth a most
                        interesting pamphlet, in which a history of the Canal, <sic>part</sic>,
                        present and prospective is given. I wish all persons in the United States
                            <emph rend="italic">that are to be</emph>, could read it.</p>
                    <p>Please insert in a conspicuous place under your editorial head, a call for a
                        public meeting at our next Court, to appoint delegates to that Convention,
                        and let it be understood, that our best men be appointed.</p>
                    <p>A CITIZEN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"A CITIZEN" expresses Augusta's interest in the Commercial Convention in
                    Norfolk. This Convention will discuss internal improvements, including an
                    ambitious project called the James River and Kanawha Canal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>David K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masincup</ln>
                        <fn>Cynthia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David K. Hoover and Miss Cynthia A. Masincup were married on September 17th
                    at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
