<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.09.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-29">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.29.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>F. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"A Visitor" writes to the Spectator with an account of a picnic at Moscow.
                    A large number of Mossy Creek Scholars proceeded from the School House under the
                    charge of Capt. Curtis to hear music directed by F. B. Carson, listen to an
                    address by the Rev. J. J. Pinkerton, and enjoy a feast.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Good County Roads Needed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As we have said on a former occasion, we believe that this healthful,
                        fertile, and beautiful Valley of Virginia, take it all in all, is the finest
                        portion of the United States, and Augusta county is the heart of the Valley.
                        There is but one thing needed in this good old country to make it the most
                        desirable to live in, and that is good county roads. Money and labor could
                        not be more profitably expended than in improving the county roads. We do
                        not mean one or two, but all the roads in the county. Every road should be
                        made a good road, and should be kept continually in that condition.-- It
                        will require a great deal of labor to make them as they should be made, but
                        when once properly made, it will not involve much expense or labor to keep
                        them in good condition, if the proper system be adopted. A few reliable men
                        who understand the business should be kept constantly employed upon each
                        road, whose duty it should be to keep the road in good condition by keeping
                        the ditches on both sides of the road open, and keeping the road well filled
                        in the centre so that the water would run off the sides into the ditches
                        instead of running in the direction of the road and washing gullies in it.</p>
                    <p>The system of calling men out "semi-occasionally" to "work the roads," as it
                        is called, will never secure good roads. They will never work long enough to
                        put the roads in good condition, and if they did, they would not be kept so,
                        for months would elapse before any more work upon them would be done, and by
                        that time there would be as many gullies and mudholes, and the ditches as
                        much filled up as before, and consequently as much labor as before would be
                        required. There is nothing to which the aphorism -- "A stitch in time saves
                        nine" -- is more applicable than to roads. In keeping roads in proper
                        repair, a lick in time saves ninety and nine.</p>
                    <p>Two reliable laborers constantly repairing the road would keep it in better
                        condition than the hundreds called from their farms once or twice a year to
                        "work the road." It would be better to levy a tax or raise a fund to be
                        appropriated to the employment of hands to be kept constantly upon the
                        roads, and who would be responsible for their condition.</p>
                    <p>It would add 25 <emph rend="italic">per cent</emph> to the value of the farms
                        in this county, if all the county roads were made good and kept in proper
                        condition. The wear and tear of buggies, carriages and wagons would be much
                        less, and the farmers could haul heavier loads to market and in shorter time
                        -- thus saving a hundred times as much as their proportion of the tax (which
                        would be small,) and at the same time escape the annoyance of being called
                        out with all their hands to work the roads at a time, probably, when they
                        are much needed on the farm. We throw out these hurried suggestions this
                        week for the consideration of our farmers and others.</p>
                    <p>We may recur to this subject again, as we deem it one of great importance to
                        the interest of all our citizens.</p>
                    <p>We should be pleased to receive the written views of our intelligent farmers
                        upon this subject, whether they concur with ours or not.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors believe that good county roads will be one of the surest ways
                    to further improve Augusta county. They suggest that a system that employs two
                    workers consistently maintaining the roads would be a more effective method of
                    maintenance than a system by which farmers are called out periodically in large
                    numbers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Not a Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A fatality, says the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>, seems to
                        pursue the Radical Congress. Everything it does has a trick in it. At best
                        it is regarded as illegitimate, by reason of being but a fractional and
                        sectional body, but to make the matter even worse, less than a quorum
                        undertook to do what only a quorum could properly and lawfully do -- order a
                        called session.</p>
                    <p>The Constitution provides that "a majority of each (House) shall constitute a
                        quorum to do business; but a smaller number may adjourn from day to day, and
                        may be authorized to compel the attendance of absent members," &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Less than a quorum adjourned, not "from day to day," but to the 16th of
                        October. There was a quorum of the Senate, but not of the House, and leaving
                        out of view the provision of the Constitution, it is to be borne in mind
                        that the terms of the resolution making contingent provision for the meeting
                        of Congress was itself violated, but under that resolution there was to be
                        no session unless a quorum of both Houses should be present. What a lawless!
                        What tricks and what tricks-setters! Such is the body that legislates for
                        forty millions of people who call themselves free and boast of a
                        Constitution and laws.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Whig charges Congress with violating the Constitution by
                    calling a session without a full quorum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Disturbances in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The frequent riots and disturbances in the South of late, says the Baltimore
                            <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph>, are not without significance. They
                        form a part of the Radical programme by which it is hoped to carry the
                        Presidential election. In every instance these riots have been inaugurated
                        by armed negroes, led by white Radicals. In every instance the Southern
                        people, knowing the object of these men, have borne insult and wrong, rather
                        than afford them the opportunity they sought for, and it has only been when
                        their lives and property have been threatened by Radical mobs that the
                        people have risen in self-defence. Knowing these facts, knowing how blood is
                        recklessly spilled and property destroyed by direction of the Radical
                        leaders, what a bitter mockery is their campaign cry -- "Let us have
                    Peace!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Baltimore Gazette claims that the disturbances and riots taking place
                    in the South are caused by Radicals seeking to win the Presidential election by
                    frightening the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Down on the Carpet-baggers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The negroes hereabouts, says the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>,
                        have declared war upon the carpet-baggers, and manifest a disposition to cut
                        themselves off from all whites and set up for themselves. When this state of
                        feeling shall extend to the negro masses throughout the South, the plans of
                        Congress will be greatly disturbed. The project of the Northern Radicals was
                        to govern the negroes by carpet-bag lieutenants. If the negroes won't be
                        directed by these lieutenants, but insist upon their own captains, what will
                        Congress do? It is fast coming to that.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Whig reports that the Freedmen have rejected the
                    carpet-baggers' leadership, and now seek office themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoneman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britt</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gen. Stoneman appointed George W. Britt flour inspector for Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares the dinner held by the Ladies of the Memorial
                    Association a "decided success."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The monthly meeting of the Staunton Building Association will take place
                    tomorrow night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum will meet in the lecture room of the Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the citizens of Augusta County, held in the Court House in
                        Staunton, on September Court day, for the purpose of appointing Delegates to
                        the Commercial Convention which will meet in Norfolk city on the fourteenth
                        of October next, upon motion, Hon. Alex. H. H. Stuart was appointed
                        Chairman, and Col. James H. Skinner, Secretary of the meeting.</p>
                    <p>Col. J. Marshall McCue explained the object and importance of the Norfolk
                        Convention.</p>
                    <p>Col. B. Christian moved that the Chairman appoint fifteen delegates, and the
                        same number of alternates to represent this county in said Convention.</p>
                    <p>Col. John B. Baldwin briefly addressed the meeting, urging the importance of
                        this county and section being represented in the proposed Convention, saying
                        that if Norfolk had forgotten this part of the country, that we at least had
                        not forgotten Norfolk, and that we hoped to make such a city of her, that
                        shortly she would not know herself.</p>
                    <p>Gen. John Echols further zealously advocated the motion showing the interest
                        that this county has in building up Norfolk, and making her "the great
                        Southern sea-port." He jocularly intimated that it would be wise to appoint
                        none but old men as delegates, as he feared that the well known hospitality
                        of Norfolk, and the preparations of welcome which were making might result
                        in leading astray <emph rend="italic">young</emph> men from the true objects
                        of the Convention.</p>
                    <p>Col. Christian thought if <emph rend="italic">"hospitality"</emph> was
                        significant of the sort of internal improvement to be promoted -- the old
                        gentlemen should not wish to monopolize.</p>
                    <p>The motion upon being put was unanimously adopted, and the Chairman appointed
                        thereunder the following Delegates and Alternates.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Delegates.</emph>-- John B. Baldwin, John Echols, Bolivar
                        Christian, J. M. McCue, R. G. Bickle, M. G. Harman, Jacob Baylor, Th. W.
                        Shelton, B. B. Donaghe, N. K. Trout, W. A. Burke, H. M. Bell, R. Mauzy, F.
                        W. Bayley, John J. Larew.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Alternates.</emph> -- Col. R. Turk, Gen. F. Price, B.
                        Crawford, Absalom Koiner, Adam McChesney, Dr. Wm. L. Waddel, Logan J.
                        Maupin, Wm. Withrow, James W. Patrick, Wm. M. Tate, J. Marshall Hanger,
                        Thos. P. Eskridge, Col. W. D. Anderson.</p>
                    <p>Upon motion, the Chairman and Secretary were added to the Delegation.</p>
                    <p>Upon motion, the meeting adjourned.</p>
                    <p>ALEX H. H. STUART,</p>
                    <p>Chairman.</p>
                    <p>JAS. J. SKINNER, Secretary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bayley</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>Logan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting is held to appoint the Delegates to the Commercial Convention in
                    Norfolk, which will be held in October.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following tribute to Virginia, we extract from the recent charge of Judge
                        Sheffey, to the Grand Jury of Rockbridge county, at the last Circuit Court
                        for that county: "Virginia is not without many blessings, although she
                        stands under the shadow of a dark cloud of affliction. She is blessed with a
                        population, white and colored, peaceful, orderly and submissive to law. She
                        is blessed with resources unsurpassed by those of any State in the Union;
                        her agricultural wealth, mineral products, water power, manufacturing
                        capacities, climate, scenery and purity of atmosphere are unsurpassed. She
                        is blessed with the cordial esteem and profound respect of civilized
                        mankind; many of those who were once our enemies being foremost in
                        applauding the unselfish devotion, calm dignity, and stern heroism of her
                        conduct during the recent war, and her patient submission and uncomplaining
                        composure under sore trials and temptations since the war ceased, although
                        peace came not; and she is blessed with that exalted self-respect which is
                        better than wealth, better than bloated prosperity, better than well fed
                        complacency, and purse-proud self-laudation and boasting, and inspired with
                        which her sons, even her colored people, when far from her borders, are wont
                        to pronounce her name with proud confidence and with the assurance that
                        honor awaits wherever it is uttered; and above all, she is blessed in that
                        she is yet standing, like the chief of the martyr, with the sword of
                        destruction suspended over her -- still stayed and withheld by an invisible
                        power; and as we gaze with fixed eyes and beating hearts at the venerable
                        old State, and so many other States, the framer of the Union and its
                        fearless defender in years gone by, now bowed down and with her head bending
                        forward to receive the blow which shall annihilate her as the old
                        Commonwealth of Virginia, and as we see the uplifted arm stretched forth to
                        destroy, still held back, may we not hope -- at any rate, let us all
                        fervently pray -- that the "arm which is not shortened" may yet save her
                        from that doom which would make freemen mourn and patriots hang their heads
                        in shame in the future!</p>
                    <p>God grant that the bitter cup may pass from her lips, and that Virginia may
                        be saved to be a true nursing mother to all the sons of the South and an
                        honor and glory to our common country. Let us with one heart cling to her
                        with a love that knows no fear, and will not be satisfied till she is
                        blessed with safety and prosperity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A "tribute to Virginia", made by Judge Sheffey, praising the State and
                    praying that the horrors of Radical reconstruction will pass.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Porterfield Kinney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Porterfield Kinney Bell, infant son of Maj. H. M. Bell, died in Staunton on
                    September 18th. He was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>Louis B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Louis B. Kelley, son of John and J. M. Kelley, died in Staunton on
                    September 25th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanard</ln>
                        <fn>Philip B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss A. H. Christian died near Goshen Bridge at the residence of her
                    brother-in-law, Maj. Philip B. Stanard, on August 23rd. She was 27 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kibler</ln>
                        <fn>David B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kibler</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David B. Kibler, son of Abraham Kibler of West Virginia, died in Augusta
                    County at the home of his Aunt, Mrs. Amanda Spitler. He was 8 years old and
                    suffered a "long and painful illness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.09.29.04" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The White Race and the Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>REMARKS OF GENERAL J. B. GORDON.</p>
                    <p>In the course of a speech delivered in Charleston on the 11th inst., General
                        James B. Gordon, of Georgia -- the representative of "Young South" --
                        addressed the colored portion of the audience as follows:</p>
                    <p>In the few words I shall say to you, my friends, if you listen to me, I hope
                        to deal with you candidly and honestly. The Radicals have told you that the
                        Southern people were your enemies. But believe me, this is not so. I was
                        opposed to your freedom. [Laughter.] We were all opposed to your freedom.
                        Now, that's honest, isn't it? ["Yes, that's so," from the crowd.] And why
                        was this so? I'll tell you. We did not do this because we were your enemies,
                        but because we had bought you and paid for you. [Great laughter.] You
                        belonged to the Northern people once, and some people think you belong to
                        them now, in the Loyal League. It was the Northern States that sent to the
                        shores of Africa and brought your fathers to the North. And when your labor
                        became unprofitable, they sold you to the Southern people.</p>
                    <p>The carpet-baggers will tell you that the North brought on the war to free
                        you. Let me ask why didn't they set you free when they owned you? You might
                        then have been born free, and might now have owned the forty acres which the
                        lying rascals promised you. I say that they did not wage the war to free
                        you, and no honest soldier who participated in it will say so. The idea
                        never was entertained. General Grant himself at one time threatened to quit
                        the service if you were freed. They set you free because they wanted to use
                        you, not from any love they had bore you. And now they tell you that we are
                        your enemies. Have we not been born on the same soil? Are not our interests
                        identical? Have we not grown up together and have not our fathers been
                        buried under the same sod? Why, then, are we your enemies?</p>
                    <p>You have been told to arm yourselves against the whites. [Cries of "No, no."]
                        Well, I am glad to hear it. What would be the result of arraying the two
                        races? A contest will come, which will be a war of races; then which race
                        must triumph? You are in the majority on the seaboard, and could destroy
                        many people. But, my friends, let me tell you the moment the war of races is
                        inaugurated that moment the death warrant of the black man on this continent
                        is signed. There are three millions of your race and forty millions of white
                        men. Now, I ask you in all reason which race must go down?</p>
                    <p>The speaker then alluded to the assertion of Helper, who said that before the
                        year 1872 no black man will have a habitation on this continent. In quoting
                        this the speaker said: -- He says so because of speculation. Lands are
                        scarce in the North, they have a surplus of labor, and they desire to blot
                        out your race in order that they might come here, take possession of the
                        place and cultivate the land. The indian once lived where you now live, but
                        where is he now? He couldn't live in peace with the white men, and he went
                        to war. The few scattering mounds that are left in the State speak the
                        result. Now, this is what Helper says must be your fate, and most singular
                        to relate, a large majority of the Radical members of Congress are
                        subscribers to his book and are giving it circulation.</p>
                    <p>Now I speak plainly. If you are disposed to live in peace with the white
                        people they extend to you the hand of friendship. But if you attempt to
                        inaugurate a war of races you will be exterminated. The Saxon race was never
                        created by Almighty God to be ruled by the African. These are truths. We
                        want peace with you. We cannot live as enemies. One or the other must go
                        down. If you turn a deaf ear to the Southern man these green leaves that now
                        clothe the forest will not grow red with another autumn before they will be
                        drenched with your blood and mine.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of the remarks of General Gordon, a representative of the "Young
                    South", made to an audience of Freedmen. Gordon encourages the Freedmen to
                    reject Northern leadership, and cautions them that if they ignore the wishes of
                    the South and instigate a racial war, their race will be exterminated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>More Heavily Taxed than Any Other Nation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes heavy taxation under Republican rule by making
                    negative comparisons between the United States's tax burden and that of other
                    nations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
