<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.12.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/02/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-12-15">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">15</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.12.15.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President's Message was presented to Congress at 1 o'clock on Wednesday
                        last. In lieu of publishing the message in full, which is very long and
                        would scarcely be read by one in twenty, we publish an abstract of it, as
                        telegraphed to the <emph rend="italic">Dispatch</emph>, which, in a brief
                        space, gives the reader the substance of it, as follows:</p>
                    <p>The President begins by calling the attention of Congress to the continued
                        disorganized condition of certain States of the Union under the various
                        reconstruction laws. A timely revocation of injustice and oppressive
                        measures is the greatest good that can be conferred upon the nation. The
                        reconstruction laws have failed, after three years' trial, have proved
                        pernicious in their results, and should no longer remain upon the
                            <sic>statue</sic> book. States to which a Constitution guarantees a
                        republican form of government have been reduced to military dependencies in
                        each of which the people have been made subject to the arbitrary will of a
                        commanding General. Although the Constitution requires that each State shall
                        be represented in Congress, Virginia, Mississippi, and Texas are yet
                        excluded from the two Houses, and, contrary to the express provisions of
                        that instrument, were denied participation in the recent Presidential
                        election.</p>
                    <p>The attempt to place the white population under the domination of persons of
                        color in the South has impaired, if not destroyed, the kindly relation that
                        had previously existed between them, and mutual distract has engendered a
                        feeling of animosity which, leading in some instances to collision and
                        bloodshed, has prevented that co-operation between the two races so
                        essential to the success of industrial enterprise in the Southern States.
                        The Union has been agitated by grave apprehensions of troubles which might
                        involve the peace of the nation. -- The Federal Constitution is now adequate
                        to the settlement of the questions growing out of the late civil war.</p>
                    <p>The President reviews the condition of the country since the end of the
                        rebellion, declaring that the acts passed were not warranted by the
                        Constitution. He says that the best interests of the country demand the
                        repeal of the tenure of office act, and the appropriation act of March 2,
                        1867, interfering as it does with the President's constitutional functions
                        as commander in chief, and denying to States the right to protect themselves
                        by means of their own militia, and should also be repealed.</p>
                    <p>The financial affairs of the Union need immediate attention as the public
                        expenses are unprecedented. [Here the President sets forth substantially his
                        letter to General Ewing.] -- Congress should make early provision to pay the
                        indebtedness of the country; the fruits of labor should be enjoyed by
                        citizens rather than used to build up moneyed monopolies in our own and
                        other lands; the debt should not become permanent; the interest on the debt
                        should be reduced, the owners of Government securities receiving seventeen
                        per cent, on each dollar. This favors the few at the expense of the many.
                        The national credit should be sacredly observed. The six per cent. interest
                        now paid by the Government should be applied to the reduction of the
                        principal in semi annual installments, which, in sixteen years, would
                        liquidate the entire national debt. The large amount of capital now invested
                        in Government securities should be released. The resumption of specie
                        payments is recommended.</p>
                    <p>The condition of our foreign affairs is reviewed. The controversy with the
                        Paraguayan Government is detailed. Negotiations are pending for the
                        construction of a ship canal across the Isthmus Darien, and a comprehensive
                        national policy would seem to sanction the acquisition and incorporation
                        into our Federal Union of the several adjacent continental and insular
                        communities as speedily as can be done peacefully, lawfully, and without any
                        violation of national justice, faith, or honor.</p>
                    <p>Foreign possession or control of these communities has hitherto hindered the
                        growth and impaired the influence of the United States. -- When firmly
                        established as an independent republic, or incorporated into the United
                        States, they would be a new source of strength and power.</p>
                    <p>No reference is made in the message to our affairs with England relative for
                        the Alabama claims, the naturalization treaty, etc.</p>
                    <p>The President renews his recommendation that the judgement of the people
                        should be taken on the propriety of amending the Constitution: First, for
                        the election of a President and Vice President by the direct vote of the
                        people instead of by the agency of the electors; secondly, that district
                        designations should be made of the person who shall discharge the duties of
                        the President in the event of vacancy in the office both of President and
                        Vice President; thirdly, that senators should be elected by a direct vote of
                        the people of several States.</p>
                    <p>In concluding, the President says: "Let us earnestly hope that before the
                        expiration of our respective terms of service, now rapidly drawing to a
                        close, an all wise Providence will so guide our counsels as to strengthen
                        and preserve the Federal Union, inspire reverence for the Constitution,
                        restore prosperity and happiness to one people, and promote on earth peace
                        and good will toward men."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An abstract of the President's Message to Congress, as published in the
                    Dispatch. The President is critical of the reconstruction laws, and speaks
                    against "the attempt to place the white population under the domination of
                    persons of color." The President also speaks on matters of national debt and
                    foreign affairs. He also speaks in favor of a reform of national elections, and
                    recommends the direct election of senators.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.12.15.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces a meeting at the Court House about the Stay Law. The
                    paper opposes suspension of the law. "We think that it should be modified so as
                    to require the debtor to pay the interest and a certain per cent of the
                    principal annually."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The military commissioners of Virginia have been ordered to report the
                    names of all court clerks and commonwealth attorneys who are disqualified from
                    holding office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: -- Augusta's subscription to the Valley R. R. <emph rend="italic"
                            >has been carried beyond all doubt.</emph> The vote under the charter
                        was a majority and not three-fifth vote, as in the Chesa. &amp; O.
                        subscription. 'Tis true the charter speaks of a vote by freeholders, but the
                        orders from Gen. Stoneman attached to each poll-book over-rides this and
                        opens the way to all entitled to vote for the Legislature, white and black.
                        Even if a freehold vote, the subscription is carried by a decent majority,
                        and great shame to the county if it had not carried it. Let the company be
                        organized at once and the most capable engineer be selected to locate the
                        route. Rockbridge has done her whole duty and the other counties will tread
                        in her footsteps beyond doubt. OMRICAN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Omrican" writes that the subscription to the Valley R. R. has
                    unquestionably been passed by a majority vote, and recommends the formation of a
                    company and the selection of engineers to complete the Railroad with all
                    possible speed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.12.15.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Presbyterian Church in Churchville will hold a fair on Christmas Eve,
                    Day, and Night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Thomas A. Montgomery died on December 8th from the effects of a
                    broken leg. "He was a good citizen and valuable member of the church, and his
                    loss will be greatly felt in his neighborhood."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>United States Tax-Payers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Federal tax collector will be in Staunton on December 22nd and 23rd to
                    collect all unpaid taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Juvenile Musical Association, under direction of Dr. Brown, gave a
                    concert in the Chapel of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution. The weather
                    prevented large attendance, but the performance was delightful. The concert will
                    be repeated in the Town Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Election for the Valley R. R. Subscription</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is the official classified vote of this county, on the question
                        of subscribing the sum of $300,000 in the stock of the Valley R. R. Company.</p>
                    <p>Sherando and Waynesboro have not yet been heard from officially.</p>
                    <p>By the amended charter of the Valley R. R. Company, adopted March 1st, 1867,
                        it only requires a <emph rend="italic">majority</emph> vote of Freehold
                        voters to carry the subscription, instead of three-fifths of the votes of
                        those voting under the military order of Gen. Stoneman, as has been
                        supposed. Whether a majority of subscription on the 5th inst., cast there
                        votes in favor of the subscription or not, we are unable to say.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>PRECINCTS.</cell>
                            <cell>Registered (white), For Subscrp.</cell>
                            <cell>Not Regist'd. (white), For Subscrp.</cell>
                            <cell>Registered (colored), For Subscrp.</cell>
                            <cell>Not Regist'd (colored), For Subscrp.</cell>
                            <cell>Registered. (white), Against Subscrp.</cell>
                            <cell>Not Regist'd. (white), Against Subscrp.</cell>
                            <cell>Registered. (colored), Against Subscrp.</cell>
                            <cell>Not Regist'd. (colored), Against Subscrp.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Court House,</cell>
                            <cell>161</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                            <cell>59</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>do doubtful</cell>
                            <cell>12</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Union Hall,</cell>
                            <cell>No poll opened.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Middlebrook,</cell>
                            <cell>36</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Swoope's Dep.</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Craigsville,</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>12</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Newport,</cell>
                            <cell>30</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenville,</cell>
                            <cell>60</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                            <cell>17</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Midway,</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                            <cell>7</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Stuart's Draft</cell>
                            <cell>no poll</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sherando</cell>
                            <cell>no returns</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fishersville</cell>
                            <cell>30</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>13</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Waynesboro,</cell>
                            <cell>no returns.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Hope,</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                            <cell>18</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Meridian,</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>44</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Sidney,</cell>
                            <cell>26</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>106</cell>
                            <cell>26</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Spring Hill,</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Solon,</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>18</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>71</cell>
                            <cell>15</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Parnassus,</cell>
                            <cell>15</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Churchville,</cell>
                            <cell>35</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Deerfield,</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The official results of the vote of Augusta county for Valley R. R.
                    Subscription. Votes are broken down by county and by race.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>George P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pratt</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Harman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bucher</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Council of the Evangelical Lutheran Congregation of Staunton resolved
                    to hire an inspector to examine the condition of the church tower.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>State Constitution, So-called</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In reference to the monstrous instrument, miss-called the Constitution,
                        adopted by the mongrel Convention, the Petersburg <emph rend="italic"
                        >Index</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>Life, under its ruthless oppression, for the white man who remained true to
                        his manhood, to his associations, to his instincts and culture, to his
                        intelligence and experience, would be so barren of all that the Spirit of
                        Freedom craves, so prolific of all which that spirit cannot look upon and
                        live, that there is no fate in the range of probability which seems not
                        preferable to such.</p>
                    <p>From beginning to end it is one perfect antidote to Peace in the communities
                        for whose oppression it was designed. Its whole structure is discriminative,
                        in favor of the one, and against the other class, and the most studied
                        effort to consummate a plan without flaw, by which it should be impossible
                        to prevent conflict, inexpressible and endless between the races which
                        inhabit Virginia, would fall short of its design, and fail of its object,
                        unless 'twere written in the very spirit, and contained the exact features,
                        which mark the despicable instrument of Tyranny. Under its operations there
                        could be but one of two results: Either the white man or the black must go
                        to the wall -- and if the former first, then both.</p>
                    <p>Industry will not be chained by sloth, intelligence will not be directed by
                        blindness, property will not submit to pauperism, liberty will not be ruled
                        by a despotism wearing the mask of license, the dwellers in a land will not
                        be jostled out by vagrant usurpers -- without a dire and bitter struggle, in
                        which these natural influences shall be worn threadbare ere submission be
                        made. There can be no government of a people, born and taught in the
                        fullness of individual and national republicanism, which unequalizes the
                        rights of its citizens, and labors to the suppression of natural
                        superiority, and the creation of artificial domination, but that government
                        shall be brought forth by force and fraud, cradled in convulsion, reared in
                        insecurity; live to the detriment of all that is noble and right in the ends
                        to which Governments are designed of God, and die by the excess of its own
                        destructive power.</p>
                    <p>And such is the accursed image which is sought to be reared in our midst by
                        these prophets of Baal. Under its yoke, all that is best and highest in our
                        people would be banished from power, all that is meanest and lowest be
                        summoned to authority. Speculating sojourners would sacrifice every
                        permanent and material interest of the people they have come to despoil,
                        housing their ill-gotten hay while the sun still shone on successful
                        rascality, while the owners and the thinkers and the workers of Virginia,
                        should see their portion parcelled out without the lawful authority to give
                        voices in the matter.</p>
                    <p>This is not declamation. The thing speaks for itself. Once in force with its
                        gerrymandering of districts and its test oaths; and the white people of
                        Virginia will be as hopeless upon their own soil as though they had never
                        held a name, a glory, a freedom, or a self-dominion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Petersburg Index criticizes the state Constitution, claiming it stands
                    contrary to peace and liberty. Claims that the constitution is discriminatory,
                    and places the white race under the authority of the Freedmen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>To Walk the Plank</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Stoneman is removing from office all court clerks and
                    commonwealth's attorneys who are ineligible under the 14th Amendment. "The
                    enforcement of this section will deprive the State of the services of many of
                    her best officers, and will supply their places with a set of scalawags and
                    carpet-baggers, whose only merit is their baseness. The greedy lust for office
                    of these people is to be gratified at last, at the expense of the best interests
                    of the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles E. Harris and Mary E. Pierce, both of Augusta, were married at Mt.
                    Sidney on November 29th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Walter T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>Winney E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Walter T. Fisher of Rockingham and Miss Winney E. Rodgers of Augusta were
                    married near Deerfield on November 26th by the Rev. A. A. P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Pelt</ln>
                        <fn>E. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Pelt</ln>
                        <fn>Jinnie R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Myers and Miss E. C. Van Pelt, and James B. Campbell and Miss
                    Jinnie R. Van Pelt, all of Augusta, were married at the same time by the Rev.
                    Dr. Huston in his parsonage at Baltimore on November 17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McComb</ln>
                        <fn>M. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarkson</ln>
                        <fn>N. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wales</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. H. McComb of Augusta and Miss Sallie B. Robinson of Covington were
                    married at the Nelson County residence of Mr. N. C. Clarkson on November 25th by
                    the Rev. S. Wales.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hodge</ln>
                        <fn>Renix</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Renix Hodge died at his residence on the Calf Pasture River, Augusta
                    County, on November 13th. He was 76 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Russell died suddenly in Parnassus, Augusta County, on December 7th.
                    He was 82 years old and "had been a consistent member of the Methodist Church
                    for forty years."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McQuain</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saunders</ln>
                        <fn>L. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cabaniss</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garland</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geiger</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Fire Association of the Institute for the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind pass
                    resolutions of sympathy for principal Covell upon the death of his son, George
                    E. Covell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.12.15.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
