<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.11.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/02/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-11-03">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">3</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.11.03.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of the opening of the Augusta County Fair, including addresses by
                    Col. John B. Baldwin, president, and Alexander H. H. Stuart and Matthew F.
                    Maury. All three praised the industry in agriculture and the mechanical arts
                    displayed by Augusta's citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.11.03.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair. Grand Success!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maury</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antrim</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caperton</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Florence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Arch</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finks</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>Jack</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper declares the Augusta County Fair a "grand success." The article
                    includes mention of the speeches and reports on winners of the sporting events.
                    The paper also provides a long account of a medieval tournament held at the
                    fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.11.03.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The ladies of Staunton's Episcopal Church gave a musical performance under
                    the direction of Prof. E. Louis Ide. They raised $100 toward building an iron
                    fence around the Episcopal cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Ladies' Memorial Association raised between four and five hundred
                    dollars at their refreshment tent at the fairgrounds. The money will go toward
                    "beautifying and adorning the soldiers' cemetery." The ladies of the Episcopal
                    Church also ran a refreshment tent at the fair. They raised between three and
                    four hundred dollars for improving the cemetery at the Episcopal Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Reconstruction."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>James P. Cowardin delivered at Staunton's Town Hall his humorous lecture on
                    "Reconstruction." The performance parodies the Virginia constitutional
                    convention of 1867 by comparing it to that of 1829. "His inimitable imitations
                    of the voice, manner, and gestures of the negro, scallawag, and carpet-bag
                    members of the convention, as he repeats their speeches as delivered in the
                    convention, verbatim et literatim, convulsed time and again the audience with
                    irrepressible laughter."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta County Court directed that an election will be held December
                    5th to determine whether or not the county will subscribe $300,000 to the stock
                    of the Valley Railroad Company. Col. Harman believes that if the county raises
                    one million dollars, then the road can be put under contract in early 1869.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bailey</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pratt</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Executive Committee of the Augusta County Fair congratulates the people
                    of the county for the success of the recent fair. The directors would now like
                    to raise money to make improvements to the fair grounds, and they urge citizens
                    to purchase bonds from the fair corporation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Education of Soldiers' Children</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Who could witness the exercises of the Augusta County Fair held here on
                        Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday last, without predicting for this
                        organization a brilliant future? The thousands assembled, including the
                        solid experience of age, and the ardent ambition of youth, cannot fail to
                        give character to the institution throughout the Valley; while the display
                        of domestic manufactures, and of improved farming implements, could not fail
                        to impress all present with the conviction that our Virginia Farmers are on
                        the road to independence.</p>
                    <p>An old negro in Albemarle county, looking at a mowing machine at work in a
                        field of clover, is said to have exclaimed, "De white folks won't want us
                        darkeys presently. Dese machines gwine do every thing. Den what we darkeys
                        gwine do for a home, hey? Tell me dat. I tell you, dis nigger gwine to work
                        now, while he can get it." Had he been at this exhibition, he would have had
                        his apprehensions abundantly confirmed.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Broaddus, Secretary for the Soldiers' Children, was present on Thursday.
                        Many contributed something to the noble work he is engaged in. But other
                        matters so occupied the immense crowd, that he could speak to only
                        comparatively a few. Would it not be well for <emph rend="italic">all</emph>
                        who did not get a chance to contribute to this work, to send him a donation
                        by mail? -- The children are put into the schools most convenient to them,
                        without regard to the church relations of Teacher or pupil. Teachers demand
                        only <emph rend="italic">One Dollar</emph> per month. Noble liberality! But
                        even at this cheap rate, thousands of Dollars will be needed. Address Rev.
                        W. F. Broaddus, Fredericksburg.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Broaddus</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The county fair was an excellent exhibition of the uses of machinery in
                    agricultural production. Reverend Broaddus sought to start a collection for the
                    Soldiers' Children, but was unable to reach many at the Fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Supporters of the Valley Railroad met in Staunton's Court House and passed
                    resolutions endorsing the proposed county subscription of $300,000 to the
                    company stock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The rational freedom which was enjoyed in America prior to the war was
                        founded upon the principles of the Constitution of the United States. There
                        can never be a restoration of the liberties and franchise of the people, nor
                        can republican government be long maintained on the continent except upon
                        the basis of the Constitution of our fathers. This is a serious truth that
                        every American whether enfranchised or disfranchised, should seriously
                        reflect upon. If it is steadily kept in view, many a politician would save
                        himself from the disgrace of frequent tergiversations, which he must be ever
                        exhibiting if he persists in seeking safety in policy merely. Principles are
                        eternal. -- Truth is ever mighty. The Constitution is the only anchor upon
                        which we can hang a hope for American liberty.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Constitution is the basis of freedom and liberties in
                    America, and should be protected as such.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Peter E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Peter E. Wilson and Miss Margaret J. B. Eidson, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Staunton on October 22nd by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchens</ln>
                        <fn>Anderson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anderson Hutchens and Miss Rebecca S. Hill, both of Augusta, were married
                    on October 27th by the Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hedrick</ln>
                        <fn>James J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James J. Hedrick of Jefferson County, West Virginia, and Miss Susan A.
                    Whitmer of Augusta, were married near Parnassus on October 27th by the Rev. A.
                    A. P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Letitia M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Gilkeson and Miss Letitia M. Tate, both of Augusta, were married at
                    Greenville on October 20th by the Rev. James Murray.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>Joel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Wheeler, wife of Joel Wheeler, died in Waynesboro on October
                    6th. She was 38 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McComb</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James McComb, Sr., died near Barter Brook on May 9th. He was 68 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grever</ln>
                        <fn>Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grever</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grever</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alice Grever, daughter of Philip and Eliza Grever, died on January 2nd
                    after a short illness. She was 16 years old. "She was a dutiful and affectionate
                    daughter and beloved by all who knew her. The voice no longer gladdens the
                    hearts of her sorrowing parents, and if anything can console them under this
                    bereavement, the thought that their loss is her eternal gain, alone can do it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.11.03.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>How to Keep Up Our Roads</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Norfolk Virginian quotes the Staunton Spectator on the importance of
                    county roads, and reports that Augusta "placed a value equal to 25 per cent of
                    that of the real estate of the county on the establishment of satisfactory
                    highways." The Norfolk paper suggests that the county put convict gangs to labor
                    on the roads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
