<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1868/va.au.ss.1868.08.25">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-08-25">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1868.08.25.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>To the Tax-Payers of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A vote will be taken on the 27th for a subscription by the county of
                        $300,000, to the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad.</p>
                    <p>Look sharp, or you will have a burden thrown upon you that will greatly
                        embarrass, if not crush you.</p>
                    <p>There are some noisy advocates of this scheme, and it may be well for you to
                        enquire, who of them reside out of the county, and how much of this tax will
                        be paid by those reside in the county, and without assailing their motives,
                        or doubting their disinterestedness, say to them, that you will take care of
                        your own interests, and that they may mind their own business.</p>
                    <p>In view of the lamentable condition of the country, threatening your
                        destruction, who of you, are willing to part with a large portion of your
                        hard earnings, and place it in the hands of others without a voice to
                        control its destination. Until a Government is re-established, and you again
                        have security for your rights, you would be wise to retain until little is
                        left in your own hands, and manage it in your own way.</p>
                    <p>But what will be done if the subscription be made? The county will execute
                        her bonds for $500,000, and if they are to avail at all in the construction
                        of the road, they must be put into market, or passed to contractors for
                        making the road. If to contractors they cannot afford to take them for more
                        than the market price, and if put into market, amidst the general distrust,
                        national, State, county and individual, if they would sell at all, it may
                        well be doubted whether they would command twenty-five cents in the dollar.
                        There is no money, in the country, to invest in that way, and foreign
                        capital will not venture in such stock.</p>
                    <p>What then have you? A debt of $300,000 fastened upon you, which must be paid
                        sooner or later -- and what have you for it? Fifty or seventy-five thousand
                        dollars worth of work done on the road. Are you ready to be shaved out of
                        $225,000 or $250,000? I am not for</p>
                    <p>ONE.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"One" writes a letter to the Editor arguing against the subscription to the
                    Valley Railroad stock, out of concern for the financial burdens this will impose
                    on the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>To be Rich and to be Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defending as understandable the charge that all women desire to be rich and
                    married.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1868.08.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Liberties Must and Shall be Preserved</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Charlottesville <emph rend="italic">Chronicle</emph> says that everything
                        indicates the steady roll of the popular wave which seems about to engulf
                        Radicalism and consign to a well merited oblivion the men who have almost
                        succeeded in subjecting a free people to the rule of a despot, and by their
                        gross mismanagement of the public finances have brought a rich and
                        prosperous country to the verge of national bankruptcy. In every State
                        election that has been held this summer the Conservative Democracy have made
                        large gains. The people at the North seem at last to appreciate the
                        importance of the question at issue, and to be inclined to decide them on
                        their merits with regard to men or to old party ties. Party lines are being
                        drawn more closely every day, in view of the live issues that now agitate
                        the country. Democrats and Whigs, Confederates and Unionists, Old
                        Slaveholders and Abolitionists, have forgotten their old prejudices against
                        each other and have ranged themselves, side by side, in favor of the
                        liberties of the whole country, where they are honest men and are influenced
                        by motives of public good, or are found fighting on the side of despotism
                        when the desire of plunder and regard for their own interests are stronger
                        than their honesty. Joe Brown the extreme secessionist -- and Sumner the
                        radical abolitionist are found in the same ranks -- while we find the
                        gallant Southern soldiers Hampton and Forrest, desiring the success of the
                        same party and the election of the same men with Hancock and Blair the brave
                        champions of the Northern cause.</p>
                    <p>In the whole history of the Anglo-Saxon race it will be found that radical
                        excess has been followed by conservative reaction, which has uniformly
                        restored the disturbed equilibrium of their government -- and during the
                        greatest excesses of modern radicalism the recollection of this fact has
                        been to us a ground of hope.</p>
                    <p>We always felt sure that this reaction would come and only feared that it
                        would be put off too late to save the Southern States. Now we think that
                        every thing indicates that it has set in in good earnest, and unless
                        something happens to check the popular movement radicalism all will go well.</p>
                    <p>We feel sure that we can see the light breaking through the cloud. We subjoin
                        a short extract from a <emph rend="italic">Sun</emph> editorial which can be
                        relied on more fully, as the <emph rend="italic">Sun</emph> is not extreme,
                        though decided and outspoken on the side of popular freedom.</p>
                    <p>"Thus it seems that if there is thus far less demonstrativeness than usual on
                        the surface of affairs, it is not the result of any want of popular
                        interest, but that perhaps a profound consciousness of the seriousness and
                        vitality of the questions at issue indisposes men to deal with them as
                        partisans or to express their emotions so much in words as in action. It is
                        certain that the nomination of General Grant has not thus far added any
                        strength to his party. In those States where elections were held just before
                        the Chicago nominations, and when his name was identified with the radical
                        ticket, and even where, as in Connecticut, the ticket bore his likeness, it
                        had no effect, except that the democratic majority was increased instead of
                        diminished. So it has been in Oregon. And as to Kentucky, the Chicago
                        nominations only seem to have had the result of adding forty thousand to the
                        democratic vote. If, as we have said, the name of Seymour has not been
                        received with more acclamation of words than that of Grant, the votes show
                        that his nomination has not injured his cause. But names have nothing to do
                        with this contest. Men are felt to be as nothing in comparison with the
                        principles which they represent and the consequences that may follow the
                        contest. The results in Kentucky and Oregon are perhaps but successive
                        billows in that current of reaction against the misrule and excesses of
                        radicalism which manifested itself in the elections in New York, California,
                        Connecticut, Pennsylvania, Ohio, etc. The name of General Grant has failed
                        to arrest that current, and the name of Mr. Seymour, if it has not given it
                        fresh strength, does not seem to have retarded it.--The most illustrious
                        names are only of interest as they symbolize ideas and principles."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article from the Charlottesville Chronicle predicting a Democratic victory
                    in the upcoming Presidential election. Claims that the ideas symbolized by the
                    two parties matter more than their candidates, and that the Democratic platform
                    is more popular.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Call for Arms</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article opposes allowing the new southern state governments to arm the
                    militia. The author asserts that is will only result in the subjugation of the
                    "whites of the South--who own the property, have the intelligence and the
                    capacity to govern--who have the most at stake, and most desire order and
                    security."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A New Dodge</head>
                <origin>Charlottesville Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article asserts that the Congressional Republicans are now discussing
                    allowing legislatures to choose southern representatives because they fear the
                    outcomes of state elections, the large African American vote notwithstanding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1868.08.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis Johnson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewis Johnson Bruce, infant son of A. M. and Mary Bruce died on August
                    15th. He was 9 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia Coldwell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>Adele</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Virginia Coldwell Points, infant daughter of W. J. and Adele Points, died
                    in Staunton on August 22nd. She was 4 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1868.08.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
