<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.06.30">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>2/24/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-06-30">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="30">30</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.06.30.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Virginia Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proceedings of the June 21, 1865, session of the Virginia State Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Hanging and Confiscation</head>
                <origin>Balt. Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The penalty of treason is death; and while we doubt the constitutionality of
                        the Confiscation Act as passed by Congress, it may be conceded that
                        forfeiture of property is one of the liabilities incurred by those who can
                        be proven to be traitors. Starting with these premises, a considerable
                        portion of the people of the North have determined that there is only one
                        conclusion to be reached, and that is that a great number of men must be
                        hanged and hundreds of thousands of acres of land must be confiscated. They
                        say, that if Mr. Davis and General Lee had resisted the authority of the
                        Federal Government at the head of fifty or a hundred men, they would
                        unquestionably have been brought to trial, and that it only makes the matter
                        worse that they were the leaders of many hundred thousands.</p>
                    <p>This statement they seem to think exhaust the argument. We do not propose to
                        discuss these points. No reasoning would probably have any effect upon those
                        persons who can see no difference between the most gigantic civil war on
                        record and the John Brown raid, and who would, at the end of a prolonged
                        contest, signalized on both sides by innumerable feats of heroism, have the
                        Southern soldiers indicted for assault and battery, or trespass. We fancy
                        that if any such soldier should be tried at Gettysburg for shooting at
                        Federal troops in the memorable battles of the 1st, 2nd and 3rd of July,
                        1863, he would be pretty sure of an acquittal, if any Pennsylvania soldiers
                        who participated in the fights should be upon the jury.</p>
                    <p>But our present business is with the future rather than the past. In view of
                        the fact that proceedings have been initiated against the persons and
                        property of many of the citizens of the Southern States, it behooves us to
                        look at the effect of such a policy upon the prosperity of the country. The
                        condition of the South is bad enough already. A new labor system is to be
                        organized, railroads and manufactories are to be rebuilt, vast tracts of
                        land which have relapsed into wilderness must be again enclosed and brought
                        under cultivation, and all this is to be done by a people who are nearly
                        bankrupt, and when the able-bodied part of the population has just been
                        largely diminished by the casualties of war. At such a moment comes the
                        rumor that the confiscation law is to be rigidly enforced. This is
                        sufficient notice to eight-tenths of the property holders of the insecurity
                        of their titles, and they feel at once that any further outlay of energy or
                        money may be altogether wasted. Now, the North is, of course, looking to the
                        South to pay her portion of the national debt; and it will be some time,
                        under the most favorable circumstances, before the latter can respond to the
                        demands of the tax-gatherer. What must be the result if a rigorous policy is
                        insisted on which altogether checks the efforts her people are willing to
                        make to restore their olden prosperity.</p>
                    <p>Again, it may be assumed that it is very desirable that the people of the two
                        sections should live in harmony together. Proceedings have already been
                        instituted in Richmond against the property of three hundred persons, and
                        the officers of the law are daily bringing new actions. If the same course
                        is pursued in all other judicial districts of the South, what must be the
                        inevitable result? A bitter feeling of hostility will be engendered towards
                        the North such as was never developed during the war, and hundreds or
                        thousands of men will be driven to the extreme of recklessness and
                        desperation. A great many patriots will say that Southern rebels deserve all
                        that can happen to them. We do not intend to discuss that question either.
                        We simply presume that the sensible men in the North desire, if only for the
                        sake of their own section, the prosperity of the South, and that they wish
                        to live amicably, if not in friendship, with their late foes. How can this
                        be accomplished? Certainly not by creating a wide spread disaffection and
                        despair throughout all the country stretching from the Potomac to the Gulf.
                        The question at issue touches the pacification of a nation, and we earnestly
                        submit that it ought not be determined by those who regard the matter in the
                        light of a street riot.--<emph rend="italic">Bult. Gazette</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article, reprinted from the Baltimore Gazette, argues against the
                    position, held by many northerners, that ex-Confederates should be punished for
                    treason by hanging or confiscation of land and property. Lenient treatment would
                    aid the speedy return of prosperity to the devastated South and promote peaceful
                    sectional reconciliation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.06.30.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the end of the war all our towns have been overrun with the negroes
                        from the surrounding country, who have imagined that freedom gave them the
                        right to live in idleness and be supported by the whites.</p>
                    <p>This idea was summarily put to flight a few days since by the arrest of all
                        the idle colored men in town, and their being required to find and pursue
                        some means of livelihood. This is a step in the right direction and Col.
                        Stewart, the Commandant of this post, deserves credit for it. Unless they
                        are made to labor there must necessarily be great suffering among this class
                        during the coming winter. We trust that they may learn from the action of
                        the Military authorities that they will not be allowed to live idle and
                        dissolute lives, and may conduct themselves in such a manner as to secure
                        profit to themselves and retain the kindly feelings of their former
                    owners.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper applauds the action of Col. Stewart, the post commandant, for
                    arresting all the "idle" black men in town. The article argues that they must be
                    "made to labor" to prevent suffering over the winter, and that to "retain the
                    kindly feelings of their former owners" they must learn that "they will not be
                    allowed to live idle and dissolute lives."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. A. T. Maupin, the newly appointed Post-Master of our town, informs us
                        that the Post Office will be opened on to-morrow, (Saturday,) and the mails
                        will be carried regularly thereafter on the Valley route. He hopes soon to
                        receive the mails by the Central Railroad, and will endeavor to have the
                        mails resumed on all the diverging routes from this point at an early day.</p>
                    <p>He desires us to say that parties can secure boxes at $2 per annum payable
                        quarterly in advance. Postage stamps are on hand now, and the latter part of
                        next week he will receive a lot of internal revenue stamps, which parties
                        can get by applying at the office. It may not be amiss to state, in this
                        connection, that Notes, Bank Checks, Receipts for $20 and upwards,
                        &amp;c., &amp;c., are not valid without a stamp is affixed, a
                        failure so to do subjects the party giving check, &amp;c., to a
                    penalty.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. A. T. Maupin, Staunton's new Postmaster, announces the opening of the
                    Post Office. The article comments on prices and the availability of stamps.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that Governor Pierpont has changed the name of
                    Staunton's "Central Lunatic Asylum" to "Western Lunatic Asylum."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that the trustees of the Staunton Academy have selected
                    Charles E. Young to serve as Principal. The article describes Young as "a
                    gentleman of education and fine qualifications as a teacher."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>H'd Q'rs Army of the Shenandoah</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes an order signed by General Torbert of the US Army of
                    the Shenandoah forbidding any ex-Confederates from appearing in public wearing
                    any "insignia of rank" in the army or navy of the Confederacy. Torbert reasons
                    that sufficient time has "elapsed since the surrender of the forces late in
                    rebellion with the United States, for all who were of such forces to procure
                    other apparel than their uniform."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James B. Barnes and Mrs. Sarah A. Fisher, of Staunton, were married on
                    April 4th by the Rev. J. C. Dice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William H. Apple of Greenville and Mrs. Emma Snyder of Staunton were
                    married on April 14th by the Rev. J. C. Dice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDonald</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William M. McDonald of Tennessee and Miss Lizzie Fisher of Staunton
                    were married on May 30th by Rev. J. C. Dice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Alfred J. Hamilton, aged 40 years, died at his Augusta County
                    residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beker</ln>
                        <fn>James Warren</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beker</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beker</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Warren, infant son of George M. and Fannie E. Beker, died in Staunton
                    on June 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Huff, wife of Frank Huff, died in Staunton on June 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
