<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.09.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/9/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-09-01">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="01">01</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.01.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.01.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>With the changes in affairs, since the cessation of hostilities, the
                        sentiments and policy of many have undergone changes, and the desire never
                        to see the "Old Dominion" turn her attention to Manufactures, for fear that
                        it might depreciate the value of her slave property or do away with the
                        institution of slavery, must give way before the march of events.</p>
                    <p>Virginia is fitted by nature to take a stand among the first Manufacturing
                        communities in the world. She is supplied with an immensity of water power,
                        a vast and varied assortment of metals and minerals of the finest quality, a
                        soil which can furnish productions more than sufficient to sustain the
                        immense labor which would be necessary to develop and manufacture the
                        abundant materials buried beneath it, and is blessed with one of the most
                        pleasant and salubrious climates in the world. All these taken together give
                        her the pre-eminance over any of her sister States, in material and
                        facilities for becoming the great manufacturing State of the Union. With no
                        drawback now, incident to the slavery question, to prevent the full
                        development of her manufacturing resources, it is the duty of the hour to
                        look forward to and help her reach an advance step in that direction.</p>
                    <p>Virginia can compete with New England for the supremacy in this and she must
                        do it. In fact it is the only sure way left her to keep pace with the
                        progress of the other States of the Union, and at the same time retrieve her
                        losses.</p>
                    <p>With the desire to advance the manufacturing interests of our State there
                        must also be kept in view, as the initiatory step, the increase and
                        improvement of her systems of intercommunication. It has been the fate of
                        nearly all her works of internal improvement to start out for some point
                        they never reach. Whether it is inability, or want of energy, or what not,
                        it is nevertheless true that they stop short of their projected
                        destinations, for an unwarrantable length of time, and consequently but few,
                        if any, of them pay anything. Their stock is dreadfully below par and all
                        from the old fogy inertia which seems heretofore to have possessed the
                        people of our State. Oh! for a live coal to put upon the back of the
                        terrapin Virginia.</p>
                    <p>Although we desire to see the rapid advancement of all our systems of
                        intercommunication, yet we confess to feeling a greater interest in those
                        nearest us. Especially would we like to see the Virginia Central Rail Road
                        extended to the Ohio River. Then ho! for a double track and many a branch
                        road to bring in the rich deposits west of this point to be manufactured at
                        home, and a big city at the other end, really entitled to be called
                        Richmo(u)nd (or mont,) which, by the immensity of its trade, will rival the
                        queen cities of the East.</p>
                    <p>With the improvement and extension of all her lines of trade, the development
                        of her resources and the advancement of her manufacturing interests, will
                        come the golden opportunity for the poor, unfortunate Virginia of to-day to
                        amass many times more wealth than she has lost in her devastation and her
                        slaves, and then for the glory of seeing New England, her successful rival
                        of to day, by her overwhelming resources for war, but second best in the
                        great race for supremacy in manufactures, by Virginia's overwhelming
                        facilities in that line fully developed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors plead for development of manufacturing in Virginia. They argue
                    that such a course would be the best way to compete with New England and recoup
                    war losses. Since slavery has been abolished, there should be no impediment to
                    carrying out such a program. The paper also advocates investment in
                    transportation and internal improvements.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Affairs are tending to order and quiet and as their first fruits, the
                        institutions of learning, so long closed, or impeded in their course, by the
                        protracted struggle thro' which we have passed, are, generally, advertising
                        an early resumption. The education of the youth of the country has been
                        unavoidably neglected, but the opportunity is now offered to make whatever
                        amends is possible, for the loss of four of the best years, to many, for
                        cultivating their minds and acquiring knowledge.</p>
                    <p>Scarcity of money should not be pleaded in this case. Teachers need food,
                        raiment and other things, which Farmers, Merchants and Mechanics can
                        furnish. If the money must, in some cases, be paid for tuition, surely the
                        amount, thus devoted for educating the youth, is not thrown away. It is
                        giving them a fortune which can not be lost, squandered, stolen or
                        destroyed--it is the best legacy the parent can bequeath to the child.</p>
                    <p>Virginia is endeavoring to resume her place in the Union. She must be
                        represented in its Legislative Halls hereafter as heretofore. She has, thus
                        far, furnished a vast array of intellect to the councils of the Country. The
                        "Mother of Statesmen" must still furnish her quota. If education is not
                        impeded she will. We, therefore, say to all, educate the youth--fill up the
                        Schools and Colleges, and Virginia will, as of yore, "when asked for her
                        jewels, point to her sons."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper advocates the importance of education. Now that the war has
                    ended, schools can be opened again, and parents should send their children
                    despite the financial cost. Only through education of the young can Virginians
                    regain her places as national political leaders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>R. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rivercomb</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roler</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayland</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>D. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports the results of a meeting to nominate candidates for US
                    Congress and the Virginia General Assembly. Maj. J. M. McCue moved to organize
                    the meeting with Col. William A. Bell as Chair and W. H. H. Lynn, Secretary. The
                    following nominations were made: Alexander H. H. Stuart for Congress; N. K.
                    Trout for Senate; and Colonel George Baylor, D. N. Van Lear, and D. S. Young for
                    House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. S. Young writes a letter to the editor declining nomination for House of
                    Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>J. I. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>C. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>G. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuqua</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Timberlake</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>T. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>B. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hirsh</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilb</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alby</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>Fred. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaysor</ln>
                        <fn>Davis A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Konklin</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seig</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>V. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawton</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gayer</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackburn</ln>
                        <fn>D. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>Madison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fretwell</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>G. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>H. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>H. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>Wash.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houseman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Markwood</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>P. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanfossen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeakle</ln>
                        <fn>G. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welch</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyer</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmonson</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Markwood</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garner</ln>
                        <fn>D. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sperry</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carmody</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saupe</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hare</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Donnall</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Many citizens of Augusta sign an open letter urging William G. Sterrett to
                    run for House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.01.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>FREDERICK SCHEFFER ESQ., of this place was swindled a short time since out of
                        goods and money to the amount of $325, in the following manner:</p>
                    <p>A man by the name of Kuhn presented himself to Mr. Scheffer and exhibited to
                        him a letter purporting to be from the Prussian Consul at New York, stating
                        that he held in his hands $1500 in money which had been sent him from
                        Germany, subject to a deduction of $25 for commission.</p>
                    <p>He furthermore stated that he had been referred to him by their mutual friend
                        Mr. Cunard as a responsible party who would attend to the collection of the
                        same. Mr. Scheffer not desiring a commission of that sort, turned him over
                        to Messrs Sheffey &amp; Allan (Bankers in our town) who undertook the
                        collection for him.</p>
                    <p>The matter as to the money being now settled, he said he was advised by Mr.
                        Cunard to consult with Mr. Scheffer as to the propriety of locating in
                        Staunton, and what sort of business would pay best. Mr. Scheffer having
                        learned from him that he was a Cabinet Maker, advised him to buy material
                        and furniture, and go to work at that business, to which he readily
                        assented.</p>
                    <p>In the meantime he proposed to purchase some goods to sell, in order to
                        employ his time, until he could receive his money. To this proposition Mr.
                        Scheffer (believing all things right) readily consented and furnished him
                        with the amount of goods stated above. He left with the goods, telling Mr.
                        Scheffer that he was going to dispose of them in the neighborhood of
                        Conrad's Store in Rockingham County. A day or two after he left Messrs Allan
                        and Sheffey informed Mr. Scheffer that they had just received a letter from
                        New York advising them, that the letter of the Prussian Consul was a base
                        forgery, and that there was no money in the hands of the Prussian Consul for
                        Kuhn.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Scheffer started immediately in pursuit of the scoundrel, and learned at
                        Harrisonburg that instead of going to Conrad's Store, he went direct to
                        Winchester.</p>
                    <p>From the Winchester News we learn that Mr. Scheffer placed the case in the
                        hands of detective Burnet, who not only succeeded in recovering the goods,
                        but in tracking the swindler to Philadelphia, where he was arrested and
                        returned to that place, and is now in durance vile. Mr. Burnett deserves
                        much credit for the manner in which he proceeded in this affair.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Detective</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper relates how a Staunton resident was swindled out of $325 in an
                    elaborate scam.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the first meeting of the County Court under the
                    restored Government of Virginia. James Wilson acted as presiding justice. D. S.
                    Young, W. G. Sterrett, and Joseph A. Waddell were appointed Commissioners of the
                    Court. John Towberman qualified as County Coroner and George Harlan as Deputy.
                    The Grand Jury brought two indictments against John W. Kuhn for forgery and
                    obtaining goods under false pretences.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conway</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Col. Charles T. O'Ferrall is completely
                    refurnishing his American Hotel, which the paper describes as one of the best in
                    the state. William Conway and Capt. James McClung preside in the office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Benjamin F. Fifer has been appointed flour
                    inspector and has begun work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that a number of 7.30 interest bearing bonds are
                    circulating in Staunton. The paper advises residents that the first-series bonds
                    sell at par in Baltimore, but not in Virginia and certainly not in Staunton. The
                    second series is rated at 99 3/8 and the third series at 99.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper comments on the "changes among business men of Staunton since
                    1862." "Of 64 persons engaged in business in Staunton, at that time, as Lawyers,
                    Doctors, Merchants and Mechanics, 20 are dead, (among which number 3 were
                    Lawyers, 2 Doctors, 7 Merchants and 8 Mechanics,) 30 left town" and the
                    remaining 14 are out of business or have changed business. The paper estimates
                    that those figures do not include "more than one half the changes among the
                    business portion of this community during the past 13 years, from deaths,
                    emigration or otherwise."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that the Virginia Hotel is being "repainted and
                    papered, preparatory to an anticipated opening." "The Bar is already in
                    operation, at which there are many practitioners." The paper declared that the
                    proprietor, Mr. F. Scheffer "is a go-ahead individual and will not stop half
                    way."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises the peaches of Davis' Nursery, near town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plunkett</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper thanks Mrs. William B. Plunkett for a present of beets averaging
                    five pounds each. "Who can beat them?" the editors ask.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Joseph W. Newman and Miss Amanda C. Argenbright, both of Augusta, were
                    married on August 22nd by the Rev. J. W. Kiracofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas W. McCue, "a highly respected citizen of Augusta," died on the
                    morning of July 11th. McCue was "about 47 years" of age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
