<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.10.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/16/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-10-27">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="27">27</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.10.27.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.10.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It may not be altogether amiss, after the elections in some of the Northern
                        States to look at their probable effect upon President Johnson's policy for
                        reconstruction.</p>
                    <p>The Republicans have thus far gained the day, but we learn from our Northern
                        Exchanges that the Democratic gain has been large. We have been unable to
                        compare the results with former elections, save in the case of Ohio.
                        Brough's majority for Governor two years ago, was [unclear]. Gov.'s majority
                        now is 26,257, which shows a clear gain for the Democratic party of 71,713,
                        which looks pretty well for a party that some have pretended to believe
                        dead. The fact is the Democratic party of the North has made a gallant fight
                        against Radicalism, which will result in a future triumph. President Johnson
                        understands this. He knows that the Republicans, by ignoring or leaving in
                        doubt their policy on important measures, have gained only a temporary
                        triumph, and that, with the defining of the issues, between the Republicans
                        and Democracy, which must take place during the session of the next
                        Congress, will come the further strengthening of the Democratic Conservative
                        party, and all that is necessary for him to do, is to continue to pursue his
                        eminently wise policy, to ensure a successful restoration of our country.</p>
                    <p>Besides a reference to these facts in every State, Republicans, as well as
                        Democrats, have endorsed his policy. If he does not reason thus, how can we
                        reconcile his acts since these elections have taken place? Has he not
                        relieved Kentucky from martial law, and liberated Stevens, Campbell and
                        others from imprisonment? Does he not still continue to persevere in his
                        policy, heedless of the storm which is gathering to vent itself in the next
                        Congress? which he understands so well to be the last blow that will be
                        struck by the radicals and in which they will vainlessly spend their
                        remaining strength. With all these things and the earnest desire expressed,
                        and acted out, by the South to unite again in a harmonious Union, and with
                        his ambitious hope of restoring the old Union, with the equality and rights
                        of the States unimpaired, we do not doubt that the result of the late
                        elections will cause him to adhere more firmly to his wise and Statesman
                        like policy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial argues that despite the Republican victory in the elections,
                    the Democrats gained ground which will encourage President Johnson in pursuing
                    his "wise and Statesman like policy" of reconstruction. The paper applauds
                    northern Democrats and the President for standing up to the radical Republicans,
                    an approach which should assure future victories for the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arbogast</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>R. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkerson</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces the arrival of Presidential pardons for the following
                    Augusta residents: Jacob H. Arbogast, James Walker, George Baylor, R. T.
                    Wallace, Thomas H. Wilson, Thomas Walker, Daniel Wilson, John Shuey, John F.
                    Smith, David Kunkle, J. T. White, and W. D. Gilkerson. The article also
                    announces that the President will begin granting pardons to those who had been
                    excluded for owning over twenty thousand dollars worth of taxable property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1865.10.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We suggest for the consideration of the Town Council, the propriety of the
                        Town taking entire charge of the water works, and employing a competent
                        mechanic, at a fixed compensation, whose sole duty it shall be to keep the
                        hydrants, &amp;c., in proper order, thus relieving those having hydrants
                        of the necessity and inconvenience of having to hunt some one to put them in
                        order, and then let the Council fix a tax on each private hydrant and
                        persons using the water.</p>
                    <p>There are about 300 hydrants in the town, which with a moderate tax would pay
                        all expenses and leave a margin for revenue to the town. Taxing the hydrants
                        and use of the water, may be objected to at first by some who have not
                        reflected about the matter, but when they sum up the expenses they pay for
                        fixing their hydrants &amp;c., during the year, most of which is for
                        labor, they will find they would be able to pay a considerable water tax and
                        save money by the operation. We hope the Council will take the matter into
                        consideration and also the improvement, much needed, of our water works. We
                        have now nothing to draw upon, in any emergency, but the water pipes, the
                        Reservoir serving but one use, at present, to stand a solitary monument of
                        its own stupendous failure.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges that the town take charge of the water works and hydrants
                    in the city. The editors advocate taxing hydrant use to help pay for the plan
                    which would relieve citizens of the burden of repairing their hydrants.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>Winfield Scott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hageman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Levy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces the arrest of Winfield Scott Graham, "a youth seemingly
                    about 20 years of age," for stealing a coat from the store of Hageman and Levy.
                    He was captured after a brief flight in the yard of Dr. Stibling. Mayor Trout
                    sent him to the county jail. "Rogues have but a poor show in Staunton, for our
                    community never rests until they are safely lodged in the County Mansion on New
                    Court House street."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carrell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Ralph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wesley</ln>
                        <fn>Flora</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Batis</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper summarizes the October proceedings of the County Court. Jno. F.
                    Smith was appointed Sealer of Weights and Measures, vice Wm. Carrell dec'd.
                    James F. Huffman, Ralph Marshall, John W. Kuhn, and William Grove were charged
                    with felonies and remanded to Circuit Court for trial. Flora Wesley (a
                    freedwoman) was acquitted on charges of stealing money. Mary Bell (a freedwoman)
                    was convicted of a felony and sentenced to the Penitentiary for two years. James
                    W. Baldwin, John G. Stover, and John H. Batis qualified as Notaries Public.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1865.10.27.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
