<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.02.24">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/02/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 7/14/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-02-24">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="00">24</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.02.24.01">
            <pageNote>On this page are articles about iron-clad ships, a speech by Mr. Long of Ohio
                on the issue of peace, and the number of persons exempted from service or on
                detailed service in several Southern states, in addition to advertisements and a
                poem.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.02.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Tax Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A summary of new proposals for taxes, drawn up by a special committee with
                    one member from each state, reveals that the new system would take one-fifth of
                    agricultural products, rather than the current one-tenth, and would use half of
                    that to feed the army. The new system would double property and business tax.
                    The intention of the new system would be to cut government expenses, to decrease
                    prices, to pay the army well, and eventually to replace the "hopelessly
                    depreciated" currency with a good currency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But let us all agree to give the LAST CRUST to sustain 'our boys' and turn
                    out OURSELVES to help them, and if we can't be free, WE CAN DIE."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor comes out strongly against croakers, as he calls those
                    pessimistic about the war's outcome. He reminds readers that the new nation
                    pledged to be free in 1861 and that if citizens would be true to themselves,
                    then they will be free.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain R. H. Phillips returned to his home in Staunton on Wednesday.
                    Phillips was in charge of the clothing department here, was captured during the
                    Hunter raid, and has been confined at Camp Chase since then.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>Nathaniel</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Massie, son of Nathaniel Massie, Esquire, formerly of Augusta
                    County, died. The editor grew up with him and grieves his death. Massie entered
                    business and was successful, then left his business to enter the University of
                    Virginia, after which he resumed his business interests in New Orleans. His
                    health was not strong, and he died at 30, leaving behind parents, brothers and
                    sisters. Two of his brothers have died in the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A mass meeting of the citizens of Augusta County will be held next Monday,
                    February 27, Court Day, in Staunton, to respond to Lincoln's action in the peace
                    conference. The editor calls on all who can to attend in order to send a strong
                    message of condemnation to the United States administration's demand for
                    unconditional surrender.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>D.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>D. writes the editor from Charlottesville, Virginia, on February 21, 1865,
                    expressing appreciation for the visit from Augusta citizens to the hospitals in
                    Charlottesville on February 14, 15, and 16. The sick and wounded men enjoyed and
                    were encouraged by the visitors and their singing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baer</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Baer married John Smith on February 9, 1865, near Churchville, with
                    Reverend George A. Shuey officiating. All are from Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>U. D.</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ann Poe, age 59, died at Spring Hill on January 20, 1865. She was the wife
                    of U. D. Poe, Esquire, and was a mother.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>$100 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClanahan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harvey, an African-American man about 21 years old who is five feet eight
                    or nine inches tall, of dark brown color, and who was wearing a dark brown Janes
                    coat and slouched hat, escaped from the jail of Augusta County on the evening of
                    February 21, 1865. Harvey was jailed for a felony. George Harlan, jailor, offers
                    a reward of $100 for Harvey's return. Harvey belongs to John McClanahan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>$500 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andy, an African-American man about twenty years old who is five feet nine
                    or ten inches tall, is slender and of dark color, and who was wearing a new
                    jeans frock coat with metal buttons, a pair of gray jeans pants, a white felt
                    hat, and a cloth cap, ran away from William D. Anderson on the night of February
                    26, 1865. Andy belongs to John C. Heiskell of Hampshire County. Anderson offers
                    a reward of $500 for Andy's return.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>School at the Augusta Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Packer</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. M. Packer announces that the current session of the school at the
                    Augusta church will continue until June 20, 1865. Charges begin at the time of
                    entering the session, and the sons of indigent soldiers may attend free.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>$200 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Z. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harriet, an African-American girl "about 15 years old, well grown and heavy
                    set," with "a bushy head of hair, and a small scar on her left cheek near the
                    mouth," ran away from the subscriber near Hebron Church on January 25, 1865. She
                    is "a bright mulatto" and was wearing "linsey" clothes. Z. D. Shafer offers a
                    rewards of $200 for her return.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other war news, advertisements, notices, and a calendar
                for 1865.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
