<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.08.25">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/2/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-08-25">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="25">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.08.25.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.08.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are much pleased to state that Gov. Pierpont has commissioned Judge Lucas
                        P. Thompson, judge of his old district--embracing the Counties of Augusta,
                        Rockbridge, Bath, Albermarle and Nelson.</p>
                    <p>The course pursued by Gov. Pierpont has caused the people of Virginia to
                        accord to him a cordial and hearty support, but we venture the assertion,
                        that the reappointing the judges of the various districts, thereby retaining
                        the acknowledged legal ability of these gentlemen on the bench, will endear
                        him more to our people. Especially does the reappointment of Judge Thompson
                        give general satisfaction and pleasure to our people. It was eminently due
                        to Judge Thompson, who has occupied the same position for many years--and
                        has, during that time enjoyed the confidence of the legal profession and the
                        people of his district. He is a gentleman in its broadest sense, has a
                        comprehensive knowledge of the law and fine attainments as a jurist. To sum
                        it up in a word, is one of the ablest judges on the bench in Virginia.</p>
                    <p>He will hold the regular fall terms in his district where elections have been
                        holden for Clerks of the Circuit Court.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper applauds the reappointment of Judge Lucas P. Thompson as District
                    Judge. The action, the editors hold, will help endear Governor Pierpont and his
                    policies to the people of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every thing is brushing up in our town. If we walk the streets after night we
                        are in danger of dropping into a mortar bed. If we were tired and desired to
                        lean against a house or door way for support, we would get our now black
                        broadcloth (if we had one,) painted white, green, led color, brown or
                        yellow. We rejoice in this improvement going on, not only for the appearance
                        of things, but because the mechanics who have been so long without a
                        sufficiency of work have now their hands full and we hope may also fill
                        their pockets. "It's an ill wind that blows the body any good." We wish some
                        sort of a wind would blow us a sufficient quantity of greenbacks to procure
                        a broadcloth with which to run the gauntlet of paint and mortar.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors comment on the many construction and painting projects going on
                    in Staunton. It improves the town's appearance, and gives work to mechanics who
                    have long had little to do.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The descendants of Africa's sable sons are ever prone to imitate. Gaudy or
                        guilded trappings catch and captivate their eyes. One of these youths
                        bethought himself to play the officer on Tuesday last by girding himself
                        with belt and sword. The prominence which he gave to the display, by moving
                        along one of our streets, attracted the attention of an officer in authority
                        who cut him short in his effort at magnificent pomposity, by ordering him to
                        come out of the paraphernalia military, and threatening punishment for a
                        like display of assumed and unauthorised rank.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a black youth recently paraded through the streets
                    of Staunton wearing a belt and sword. He was stopped by a military officer.
                    According to the editors, the event showed that "the descendants of Africa's
                    sable sons are ever prone to imitate."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article announces that a medieval Tournament will be held for the
                    "gallant youth of Augusta" near Staunton on August 31st. "Knights from a
                    distance are requested to attend, and we need not exhort the gallant knights of
                    Augusta to see to it that the credit of the old county does not suffer."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Sally More</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Susan S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sally More, infant daughter of Rev. George B. and Susan S. Taylor, died on
                    August 13th. "God gave, he took, he will restore, He doeth all things well."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
