<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.sv.1865.12.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/20/01/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-12-15">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="00">15</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.sv.1865.12.15.sgml.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Message of the President to the U. S. Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The full text of President Johnson's recent address to both houses of
                    Congress. For the full text of Johnson's speech see ****</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.sv.1865.12.15.sgml.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals in the United States Congress, not content with the overthrow of
                        slavery in the Southern States, seem intent upon still further goading our
                        section, under the shallow pretense of protecting the emancipated slaves.
                        The know full well that the best friends the poor negroes have are the
                        Southern people, their former owners, and if left alone, they will be made
                        useful laborers and be properly cared for. But this does not suit the
                        Radical faction. Without the negro as a hobby their party must sink into
                        oblivion. Desperate cases require desperate remedies, and desperate are the
                        efforts of the Radicals to keep their party together.</p>
                    <p>Just before the assembling of Congress, a Radical caucus was held and a
                        course mapped out, evidently looking to the forestalling of public opinion
                        on the forthcoming message of the President, and likewise to commit the
                        Republican members to the Radical policy.-In the pursuance of this plan,
                        Messrs. Sumner, Wade and Stevens, on the first opportunity after the meeting
                        of Congress, presented a series of resolutions and bills, aimed directly at
                        the further humiliation, if not the destruction of the Southern people.</p>
                    <p>Among these, the bill presented by Mr. Sumner, to preserve the trial by jury,
                        to the effect that, in sections where one-sixth of the population are
                        Africans, one-half of grand juries shall consist of persons of African
                        descent, and a like proportion of petit juries, where the cases refer to
                        injuries inflicted of persons of African descent upon whites and <emph
                            rend="italic">vice versa</emph>, and prejudice to said race is made the
                        ground for challenging or expulsion, is most particularly aimed at the
                        Southern people. If not, why not make a general law for such formation of
                        juries, for descendents of the African are to be found in every section of
                        the Union? This bill aimed at the South, if passed, will not that
                        immediately on its passage, African labor will ceased [MISSING LINES] forced
                        to go North to find employment.--Being a citizen, no laws can be framed by
                        Northern Legislatures, as was done in days gone by, to prevent his coming
                        among them, and soon in Northern States, and no where else, will the African
                        number one-sixth of the population. The South will then have no further
                        trouble on this score, but the North will. Their juries will be framed in
                        the plan of this proposed law of Congress, until the unnatural climate of
                        the North, brings to early graves the African race of this Continent. </p>
                    <p>They can live long an easily, become useful members of society and be amply
                        protected, and increase instead of diminish in the congenial climate of the
                        South, if their pretended Northern friends would cease their silly and
                        malicious interference, and it is to be hoped that they will cease ere long,
                        for every blow struck at the South, thus far, falls, and falls heavily, on
                        the head of the poor negro.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Radicals are not content in overthrowing slavery, but continue
                    to goad the South "under the shallow pretense of protecting the emancipated
                    slaves" and suggests that blacks would be most helped "if their pretended
                    Northern friends would cease their silly and malicious interference."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.sv.1865.12.15.sgml.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. L. B. WALLER, returned to this place on Saturday, from Gettysburg,
                        bringing with him the remains of Lieut. Charles T. Francisco, 52d Va.,
                        Regiment, who was wounded in the fight at that place, and died shortly
                        thereafter.</p>
                    <p>On Monday last, his funeral took place at the Presbyterian Church, where an
                        appropriate discourse was delivered, by the Rev. Mr. Baker and his body
                        interred the Thornrose. Cemetery.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waller</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>L. B. Waller returned to Staunton from Gettysburg recently, with the
                    remains of Lieut. Charles T. Francisco. A funeral was held at the Presbyterian
                    Church last Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ABOUT ten o'clock, on the night of the 4th inst., Mr. G. W. Dudley, while
                        returning home from Staunton, was attacked by two negros, who succeeded in
                        robbing him of eight dollars and some papers. Look out for such fellows and
                        try the effect of a little powder and lead on them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. Dudley "was attacked by two negroes" while returning home from
                    Staunton on December 4. The author warns readers to beware "such fellows and try
                    the effect of a little powder and lead on them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtz</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Holtz and James Snyder were married near Middlebrook on November 30 by
                    Rev. J. D. Shirey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ann Wiseman and George Dudley were married near Middlebrook on November 30
                    by Rev. J. D. Shirey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>Robt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earman</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Ella L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Van Lear and John Earman were married on December 7 at the home of
                    Robert Van Lear near Spring Hill. Rev. William Baker performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buford</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Morrison and John Buford were married in Staunton on December 7
                    by Rev. Wm. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shields</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shields</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Shields and James Collins were married near Greenville on November
                    9 by Rev. George Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiner</ln>
                        <fn>Harman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Louisa Harrison, of Augusta, and Capt. Harman Hiner, of Orange, were
                    married at the American Hotel in Staunton on December 13 by Rev. J. C. Dice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Celmick</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lorentz</ln>
                        <fn>Lou. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lorentz</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Beard, formerly of Mint Spring, and Lou. Lorentz, of West Virginia,
                    were married at the home of the bride's father on October 29 by Rev. Daniel
                    Celmick.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>Farncis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddy</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Lizzie Larew, of Augusta, and Joseph Waddy, of Louisa, were married on
                    December 12 at the home of the bride's father by Rev. Farncis McFarland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelter</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelter</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Pelter died at his home near Waynesboro on November 3. Requests
                    papers to the West to publish the notice in the hopes of reaching James Pelter
                    who "went West many years ago" and was last heard from in Missouri when
                    preparing to cross the Plains.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.sv.1865.12.15.sgml.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
