<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.01.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/27/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 7/13/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-01-06">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.01.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Salt Works</head>
                <origin>Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report on the damage to the salt works in Saltville, Virginia, reveals
                    that the works can be repaired quickly and that agents who are overcharging for
                    salt are doing so without a justifiable basis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Cavalry Fight in the Valley--Amusing Scenes</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Confederate attack at Lacey's spring, nine miles west of Harrisonburg,
                    produced a series of blunders in the enemy camp and are related in this article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Negroes</head>
                <origin>Savannah News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that African Americans in Savannah joined with Sherman's men on
                    their recent march through the city only when forced. Many others hid in nearby
                    swamps and forests, and some of those who went with Sherman have returned
                    already.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other articles on the war, advertisements, notices, and
                a poem entitled "To Him Who Despairs."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.01.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"With this our first . . ."</p>
                    <p>With this our first issue in the year 1865, we return our thanks to our
                        friends and patrons for the many act[s] of kindness showered upon us, and
                        wish them all a full share of prosperity and happiness for many years to
                        come.</p>
                    <p>Though our people have been harrassed [sic] at times, during the past year,
                        by the presence of an overbearing enemy, yet we rejoice that the suffering
                        in our midst has been no greater. We believe that on this account we have
                        much to be thankful for.</p>
                    <p>During the last twelve months, notwithstanding the numbers brought against us
                        and the eventful chances of war, the gain has been decidedly on the side of
                        the Confederacy. Sherman has advanced through the state of Georgia and now
                        holds the city of Savannah, but the country thro' which he passed is still
                        as much unconquered as it was before his onward movement commenced. To
                        compensate for this movement, the only approximation to a successful one of
                        the enemy during the year 1864, many thousand square miles of our territory
                        held by the enemy on the first of January 1864 are again in our undisputed
                        possession. Their army west of the Mississippi has been routed and
                        disorganized, while the grand Union armies of the Potomac and James, from
                        which such great things were predicted and expected, have accomplished
                        nothing and with the great Captain of the age and his gallant army
                        confronting them we have an abiding confidence that the ill success of the
                        hordes of Grant will be continued through the campaigns of 1865.</p>
                    <p>The new year brings with it new duties. Let each and all of us resolve to do
                        our whole duty, and never, for one moment, give away to despondency, that
                        worst enemy of our cause, but give a "long pull, a strong pull and a pull
                        all together," relying confidently that with an united effort the
                        independence of our country must ultimately be achieved.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor thanks friends and patrons for their support and notes that they
                    all have much to be grateful for at the beginning of a new year. He asserts that
                    many gains for the Confederacy occurred in 1864, noting that much of the
                    territory held by the North at the beginning of 1864 is no longer in their hands
                    and that even all the territory Sherman has passed through remains unconquered.
                    The editor is certain that Lee will continue to triumph over Grant and that
                    "with an united effort the independence of our country must ultimately be
                    achieved."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Dinner to the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The dinner that was to be held on New Year's Day for General Early's men
                    has been postponed until Saturday, January 7, 1865. The editor calls upon the
                    people to support this dinner generously so that it will be a memorable and
                    rousing one for the troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor states that the communication regarding General Early's army
                    that was referred to in the previous issue was inadvertently not printed in that
                    issue and is printed this week. The editor calls the attention of readers to it
                    again.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator--General Early</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>General Early.</p>
                    <p>For the Vindicator.</p>
                    <p>This distinguished officer has so disposed his troops as to afford ample
                        protection to the County of Augusta. Their continuance in their present
                        position will depend on the spirit which may be manifested by the people.
                        The Army must be fed. The people have the means of doing it. If they wish
                        protection for their families and property, they must supply their defenders
                        with the necessaries of life. If these cannot be furnished, the troops must
                        be removed, and the country left open to the incursions of the enemy. An
                        enlightened self-interest therefore, (to say nothing of patriotism) demands
                        that the farmers should act with liberality. One fifth of their surplus will
                        maintain the army. Common sense would dictate the propriety of even giving
                        that much to save the residue. But this is not asked. All that is required
                        is that they shall sell, at moderate prices, a small part of their crops, to
                        ensure the safety of their families and firesides.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The army of General Early has been positioned in such a way as to provide
                    protection for Augusta County. Their continued presence depends on their being
                    furnished sufficiently. Out of both patriotism and self-interest, the people of
                    Augusta should supply the army liberally and not hoard supplies for themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harner</ln>
                        <fn>Martha E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha E. Harner married William A [illegible] on November 23, 1864, with
                    Reverend C. Beard officiating. All are from Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byrd</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byrd</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth J. Bryd, daughter of Dr. James H. Byrd, married Captain J. C.
                    Matheny, Clerk of the Circuit and County Courts of Highland County, on December
                    22, 1864, with Reverend J. W. Carter officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Offlighter</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Offlighter, Company D, 25th Regiment of Virginia Infantry, died
                    at the home of his brother near Calvary Chapel on December 16, 1864. He had been
                    captured on May 12, 1864, taken to Elmira, New York, and sent home when his
                    health deteriorated. He arrived home November 23, 1864, lingered three weeks,
                    and then died in the care of his sisters, brother, and friends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Augusta Medical Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Medical Society will meet on January 13, 1864, at 11:00 a.m. to
                    conduct important business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Overseers of Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Overseers of Poor will meet at the office of N. K. Trout next Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Special Notice to the Ladies of the Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Special Notice to the Ladies of the Valley.</p>
                    <p>A soldier belonging to the Artillery of Genl. Earley's army, camped near
                        Fishersville is anxious to open a correspondence with any of the young
                        ladies of the Valley with a view to matrimony. He has been in the army since
                        the commencement of the war--has been in every battle his company has been
                        engaged in and wounded twice--about twenty two years old. For further
                        particular's address, with full description of self.</p>
                    <p>Henry St. Leon,</p>
                    <p>2d Co. Richmond Howitzers,</p>
                    <p>Cutshaw's Art'y Batt'l</p>
                    <p>Army of the Valley.</p>
                    <p>Jan. 6--2t*.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Henry St. Leon, 2nd Company, Richmond Howitzers, Cutshaw's Artillery
                    Battalion, Army of the Valley, advertises that a soldier in the Artillery of
                    General Early's army, camped near Fishersville, wants to correspond with young
                    women in the Valley, "with a view to matrimony." He has been in the army since
                    the beginning of the war, has been in every battle his company has been engaged
                    in, and has been wounded twice. He is about 22 years old. For more information,
                    interested parties should send full particulars about themselves to Henry St.
                    Leon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other articles on the war, a calendar for 1865,
                advertisements, and notices, including a number of estray notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
