<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.09.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/9/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-09-15">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="15">15</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.15.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.09.15.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Many and chimerical are the stories related by correspondents of the radical
                        press of the North, who write from pretended localities in the South, and
                        who serve up for the insatiate maw of the Northern masses, dishes, which
                        ought to satiate the appetite of the most rabid radical among them. Some of
                        these radicals, of the more moderate kind, like those men of the North who
                        really loved the Union, for which they fought and bled, are exhibiting
                        considerable nausea from the over doses administered by these garrulous
                        correspondents. They, experiencing the effects of a healthful nausea, begin
                        to understand these penny a line scribblers, who either go through the
                        South, not to see what they should see, or in their quiet apartments in the
                        North, far from scenes and things which they pretend to describe, cull from
                        their imaginations long and prosy articles, which the most casual observer
                        must know and understand to be entirely without foundation.</p>
                    <p>To feed the popular mind of the North, at present, upon marvelous and inhuman
                        stories of cruelty to freedmen and indestructible animosity to the Union, is
                        their object, in order to create feelings of hostility and keep alive those
                        engendered by a hotly contested struggle, and thereby prevent the
                        consummation of what the men who fought and bled in the struggle most
                        earnestly desired, the preservation of the Union of our fathers. To do this
                        may subserve a temporary purpose, but must of necessity, ultimately, when
                        truth and reason shall be heard, redound to the everlasting disgrace of all
                        such scribblers, who, attempting to retard the restoration of order and
                        prosperity in the South, are retarding, not only the prosperity of the
                        North, but of the United Republic.</p>
                    <p>Our readers can scarcely realize the extent of the wonderful Munchausenism
                        emitted by these real or pretended travelers through the South in search of
                        news. We clip a portion of one of the latest, from a correspondent, who
                        signs himself "Mendez Pinto" and styles himself "Raleigh Correspondent of
                        the Associated Press." So utterly incredible is his recital that we incline
                        to the belief that it was intended as a caustic sarcasm against the relaters
                        of wonderful disloyalty and terrible cruelty on the part of the whites of
                        the South. Whether it is a genuine correspondence or intended as a piece of
                        irony upon the wandering scribblers who infest the South, but to defame us,
                        it suffices to show the animus of the hireling writers sent among us. Here
                        it is:</p>
                    <p>"Judge Carter, who has returned from an extensive trip through the South,
                        states that the cruelty to the freedmen and the homicides among them by the
                        whites are increasing to a fearful extent. For the most trivial offences the
                        poor blacks are hung up to the forest trees by their thumbs, and Judge
                        Carter assures us that while in this position they are frequently stuck full
                        of pine slivers, which are set on fire. Judge Carter saw portions of one
                        freedman that had been subjected to this treatment. The missing portions had
                        been manufactured into sausages. The wife of a notorious secessionits,
                        residing at Pelican Turn-Out, on Saturday, deliberately butchered one of his
                        servants for attempting to eat an apple plucked without permission from the
                        orchard. As fast as children are born they are thrown into the wells; and so
                        alarmingly extensive hast this practice become that in one
                        section--Guerrillas' Retreat--the wells were all choked up, and many of the
                        whites, by a stroke of retributive justice, had died of thirst. Judge Carter
                        passed through the great pine woods south of Raleigh. On every tree at least
                        one negro was suspended, as often by the heels as the head; and sometimes
                        there were so many freedmen to a pine that it resembled a banyan tree."</p>
                    <p>Whether "Mendez Pinto" is a regular correspondent, or merely writes in a
                        caustic strain to defeat the object of the scribbling wanderers, who do not
                        try to represent the sentiments and feelings of the Southern people, we
                        trust he may write often and more marvelous stories still, for the tales he
                        tells utterly destroy the effect intended by those who write more plausible
                        imaginings of Southern sayings and doings.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces northern newspapers for printing stories about
                    continuing southern violence toward freedmen and hatred for the Union. The
                    editors suggest that such stories are sensational, fictional, and damaging to
                    the cause of reunion. The paper argues that such stories serve only to drive
                    northern moderates into the southern camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>President Johnson has written an admirable letter to Governor Sharkey, of
                        Mississippi, on the subject of organizing the Militia force of the State,
                        for the purpose of enforcing the law and preserving order, from which we
                        clip the following:</p>
                    <p>"If there was any danger from an organization of the citizens for the purpose
                        indicated, the military are there to suppress, on the first appearance, any
                        move insurrectionary in its character. One great object is to induce the
                        people to come forward in defence of the State and federal governments.
                        General Washington declared that the people, or the militia, was the arm of
                        the constitution, or the arm of the United States, and, as soon as it is
                        practicable, the original design of the government should be resumed under
                        the principles of the great charter of freedom handed down to the people by
                        the founder of the republic. The people must be trusted with their
                        government, and if trusted, my opinion is that they will act in good faith
                        and restore their former constitutional relations with all the States
                        composing the Union."</p>
                    <p>These are the words of a man who came into office with the feelings and
                        prejudices of the Southern people decidedly against him, but who, by his
                        firmness and decision of character and his determination, repeatedly
                        exhibited, to restore the Union as it was, and as speedily as possible, has
                        won for himself the lasting confidence and support of the Southern public.
                        Nor does this letter lower him in the estimation of the conservative people
                        of the United States, but rather places him more firmly in their confidence
                        and shows that he is eminently worthy of it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds President Andrew Johnson's position supporting the
                    re-mustering of southern state militias. The editorial remarks on the great
                    change from hostility to confidence in southern support for the president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ettinger</ln>
                        <fn>Joel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alby</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Joel Ettinger, the agent for Stieff Pianos in
                    Staunton, will show a piano recently purchased by Mr. J. W. Alby as a model for
                    prospective buyers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.15.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Joseph N. Ryan, elected Clerk of the Circuit
                    Court, has been deemed eligible to take office by Governor Pierpont. This is a
                    victory for "the many friends of Mr. Ryan in this county" against those who
                    argued that Ryan was ineligible for office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hirsh</ln>
                        <fn>Gabriel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Robert Williams, "a freedman who was shot while
                    attempting to rob the store of Mr. Gabriel Hirsh of Staunton," escaped from
                    jail. Williams had been sentenced to one year in the penitentiary by the
                    corporation court of Staunton. A man named Gibson attempted to escape at the
                    same time, but was stopped by the guard.</summary>
                <note>See article in August 18, 1865, issue of the Vindicator.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that upon the authority of the Provost Marshal at
                    Staunton, no persons are authorized to collect government property in the
                    section. "All persons so pretending are merely using this subterfuge to steal
                    said property."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cason</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Jacob Cason has been committed to jail on the
                    charge of shooting with intent to kill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teawalt</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William H. Teawalt, of Woodstock, Shenandoah County, married Miss Mary
                    Lizzie, daughter of David Beard, at the residence of the bride's father near
                    Mint Spring, Augusta County, on September 7th. The Rev. Mr. Dice presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary B. Bell, wife of John J. Bell of Waynesboro, died "after a
                    painful illness of several months" on June 3rd. She was 49 years old. "She was a
                    Christian woman, a valued member of the Presbyterian church. She discharged well
                    and faithfully her duties as a wife, a mother and mistress."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.15.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
