<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.08.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/2/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-08-18">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="18">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="08" image="va.au.rv.1865.08.18.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Suffrage Question--A Dialogue</head>
                <origin>The Boston Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Negro</emph>--"Go way dar; you Injun and Chinaman no
                        account--no account a' tall."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Indian</emph>--"Ugh!"</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chinese</emph>--"Chinaman have big country--do much
                        business. American man come long way to get tea, silk, many tings."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Negro</emph>--"Go way, I say; you got no right suffrage;
                        you ain't a man and a brudder."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Indian</emph>--"Me right of suffrage from the Great
                        Spirit. This country my hunting ground; pale face bring thunder and
                        lightning and fire-water, and drive poor Indian away, but the Great Spirit
                        looks on. Ugh!"</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Negro</emph>--"Pale face no account; de chief Judge say
                        dat nigger superior race down Souf, and I guess he know."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chinese</emph>--"How much monish you got? You work now?"</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Negro</emph>--"Catch dis nigger working now. Yah, yah, no
                        sah, dis child under de protection of de Government--Yah, yah, work; yah
                        yah. Look yeah you China man, we gwine to vote now we niggers, you China men
                        and you Injuns belong to the 'ferior race, and dese white men no 'count
                        tall. You just wait till Fred Douglass is de President, den you see who's de
                        'ferior race."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Indian</emph>--"My tribe fight for the pale face in the
                        army of the great chief Pope, we have much farm, little Injun go to school,
                        me go to see the great Father Lincoln, me no vote. Ugh!"</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chinese</emph>--"Me see great Mandarin American man in
                        the great empire of ze sun; he say much fine thing; me come to America land,
                        me like America land; China man no vote; me see African man vote; he no
                        Mandarin; American man come to his country; Injun man fight for Merica land
                        he no vote."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Negro</emph>--"Yah! yah! you don't know noffin tall;
                        don't you see de declaration independence don't mean you folks; it means
                        consent of the governed, don't you see; and we niggers don't give our seat,
                        dats de ting; massa Sumner told me dat hisseff."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Indian</emph>--"Ugh! me fight pale face--Ugh! ugh! ugh!
                        (with a war whoop.")</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chinese</emph>--"Me no consent, me steal much."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Negro</emph>--"Yah! yah! yah! You go long; you no 'count
                        tall."</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Exeunt Omnes</emph>
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reprints an article from the Boston Post ridiculing the idea of
                    voting rights for African Americans, Asians and Native Americans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.08.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The time is approaching when the people of Virginia will be called upon to
                        select persons to represent them in Congress and the General Assembly. As
                        was the case in the various elections for County and municipal officers, in
                        regard to the reorganization of the State, if we elect men who will not be
                        allowed to take their seats, we retard for a time the restoration of the
                        State in the Union, and besides, the radicals will again imagine they have
                        something to rail against. There are good loyal men in our midst,
                        unexceptionable to any one, who are qualified to represent us and who will
                        most assuredly be allowed admission to their respective bodies. These are
                        the men from among whom we must make our selections if we desire the
                        restoration of law and order here and the speedy resumption of our place as
                        one of the United States. This course will relieve us of many drawbacks
                        incident to the present disordered state of affairs and will also silence
                        the tongues of the radicals, by disarming them of the only argument they
                        have attempted to use against us to prove that we are disloyal still, not
                        having yielded in good faith, and that we have sworn and subscribed to the
                        oaths of Allegiance and Amnesty with a mental reservation. Therefore we
                        suggest that the August Court, Monday 28th inst., when there will be a good
                        a representation from all portions of the County present, affording a fine
                        opportunity for a general interchange of sentiments, that a ticket be
                        arranged which will be acceptable to the people generally and
                        unexceptionable to the authorities.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges that the voters select "good loyal men . . .
                    unexceptionable to the authorities" in the upcoming congressional elections.
                    Doing so will deny ammunition to radical Republicans which could be used to deny
                    southern representatives their seats in congress and readmission to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hirsh</ln>
                        <fn>Gabriel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loeb</ln>
                        <fn>Leo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article reports an attempted night-time burglary of the store of Mr.
                    Gabriel Hirsh by "Robert Williams, a negro boy, from Covington." Williams'
                    actions aroused Mr. Leo Loeb, who slept in a room above the store. Loeb snuck
                    downstairs and fired several shots with a pistol, one of which struck Williams
                    in the breast. Williams ran upstairs and leapt out a window to escape. He was
                    arrested the following day and committed to jail for trial after giving "several
                    conflicting accounts of the manner in which he received the wound," and
                    subsequently confessing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that the officers elected for the Corporation of
                    Staunton have qualified, and civil cases within the jurisdiction of the court
                    have been turned over to it by the military authorities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Jas. Gibson "was arrested and brought before the
                    Mayor" for "stealing a watch from a negro man." He was sent to jail to await
                    trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fagan</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickinson</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James Fagan and Miss Mary E. Pearson, both of Staunton, were married at
                    the Baptist Church by Rev. A. L. Dickinson on August 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>M. Thompson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. M. Thompson McClure and Miss Kate Bumgardner, both of Augusta County,
                    were married in Greenville by the Rev. Dr. McFarland on July 27th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesell</ln>
                        <fn>Bardary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Henry Crist and Mrs. Bardary A. Whitesell, of Mint Spring, Augusta
                    County, were married at the Wesleyan Female Institute, Staunton, by the Rev. J.
                    C. Dice on August 10th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
