<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0530"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0530">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John Miller,
                    1871, Claim No. 2544</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john miller, 1871 claim no 2544</title>
        <author>Miller, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 23 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0530</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498417</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John Miller, 1871,
                            Claim No. 2544</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john miller, 1871 claim no 2544</title>
            <author>John Miller</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #2544</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Home Front, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0530T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>John Miller filed this claim in 1871 for $590, claiming Union forces under
                    General Sheridan took four horses in 1864. John was a 57 year old minister of
                    the Dunker Church and a farmer. He gave money to help others flee to Union lines
                    and sent his own son to the Union in 1862. The commission allowed $500.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Large Iron Grey horse</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$130.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bay Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$140.00</cell>
                            <cell>$120.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Two Iron Gray Mares</cell>
                            <cell>$300.00</cell>
                            <cell>$250.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimant is a Preacher of the Dunkard Denomination, and lived on his farm in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> Virginia from which the property for
                    which he claims Compensation was taken.</p>
                <p>The loyalty of Claimant is established by his own statement, and the testimony of
                    two or three witnesses. He sent his son North to keep him out of the the Rebel
                    Army and assisted Union men and soldiers to escape to the Union lines.</p>
                <p>The horses were taken the 29<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of Sept 1864 by
                    Soldiers of Gen Sheridan's Command, and we allow for them the sum of Five
                    hundred dollars.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>John Yates and John Wampler</byline>
                <p>We the undersigned Loyal Citizens of Augusta County Virginia do hereby certify on
                    Oath that we have known the claimant John Miller for many years and know him to
                    have been Loyal to the Government of the United States before and at the time
                    and since the taking of the poperty and supplies in the claimants petition
                    mentioned.</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed to before me this 29<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    of April 1871 H. G. McCausland MP</p>
                <p><name type="witness">John Yates</name>, <name type="witness">John Wampler</name>
                    Mt Sidney</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>John Miller</byline>
                <p>United States of America, State of Virginia, S.S.</p>
                <p>J. W. G. Riley, a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioners
                    appointed under the Act of Congress, of March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi>,
                    1871, to take and record testimony. Do hereby certify that the reason for taking
                    the following depositions is, and the fact is, the Matter of claim of John
                    Miller Vs. the United States of America, and the witneeses herein named, being
                    first duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness Says-I am 57 years old, I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and am
                    a minister and farmer <hi rend="super">by</hi> occupation. I resided in
                    the same County for the 6 months prior to April 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>
                    1861 and have not changed my residence since 1846.</p>
                <p>3<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says-I never passed beyond the military or
                    Naval lines of the United States and entered the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never took any oath of allegiance
                    to the Confederate States. I was asked to do so, but refused.</p>
                <p>5<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I took an Amnesty oath in 1865, at
                    Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I never asked for a pardon from the
                    President.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never was in any way connected
                    with the civil service of the so called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never held any office or place of
                    trust, honor or profit in the Confederate States Government, or any of its
                    States or territories. I held no clerkship or had any agency or employment of
                    any kind.</p>
                <p>9<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never was in any capacity in the
                    Military or Naval service of the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>10<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never was in any manner or form
                    in the Army or Navy of the Confederacy. I furnished no substitute. I had nothing
                    to do with any department or bureau of the Confederate Government. Nor had
                    charge of stores, or supplies, wagons, teams, trains vessels or munitions of
                    war, for the Confederate Government Army or Navy.</p>
                <p>11<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never was in any way connected
                    with the Army or Navy of the Confederacy. I never furnished any supplies or
                    property of any kind to the Army, Navy, <orig reg="Militia">Malitia</orig>,
                    Homeguards or any other way. I never give any information.</p>
                <p>12<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I was no way engaged or employed,
                    in the manufacture of munitions of war for the Confederate Army or Navy.</p>
                <p>13<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says I have never been in any way
                    engaged in the Collection of any stores, supplies or any article for the use and
                    benefit of the so-called Confederacy.</p>
                <p>14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never was engaged in blockade
                    running or intercourse between the lines. Nor engaged in the trade or <orig
                        reg="traffic">traffick</orig> of blockade goods.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Say-I did not leave the Confederate
                    States between the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> April 1861 and the 19<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> June 1865.</p>
                <p>16<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never had any interest in any
                    Boat or vessel used in navigating the Ocean to or from <del hand="h1">the</del> any port
                    of the Confederacy, or any of its waters.</p>
                <p>17<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never was arrested by either the
                    Confederate or United States Government.</p>
                <p>18<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-The Confederate Authorities took
                    one horse from me and Corn on several occasions. I think I received pay in
                    Confederate funds.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I was threatened with being driven
                    away, on account of my Union Sentiments. I never was molested otherwise.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness Says, I never contributed any thing
                    except to furnish money to aid some soldiers and citizens to get into the Union
                    lines. I also sent my son into the Union lines, in 1862, and he remained in the
                    North and West until after the Close of the War.</p>
                <p>23<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, I had no near relatives in either
                    Army.</p>
                <p>24<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I have never owned any Confederate
                    Bonds. Nor voluntarily done anything to support the Credit of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>25<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I <orig reg="gave">give</orig> no
                    aid or comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I never was engaged in making
                    raids into the United States from Canada, or in the destruction of the Commerce
                    of the United States.</p>
                <p>27<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I never held in custody any person
                        taken<del hand="h1">g</del> and held as prisoners of the War, or otherwise.</p>
                <p>28<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I never was a member of any
                    Society or Association for the purpose of imprisoning or persecution of any
                    person because of their loyalty to the United States.</p>
                <p>29<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I never was <hi rend="super"
                        >a</hi> paroled prisoner of the United States.</p>
                <p>30<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says I never held any office in the
                    United States, nor educated at any Military or Naval school.</p>
                <p>31<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness Say, I received no pass, except when at
                    Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I had to get one to reach my home. I
                    took no oath to obtain it.</p>
                <p>32<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, I never was under any disabilities
                    imposed by any article of the Constitution. I have held no Office since the war.</p>
                <p>33<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, My sympathies were all the time
                    with the Union, and not the rebellion. I voted for the Ordinance of Secession,
                    which I have regretted all the time, but was deceived <del hand="h1">by</del> into it.
                    After the Ordinance was adopted I adhered to the Union and against the State.</p>
                <p>34<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I do solemnly declare that from
                    the beginning of hostilities against the United States to the end thereof my
                    sympathies were in favor of the Union Cause, and that I never done or sought to
                    do anything to retard its success, and was willing at all times ready and
                    willing to aid and assist said Cause, so far as my mean and power and the
                    circumstances of the case permitted.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. September 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John Miller</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 11th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Peter S. Miller</byline>
                <p>Peter S. Miller, introduced to prove the taking of property named in the
                    claimants petition and being duly sworn Answers as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness say, I am 22 years old, I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and by
                    occupation a farmer. I was present and saw all the property named in the
                    petition taken.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, The property was taken on the 29<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> September 1864, it was taken from the claimants
                    farm, and was taken by <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super"
                    >l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan's Army. The claimants family were preent at the taking.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, There was Captain present, I did
                    not know his name, he belonged to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan's command. The Captain
                    ordered it to be taken.</p>
                <p>7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, Two of the horses were taken out of
                    the stable, and the other two from the lot at the house. One of the Mares was
                    rode away by the Captain, and the others by the soldiers. The horses were taken
                    in the direction of the Camp at Mt. Sidney. They were not followed.</p>
                <p>10<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, I do not know the use for which
                    the property was taken. I did not see the property after it was removed from the
                    premises. The Claimant complained to the Officer. The Captain said he could not
                    help it, that he was obliged to take them.</p>
                <p>12<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-There was no receipt given or asked
                    for. The property was taken in the day time, between 11 Oclock A.M. and 3 P.M.</p>
                <p>14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, The Army was encamped at Mt.
                    Sidney, about One mile away. It only remained a part of a day. I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> think there had been any battle or skirmish near
                    there.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, The horses were all in good
                    condition and order. The gray horse was 6 years old, he was worth $165. One bay
                    Mare was 5 years old, worth $150.00. The grey Mares were 4 years old, and worth
                    $320-$160 each.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I think the property was taken for
                    the use of the Army and not for gratification.</p>
                <p>20<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I suppose the horses were for the
                    use of the Army.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness Says-I think there was such a necessity
                    as justified the officer in taking them.</p>
                <p>22<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, I believe there was such a
                    necessity in the Army, that justified the taking and that the Government should
                    pay for them.</p>
                <p>23<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, The Captain said he had orders to
                    take them. Further this deponent saith not. September 11<hi rend="super"
                        >th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Peter S. Miller</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 11 day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Joseph Click</byline>
                <p>Joseph Click a witness introduced by claimant to prove his loyalty to the United
                    States Government being duly sworn Answers as follows.</p>
                <p>1st Witness says-I am 52 years old, I reside in Augusta Co. Va. and am a farmer
                    by occupation. I have known the claimant Rev. Jno. Miller, about 30 years. I
                    live 1/2 mile from him. I saw him very frequently during the War, and talked
                    with him about the war, and believe he was <del hand="h1">a</del> strictly loyal to the
                    United States, and opposed to Secession, and his neighbors both Union and rebel
                    so regarded him. I know of nothing except to send his son and others through to
                    the Union lines. I never knew him to do anything for the Confederacy or
                    rebellion except what he was compelled to do.</p>
                <p>He intended had the Confederate States, gained its independence to remove to the
                    West, and not remain in the Confederacy. He could not have shown any claim of
                    loyalty to the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. September 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Joseph Click</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> day
                    Sept. 71.</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> U States Commissioner and Special Comr for
                    State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>John Wampler</byline>
                <p>John Wampler, a witness introduced to prove the loyalty of the claimant being
                    duly sworn Answers as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness Says, I am 43 years old, I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and a
                    farmer by occupation. I have known the claimant 30 years. I live less than One
                    mile from him. I saw him often during the war, and talked with him about the
                    war. I always heard him speak against the rebellion and in favor of the Union,
                    his neighbors regarded him as a true loyal man. He is a Minister in the Dunkard
                    Church. He never done anything for the United States, that I know of except to
                    send his son into the Union lines. He done nothing for the Rebellion but what he
                    was forced to do. He was too good a Union man to have established any claim of
                    loyalty to the Confederacy had it been successful.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. September 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Wampler</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 11th day of Sept 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">W G Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
