<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0543"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0543">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Simon Stickley,
                    August 22, 1871, Claim No. 978</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of simon stickley, august 22 1871 claim no 978</title>
        <author>Stickley, Simon</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 11 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0543</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498430</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Simon Stickley,
                            August 22, 1871, Claim No. 978</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of simon stickley, august 22 1871 claim no 978</title>
            <author>Simon Stickley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche #506</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0543T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Simon Stickley filed this claim in 1872 for $135, claiming the Union army under
                    General Hunter's command took one horse in 1864. Stickley was a 32 year old
                    farmer who was arrested once by Confederate authorities. He failed to answer
                    questions 10 to 13 and only one neighbor testified to his loyalty. The claim was
                    disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One horse</cell>
                            <cell>$135.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$135.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimant swears only to his loyal sympathies. He did not vote at all on the
                    Ordinance of Secession and does not answer questions from 9 to 14 in printed
                    list.</p>
                <p>He calls but one Witness to Confirm his claim to loyalty. And without going into
                    any specific statements he says I always considered Claimant loyal and he was so
                    regarded by his neighbors.</p>
                <p>We reject this claim.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Simon Stickley</byline>
                <p>United States of America</p>
                <p>State of Virginia</p>
                <p>I, W.G. Riley, a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioner of
                    Claims appointed under the Act of Congress of March 3, 1871 to take and record
                    testimony Do hereby certify that the reason for takng the following depositions
                    is and the fact is the matter of Claim of Simon Stickley vs. the United States
                    of America and the witness herein named being the first duly sworn answereth as
                    follows -</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness Says - I am thirty two years old I live in Augusta County Va by
                    occupation a farmer. I have resided where I do now for ten years.</p>
                <p>3 Witness Says - I never passed beyond the Military or Naval lines of the United
                    States and entered the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4 Witness Says - I never took and oath to the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5 Witness Says - I have taken an amnesty oath. I took it after the was ended. I
                    have never been pardoned by the president.</p>
                <p>6 Witness Says - I never was in any manner connected with the civil service of
                    the Confederate States - I never held any office, under the Confederate
                    Government.</p>
                <p>8 Witness Says - I never held any clerkship or office of any kind or done
                    anything whatever for the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>9 Witness Says - I never was in any capacity in the Military or Naval service of
                    the Confederacy. I have never done anything directly or indirectly for the
                    Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>14 Witness Says - I never was engaged in blockade running or anything of the
                    sort.</p>
                <p>15 Witness Says - I did not leave the Confederate States between the 19th of
                    April 1861 and the 19th of April 1865.</p>
                <p>16 Witness Says - I never owned any vessel. I never had any interest in any
                    vessel.</p>
                <p>17 Witness Says - I was arrested in 1864 by the Confederate Government, where I
                    now reside. I don't know who arrested me. I took no oath to be released. I never
                    was arrested by the United States Government.</p>
                <p>18 Witness Says - I had some corn, bacon and a horse taken by the Confederate
                    authorities. I don't recollect of being paid at all.</p>
                <p>20 Witness Says - I was threatened or injured or molested on account of my union
                    sentiments.</p>
                <p>21 Witness Says - I contributed no money or property in aid of the United States
                    Government.</p>
                <p>23 Witness Says - I had no relatives in either the Union or Confederate Armies
                    that I know of.</p>
                <p>24 Witness Says - I have never owned any Confederate bonds, I have never
                    contributed to support the credit of the so called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>25 Witness Says - I have never given aid or comfort to the Rebellion.</p>
                <p>26 Witness Says - I never was engaged in making raids into the Unted States from
                    Canada.</p>
                <p>27 Witness Says - I never was engaged directly or indirectly in holding in
                    custody any persons taken by the Confederate Government as prisoners of war.</p>
                <p>28 Witness Says - I never persecuted any person on account of their loyalty to
                    the United States.</p>
                <p>29 Witness Says - I never was a <orig reg="paroled">parolled</orig> prisoner of
                    the United States</p>
                <p>30 Witness Says - I have never held any office, in the army or Navy of the United
                    States. I was not educated at West Point nor at the Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>31 Witness Says - I did receive a pass from the Confederate Government, but I did
                    not use it for any purpose.</p>
                <p>32 Witness Says - I am under no disabilities. I have never held any office under
                    the United States Government since the war.</p>
                <p>33 Witness Says - At the beginning of the Rebellion I sympathized with the Union
                    and not with the rebellion. I not vote at all on the Ordinance of Secession.</p>
                <p>34 Witness Says - I declare that from the beginning of hostilities against the
                    United States to the end thereof, I was constantly with the cause of the United
                    States, and was willing to aid the Union at all times as far as I was able and
                    further the deponent saith not August 22nd 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Simon Stickley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>George Welch</byline>
                <p>George Welch a witness introduced by Simon Stickley the claimant to prove
                    property being first duly sworn answereth as follows</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness Says - I am seventy two years old. I live in Augusta County Va,
                    by occupation a farmer. I saw the property mentioned in the claimant's petition
                    taken.</p>
                <p>4 Witness Says - The property was taken in 1864. It was taken from my farm the
                    horse was hired there, the property was taken by the soliders.</p>
                <p>6 Witness Says - The Colonel was there at my house. I don't know to what regiment
                    he belonged, but he was under the command of <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>.
                    Hunter.</p>
                <p>8 Witness Says - The horse was removed by soldiers.</p>
                <p>9 Witness Says - The horse removed to Staunton.</p>
                <p>11 Witness Says - No complaint was made on account of such taking.</p>
                <p>12 Witness Says - No receipt was given and none was asked for.</p>
                <p>13 Witness Says - The horse was taken about twelve o'clock in the day time.</p>
                <p>15 Witness Says - He was very nice good and fat he was three years old and worth
                    one hundred and thirty five dollars, what the claimant has charged.</p>
                <p>19 Witness Says - I suppose that the horse was taken for the use of the United
                    States Army, and not for individual use, and by some one who had authority to
                    take it and I think it was taken for some purpose so useful as to warrant the
                    Government to pay for it and further the deponent saith not. August the 22nd
                    1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">George Welch</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Daniel Fishburn</byline>
                <p>Daniel Fishburn a witness introduced by the claimant for proof as to his loyalty
                    being first duly sworn answereth as follows -</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness Says - I am fifty one years old. I reside in Augusta County Va. by
                    occupation a farmer. I have known the Claimant for twenty years. I lived near
                    him, and saw him often during the war. I always considered him loyal to the
                    United States Government. He was so considered by his neighbors. I had frequent
                    conversations with him, and I think he was too loyal to the United States
                    Government to have been considered loyal to the Confederacy if it had been
                    maintained as a separate Government. I have never known him to aid the
                    rebellion. And further the deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Daniel Fishburn</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn &amp; subscribed before me this 22nd day of August 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
