<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0518"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0518">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Mary Blackburn,
                    1875, Claim No. 1378</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of mary blackburn, 1875 claim no 1378</title>
        <author>Blackburn, Mary</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 28 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0518</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498405</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Mary Blackburn, 1875,
                            Claim No. 1378</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of mary blackburn, 1875 claim no 1378</title>
            <author>Mary Blackburn</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #1378</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1875">1875</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Home Front, Patriotism, Race Relations, Slavery, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0518T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Mary Blackburn filed this claim in 1875 for $476, claiming the Union army took
                    two horses, two cattle, bacon, flour, a saddle, and two bridles in 1864. Mary
                    was a 45 year old former slave whose freedom was bought by her first husband
                    John Patrick. Included is testimony from four African Americans, including
                    Mary's second husband Samuel, and her previous owner Henry Mish. The commission
                    allowed $355.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Two horses @ 150. each</cell>
                            <cell>$300.00</cell>
                            <cell>$250.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Two head of Cattle 40.</cell>
                            <cell>$80.00</cell>
                            <cell>$60.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>300 lbs. bacon @ 25c per lb.</cell>
                            <cell>$75.00</cell>
                            <cell>$35.00</cell>
                            <cell>$40.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bl. of flour</cell>
                            <cell>$10.00</cell>
                            <cell>$10.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Saddle</cell>
                            <cell>$7.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$7.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Two Bridles @ 2.00</cell>
                            <cell>$4.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$4.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The claimant is a colored women and was the wife of John Patrick during the war,
                    he was a free man and bought her from her owner; they were industrious and
                    well-to-do and were well known friends of the Union. The property charged
                    belonged to John Patrick and was taken during his lifetime, by command of <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr><unclear>Averall</unclear> in June 1864. The
                    widow his present Claimant left no known kin. She has marrried since his death,
                    Blackburn who was a Union soldier during the war.</p>
                <p>All the facts in support of the claim are satisfactorially established by several
                    witnesses. It is proved that the horses and cows were good, and in good
                    condition when taken. We allow the sum of three hundred and fifty-five dollars.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name>, and
                        <name type="other">Orange Ferris</name><abbr expan="Commissioners"
                    >Comrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Samuel Blackburn</byline>
                <p>United States of America, State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p>J.W.G. Riley, a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioners of
                    Claims appointed under the Act of Congress of March 3<hi rend="super"
                    >d</hi> 1871 to take and record testimony. Do hereby certify that the reason for
                    taking the following deposition is and the fact is the matter of claim of Mary
                    Blackburn Colored vs. the United States of America and the witnesses herein
                    named being first duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>Samuel Blackburn, <hi rend="super">(Colored)</hi> a Witness</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I am 38 years old, I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> by
                    occupation a farmer. I have resided in this County for 28 years.</p>
                <p>3<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says-I did not pass the United States
                    military lines and enter the Confederate lines.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never took any oath to the
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I have taken the Amnesty Oath in
                    Augusta County, in 1866. I never was pardoned by the President.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never done anything for the rebel
                    states except as forced.</p>
                <p>7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never held any office place of
                    trust, profit or honor in the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>8<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness say being a colored man I never done
                    anything for the Confederate Government, Army or Navy.</p>
                <p>14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness say I never was engaged in blockade
                    running.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I was not out of the State of <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> at any time.</p>
                <p>16<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was in any way interested
                    in the navigation of any vessel to or from any port of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was arrested by the
                    Confederates, nor by the <abbr expan="United">U.</abbr> States Government.</p>
                <p>18<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I had some clothes taken by the
                    Confederates and received no pay therefor.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I was threatened with beings shot
                    because of my <orig reg="principles">principals</orig>. I never was molested.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I have never contributed anything
                    except about 2 1/2 months labor in <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Sheridan's
                    Army, and with <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Burney at Hatcher's run, near
                    Petersburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p>23 Witness says I had no relatives in either army to my knowledge.</p>
                <p>24<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never owned any Confederate Bonds
                    or interest therein. Nor did any thing to support the credit of the Confederate
                    States. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> aid to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was engaged in making raids
                    into the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> from Canada, or in the
                    destruction of Commerce.</p>
                <p>27<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was engaged in holding in
                    custody any person as prisoner of war.</p>
                <p>28<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never belonged to any society for
                    the expulsion or persecution of any persons, because of their loyalty to the
                    United States.</p>
                <p>29<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was paroled by the United
                    States.</p>
                <p>30<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never held any office and being a
                    colored man I have no education.</p>
                <p>31<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I never received any pass from the
                    Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>32<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I had no disabilites.</p>
                <p>33<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I was a Union man all my days. I had
                    no vote.</p>
                <p>34<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I have always been for the United
                    States, and ready at all times to aid her cause.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. September 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Samuel Blackburn</name> his mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Adelaide Hunter</byline>
                <p>Adelaide Hunter, <orig reg="colored">colered</orig> woman, a witness introduced
                    by claimant to prove the taking of the property named in the petition, being
                    duly sworn as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I am 53 years sold. I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I am
                    house keeper. I <del hand="h1">have</del> was present when the property named in the
                    petition was taken. I saw it taken. There were two horses, two Cows, One barrel
                    of Flour, the Bacon of 3 Hogs, two Bridles and One Saddle. I suppose the hogs
                    weighed about 150 <abbr expan="pounds">lbs</abbr> each.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the property was taken in June 1864
                    from the claimants premises in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> by officers and soldiers of the United States
                    Army under Command of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter. An officer
                    ordered the soldiers to take the property.</p>
                <p>7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the soldiers <orig reg="came"
                    >come</orig> in and took the property.</p>
                <p>8<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the horses were rode and led away,
                    and the Cows were driven. They carried the flour and Bacon away on their
                    shoulders.</p>
                <p>9<hi rend="bold">th</hi> Witness says they were encamped about 1/2 mile away,
                    where they took property too.</p>
                <p>10<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says they said they wanted the property
                    to help in breaking down the rebellion, and I suppose it was used for that
                    purpose. I never saw it afterwards.</p>
                <p>11<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says there was no complaint made to any
                    officer.</p>
                <p>12<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says there was no receipt asked for or
                    given that I know of.</p>
                <p>13<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the property was taken in the day
                    time, publicly between 10 A.M. and evening.</p>
                <p>14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says there was no encampment near,
                    except for a few hours when they moved and camped for one night about 3 miles
                    from claimants. There had been no battle or skirmish near. I knew none of the
                    officers at all.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says The one was 6 years old and in good
                    condition and worth $150.00. The other was about 9 years old, also in condition
                    and worthy fully $150.00. The Cows were worth $35.00 &amp; 25$ or $60 for
                    both. I do not know what the flour was worth. I suppose the Bacon was worth
                    about 25 cents a pound. The bridles were worth $1.00 a piece and the saddle
                    about $10.00 the property was all good and I think fully worth my valuation.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I would think the property was
                    taken for the Army and not for private use.</p>
                <p>20<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says-I suppose they needed the articles
                    of property.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says-I think they needed what they took.</p>
                <p>22<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says-I think there was such a necessity
                    as to justify and require the Government to pay for the property.</p>
                <p>23<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I think the officers and soldiers
                    were acting under orders in taking the property.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. Sept. 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Adelaide Hunter</name> her mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>William Poindexter</byline>
                <p>William Poindexter, <orig reg="colored">colered</orig> man introduced to prove
                    the loyalty of claimant, being duly sworn, answers and follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I am 47 years old. I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virgina">Va.</abbr> I am by
                    occupation a laborer I have known the claimant for 15 years. I saw her
                    frequently during the war, and after talked about the war, and I am fully
                    satisfied that the claimant was in sympathy entirely with the Union cause, and
                    she was so regarded by the neighbors. Had no <orig reg="opportunity"
                    >oppertunity</orig> to do anything for the Union cause, and done nothing for the
                    Confederates, except what was forced.</p>
                <p>I am satisfied that in sympathy she would constantly adhered to the Union cause,
                    &amp; against the Confederates. Being <orig reg="colored">colered</orig>,
                    regarded the cause of the Union, as her friend.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>Sept 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871. <name type="witness">William
                        Poindexter</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to subscriber before me this 6th day of Sept 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WJ Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Mary Blackburn</byline>
                <p>1. My name is Mary Blackburn, but at the time my property was taken it was Mary
                    Patrick. My age is about 45 years my residence near Middlebrook in Augusta
                    County. I have resided at the same place about four years. I am a house keeper.</p>
                <p>2. I am the claimant, but the property was taken in the life time of my first
                    husband John Patrick, who died in 1867 or 1868, &amp; who purchased me from
                    Henry Mish. I am the mother of three children all by my first husband, and all
                    of them sold to traders whilst I was in slavery. I have never heard from them
                    since, and know not where they are or whether dead or living.</p>
                <p>4. I resided with my husband, in the same neighborhood for the six months
                    previous to the beginning of the war. I lived with my deceased husband all the
                    time of the War, and in the same neighborhood.</p>
                <p>5. I was in favor of the Union cause.</p>
                <p>6. I never did anything in word or act against the Union cause.</p>
                <p>7. I felt a willingness to help the cause of the Union at all times, because of
                    the manner in which my children were torn from me.</p>
                <p>8. I had no <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig>.</p>
                <p>9. I had no relations in the Union Army.</p>
                <p>10. I was not and I never made a contribution of any kind.</p>
                <p>12. If I did anything it was on the Union side. I was in my feelings with the
                    Union.</p>
                <p>14. I always felt glad when the Union army whipped.</p>
                <p>15. I had none.</p>
                <p>16. I took no oath.</p>
                <p>17. W.D. Henry, Jacob Carwell, &amp; Michael Carwell, &amp; Henry Mish
                    all of that neighborhood.</p>
                <p>18. I was never threatened at all and never arrested.</p>
                <p>20. The Confederates took a horse, it was taken by <abbr expan="General"
                    >Genl.</abbr> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Causland's troops. I had no other
                    property taken by the confederates.</p>
                <p>22. I never did anything that I know of.</p>
                <p>24. I was in no service of the Confederacy, military or civil. I never took any
                    oath.</p>
                <p>27. I never had charge of goods or stores of the Confederate army or Government,
                    or any share or interest. I never was engaged in any blockade or other trade or
                    business.</p>
                <p>30. I had nothing to loan or subscribe, and I never contributed anything to
                    raising or equipping troops or anything else.</p>
                <p>32. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> any information. I belonged to no
                    society or organization. I took no oath. I never had a pass. I took no amnesty
                    oath I never was a prisoner of the United States.</p>
                <p>42. There were no fines levied against me. To questions from 44 &amp; 51
                    inclusive, I answer no.</p>
                <p>66. My husband John Patrick was the owner of the property when taken, he bought
                    the horses, one from <abbr expan="William">W<hi rend="super"
                    >m</hi>.</abbr> Basserman, near Middlebrook and the other from a man in Highland
                    County, whose name I have forgotten, and the Cow and heifer (2 years old) he
                    bought the cow and raised the heifer. We raised the hogs that made the bacon,
                    and bought the flour, and the Saddle &amp; bridles. We were living on rented
                    land, belonging to D. Baylor. I suppose there were 150 acres, about 50 acres in
                    timber. I have filed no petition bankruptcy.</p>
                <p>69. I am married, my husbands name is Samuel Blackburn, we were married in 1868,
                    December 31. My first husband John Patrick died in 1867 or '68, he was a Union
                    man. he made no will. I had as I have stated three children, hamed John F.
                    Patrick, Philip Patrick, &amp; George M. Patrick, they were sold to a trader
                    and carried off. I have no knowledge of them at all. My deceased husband did
                    nothing at all in aid of the rebellion. My children were quite young when sold.</p>
                <p>70. My husband bought me the year the War commenced, I think it was. I lived with
                    my husband who rented land and farmed, he had been a free man for about ten
                    years before he purchased me. he paid over one thousand dollars for me. I
                    belonged to Henry Mish. I am not in his debt or employment. If my children are
                    living would be interested. I suppose my present husband too.</p>
                <p>72. I was present and saw the property taken. The horses were taken from the
                    field and bridled at the house, and the saddle put on at the same time and rode
                    away. The Cattle were in the Meadow close to the house, where the soldiers went
                    and brought it down, and carried it to their Camp a short distance from my house
                    and the flour out of the house. The property was all taken in day light. The
                    Army came about 9 oclock A.M. and left in the afternoon.</p>
                <p>74. There was no complaint made, by husband was sick at the time. I told one of
                    them that I thought he might leave me a little flour. I knew no names of any
                    soldier or officer, and did not ask for a receipt. I have never received any pay
                    nor did my husband, ever ask or try to get any in his life time.</p>
                <p>77. The Army was in camp, near my house for a part of the day. They came from the
                    West and crossed the Mountain from Pond Gap to Summerdean, and when they left
                    they started in the direction of Staunton. The Army was in command of General
                    Averall, but generally known as <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter's, and
                    it was in June 1864. There had been no battle in that vicinity.</p>
                <p>79. The horses were in good condition, and of good quality, one was a young horse
                    and the other not old. They worked and rode well, and of good size. I think they
                    were worth one hundred and fifty dollars each. The Cattle were fat, and from
                    their size, they cow being very large and the heifer very large too. I think
                    they were worty fifty dollars, and thirty dollars. The bacon was averaged by the
                    weight of the hogs when killed, which was 150 <hi rend="super">lbs</hi>
                    each for two and 100 <hi rend="super">lbs</hi> for the third, and we had
                    used but little of the bacon, we had none but us two in family. Flour was worth
                    ten dollars in good money. The Saddle was some worn and the bridles were very
                    good. I do not know whether an officer was present or not. They were in camp in
                    our meadow.</p>
                <p><name type="claimant">Mary Blackburn</name><orig reg="her">his</orig> mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Michael Carwell</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Michael Carwell</p>
                <p>My name is Michael Carwell, my age is 63 years. My residence near Middlebrook in
                    Augusta County, my occupation a farmer. I have no interest directly or
                    indirectly in the claim and in no way related.</p>
                <p>52. I testify in behalf of the claimant.</p>
                <p>53. I have known the claimant for about fifteen years, and knew her intimately
                    during the war, and always found her willing and ready to do all she could for
                    the Union cause. She would receive and conceal provisions &amp;c for persons
                    who were making their escape from the rebel army through the lines. She could be
                    depended on, and her deceased husband John Patrick, whom I knew intimately was a
                    faithful co-worker. They were free, Patrick having purchased hiw wife, the
                    claimant in this casee, and they were past common for their industry and economy
                    and regarded by all strictly honest, by their industry &amp;c they made
                    money and saved it. I was a Union man myself, and always felt safe in confiding
                    in them, and trust my secrets and plans with them. I have known them to be
                    threatened by rebels, because of their intimacy with Union men and because they
                    were suspected for harboring Union men and provisions.</p>
                <p>I was not present and did not see the property taken, but I do know that they had
                    such property and the morning after the Army passed their property was gone.
                    They told me that the Union Army commanded by General Averall or Crooks, who had
                    crossed the Mountain from Pond Gap to Summerdean, had taken their property, and
                    I believe they did. I never saw the property afterwards. There is no doubt that
                    the property really belonged to them and no one <hi rend="super">else</hi>
                    white or <orig reg="colored">colered</orig> had any interest in the property.
                    John Patrick was a farmer and made money at it. The horses were really good
                    animals young and strong farm horses. I think they were worth one hundred and
                    fifty a piece. I do not know what the cattle were worth, but suppose sixty or
                    seventy dollars, bacon was selling at 25 cents in good money and flour ten
                    dollars per barrel in good money.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">M Carwell</name>
                </p>
                <p>I will add that I knew Samuel Blackburn the present husband of the claimant,
                    during the War, he was a slave, belonging to John Randolph of Albemarle County,
                    he went off with the Union Army, and remained until after the close of the war.
                    I have no doubt of his loyalty, his reputation is that of an honest man.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">M Carwell</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Henry Mish</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Henry Mish</p>
                <p>My name is Henry Mish, my age is 62 years my residence near Middlebrook in August
                    County. My occupation a farmer. I have no beneficial interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>I testify in behalf of the claimant.</p>
                <p>53. I have known the claimant Mary Blackburn, since 1837. She was my servant for
                    twenty years. I got her with my wife, and sold her to her husband John Patrick
                    deceaseed in 1869. He was a free man, and had been for a number of years.</p>
                <p>54. They lived about one mile from me.</p>
                <p>55. I saw them frequently sometimes, two or three times a week.</p>
                <p>56. From all I heard them say and do, I regarded him and the claimant as in every
                    way loyal to the Union.</p>
                <p>57. I do not know of anything, of myself but heard from others that they did aid
                    persons who were trying to go through the lines.</p>
                <p>58. I know of nothing done by them against the Union. He was impressed at one
                    time to haul a load of supplies for the Confederate army, but he told me that if
                    done so again, they would have to tie him. The claimant I am satisfied never did
                    anything at all.</p>
                <p>60. I never heard anything against their loyalty to the Union, and believe that
                    the Union men of the neighborhood had confidence in them.</p>
                <p>61. Michael Carwell, Washington and Jacob Hess, John Engleman, &amp; <abbr
                        expan="George">Geo</abbr> Rubush, I think they all would testify to their
                    loyalty if called upon.</p>
                <p>62. I adhered to the Union myself and was treated as such by my rebel neighbors,
                    during the war and since, and the claimant &amp; her deceased husband knew I
                    was.</p>
                <p>63. John Patrick told me that he was threatened by some rebels.</p>
                <p>64. From my knowledge of them, I could not testify to their loyalty to the
                    Confederates, had they gained an independence. I was not present and did not see
                    the property taken, but I saw the horses and cattle at claimants house about an
                    hour before the Army arrived, and I know they were gone the next morning. They
                    told me that the Union army had taken them, and I believe they did, as I never
                    saw the property afterwards. The Army was in command of <abbr expan="General"
                        >Genl.</abbr> Averal and Crooks, and it was in June 1864. The horses were in
                    good condition and so were the cattle. The horses were young &amp; strong
                    and I think they worth One hundred and Seventy dollars each. I paid that, for
                    not as good. I would think the cattle were worth forty or forty five dollars a
                    piece. I know nothing of the other property charged, but believe they were too
                    honest to make a false charge. John Patrick <abbr expan="deceased">dec<hi
                            rend="super">d</hi>.</abbr> and the claimant, were of the most
                    honest and industrious character. Samuel Blackburn, present husband of the
                    claimant, is an honest upright man, and I believe loyal to the Union, I never
                    heard anything to the contrary. I know he is a working republican.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Henry Mish</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
