<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0139"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0139">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Amelia McCray,
                    September 14, 1871, Claim No. 6898</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of amelia mccray, september 14 1871 claim no 6898</title>
        <author>McCray, Amelia</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 13 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0139</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498364</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Amelia McCray,
                            September 14, 1871, Claim No. 6898</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of amelia mccray, september 14 1871 claim no 6898</title>
            <author>Amelia McCray</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington
                            D.C., fiche #63</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0139T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Amelia McCray claimed the value of three horses. The Commissioners rejected her
                    claim, designating her behavior during the war as neutral, rather than truly
                    loyal to the United States Government. There is some dispute in the historic
                    record as to whether McCray lived in Augusta County or Rockbridge County.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Mare 3 years old</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Mare 4 years old</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Grey Mare 9 years old</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$430.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$430.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Mrs M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cray has resided in Virginia over 40 years. Had
                    three sons in the Confederate Army. She made for one of her sons a suit of
                    clothes as she says to keep him from freezing. She says her sympathies were with
                    the Union. She felt she wanted nothing to do with the war any way.</p>
                <p>One witness James M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cutchan 66 years of age is called
                    to prove her loyalty. He has known her from childhood &amp; as far as he
                    knows she did not take an active part either way in the war. Did nothing for
                    either army. "Was regarded as opposed to the war being a lady she said nothing
                    either way."</p>
                <p>Giving the utmost force to her testimony Mrs M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cray
                    at best was but a neutral, a very fair record for a Virginia lady with three
                    sons in the Confederate Army. It is not enough to entitle her for compensation
                    for property taken for the use of the Union Army. The claim is rejected.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Amelia McCray</byline>
                <p>Before the Commissioners of Claims Under the Act of March 3, 1871</p>
                <p>Amelia M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cray vs. The United States</p>
                <p>On the 14th day of September 1871 at Staunton, Augusta County and State of
                    Virginia, personally came Amelia M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cray claimant and
                    James M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cutchan and Samuel Clemmer her witnesses in
                    a cause now pending before the Commissioners of Claims, in the name of Amelia
                    McCray vs the United States, before me a U.S. Commissioner, and also a Special
                    Commissioner appointed by the Commissioners of Claims.</p>
                <p>Present Amelia M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cray, claimant. The said claimant,
                    and each of said witnesses, were first before any questions were put to them,
                    properly and duly sworn to tell the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the
                    truth, relative to the matters in which they were to testify, and the testimony
                    of the claimant and said witnesses were taken down by me, in in my presenece;
                    and I read over the <hi rend="super">to</hi> said claimant and to each of
                    said witnesses their respective depositions; and the said depositions were duly
                    signed in my presence.</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> U.S. Commissioner And Special Commissioner</p>
                <p>Deposition of Amelia M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cray</p>
                <p>Ques 1st Answer. Witness Says, I am 62 years old. I reside in Rockbridge County,
                    Va. I am a house keeper. I have resided at the same place since the 1829, Never
                    having changed my residence.</p>
                <p>3 Witness Says, I never left my home during the War. I never took any oath or
                    affirmation to the Confederate Government. Never asked any pardon. I never took
                    the Amnesty Oath.</p>
                <p>7 Witness Says, I never held any place or done any service whatsoever for the
                    Confederate States, In any department, or bureau. I never <orig reg="gave"
                    >give</orig> any information to any Confederate Officer, or had <del hand="h1">it</del>
                    any thing to do with the Confederacy civil or Military. I never was engaged in
                    the manufacture of any article for the use of the Confederate Government, Army
                    or Navy.</p>
                <p>14. Witness Says I never had any interest in any goods brought into or exported
                    from the Confederate Ports. I never was arrested by either Government. I never
                    had any property taken by the Confederate authorities I never was threatened, or
                    molested by the Confederates.</p>
                <p>21 Witness Says I never contributed anything for the U.S. Government.</p>
                <p>22 Witness Says, I had three 3 sons in the Confederate Army. I had no relative in
                    the Union Army that I know of. I made one of my sons a suit of clothes to keep
                    him from freezing that was all.</p>
                <p>I never owned any Confederate Bonds, or did anything to support the credit of the
                    Confederacy. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> any aid and Comfort to the
                    rebellion.</p>
                <p>33 Witness Says, When the war commenced my sympathies were in favor of the Union
                    and remained so.</p>
                <p>34 Witness Says, My sympathies were with the Union Cause and I felt that I wanted
                    to have nothing to do with the War, in any way.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Amelia <orig reg="McCray">Mcray</orig></name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> September
                    1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for the State of Virginia</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>James McCutchan</byline>
                <p>Depositions of James M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cutchan to prove the loyalty
                    of the Claimant to the United States</p>
                <p>Ques. 1 Answer Witness Says, I am 66 years old, I reside in Augusta Co. Va. I
                    have known the Claimant from early childhood. As far as I know she did <hi
                        rend="super">not</hi> take an active part either way, in the war. I
                    never knew her to do anything to aid the Union or its Cause. She done nothing
                    for the Confederates, except what she was compelled to do.</p>
                <p>She was regarded as opposed to the war, being a lady she said nothing either way.</p>
                <p><del hand="h1">General</del> Interrogatory</p>
                <p>Ques. Do you know of other matters relative to this claim? If so state the same
                    fully.</p>
                <p>Answer. The Claimant said she would rather her sons had went with others to the
                    Union lines.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">James M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cutchan</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of
                    September 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> U.S. Commissioner and Special Com. for state
                    of Virginia</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Samuel Clemmer</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Samuel Clemmer to prove the taking &amp; furnishing of the
                    property</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 21 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a Farmer. I
                    was present &amp; saw the horses mentioned in the petition taken.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says: The horses were taken in June 1864 from claimants farm, by
                    Soldiers &amp; officers of Genl. Averills <abbr expan="command">Comd</abbr>.</p>
                <p>5 Witness says: The claimant, Mr. Henry Reed &amp; myself were present when
                    the property was taken</p>
                <p>6 Witness Says: I saw no officer present when the property was taken.</p>
                <p>7 Witness Says: The horese were taken by Soldiers of the Union Army, <abbr
                        expan="commanded">Comd.</abbr> by Genl. Averill.</p>
                <p>8 Witness Says: The property was rode off by Soldiers</p>
                <p>9 Witness says: The horses were taken along with them, the Army was marching
                    towards Lexington</p>
                <p>10 Witness says: I suppose the horses were taken for the use of the army.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says: The claimant made some complaint to the Soldiers. She thought
                    they ought to leave her one horse at any rate</p>
                <p>12 Witness says, There was no receipt asked for &amp; none given</p>
                <p>13 Witness says: The property was taken about 10'clock in the day. It was not
                    taken secretly.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says, When the property was taken, No part of the army was encamped in
                    that vicinity There had not been any battle or skirmish near. I did not know the
                        <abbr expan="Quarter">Qr.</abbr><abbr expan="Master">Mr.</abbr> or any of
                    them.</p>
                <p>15 Witnesss says: The horses were in nice condition. One <orig reg="dun"
                    >dunn</orig> mare was five years old, was worth $150.00. Another dun Mare, three
                    years old, was worth One hundred &amp; twenty five dollars. One grey mare,
                    eight years old, was worth One hundred &amp; forty dollars.</p>
                <p>19 Witness Says: I think the property was taken for the use of the army,
                    &amp; not for private use.</p>
                <p>20 Witness says: I suppose they were taken for the necessary use of the army.</p>
                <p>21 Witness says: I believe the necessity justified them in taking them.</p>
                <p>22 Witness says, I believe it was taken for some purpose so necessary as to
                    justify the Govt. in paying for it.</p>
                <p>23 Witness says: I believe the officers gave them orders to take it &amp;
                    further this deponent sayeth not</p>
                <p>Sept. 15th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">S.T. Clemmer</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>Archive Office, WAR DEPARTMENT, May 1, 1877</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 223. Case of Amelia M<hi rend="super"
                    >c</hi>Cray, Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>Bill &amp; foucher for one Dun Mare Sold to the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate States">CS</abbr> for the use of the Army valued at
                    $375.00</p>
                <p>Paid Novr. 30<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863, by R. Turk Asst QM C.S. Army
                    Signature on file.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
