<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0312"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0312">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Adam Fix, May
                    18, 1871, Claim No. 7011</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of adam fix, may 18 1871 claim no 7011</title>
        <author>Fix, Adam</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Ditigal History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 14 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0312</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498379</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Adam Fix, May 18,
                            1871, Claim No. 7011</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of adam fix, may 18 1871 claim no 7011</title>
            <author>Adam Fix</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche # 458</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0312T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Adam Fix filed this claim May 18, 1871, for $180, claiming that Union troops
                    confiscated 1 mare from his Augusta County farm. The claim was disallowed in
                    1872.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One dun mare</cell>
                            <cell>$180.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$180.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The Proofs in this case will not warrant in finding that the property was taken
                    for the use of the Union Army. But one witness gives any evidence on this branch
                    of the claim. He says he "did not see the horse taken from the field, but saw it
                    led away" &amp; further says it was taken from the farm of the claimant in
                    June 1864 by soldiers of the Union army under Gen. Hunter - no officer present
                    only soldiers - taken in the day time - The Army was not encamped near - no
                    skirmish nor battle near - They told me they were ordered to take it - excepting
                    the opinions &amp; conclusions of the witness, such is the substance of all
                    the testimony given by the witnesses - Soldiers pillaging or stealing if
                    discovered always said they were ordered to do it.</p>
                <p>If the property was taken legitimately &amp; <unclear>regularly</unclear> for
                    the use of the Army it is not proved &amp; the claim must be disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Adam Fix</byline>
                <p>Before the Commissioner of Claims, under Act of March 3, 1871</p>
                <p>Adam Fix vs. The United States</p>
                <p>On this fourteenth day of Sept. 1871, at Staunton in the County of Augusta and
                    State of Virginia, personally came Adam Fix claimant and Jno. G. Troxall
                    &amp; Jno. Buchanan his witnesses, in a cause now pending before the
                    commissioners of claims in the name of Adam Fix vs. The United States, before me
                    as a United Commissioner and also special Commissioner appointed by the
                    Commissioner of Claims.</p>
                <p>Present Adam Fix claimant and Attorney for said Claimant</p>
                <p>The said claimant &amp; each of said witnesses were first, before any
                    questions were put to them, properly and duly sworn to tell the truth, the whole
                    truth and nothing but the truth, relative in the matter in which they were to
                    testify and the testimony of the claimant and said witnesses were taken down by
                    me, or in my presence, and I read over to said claimant and to each of said
                    witnesses their respective depositions, and the said depositions were duly
                    signed in my presence.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W.G. Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>U.S. Commissioner<lb/>And Special Com.</p>
                <p>Deposition of Adam Fix</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 37 years old. I reside in Augusta Co, I am a farmer. I
                    resided where I live now.</p>
                <p>2 Witness says I resided in Augusta Co.</p>
                <p>3 Witness says I never passed the lines of US Army or Navy &amp; entered the
                    rebel lines. Never took any oath of allegiance to the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr> States</p>
                <p>5 Witness says I took an amnesty oath in 1865 in Staunton. It was required of
                    all. Have never been pardoned.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says I never was directly nor indirectly in any manner connected with
                    the civil service of the Confed. States.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says: I never held and position of honor profit or trust under the
                    Confed. States.</p>
                <p>8 Witness says: Never held any clerkship or office of any kind</p>
                <p>9 Witness says: Never was in the military or naval service of the Confed. States.</p>
                <p>10 Witness says. Never was an officer soldier sailor or marine, or in any way
                    employed in any Department of the Confed. States. Never had charge of any stores
                    supplies trains or teams, in or for the Confed. Govt at any time.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says. I never was in any service or employment of any kind under the
                    Confed. Govt. Never gave any information to any officer or soldier sailor or
                    marine of the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says: Never was in any way engaged, or employed, in the manufacture of
                    munitions of war or goods of any kind, for the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>13 Witness says. I never was directly nor indirectly employed in the collection
                    or impressment of stores or supplies for the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>14 I never was engaged in blockade running or illicit traffic between the lines.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says: I did not leave the Confed. States between the 19 of April 1861
                    x the 19th of April 1865.</p>
                <p>16 Witness says: I never was interested in any way, in any vessel, engaged in
                    navigation to or from any part of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17 Witness says: I never was arrested either by the U.S. or Confed. Govts</p>
                <p>18 Witness says: I had some cattle grain &amp; hay taken by the Confed Govt.
                    They were taken in 1864, for Govt. use, Rec'd no pay for them.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says: The Confederates threatened to imprison me &amp; my property
                    to be taken from me, if I did not send my brothers wife off. Almost every night
                    crowds were about my house.</p>
                <p>21 Witness says. I did nothing but to send my brother to the Union Army &amp;
                    supported his wife &amp; children. I fed him &amp; others in the
                    mountains for several months.</p>
                <p>23 Witness says: I had a brother in law in the Union Army, no near relative in
                    the Confed. Army. did not supply him with either equipments or money</p>
                <p>24 Witness says. Have never owned any Confed. bonds. Have never done anything to
                    support the credit of the Confed. States</p>
                <p>25 Witness says. I have never given aid or comfort to the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>26 Witness says I never was engaged in making raids from Canada nor in the
                    destruction of the commerce of the U.S.</p>
                <p>27 Witness says: I never was engaged in holding in custody persons taken as
                    prisoners of war by the Confederates.</p>
                <p>28 Witness says: I never was a member of any society for the expulsion or
                    persecution of any persons on account of Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>29 Witness says: I never was a <orig reg="paroled">parolled</orig> prisoner of
                    the United States.</p>
                <p>30 Witness says: I never held any office in either the Army or Navy of the U.S.
                    was not educated either at West Point or the Naval Academy</p>
                <p>31 Witness says: I never <abbr expan="received">recd</abbr> any pass from any
                    officer of the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>32 Witness says: I am not &amp; never was under any diabilities imposed by
                    the fourteenth amendment of the Constitution of the U.S. Have not held any
                    office under the U.S. Govt since the war.</p>
                <p>33 Witness says: At the beginning of the war I was for the Union. Did not vote
                    either for or against the ordinance of secession, would have voted against it
                    but I was sick. After the adoption of the ordinance of secession I adhered to
                    the Union &amp; did not go with my state.</p>
                <p>34 Witness says: I solemly declare that from the beginning to the end of the War
                    my sympathies were constantly with the cause of the Union.</p>
                <p>General Interrogatory:</p>
                <p>Do you know of any other matter relative to the said claim if you do state it
                    fully</p>
                <p>Answer. I would only say further that during the whole war I harbored &amp;
                    fed men escaping from the Confederacy &amp; going to the Union army;
                    &amp; further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>September 14th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Adam Fix</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me, this 14th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W.G. Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>U.S. Commissioner and Spec. Com. for the State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>John G. Troxall</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Jno. G. Troxall to prove taking &amp; furnishing of property</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 27 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a farmer. I
                    was present when the property named was taken &amp; saw it carried off.</p>
                <p>Ques 2 Witness says: Did not see the horse taken from the field but saw it led
                    away.</p>
                <p>3 Witness says: Did not see any thing else taken</p>
                <p>4 Witness says: The property was taken from farm of claimant in June 1864
                    soldiers of the Union Army under Genl. Hunter</p>
                <p>5 Witness says: My Father &amp; Brother were present.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says: There was no officer present only soldiers.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says: The property was taken from the field by the soldiers. The
                    claimants people said it was the finest horse they had.</p>
                <p>8 Witness says: The horse was led off by the Union soldiers.</p>
                <p>9 Witness says: It was taken to the army. did not follow it did not see it again.</p>
                <p>10 Witness says: The property was taken for the use of the Govt.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says: No complaint was made on account of the taking</p>
                <p>12 Witness says: No receipt was either given or asked for</p>
                <p>13 Witness says: The property was taken in the day.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says: When the property was taken the Army was not encamped near. No
                    skirmish nor battle near. Did not know the <abbr expan="Quarter">Qr.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Master">Mr.</abbr> of any of them.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says: The horse in fine condition 4 years old worth one hundred sixty
                    five dollars.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says: I believe the property was taken for the army &amp; not for
                    private use.</p>
                <p>22 Witness says: I believe it was taken for the necessary use of the Govt.
                    &amp; they ought to pay for it.</p>
                <p>23 Witness says: They told me they were ordered to take it &amp; further this
                    deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 14th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John G. Troxall</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 14th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W.G. Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>US Commissioner and Special Com. for State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>John Buchanan</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Jno. Buchanan to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says I am 28 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a farmer.
                    Have known the claimant all my life live near him. Saw him often during the War.
                    I talked with him often. He was loyal to the U.S. Govt. He was so regarded by
                    his neighbors. Never knew him to do anything for the Confed. Govt. He aided men
                    to go to the Union Army &amp; supported his brother in laws family while he
                    was in the Union army. He supplied deserters from the Confed. Army with food. He
                    was often molested &amp; disturbed on account of his Union sentiments. He
                    was too loyal to the U.S. Govt. to have been loyal to the Confed. Govt. had it
                    succeeded &amp; further this deponent sayeth not</p>
                <p>Sept 14th 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">John Buchanan</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 14th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W.G. Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>US Commissioner and Special Com. for the State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>W. G. Riley</byline>
                <p>I hereby certify that the foregoing eleven pages of Depositions (including this
                    certificate) of the claimant &amp; his witnesses, were taken by me at the
                    time and place and in the manner before mentioned.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W.G. Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>Special Com. for State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>Archive Office, WAR DEPARTMENT, Nov 30, 1878</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 353</p>
                <p>Case of Adam Fix, Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>Bill &amp; voucher for 50 bushels of Corn at $2.50 per bushel sold to the C.
                    States amounting to $125.00. Paid at Staunton Va. Feb 25th 1864 by Maj. H.M.
                    Bell Q.M. C.S. Army</p>
                <p>Rejected 1872</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
