<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0527"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0527">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Thomas and Nancy
                    Jefferson, 1877, Claim No. 15,385</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of thomas and nancy jefferson, 1877 claim no 15 385</title>
        <author>Jefferson, Thomas and Nancy</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 17 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0527</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498414</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Thomas and Nancy
                            Jefferson, 1877, Claim No. 15,385</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of thomas and nancy jefferson, 1877 claim no 15 385</title>
            <author>Thomas and Nancy Jefferson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #15385</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1877">1877</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Death/Casualties, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0527T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Thomas and Nancy Jefferson filed this claim in 1877 for $117, claiming Union
                    forces under General Sheridan required Nancy's nursing services as well as
                    appropriated 3 barrels of flour and a hog in 1865. Nancy was a 35 year old
                    African American housekeeper married to Thomas, also of African American
                    descent. The commission allowed $42.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>To services for the space of 7 1/2 weeks nursing Adjt. Ast. Genl.
                                Fry who was wounded near Waynesboro at $10 per week</cell>
                            <cell>$75.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$75.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 barrels of flour</cell>
                            <cell>$24.00</cell>
                            <cell>$24.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Hog</cell>
                            <cell>$18.00</cell>
                            <cell>$18.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The claimants are respectable colored people. The services charged in item No. 1
                    were rendered by them, and we regret that they can not be allowed not being
                    within our jurisdiction.</p>
                <p>The other items were taken in March 1865 by the soldiers of <abbr expan="General"
                            >Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan's command for Army
                    use.</p>
                <p>We allow for the items as charged. The hog was estimated at 180 lbs, &amp;
                    pork was then high.</p>
                <p>Claimants' loyalty fully proved. We allow $42.00</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name>, <name
                        type="other">O. Ferris</name><abbr expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of
                    Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Nancy Jefferson</byline>
                <p>United States of America, State of Virginia SS</p>
                <p>J.W.G. Riley a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioners of
                    Claims appointed under the act of Congress of March 3<hi rend="super"
                    >rd</hi> 1871 to take and record testimony Do hereby certify that the reason for
                    taking the following depositions is and the fact is the matter of claim of
                    Thomas Jefferson and wife vs. the United States of America and the witnesses
                    herein named being first duly sworn answereth as follows.</p>
                <p>1 Witness says-I resided in the County of Augusta six months prior to the 1<hi
                        rend="super">st</hi> of April 1861. I have resided there for 14 years
                    two years ago I moved into Waynesboro.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says-I never took any oath of allegiance to the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5 Witness says-I have never taken any amnesty oath. I never was in any manner
                    connected with the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says-I never held any office of profit under the Confederate Government
                    I never aided the Confederate Government in any manner</p>
                <p>14 Witness says-I never was engaged in blockade running or any thing else that
                    would benefit the Confederate States</p>
                <p>15 Witness says-Between the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> of April 1861 and
                    the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> of April 1865 I did not leave the
                    Confederate States</p>
                <p>16 Witness says-I never was interested in any vessel engaged in navigating the
                    ocean to or from the Confederacy</p>
                <p>17 Witness says-I never was arrested by the Confederate Government. I never was
                    arrested by the United States Government</p>
                <p>18 Witness says-I had provisions taken by the Confederate authorities sometimes
                    they would pay and sometimes they would not</p>
                <p>20 Witness says-I never was injured on account of my union sentiments</p>
                <p>21 Witness says-I never contributed any money or property to aid the United
                    States Government</p>
                <p>23 Witness says-I had a brother in the Confederate Army he was forced in to wait
                    on an officer</p>
                <p>24 Witness says-I never owned any Confederate bonds or done anything to support
                    the credit of the Confederate States</p>
                <p>33 Witness says-At the beginning of the war I sympathized with the Union and not
                    with the rebellion. I had no vote I am a colored woman but my sympathies were
                    all the time with the Union.</p>
                <p>34 Witness says-I solemnly declare from the beginning of hostilities to the end
                    thereof my sympathies were constantly with the cause of the United States and I
                    was ready at all times to do anything for the United States in my power.</p>
                <p>Questions by the Commissioner</p>
                <p>1 How old are you where do you reside and what is your occupation. Answer I am
                    thirty five years old I reside in Augusta County Virginia by occupation a house
                    keeper I am a married colored woman.</p>
                <p>Further the deponent saith not. Aug the 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p><name type="claimant">Nancy Jefferson</name> Her mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Fannie Sheppard</byline>
                <p>Fannie Sheppard a witness introduced by the Claimant to prove the taking of the
                    property being first duly sworn answereth as follows</p>
                <p>1 Witness says-I was present when the articles mentioned in the Claimants
                    petition were taken I also know that the Claimant nursed acting Assistant
                    Adjutant Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi> Fry belonging to <abbr expan="General"
                            >Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr> Talbot's command wounded
                    through both <orig reg="thighs">thies</orig> and in the body between Waynesboro
                    and the Blue ridge at ten dollars per week for seven weeks and a half.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says-The articles that I saw taken that are mentioned in the Claimant's
                    petition were taken in 1865 from the premises of the Claimants by officers and
                    soldiers under <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>
                    Sheridans command</p>
                <p>8 Witness says-The property was removed by soldiers some of it was eaten on the
                    spot</p>
                <p>11 Witness says-No complaint was made on account of such taking</p>
                <p>12 Witness says-There was no receipt give except a piece of paper by the wounded
                    man Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi> Fry to show what command he belonged to</p>
                <p>13 Witness says-The property was taken in the daytime in the afternoon none of it
                    was taken secretly</p>
                <p>14 Witness says-They were encamped near the house of the Claimant. They had been
                    skirmishing during the day.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says-The condition of the property was good when taken they took three
                    barrels of flour at eight dollars a barrel and one hog weighing one hundred and
                    eighty pounds at ten dollars per hundred.</p>
                <p>22 Witness says-I believe the property of the Claimant was taken for some purpose
                    so necessary and useful that the Government ought to pay for it and also for the
                    services rendered by the Claimants to<abbr expan="General"> Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi></abbr> Fry while wounded at their house and
                    Further the deponent saith not August the 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Fannie Sheppard</name> her mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Nelson Taylor</byline>
                <p>Nelson Taylor a witness introduced by the Claimants to <orig reg="prove"
                    >proove</orig> loyalty being first duly sworn answereth as follows-</p>
                <p>1 How old are you where do you reside and what is your occupation. Answer I am
                    sixty seven years old I reside in Waynesboro Augusta County Virginia by trade a
                    Cooper</p>
                <p>2 How long have you known the claimants? Answer I have known the claimants for
                    many years I knew them all the war they are both colored people. They were true
                    to the United States Government during the war they were so regarded by their
                    neighbors. I have never known either one of them to do any thing against the
                    Union cause. They were always ready and willing to help the Union cause and to
                    aid it to the extent of their power and ability they were too loyal to the
                    United States Government to have been loyal to the Confederacy if it had been
                    maintained as a separate Government.</p>
                <p>Further the witness saith not Aug the 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Nelson Taylor</name> his mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>John James</byline>
                <p>John James a witness introduced by the Claimants for proof as to loyalty being
                    first duly sworn answereth as follows</p>
                <p>1 How old are you where do you reside and what is your occupation? Answer I am
                    thirty six years old I live in Waynesboro Augusta County Virginia by occupation
                    a laborer</p>
                <p>2 How long have you known the Claimants Answer I have known the claimants
                    mentioned in the petition twelve or thirteen years they were both loyal to the
                    United States Government during the war and so regarded by their neighbors they
                    are both colored people and they were ready at all times to aid the United
                    States when called upon and</p>
                <p>Further the deponent saith not August the 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">John James</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 16th day of August 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Thomas and Nancy Jefferson</byline>
                <p>May 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 77</p>
                <p>Waynesboro Augusta Co Va.</p>
                <p>CF Benjamin <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq</abbr></p>
                <p>Sir, Your Postal <unclear>Crard</unclear>, under date of May 16<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> Inviting <del hand="h1">of</del> our attention to the
                    provision of an act of Congress section 2., <orig reg="alleging"
                    >Alledgeing</orig> that it is for the benefits of the parties interested in a
                    claim of Thomas Jefferson &amp; wife, against the <abbr expan="United"
                    >U</abbr> States No. 15385.</p>
                <p>This claim we had sent to Washington City, in 1872, or early 1873. We were
                    informed <hi rend="super">it</hi> was not acted on by the court for
                    Southern claims. This statement must have been correct, although the impression
                    was that the court did not adjudicate <unclear>ascs</unclear> of that kind. We
                    would very Respectfully beg leave to ask your <orig reg="advice">advise</orig>
                    in regard to how we shall act in the premises &amp; also if you think the
                    court will allow &amp; pay a Just claim of that kind. <hi rend="underline"
                        >Our Loyalty</hi> is <hi rend="underline">in</hi>disputable, <hi
                        rend="underline">as we are colored persons</hi>, and only suffered our House
                    to be used as a Hospital, and furnished <orig reg="sustenance"
                    >sustainance</orig> and the attendance upon the sick soldier, because he was
                        <orig reg="wounded">wouned</orig> at our door, and the Confederates would
                    have <orig reg="stripped">
                        <hi rend="underline">striped</hi>
                    </orig> and <hi rend="underline">murdered</hi> him after <del hand="h1">he was
                    wouned</del> he was shot down, had he not been cared for by us. It would only be
                    an act of Justice to pay us. Be Kind enough to advise as requested and allow us
                    to subscribe our selves</p>
                <p>Your <abbr expan="obedient">Ob<hi rend="super">t</hi></abbr><abbr
                        expan="servants">servts</abbr></p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant"><abbr expan="Thomas">Tho<hi rend="super"
                        >s</hi></abbr> Jefferson and Nancy Jefferson</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Charles F. Benjamin</byline>
                <p>Office of the Commissioners of Claims, Washington, D.C., July 9, 1872</p>
                <p>Memorandum: Depositions are on file in this office in support of the claim of <hi
                        rend="underline">Thomas Jefferson</hi> and <hi rend="underline">Wife</hi>,
                    but no petition appears to have been presented as required by paragraph 1 of the
                    accompanying rules and regulations. Please return this card with the petition
                    when forwarded.</p>
                <p><name type="other"><abbr expan="Charles">Chas</abbr> F. Benjamin</name> Clerk</p>
                <p>A. H. Fulz <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq</abbr>. Staunton, Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>A. H. Fultz</byline>
                <p>Staunton, Va. June 11 1877</p>
                <p>Hon Charles F. Benjamin</p>
                <p>Dear Sir:</p>
                <p>I <abbr expan="received">rec<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> from you a few
                    days ago, the Enclosed letter of Thomas Jefferson and from the endorsement it
                    seems that there has been no testimony taken in support of the Claim. I am
                    surprised at this, because immediately upon the filing of the claim, we took,
                    before Judge Riley, the then Commissioner, the testimony of a large number of
                    witnesses, proving beyond all question, the loyalty of the petitioners and the
                    justice of their Claim. This testimony was, of course left with Judge Riley to
                    be forwarded to your office, and I suppose he must have neglected to do so. Will
                    you please inform me what course to pursue in order to get in this testimony. I
                    am very anxious to have the claim allowed, not only because I believe it to be
                    just but because the petitioner is one of our most worthy <orig reg="colored"
                        >coloured</orig> men and if any one in the south is entitled to compensation
                    he is. Hoping to hear from you soon I remain</p>
                <p>Very Respectfully Your <abbr expan="obedient">Obt</abbr><abbr expan="servant"
                            >Serv<hi rend="super">t</hi></abbr></p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">A.H. Fultz</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
