<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0308"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0308">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Henry Demasters,
                    August 18, 1871, Claim No. 11452</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of henry demasters, august 18 1871 claim no 11452</title>
        <author>Demasters, Henry</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 12.0 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0308</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498375</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Henry Demasters,
                            August 18, 1871, Claim No. 11452</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of henry demasters, august 18 1871 claim no 11452</title>
            <author>Henry Demasters</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche # 449</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Family, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0308T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Henry Demasters filed this claim August 18, 1871, for $270.00, claiming that
                    Union troops confiscated 1 bay mare, 2 heifers, and 2 guns. The claim was
                    disallowed (date of disallowment not given; claim was still active in 1872).</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Bay Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$180.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$180.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 young heifers</cell>
                            <cell>$55.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$55.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 guns - 1 rifle $25, 1 matchlock $10</cell>
                            <cell>$35.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$35.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>This claim is wholly rejected. -</p>
                <p>Report -</p>
                <p>The claimant resided in Augusta County Virginia during the war.</p>
                <p>He says in his testimony that he voted for the Ordinance of Secession to prevent
                    War - We reject the claim.</p>
                <p>Loyalty not proved. -</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>
                </p>
                <p><abbr expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>Henry Demasters</byline>
                <p>United States of America</p>
                <p>State of Virginia</p>
                <p>I W.G. Riley, a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioners of
                    Claims appointed under the act of Congress of March 3rd 1871 to take and record
                    testimony Do hereby certify that the reason for taking the following depositions
                    is and the fact is the matter of claim of Henry Demasters vs the United States
                    of America and the witness herein named being first duly sworn answereth as
                    follows.</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness says - I lived in the County of Augusta six months prior to the
                    1st of April 1861</p>
                <p>2 Witness says - I resided at the same place between the 1st of April 1861 and
                    the 1st of June 1865.</p>
                <p>3 Witness says I never passed beyond the military or Naval lines of the United
                    States and entered the Rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says - I never took any oath of allegiance to the Confederate States</p>
                <p>5 Witness says - I have taken the amnesty oath I have never been pardoned by the
                    President.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says - I never was in any way connected with the Confederacy I never
                    held any office under the Confederacy I never was directly or indirectly
                    connected with any department of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says - I never was engaged in blockade running I never did any thing
                    for the Confederacy in my life.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says - I did not leave the Confederate States between the 19th of
                    April 1861 and the 19th of April 1865</p>
                <p>16 Witness says - I never was the owner or had any interest in any vessel in my
                    life.</p>
                <p>17 Witness says - I never was arrested by the Confederate Government I never was
                    arrested by the United States Government.</p>
                <p>18 Witness says - None of my property was ever taken by the Confederate
                    Government.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says - I don't think I was ever threatened on account of my union
                    sentiments.</p>
                <p>22 Witness says - I did nothing for the United States Government during the war</p>
                <p>23 Witness says - I had two sons in the Confederate Army they got out of the same
                    and went into the Union Army. I gave them a little money after they left the
                    Confederacy to take them to the Union Army.</p>
                <p>24 Witness says - I never owned any Confederate bonds I never did any thing to
                    support the Confederacy or give aid to support the Confederacy or give aid and
                    comfort to the Rebellion</p>
                <p>26 Witness says - I never was engaged in making raids into the United States from
                    Canada.</p>
                <p>29 Witness says - I never was a parolled prisoner of the United States</p>
                <p>30 Witness says - I have never held any office in the Army or Navy of the United
                    States. I was not educated at West Point or at the Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>31 Witness says - I never received any pass from any officer of the Confederate
                    Government.</p>
                <p>32 Witness says - I never was under any disabilities imposed by the 14th Article
                    of the amendments to the Constitution of the United States I have never held any
                    office under the United States Government since the war.</p>
                <p>33 Witness says - My sympathies were with the Union cause and not with the
                    Rebellion I voted for the ordinance of secession I was told if I did not vote
                    that way it would <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> up a war I adhered to the Union cause and did not go
                    with the State after the Ordinance of Secession was adopted.</p>
                <p>34 Witness says - From the beginning of hostilities against the United States to
                    the end thereof my sympathies were constantly with the cause of the United
                    States I was at all times ready and willing to aid the Union so far as my means
                    and power and the circumstances of the case permitted.</p>
                <p>Questions by the Commissioners</p>
                <p>Quest 1 How old are you where do you reside and what is your occupation?</p>
                <p>Answer I am sixty two years old I reside in Augusta County Virginia by occupation
                    a farmer and further the deponent saith not August the 17th 1871</p>
                <p>X (his mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>William Gibson</byline>
                <p>William Gibson a witness introduced by the Claimant to prove the taking of the
                    property being first duly sworn answereth as follows.</p>
                <p>Quest Witness says - I saw all the articles specified in the claimant's petition
                    taken</p>
                <p>4 Witness says - The articles mentioned in the claimant's petition were taken
                    from his farm about the 7th of June 1864 they were taken by soldiers under <abbr
                        expan="Generals">Genls</abbr> Averill's and Crook's command</p>
                <p>8 Witness says - I don't know whether the horse was rode or led the cattle were
                    driven</p>
                <p>11 Witness says - I heard no complaint to any officer on account of such taking</p>
                <p>12 Witness says - I don't know that any receipt was asked for or any given</p>
                <p>13 Witness says - It was taken in the daytime none of it was taken secretly</p>
                <p>14 Witness says - The night before they were encamped near there the next day
                    they came to Staunton Virginia. I knew none of the officers.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says - the horse was a young horse and in good condition the cattle
                    were in good condition - I think the horse was worth what the claimant has
                    charged in the petition also the cattle. I think the rifle was worth twenty
                    dollars I do not know much about the other gun.</p>
                <p>22 Witness says - I suppose that the property was taken for some purpose so
                    necessary that the Government ought to pay for it</p>
                <p>23 Witness says - I suppose it was taken by some officers or soldiers who had
                    authority to take it the soldiers said they had orders to take all property that
                    could be used to break down the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Questions by the Commissioner</p>
                <p>Quest 1 How long have you known the claimant</p>
                <p>Answer I have known him ten years I saw him often after 1863 he seemed to be
                    loyal to the United States during the war and was so regarded by his neighbors
                    and to the best of my belief he was loyal to the United States during the war. I
                    never knew him to do anything against the United States Government I never knew
                    him to do anything for the Confederate Government - he was too loyal to the
                    United States Government to have been considered a loyal man to the Confederacy
                    if it had been maintained as a separate Goverment</p>
                <p>Quest 2 How old are you where do you reside and what is your occupation</p>
                <p>Answer I am forty two years old I reside in Augusta County Virginia by occupation
                    a farmer</p>
                <p>Further the witness saith not</p>
                <p>August 17th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">William Gibson</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Alexander Gibson</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>Alexander Gibson a witness introduced by the Claimant to prove loyalty being
                    first duly sworn answereth as follows -</p>
                <p>Quest 1 How old are you where do you reside and what is your occupation?</p>
                <p>Answer I am forty years old I reside in Augusta County Virginia by occupation a
                    farmer</p>
                <p>Quest 2 How long have you known the claimant</p>
                <p>Answer I have known the claimant eight years - I saw him often during the war I
                    talked to him about the war he was loyal to the United States during the war and
                    was so regarded by his neighbors - I never knew him to do anything for the
                    United States except to harbor a few deserters from the Confederate Government
                    except what he was forced to do - I think he was too loyal to the United States
                    to have been considered loyal to the Confederacy if it had been maintained as a
                    separate Government further the deponent saith not August 17th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Alexander Gibson</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 17th day of August 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W.G. Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>(seal)</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com</abbr> for
                    the State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <!--Enter each person's testimony here!-->
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
