<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0509"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0509">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of David Guthrie,
                    1873, Claim No. 14090</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of david guthrie, 1873 claim no 14090</title>
        <author>Guthrie, David</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 53 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0509</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498396</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of David Guthrie, 1873,
                            Claim No. 14090</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of david guthrie, 1873 claim no 14090</title>
            <author>David Guthrie</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #14048 / #14090</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1873">1873</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Agriculture, Economy, Patriotism, Slavery</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0509T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>David Guthrie filed this claim in 1873 for $849, claiming the Union army under
                    General Beatty's command pastured their animals on his property in addition to
                    taking corn, hay, cord wood, rails, and some of his horses in 1863 and 1865.
                    David was a 71 year old farmer who resided near Jonesboro, Washington County,
                    Tennesse during the war. The Union army took his property from there. David
                    moved to Augusta County after the war. All witnesses are from Jonesboro,
                    Tennesse. Included in the claim is testimony of William Watkins, a slave working
                    for David but owned by Susan W. Watkins. The Commission did not consider the
                    second claim separately as it was extremely similar to his first claim. Both
                    claims were disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>7 items amounting to</cell>
                            <cell>$849.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$849.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>Claimant is <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> years old, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> farmer in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>boro Tennessee during the
                    war and swears to his loyal sympathies and votes. He calls two witnesses who
                    were not intimately acquainted with him and who cannot testify to any loyal
                    conduct or conversation of his but who say they were Union men themselves and
                    think that he was regarded as a Union man in the Community. But on the other
                    hand the claimant received $750 from Confederate Authorities, for leather and
                    horses used for the army during the second or third year of the war, and he
                    travelled back and forth two or three times from Tennessee to Virginia.</p>
                <p>In view of these facts the testimony in favor of loyalty of Claimant is
                    insufficient and unsatisfactory and we therefore reject the claim.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>David Guthrie</byline>
                <p>David Guthrie Claimant being duly sworn deposes and says I am 71 years of age
                    reside at Fishersville Augusta County Virginia by occupation a Farmer and
                    Merchant.</p>
                <p>1. I resided near Jonesboro Washington County Tennessee. I was at my then
                    residence, my occupation was Farming and Merchant.</p>
                <p>2. I resided at my then residence in Washington County Tennessee. I was
                    personally here during that period and my business was Farming and selling
                    Goods, and did not change my residence during that time.</p>
                <p>3. I never did.</p>
                <p>4. I never did.</p>
                <p>5. I never did. Never was.</p>
                <p>6. Never was.</p>
                <p>7. I never did.</p>
                <p>8. I never did.</p>
                <p>9. Never was.</p>
                <p>10. No to all points of the question.</p>
                <p>11. No to all points of the question.</p>
                <p>12. No to all points of the question.</p>
                <p>13. No to all points of the question.</p>
                <p>14. No to all points of the question.</p>
                <p>15. I did not.</p>
                <p>16. I never was.</p>
                <p>17. I was arrested by <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Williams at my Home in
                    Washington County Tennessee in the fall of 1863 and kept under arrest about 4
                    hours. I took no oath to the Confederacy to get released. I never was arrested
                    by the United States Government.</p>
                <p>18. The Rebels took at one time about 1500$ in State Bank money from me and Grain
                    at various times.</p>
                <p>19. I was frequently threatened by the Rebels came very near being Shot several
                    times by them on account of my Union sentiments, <abbr expan="General"
                    >Genl</abbr> Williams for one told me if he caught me out of my own yard he
                    would have me shot, and others threatened me whose name I do not recollect.</p>
                <p>20. I do no remember of ever being personally molested except when I was arrested
                    by <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Williams in the fall of 1863.</p>
                <p>21. I do not recollect of having done so.</p>
                <p>22. I did not, except to feed Union soldiers and Union men.</p>
                <p>23. I had some distant relations in both <orig reg="Armies">Armys</orig> but
                    never saw them and never did anything for them.</p>
                <p>24. I never did.</p>
                <p>25. I never did.</p>
                <p>26. Never was.</p>
                <p>27. No to all points of the question.</p>
                <p>28. Never was.</p>
                <p>29. Never was.</p>
                <p>30. Never did. Never was. Was not.</p>
                <p>31. Have no recollection of ever receiving any Pass.</p>
                <p>32. I am not. Have not.</p>
                <p>33. I sympathized with the Union all the time. I was a Union man all the time. I
                    adhered to the Union, voted and acted with the Union cause.</p>
                <p>34. In conclusion I do solemnly declare that from the beginning of the
                    hostilities against the United States to the end thereof, my sympathies were
                    constantly with the cause of the United States that I never of my own free will
                    and accord did anything or offered or sought or attempted to do antyhing by word
                    or deed to injure said cause or retard its success and that I was at all times
                    ready and willing when called upon or if called upon to aid and assist the cause
                    of the Union or its supporters so far as my means and power and the
                    circumstances of the case permitted.</p>
                <p>And being further examined by James O. Senter Claimants Attorney says, I saw the
                    two acres of Meadow used for pasture for months by <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col</abbr> Reeves of <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Beatys Command from
                    April to July 1865. I saw the 12 acres of Red Clover pastured by <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl</abbr> Beatys Command from April to July 1865. I did
                    not see the two Mares taken nor in their possession but was told by several
                    Officers of the Command <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> Lawson for one that they
                    were in their possession and service. The Mares were in good condition sound and
                    was worth 225$ for the two. The 2 acres of pasture was good Meadow and the use
                    of it for three months was worth at least 25$ The Hay that I could have made
                    from it would have been much more. The Clover was good and was worth 50$ at a
                    very low estimate 50$. I never have received any pay for any of said property.</p>
                <p>And being further examined by Special Commissioner in asnwer to the second set of
                    questions says.</p>
                <p>1. I was when the pasture was used.</p>
                <p>2. I saw the Meadow pastured and the Red Clover pastured.</p>
                <p>3. I did not.</p>
                <p>4. From my premises from April to July 1865 by <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>
                    Beatys Command.</p>
                <p>5. John E. C. Smith and others was present.</p>
                <p>6. There was officers present but did not know their names. The Officers
                    Headquarters was at Jonesboro at the time.</p>
                <p>7. The pasture was used on the premises and the Horses rode off.</p>
                <p>8. Horses rode off.</p>
                <p>9. Horses taken to <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> Lawsons Camp about one mile
                    from Jonesboro <abbr expan="Tennessee">Tenn.</abbr></p>
                <p>10. The Officers tole me so. Taken for the use of the <abbr expan="United States"
                        >U.S.</abbr> Army.</p>
                <p>11. No complaint made. <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> Lawson told me the Horses
                    should be returned but they never was.</p>
                <p>12. No Voucher or Receipt asked for. I did not get to see any officer to ask for
                    it before they left.</p>
                <p>13. Taken and used in the day time openly.</p>
                <p>14. No part of the army encamped in that vicinity, had been no battles or
                    skirmishes near there it was after the war had about closed, did not know any of
                    the <abbr expan="Quartermasters">Q.M.<hi rend="super">e.</hi></abbr>
                    names.</p>
                <p>15. The Meadow was good and the Red Clover was very good pasture. The Horses was
                    taken in the latter part of June 1865 by <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>
                    Beatys command and was good sound Mares and worth not less than 225$ for the
                    two. The pasture was used between April and July 1865.</p>
                <p>16. I had the Meadow and Clover pasture measured and know that there was two
                    acres of the Meadow and 12 acres of the Clover. The Mares I know was taken and
                        <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> Lawson told me they had them.</p>
                <p>19. I know that it was taken for the actual use of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Army.</p>
                <p>20. I know that their necessities compelled them to take the property.</p>
                <p>21. I know that it was a Military necessity that they used the pasture and took
                    the 2 Mares.</p>
                <p>22. I know that they ought to pay me for the property.</p>
                <p>23. I believe that it was taken and used under the orders of the Officers who had
                    the authority to order and take such articles for the use of the Army. I owned a
                    farm of about 60 acres at that time about 50 acres of it cleared. I have never
                    received any pay for any of said property. Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">David Guthrie</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thornburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Robert L. Blair</byline>
                <p>Robert L. Blair witness to prove the Loyalty of Claimant being duly sworn deposes
                    and says. I am 66 years of age, reside at Jonesboro Washington County Tennessee
                    by occupation an Iron maker.</p>
                <p>I have known Claimant for perhaps 10 years before the war. I was well acquainted
                    with him during the war. I lived about 1/2 miles from him. I saw him perhaps
                    twice a week during the War. I conversed with him about the war its causes and
                    progress. I was an adherent to the cause of the South and Claimant regarded me
                    as a Southern man in sentiment. His sympathies was with the Government of the
                    United States. I know this from his conversations with me on the subject. He
                    conversed with me both in the presence of others and alone. His public
                    reputation as to loyalty was very good. He was regarded as a Union man and never
                    heard it questioned. I do not know of the Claimant ever giving anything to aid
                    the Union causes or ever giving any information to the Officer or soldiers of
                    the Union Army. I do not know of his ever being threatened or molested on
                    account of his Union sentiments. I do not know of him ever contributing anything
                    to aid the Confederate States or ever owning any Confederate Bonds, or ever
                    doing anything to sustain the credit of the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Ques. Do you know of any act done of language used by the Claimant that would
                    have prevented him from establishing his loyalty to the Confederate States had
                    they been maintained as a <orig reg="separate">seperate</orig> Government.</p>
                <p>Ans. If the Confederacy had beenb maintained as a separate Government he could
                    not have established his loyalty to it by me.</p>
                <p>I am not related to Claimant and have no interest in his Claim.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">R.L. Blair Sr.</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thornburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>S. L. Shipley</byline>
                <p>S. L. Shipley Witness to prove the Loyalty of Claimant being duly sworn deposes
                    and says I am 55 years of age, reside one mile South of Jonesboro Washington
                    County Tennessee, by <orig reg="occupation">ocupation</orig> a Farmer.</p>
                <p>I have known Claimant about 16 or 18 years. I was well acquainted with him during
                    the later part of the war. I lived about one hundred yards of Claimant. I saw
                    him frequently. I frequently talked with him about the War its causes and
                    progress. I was a Union man and Claimant so regarded me. His sympathies appeared
                    to be with the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> I knew this from his
                    conversations. His conversations was generally alone with me. He was publicly
                    regarded as a Union man. He was regarded by his loyal neighbors as a Union man
                    as far as I knew. I do not know of him ever giving anything to aid the Union
                    cause, or ever giving any information to the Officers of the Union Army.</p>
                <p>I know that he was once arrested by <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Williams
                    and released I do not know of him ever giving any aid to the Confederacy or ever
                    giving any information to the Officers or soldiers of the Confederate Army, or
                    ever owning any Confederate Bonds, or ever doing anything to sustain the credit
                    of the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Ques. Do you know of any act deed or language used by the Claimant that would
                    have prevented him from establishing his loyalty to the Confederacy had it been
                    maintained as a <orig reg="separate">seperate</orig> Government.</p>
                <p>Ans. I would consider it doubtful whether he could have established his loyatly
                    to the Confederacy or not, if it had gained its Independence.</p>
                <p>I am not related to David Gutherie the Claimant and have no interest in his Claim
                    whatever.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>Shipley</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thornburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>John E. C. Smith</byline>
                <p>John E. C. Smith Witness to prove the taking of Claimants property being duly
                    sworn, deposes and says I am 35 years of age, reside about 3/4 of a mile West of
                    Jonesboro, Washington County, Tennessee by <orig reg="occupation"
                    >ocupation</orig> a Farmer and Tanner.</p>
                <p>And being further examined by James O. Senter Claimants <abbr expan="Attorney"
                        >Atty.</abbr> says.</p>
                <p>I saw the 2 acres of Meadow and the 12 acres of Red Clover pastured belonging to
                    David Gutherie the Claimant. I think it was the 4<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    Tennessee Infantry that pastured the Meadow, and I believe that it was the same
                    command that pastured the 12 acres of Clover, they were all under the command of
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Beaty. The Meadow and Clover was good.
                    There was about 2 acres of the Meadow and not less than 12 acres of the Clover.</p>
                <p>I do not know of him ever receiving any pay for said pasture.</p>
                <p>And being further examined by Special Commissioner in answer to the Second set of
                    questions says.</p>
                <p>1. I was.</p>
                <p>2. I saw them pasture the 2 acres of Meadow and the 12 acres of Clover.</p>
                <p>3. I did not.</p>
                <p>4. Used on Claimants premises from April to July 1865 by <abbr expan="General"
                        >Genl</abbr> Beatys Command.</p>
                <p>5. Claimant and others was present.</p>
                <p>6. Officers was present but I did not know them.</p>
                <p>7. Used on Claimants premises.</p>
                <p>8. Used in the premises by the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Soldier.</p>
                <p>9. Taken and used in premises.</p>
                <p>10. Taken for the use of <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Beatys Command.</p>
                <p>11. Heard no complaint made.</p>
                <p>12. I do not know of any Voucher or Receipt being asked for or received.</p>
                <p>13. Used during both day and night openly.</p>
                <p>14. No Army encamped near there, had been no battle or skirmish near there, did
                    not know any of the <abbr expan="Quartermasters">Q.M<hi rend="super"
                        >s</hi>.</abbr></p>
                <p>15. The Pasture was all good.</p>
                <p>16. I believe there was 2 acres of the Meadow from the size of it, and at least
                    12 acres of Clover or more.</p>
                <p>19. I know that it was taken for the use of the U.S. Army because I saw them
                    using it.</p>
                <p>20. I believe it was taken in consequence of a necessity for such pasture at that
                    time.</p>
                <p>21. I believe that it was a Military necessity that it was taken and used.</p>
                <p>22. I believe the Government ought to pay him for it, as they got it and used it
                    for the benefit of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Army.</p>
                <p>23. I believe that it was taken and used by or under the order or authority of
                    some Officer or person having the proper authority to do so.</p>
                <p>I am not related to Claimant and have no interest in his Claim. He was the owner
                    of a farm at that time of about 130 acres, the largest part of which was
                    cleared.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">John E. C. Smith</name> his mark</p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thornburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>D.G. Thurnburgh</byline>
                <p>To the <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon</abbr> Commissioners of Claims Washington D.C.</p>
                <p>Sirs,</p>
                <p>I herewith certify that the Claimant David <orig reg="Gutherie">Guthery</orig>
                    together with his witnesses Robert L. Blair, S. T. Shipley and John E.C. Smith
                    personally appeared before me the 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of May
                    1872 at Jonesboro Washington County Tennessee appearing as Attorney for the
                    Claimant. The above claimant is a citizen of Fishersville Augusta County
                    Virginia. Witnesses are all citizens of Washington County <abbr
                        expan="Tennessee">
                        <hi rend="underline">Tenn</hi>
                    </abbr> Some of the <abbr expan="Loyal">Loyl</abbr> Citizens of this place agree
                    that this claim is unjust.</p>
                <p>Respectfully Submitted</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">D.G. Thurnburgh</name>
                </p>
                <p>Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>Claims Commission regarding Gutherie's Second Claim</byline>
                <p>No. 14090</p>
                <p>The Claim of David Gutherie</p>
                <p>This Claim consists of 3 items amounting to $300.00. Amount Disallowed. $300.00</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>.</hi>, in the State
                    of <hi rend="underline">Virginia</hi>.</p>
                <p>This Claim is presented by the same party and through the same Agent as Claim
                    14048 and it <orig reg="doesn't">dont</orig> appear that there is any reason
                    good or bad for dividing the claim into two parts. The evidence of loyalty is
                    not particularly strengthened in this second claim.</p>
                <p>Two witnesses are called one of whom was confessed disloyal who gives it as his
                    opinion that claimant was loyal and another knew him only a short time before
                    the close of the war. Claimant himself says nothing about receiving pay for
                    leather and horses in his answer to interrogaties filed with this claim, but
                    alleges that Rebels took $1500 in Bank paper from him.</p>
                <p>The facts and circumstances developed in counnection with this claim does not
                    diminish or change the unfavorable impression made by the other, and we
                    therefore reject this claim also.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>David Guthrie</byline>
                <p>In the matter of David Guthrie</p>
                <p>Claimant aged 71 years Being duly Sworn deposes and says. He resides in
                    Fishersville Augusta County Virginia and has been a Farmer and Merchant, And
                    further says in answer to first set of questions.</p>
                <p>1. I lived West about three eights of a miles from Jonesboro Washington County
                    Tennessee. I was at home and was Merchandizing and farming.</p>
                <p>2. I resided three eights of a mile West of Jonesboro Washington County Tennessee
                    and was at home until the Spring of 1863. I then went to Virginia two or three
                    times, I went to see my <orig reg="friends">frinds</orig> and to lay out my
                    Confederate money in something and was farming I did not chnage my residence.</p>
                <p>3. I never did</p>
                <p>4. I never did</p>
                <p>5. No sir. No sir.</p>
                <p>6. No sir</p>
                <p>7. No indeed</p>
                <p>8. No sir</p>
                <p>9. No sir</p>
                <p>10. No to all points of the question.</p>
                <p>11. No to all points of the question</p>
                <p>12. No sir</p>
                <p>13. No to all points of the question</p>
                <p>14. No to all points of the question</p>
                <p>15. No sir</p>
                <p>16. No sir</p>
                <p>17. I was arrested once but do not recollect the time, by old General Williams of
                    the rebel army. I was at home. I was kept about four hours, I was reprimanded
                    and released. Never was arrested by the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr>
                    Government.</p>
                <p>18. About fifteen Hundred dollars worth of leather at one time, also a couple of
                    horses it was taken in the Winter of 1862-3. It was I suppose to shoe the army.
                    They sent me about seven hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
                <p>19. I dont recollect</p>
                <p>20. I believe not</p>
                <p>21. I never did</p>
                <p>22. I never did</p>
                <p>23. I dont recollect of having any in either army.</p>
                <p>24. I never did</p>
                <p>25. Not of my knowledge</p>
                <p>26. No sir</p>
                <p>27. No Sir</p>
                <p>28. No sir</p>
                <p>29. No sir</p>
                <p>30. No Sir. No Sir. No Sir</p>
                <p>31. I dont think I ever did</p>
                <p>32. I am not</p>
                <p>33. I sympathized with the Union Cause. My feelings and language were for the
                    Union. On the Union side I exerted my influence and Cast my vote. I voted
                    against <orig reg="Separation">Seperation</orig>. No Ratification I adhered to
                    the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>34. My sympathies were constantly with the Cause of the Union, I never of my own
                    free will and accord, did anything or offered or sought or attempted to do
                    anything by word or deed, to injure said cause or retard its success and I was
                    at all times ready &amp; willing when called upon or if called upon to aid
                    and assist the Cause of the Union or its supporters so far as my means and
                    powers and the circumstances of the case permitted.</p>
                <p>And being further examined by James O. Senter Claimants Attorney says</p>
                <p>I saw the most of the Corn taken, it was ripe and taken out of the field and it
                    was worth One dollar per bushel. And was taken by 7<hi rend="super"
                    >th</hi> Ohio Cavalry, in September and October 1863. I saw a part of the hay
                    taken the hay was good, and was worth One dollar per Hundred And was taken by
                        7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Ohio Cavalry. I saw them driving my two
                        <orig reg="cattle/beef">beeves</orig> away. They were tolerable good <orig
                        reg="cattle/beef">beeves</orig>. And was worth about six cents per poud. And
                    was taken by the 12<hi rend="bold">th</hi><abbr expan="Kentucky">Ky</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> in <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 1863. I
                    saw them taking the rails. They were medium rails, and were good, and dont know
                    what they are worth. The most of the rails were taken in March and April 1865 by
                    the 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Tennessee Infantry; never received any pay
                    for this property. I owned a little place here then, One of about fifteen and
                    one twenty seven acres. And the other about fifteen acres. It would average per
                    acre forty or fifty bushels to the acre of Corn. And all together was worth
                    about thirty three hundred dollars.</p>
                <p>And being further examined in answer to second set of questions says.</p>
                <p>1. Was present</p>
                <p>2. I saw the most of the corn and part of the hay. I saw five hundred pounds of
                    the beef &amp; I saw two thirds of the rails taken.</p>
                <p>3. I did not</p>
                <p>4. In Septemtber 1863 and October, and in April, May, June, and July 1865. taken
                    on my place By the 4<hi rend="super">th</hi><abbr expan="Tennessee"
                    >Tenn</abbr> Infantry and by the 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Ohio <abbr
                        expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> and the 12<hi rend="super">th</hi><abbr
                        expan="Kentucky">Ky</abbr> Cavalry.</p>
                <p>5. I dont recollect</p>
                <p>6. I dont know</p>
                <p>7. Corn was taken in wagons and in sacks. The hay was hauled and carried, I saw
                    them driving the <orig reg="beef cattle">beeves</orig> off. Rails were taken for
                    fuel. I saw them burning the rails. I dont recollect any</p>
                <p>8. It was removed by soldiers on horseback and in wagons. They carried the rails
                    on their shoulders. and drove the <orig reg="beef cattle">beeves</orig> off on
                    foot.</p>
                <p>9. It was taken to their camp, I suppose. I got two vouchers for the corn did not
                    follow up for any thing else. The first evening &amp; no other time.</p>
                <p>10. I believe it was taken for the use of the army, I suppose. They fed the
                    horses on the corn, I suppose it was my corn. I did not see anything else used
                    that I know of.</p>
                <p>11. I dont recollect only to the <abbr expan="Quartermasters">Q.M<hi
                            rend="super">s.</hi></abbr> Lt. M. Ruth &amp; Lt. A. Hall.
                    They gave me a memorandum receipts.</p>
                <p>12. I did not I dont think</p>
                <p>13. It was generally taken in daytime all hours of the day did not take it
                    secretly.</p>
                <p>14. Yes sir, Camped on and on both sides of my place. 4<hi rend="super"
                        >th</hi><abbr expan="Tennessee">Tenn</abbr> Infantry Stayed from April until
                    July. No battle or skirmish near.</p>
                <p>15. The Corn was on the stalk and in the field about ripe and in good Condition
                    and was worth One dollar per bushel. The hay was taken out of my barn. It was
                    good. And was worth One dollar per hundred. The two head of cattle were killed
                    after they drove them off <add hand="h1" place="inline">and were</add> in tolerable good eating order.
                    And was worth six cents per pound.</p>
                <p>16. Only from my own judgement as to amount of corn. I saw one half or two thirds
                    of the Corn taken I dont know how many bushels I saw taken. I knew the amount of
                    hay by the amount of hay I had in the barn it was guess work with me entirely. I
                    cant say how many pounds was taken. I suppose though from two to three thousand
                    pounds taken. They took two <orig reg="beef cattle">beeves</orig> I saw and I
                    judged they would weigh two hundred and fifty pounds each.</p>
                <p>18. I saw the soldiers carrying and burning my rails. I cant say anything about
                    it as to numbers. I saw taken the rails disppeared and they were camped there
                    about medium rails five or six years old. I dont think the officers tried to
                    prevent them from taking the rails. I am not certain I made any complaint</p>
                <p>19. I believe it was taken for the use of the army I dont know what other use
                    they could have for it.</p>
                <p>20. I dont know. I dont believe they had supplies. They said they would not take
                    it if I would point out some rebel neighbors corn.</p>
                <p>21. I suppose they were justifiable dont think they would taken it if they did
                    not need it.</p>
                <p>22. I suppose the Government ought to pay for it. Simply because it was taken for
                    the use of the army.</p>
                <p>23. I have no doubt part of it was because they gave me some receipts. I owned
                    some land at this time and <add hand="h1" place="inline">it</add> was worth thirty three Hundred dollars.
                    I never received any pay for this property either in part or in whole.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant"><abbr expan="David">D.</abbr> Guthrie</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">D. G. Thurnburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                <byline>William R. Sevier</byline>
                <p>William R. Sevier Claimants witness to prove loyalty being duly sworn deposes and
                    says. He is aged 49 years. Resides in Jonesboro, Washington County Tennessee and
                    is a Physician by Profession and further says</p>
                <p>I have known the Claimant for from those to five years previous to the war. I
                    knew him well during the war. And were both residents of the town of Jonesboro
                        <abbr expan="Tennessee">Tenn.</abbr> I saw him often. I cannot remember,
                    very likely we did converse about the war. I was a Union man. And I suppose
                    claimant regarded me as being a Union man. I think the Claimants sympathy was
                    with the Government of the United States. I know this from general report and
                    perhaps by conversations with him. I do not recollect distinctly of at any time
                    conversing with him. I think he was regarded as being a Union man. I do not know
                    of his ever giving anything to aid the Union army or cause or that he ever gave
                    any information to aid the officers or soldiers in their movements or cause. The
                    claimant was arrested on the same day I <add hand="h1" place="inline">was</add><abbr expan="September"
                        >Sept</abbr> 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863 and detained an hour or
                    so, and then released. I do not know of claimant contributing any thing to
                    sustain the credit of the Confederate States or that he ever owned any
                    Confederate <add hand="h1" place="inline">bonds</add>. I knew nothing of his financial
                        <del hand="h1">condition</del><add hand="h1" place="inline">affairs</add>. I regarded him as a Union man and I
                    think he was uniformly considered as such. I do not know whether this would have
                    prevented him from establishing his loyalty to the Confederacy or not if it had
                    maintained itself as a <orig reg="separate">seperate</orig> Government. I am not
                    related to Claimant either by affinity or Consanguinity And have no interest in
                    his Claim And further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness"><abbr expan="William">W.</abbr>R. Sevier</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thurnburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                <byline>Henry Hoss</byline>
                <p>Henry Hoss Claimant witness to prove loyalty being duly sworn deposes and says.</p>
                <p>He is aged 53 years. Resides One mile North East of Jonesboro Washington County
                    Tennessee. And is by occupation a farmer, And further says. I have been
                    acquainted with Claimmant for several years previosu to the war. I knew him very
                    well, but was not as intimate with him as I was with other men. I lived in about
                    three fourths of a mile of Claimant. I saw him often. I was a Union man and
                    Claimant could not have regarded me otherwise. The general understanding with
                    Union men here was that Claimants sympathy was with the Government of the United
                    States. I do not know of Claimant contributing any money or property to aid the
                    Union Cause or army or that he ever gave any information to aid the officers or
                    soldiers in their movements and cause. I have good reason to believe he was
                    arrested at one time by the Confederate Authorities at this place. I do not know
                    of Claimant ever giving any money property, or information to aid the
                        Confederate<del hand="h1">ment</del> Government officers or soldiers. Or that he ever
                    did anything to sustain the Credit of the Confederate States. I know from
                    Claimants public reputation that he was a Union man. And do not know whether
                    this would have prevented him or not from establishing his loyalty to the
                    Confederacy if it had maintained itself as a <orig reg="separate"
                    >seperate</orig> Government. I am not a relation of Claimant nor have I any
                    interest in his claim. And further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Henry Hoss</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thurnburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                <byline>William Watkins</byline>
                <p>William Watkins (colored) Claimants witness to prove taking of property, being
                    duly sworn deposes and says</p>
                <p>He is aged about 66 years, lives about two miles East of Jonesboro Washington
                    County Tennessee and is farming.</p>
                <p>And in answer to claimants attorney James O. Senter says. I saw them taking the
                    Corn. The corn, was on the stalk and was sound and ripe. And I dont know what
                    corn was worth. It was taken by the Federal Soldiers I dont recollect at this
                    time what Command it was. And it was taken about October 1863. I saw them, have
                    some of Claimants hay. I saw where they had taken it out of the barn and saw
                    where they had strewn the hay on the ground. The hay was No one hay, and I think
                    it was at that time worth about One dollar per Hundred. And was taken about
                    October 1863 And do not at this time recollect what Command it was. I saw them
                    take a bay horse common size. And from three to five years old. And was an good
                    nice horse. And was worth One hundred and twenty five dollars at the least. I
                    saw them taking the rails. And they were good Chestnut rails. And were old. They
                    were burning them at their camp fires. I dont know what they were worth. Cannot
                    price them. I do not know the Command that took the horse or rails. The horse
                    was taken in October or September 1863. And the rails were taken about that tim
                    a part of them and others taken at different times. I saw them taking the Cord
                    wood at the same time the wood had been cut and was green and was good fire
                    wood. And the wood was worth two dollars per cord delivered in Jonesboro. And it
                    was taken in September or October 1863. I was seeding wheat at the time. I dont
                    know the Commands that took any of hte property. I do not know of Claimant ever
                    receiving any pay for this property. The Claimant owned some land at that time
                    about forty five or fifty acres and I think he held it at forty five dollars per
                    acre. I was a slave at that time and lived with Claimant and I belonged to Mrs.
                    Susan W. Watkins.</p>
                <p>And being further examined in answer to second set of questions</p>
                <p>1. I was present</p>
                <p>2. I saw some of the corn taken load after load in the day. I saw them carrying
                    hay. I saw them take the horse. I saw them take and burn a part of the rails in
                    day and I saw them taking the cord wood.</p>
                <p>3. I did not</p>
                <p>4. In September and October of 1863. And was taken on Claimants farm, And was
                    taken by Federal Soldiers do not know the Command.</p>
                <p>5. The Claimant was present. And his family.</p>
                <p>6. There was some officers there. I heard the officers order it taken. They said
                    they had to have feed for their horses did not make any difference whether it
                    was Federals or rebels they took from.</p>
                <p>7. It was carried off in wagons and sacks. And I suppose without leave.</p>
                <p>8. It was taken by soldiers in wagons and in sacks. They carried the rails and
                    burned them in their camp fires. The horse they led away. They cord wood they
                    burned at their camp fires.</p>
                <p>9. They used it <orig reg="there">their</orig> on the farm. I saw them using it
                    right there..</p>
                <p>10. It was taken to keep the stack up. I saw them feeding and using it.</p>
                <p>11. I did not hear any.</p>
                <p>12. I did not hear any asked for</p>
                <p>13. It was taken day and night. They did not take it secretly they took it boldly
                    and above board.</p>
                <p>14. Yes sir. They camped on it and close around the edge of the farm. Do not know
                    the command. They were there two or three times and <orig reg="stayed"
                    >staid</orig> all night once, and three or four days the other times. No battle
                    of skirmish near. I did not know the <abbr expan="Quarter Master">Q.M.</abbr></p>
                <p>15. The corn was on the hard order betwixt and between ripe and green. The corn
                    was in the field, dont know what it was worth. The hay was in the barn, and was
                    good sound hay, And it was worth One dollar per Hundred. The bay horse was a
                    nice good sized horse. And was from three to five years old. And was worth One
                    Hundred and twenty five dollars at a low rate. And it seems to me he was
                    branded. I am not certain.</p>
                <p>16. I have been farming all my life and I believe there was four hundred bushels
                    taken, the field had about twenty acres in all And I dont think they left more
                    than fifty or seventy five bushels in the field for I gathered the <orig
                        reg="balance">ballance</orig>. I cant say how much hay they took.</p>
                <p>17. I say fifteen cords of wood or more. I saw them burning it. It was not
                    measured. The wood was green and was cut to haul to town. And was taken on
                    Claimants farm and was worth two dollars a cord in Jonesboro.</p>
                <p>18. I saw them taking the rails. Soldiers were carrying them and <orig
                        reg="putting">puting</orig> them on the fire. I think the fence I saw them
                    taking was One hundred panels long one of them and the other seventy five panels
                    long. And they were ten rails for I built them myself. The rails were good Old
                    Chestnut rails. The officers did not try keep them from burning them all burnt
                    the rails together. I think the old man Complained about burning his rails and
                    some of the soldiers threatened him.</p>
                <p>19. I fully believe it was taken for the use of the army for I saw them using it.</p>
                <p>20. I suppose it was necessary for them to take a part, but they waste as as they
                    use.</p>
                <p>21. I <orig reg="reckon">recon</orig> they were justifiable in taking it. They
                    were away from home and had to have some thing to go on.</p>
                <p>22. I would say he was entitled to some pay.</p>
                <p>23. I believe the officers ordered it taken, because they were there and did not
                    object. I do not know of Claimant ever <orig reg="getting">geting</orig> any
                    pay. He owned some land at that time, a Small farm. I was a slave at that time.
                    And was working for him. Mrs. Susan W. Watkins was my mistress. I have no
                    interest in this Claim.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">William Watkins</name> his mark</p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thurnburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d17">
                <byline>J.E.C. Smith</byline>
                <p>J.E.C. Smith Claimants witness to prove taking of property being duly sworn
                    deposes and says</p>
                <p>He is aged 35 years. And lives One mile West of Jonesboro Washington County
                    Tennessee, Farmer by Trade.</p>
                <p>And in answer to claimants Attorney James O. Senter says.</p>
                <p>I saw the Federal Soldiers and they said they belonged to the 7<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> Ohio <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> taking
                    Claimants Corn. And I am not certain but think it was in the Fall of 1863. It
                    was good corn and was in the field, and was on the stalk. And dont recollect
                    what it was worth but think about seventy five cents a bushel. I saw them
                    pasturing their stock on his fields and in his meadow. The claimant owned a
                    farm, it was a pretty good place. I do not know of Claimant ever <orig
                        reg="getting">geting</orig> any pay for this property. I am not related to
                    the Claimant And have no interest in this claim</p>
                <p>And being further examined in answer to second <orig reg="set">sett</orig> of
                    questions says</p>
                <p>1. I was</p>
                <p>2. I saw them take the corn</p>
                <p>3. I saw them pasturing also</p>
                <p>4. In the Fall of 1863 on Claimants farm. And the soldiers said they belonged to
                    the 7<hi rend="super">th </hi>Ohio Cavalry.</p>
                <p>5. I saw Claimant and his folks in his yard about fifty yards from the field</p>
                <p>6. I expect <orig reg="there">their</orig> was. (I dont know) As to <orig
                        reg="balance">ballance</orig> of corn.</p>
                <p>7. I dont know whether the Claimant <orig reg="gave">give</orig> them leave of
                    not.</p>
                <p>8. It was taken in their arms and on their shoulders and in sacks on their
                    horses.</p>
                <p>9. They carried it to camps near town and near Claimants house. I saw them it was
                    in plain view of me. I did not follow them.</p>
                <p>10. It was taken for to feed their horses on. I saw them feeding the corn what I
                    saw them taking.</p>
                <p>11. I didnt hear any</p>
                <p>12. Not as I know of</p>
                <p>13. What I <orig reg="saw">seen</orig> was taken in the morning early and of an
                    evening late. They did not take it secretly.</p>
                <p>14. Yes Camped right there by him it was called the 7<hi rend="super"
                    >th</hi> Ohio <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> I cant say how long they were
                    there. No skirmish. I did not know the <abbr expan="Quarter Master">Q.M.</abbr>
                    or any of the officers.</p>
                <p>15. The corn was ripe, and in the field on the stalk, and was pretty good corn
                    and I think it was selling at seventy five cents at that time.</p>
                <p>16. I dont know as to quantity. I dont know how much I saw taken.</p>
                <p>19. I think it was taken for the use of the army I saw them feed the Corn.</p>
                <p>20. I dont think they had much supplies here at that time. I dont think the
                    officers would have let them take the corn if they had had supplies.</p>
                <p>21. I expect the necessity justified them to take it.</p>
                <p>22. I dont know they had nothing to feed, and I guess they ought to pay for it.</p>
                <p>23. I do not know whether it was or not. I am not related to Claimant. The
                    Claimant owned a farm at that time a small farm. And I suppose it was worth
                    about fifteen dollars per acre. I do not know of Claimant ever <orig
                        reg="getting">geting</orig> any pay for this property. And further deponent
                    sayeth not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">J.E.C. Smith</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thurnburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d18">
                <byline>William R. Boyd</byline>
                <p>William R. Boyd Claimants witness to prove taking of property being duly sworn
                    deposes and says.</p>
                <p>He is aged 41 years. Resides in Jonesborough Washington County Tennessee. And is
                    a Cabinet Maker by Trade.</p>
                <p>And in answer to second <orig reg="set">sett</orig> of questions of Claimants
                    Attorney James O. Senter says</p>
                <p>I saw the beef of Claimant taken in the Fall of 1863. I dont know the Command. I
                    think he had about three head of <orig reg="beef cattle">beeves</orig> taken.
                    And they would have weighed about two hundred and fifty <orig reg="net"
                    >nett</orig>. And I suppose it was worth about ten cents per pound at that time.
                    They were good grass fed <orig reg="beef cattle">beeves</orig>. I do not know of
                    Claimant receiving any pay for this property. The Claimant owned some land at
                    that time. I suppose the land he owned was worth two or three thousand dollars.
                    I am a poor judge of the Value. I am not related to Claimant and have no
                    interest in his Claim in any way.</p>
                <p>And being further examined in answer to second <orig reg="set">sett</orig> of
                    questions says</p>
                <p>1. I was present</p>
                <p>2. I saw the three <orig reg="beef cattle">beeves</orig> as <orig reg="well"
                    >will</orig> as I remember taken</p>
                <p>3. I did not</p>
                <p>4. I think it was in the Fall fo 1863 taken <orig reg="off">of</orig> of his
                    premises. I do not know by whom it was taken.</p>
                <p>5. I believe William Watkins (<abbr expan="colored">col<hi rend="super"
                        >d</hi></abbr>) was present.</p>
                <p>6. That is a question I cant answer</p>
                <p>7. &amp; 8. They just went into the field &amp; drove them out, I dont
                    recollect what they said about it.</p>
                <p>9. I saw them take them and bring them into town here.</p>
                <p>10. I suppose they <orig reg="ate">eat</orig> them up themselves. I did not see
                    them butchered.</p>
                <p>11. Not that I know of.</p>
                <p>12. None that I know of</p>
                <p>13. No sir in the day, I dont know as to the hour probably about the middle of
                    the afternoon. They took it publicly</p>
                <p>14. I dont think there was on the farm by a little distance off I do not know the
                    Command. They <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> here about two weeks. No battle or
                    skirmish near. I did not know any of the <abbr expan="Quarter Master"
                    >Q.M.</abbr> or officers</p>
                <p>15. There was three I think of cattle taken and were drove off on foot. They were
                    not fat would have weighed about two Hundred and fifty pounds each. And at that
                    time we had to pay about ten cents per pound. I have not talked to Claimant
                    about the Value.</p>
                <p>19. I suppose they took it for the use of the army.</p>
                <p>20. I cant tell</p>
                <p>21. I cant answer that</p>
                <p>22. I suppose they took it and <orig reg="ate">eat</orig> it. I cant say whether
                    they ought to pay for it or not.</p>
                <p>23. I suppose the soldiers took it by authority or they would not have done it.
                    The Claimant owned some land at that time and I think it was worth two or three
                    Thousand dollars. I am not related to Claimant nor have no interest in his
                    claim. I do not know of his every receiving any pay for this property.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness"><abbr expan="William">Wm.</abbr> R. Boyd</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thurnburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d19">
                <byline>D.G. Thurnburgh</byline>
                <p>To the Hon Commissioners of Claims Washington D.C.</p>
                <p>Sirs</p>
                <p>I herewith certify that the claimant David Guthrie together with his witnesses
                    Dr. William R. Sevier, Henry Hoss, William Watkins <orig reg="colored"
                    >colered</orig> J.E.C. Smith and William R. Boyd personally appeared before me
                    the 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of May 1872 at Jonesboro Washington
                    County Tennessee and were duly sworn and deposed as their <orig
                        reg="depositions">deposions</orig> show James O. Senter of Panther Springs
                    Hamblin County Tennessee appearing as Attorney for the Claimant. The claimant is
                    a citizen of Fishersville Augusta County Virginia witnesses are all citizens of
                    Washington County Tennessee.</p>
                <p>Respectfull Submitted</p>
                <p><name type="other">D.G. Thurnburgh</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d20">
                <byline>John Boyd</byline>
                <p>State of Tennessee, Wasington County</p>
                <p>Personally appeared before me John F. Grisham Clerk of the County Court in and
                    for the State and County aforesaid John Boyd who being duly sworn according to
                    Law says: that he was acquainted with Mr. David Guthrie and lived within a few
                    hundred yards of him during the late Rebellion. Affiant has had divers
                    conversations with Mr Guthrie which lead affiant very clearly to believe Mr
                    Guthrie to be a Union man and a friend of our Government that the said Guthrie
                    was by Union men generally considered a friend to the Union, that from the best
                    of my knowledge information and belief I can but believe said Guthrie to have
                    been a Union man</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Boyd</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of
                    March 1874 and I have no interest in this claim.</p>
                <p><name type="other">John F Grisham</name><abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Court">Ct.</abbr> Clerk</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d21">
                <byline>S.T. Shipley</byline>
                <p>State of Tennessee Washington County</p>
                <p>Personally appeared before me John F. Grisham Clerk of the County Court in and
                    for said State and County. S.T. Shipley who being duly sworn according to law
                    says: that he was acquainted with Mr. David Guthrie that he lived a near
                    neighbor to him from about the middle the year 1862 up to the time of his
                    removing to Virginia which was some time in the year 1866. that I believed him
                    and always looked upon him as a Union man and a friend ot the Government.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">S T Shipley</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of
                    March 1874. And I have no interest in the prosecution of this Claim.</p>
                <p><name type="other">John F Grisham</name> Clerk</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d22">
                <byline>Letter from David Guthrie to J. T. Harris</byline>
                <p>Fishersville Dec 29/<abbr expan="1874">74</abbr></p>
                <p>Hon J.T. Harris</p>
                <p>Dear Sir, I have been waiting to hear from <orig reg="Jonesboro"
                    >Jonesborough</orig> when it will be necessary for myself to go to Tennessee on
                    other business &amp; then try to get signed to a petition for a rehearing
                    which a friend <orig reg="writes">wrights</orig> to me I can get as many loyal
                    signers as I want &amp; will herein enclose a letter from Mrs Mary J. Ryle
                    now living in <unclear>Renesville</unclear><abbr expan="Tennessee">Tenn</abbr>
                    who boarded at my house nearly all the war time &amp; within say 300 <abbr
                        expan="yards">yds</abbr> the remainder of the time &amp; learning by
                    letter that Congress had rejected my claim set down under &amp; sent me the
                    enclosed statement which I suppose she intends for me to use if necessary She is
                    a Lady of very high standing High minded &amp; I know if I was at <abbr
                        expan="Jonesboro">JB</abbr> at this time that I could see to sign a
                    statement to prove the same. The Rebel <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi></abbr> Jackson lived in fully view of my house
                    so not over 300 yds distant Therefore Jackson <abbr expan="asked">ask<hi
                            rend="super">d</hi></abbr> the favor of me as his neighbor to
                    protect his farm in from injury by Loyal troops with the
                    <unclear>promise</unclear> to do as much for my family (Mrs Ryle then boarding
                    at my house)</p>
                <p>I see I have a Petition paper here ready for the signatures of Loyal persons
                    &amp; suppose will have to go to <orig reg="Jonesboro">Jonesborough</orig>
                    to <orig reg="procure">procuse</orig> signers as a friend there has written to
                    me that I could get as many Loyal signers as I want of attendance to, and
                    suppose I had better go very soon if not too late now but will be governed by
                    your advice in the matter as I know you will direct what think will be best for
                    my interest as I am now a broken down <hi rend="underline">old man</hi> not able
                    now with a very delicate wife to make a living. Your advice and attention will
                    very oblige your <abbr expan="friend">fr.</abbr></p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant"><abbr expan="David">D</abbr> Guthrie</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d23">
                <byline>Letter from David Guthrie to J. S. Harris</byline>
                <p>Fishersville <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> March 13/<abbr expan="1874"
                    >74</abbr></p>
                <p><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr><abbr expan="John"
                        >Jno</abbr> T. Harris</p>
                <p>Dear Sir</p>
                <p>I was so much surprised at the idea of being reported as disloyal I concluded to
                    write to Shelby T Shiply Sherriff of Washington County for number of years both
                    prior &amp; since the war whose House &amp; Home was just across the
                    road from my house in talking distance informing him of the report of disloyalty
                    &amp; He has taken the trouble to get up a certificate from himself and one
                    from Mr <abbr expan="John">Jno</abbr> Boyd also a very close neighbor &amp;
                    saw each other almost every day and have every chance of knowing my true <orig
                        reg="sentiments">sentements</orig> &amp; acts and suppose would have
                    stated the facts of Dr Sevier &amp; myself both being put in prison by the
                    rebels dangerous union men which was certainly no secret (but forgotten) The
                    cruel War I certainly labored against <orig reg="believing">beleiving</orig>
                    that I would <hi rend="underline"><orig reg="lose">loose</orig> greatly</hi> by
                    it which is certainly true and have <hi rend="underline"><orig reg="really"
                            >realy</orig> lost</hi> nearly all I was worth at the commencement of
                    the <hi rend="underline">war</hi> &amp; if I <orig reg="lose"
                        >loose</orig><del hand="h1">the</del> my claim now will place me without means for a
                    support in my 74<hi rend="super">th</hi><add hand="h1" place="inline">year.</add> I hope it is not
                    too late to introduce evidence to prove the report of disloyalty as <orig
                        reg="really">realy</orig> a slander &amp; I must suspect &amp;
                    certain Rebel <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> of that county as that man who I
                    know is since the war is <orig reg="really">realy</orig> an enemy your attention
                    to this matter if not too late will certainly greatly oblige your friend D
                    Guthrie</p>
                <p>PS It can be proven that the rebel army whilst located at
                    <unclear>Renersville</unclear> sent an agent &amp; he
                    <unclear>locked</unclear> up my store by impressing nearly every thing it
                    sontained over $2,000 a greater part in Spanish sole leather. I had succeeded in
                    getting through the rebel lines, but a rebel telegram informed the rebels then
                    at <unclear>Renersville</unclear> in less than two days They afterward took
                    possession of my store room &amp; a dwelling attached &amp; hotel <orig
                        reg="until">untill</orig> the surrender simply because I was Union
                    &amp;c. <name type="claimant">
                        <abbr expan="David Guthrie">D G</abbr>
                    </name></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d24">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>WAR DEPARTMENT ADJUTANT GENERAL'S OFFICE, April 29, 1892.</p>
                <p>Respectfully returned to the Department of Justice, by authority of the Secretary
                    of War, inviting attention to the following report, viz:</p>
                <p>There are on file in this office five vouchers signed by <hi rend="underline">D.
                        Guthrie</hi> (in favor of <hi rend="underline">David Guthrie</hi>) and dated
                    Jonesboro, Haynesville, &amp; Bristol, <abbr expan="Tennessee">Tenn.</abbr>,
                    and Abingdon, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, for rent of house, hauling, one
                    mule, and forage. Also two claims of <hi rend="underline">David Guthrie</hi>, of
                    Washington <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>, <abbr expan="Tennessee"
                    >Tenn.</abbr>, for value of leather &amp;c seized by the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate States">C.S.</abbr></p>
                <p>No further information found.</p>
                <p><name type="other">
                        <unclear>Allen J. Wilkins</unclear>
                    </name> Ass't Adjutant General</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
