<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0107"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0107">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Benjamin T.
                    Bagby, August 3, 1872, Claim No. 15,503</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of benjamin t bagby, august 3 1872 claim no 15 503</title>
        <author>Bagby, Benjamin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 18 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0107</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498332</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Benjamin T. Bagby,
                            August 3, 1872, Claim No. 15503</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of benjamin t bagby, august 3 1872 claim no 15503</title>
            <author>Benjamin T. Bagby</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8544</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1874">1874</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National
                        Government, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0107T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Bagby's claim for 16 horses and 3 cattle was disallowed on the grounds that he
                    served in the Home Guard and sent a substitute into Confederate service. He
                    appealed this decision to the Congressional Court of Claims in 1892, when he was
                    again found disloyal.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>16 Horses worth $150</cell>
                            <cell>$2400.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$2400.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 Cattle worth $30</cell>
                            <cell>90.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>90.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>This claimant, when he filed his petition ought to have known he was entitled to
                    no pay through this commission. He resided in Augusta Co. Va. &amp; was
                    within the conscript age. In 1864 he was in the rebel Home Guard for two months
                    he was employed in the manufacture of horseshoes for the Confederate government.
                    The Confederates paid him for property they took from him. We would the more
                    readily believe him when he says his service in the Home Guard &amp; the
                    putting a substitute in the Confederate Army were compulsory, only, that he
                    swears he never was in the Qr. Master service in the Confederate Govt. and his
                    own witness Tinsdale swear that "he was quarter master", and he further swears
                    he "neither voted for nor against the ordinance of secession" while the record
                    of the votes in Augusta Co. shows that he voted for the adoption of the
                    ordinance.</p>
                <p>Mr. Bagby was disloyal &amp; the claim is disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>Benjamin T. Bagby</byline>
                <p>My name is Benj. T. Bagby, my age 43 years, my residence Staunton V<hi
                        rend="super">a</hi>., in the State of Virginia, and my occupation a
                    Contractor; I am the claimant, and have a beneficial interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>Ques 2. Witness says, I resided during the war on my farm in Augusta Co. Va. My
                    farm contains 400 acres. I had about 200 acres in cultivation. I did not leave
                    the State during the war.</p>
                <p>3 No in full</p>
                <p>4 Witness says, I don't recollect that I took any oath of Allegiance to the
                    Confederate Govt.</p>
                <p>5 Witness says, I took the amnesty oath after the war. Never asked for a pardon.</p>
                <p>6 No in full</p>
                <p>7 No in full</p>
                <p>8 No in full</p>
                <p>9 No in full</p>
                <p>10 No in full</p>
                <p>11 Witness says, No in full</p>
                <p>Witness says, I was forced out as one of the home guard, about the 25 of May 64.
                    I got back home about the 25 of June 64. I rendered no immediate service
                    &amp; was one of the home guard contrary to my wishes.</p>
                <p>13 Witness says, I was conscripted in the Rebel service &amp; furnished a
                    substitute to keep out. I don't think my substitute ever went into the Army, he
                    deserted from Richd. Every man from 18 to 45 years old was subject to military
                    duty, &amp; had it to perform or leave the State. I think it was quite a
                    difficulty to get to the Union lines, during the war.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says, I was never in the <abbr expan="Quarter">Qr</abbr>. <abbr
                        expan="Master">Mr</abbr>. service in the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                    >Confed</abbr>. <abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>16 No in full</p>
                <p>17 No in full</p>
                <p>No in full</p>
                <p>19 Witness says, I manufactured horse shoes for the Confederate Govt. about 2
                    month in 1865. My substitute had failed to keep me out of the army, &amp;
                    the detail was the last resort to keep out of the army, &amp; I got it for
                    that purpose.</p>
                <p>20 No in full</p>
                <p>21 No in full</p>
                <p>22 No in full</p>
                <p>23 No in full</p>
                <p>24 No in full</p>
                <p>25 Witness says, I had ten horses taken from me by the Confederate Authorities,
                    and corn, Wheat &amp; bacon, paid for some of it in Confederate money. I
                    received no pay for the horses.</p>
                <p>26 No in full</p>
                <p>No in full</p>
                <p>28 No in full</p>
                <p>29 No in full</p>
                <p>30 Witness says, I had two brothers in the Confederate army, J.N. &amp; Geo.
                    A. Bagby. One died about 2 weeks ago, the other resides in Staunton Va. Did not
                    furnish them with military equipment, money, or clothing.</p>
                <p>31 No in full</p>
                <p>32 No in full</p>
                <p>33 No in full</p>
                <p>34 No in full</p>
                <p>35 No in full</p>
                <p>36 No in full</p>
                <p>37 No in full</p>
                <p>38 No in full</p>
                <p>39 No in full</p>
                <p>40 Witness says, I was opposed to secession, voted in 1860 for S.A. Douglas, for
                    Presdt. of the U.S. regarding him as a National man. I also voted for the Union
                    Candidates to the Convention, which passed the ordinance of secession. I neither
                    voted for nor against the ordinance of secession. After the Ordinance of
                    secession was adopted, like every one else in Va. I was compelled to go with my
                    State.</p>
                <p>41 Witness says I never did anything voluntarily for the Rebel cause, what
                    service I rendered the Confederate Govt. was through extreme necessity, being
                    forced to do so. And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">B.T. Bagby</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 5th day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>Deposition of B.T. Bagby, claimant, to prove the taking, furnishing &amp;
                    value of his property</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says, I did not see the property taken, mentioned in my petition.
                    I was in the home guard at the time. The property was on my farm, 16 horses
                    &amp; three cattle, When Genl. Hunter came to this place, &amp; they
                    were not there when he left. There was no one <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> them. They were taken by
                    Genl. Averills command, in June 1864. A large no. of soldiers were engaged in
                    taking the property, so I was informed. Five or six of my colored people were
                    present, Hardy, Jim, Harry &amp; Fountain. I do not know whether any officer
                    was present or not. I made no complaint. No receipt was asked for &amp; none
                    given. The property was taken in the day time, I think the army was on the march
                    in the direction of Lynchburg, when my property was taken. The property was all
                    taken from my farm. The horses were all in splendid condition, were from 4 to 7
                    years old. I had sixteen taken, I was speculating in horses, &amp; this lot
                    were selected, &amp; were of no 1 quality. They would have made good
                    Artillery horses, were large draught horses. My colored people told me when I
                    came home that they were put in the artillery service of the U.S. Government.
                    The horses, were worth 150$ each, before and since the war, &amp; would
                    bring it now. I had taken at the same time 3 beef cattle, by Genl. Averills
                    soldiers, were 2 years old, in very good condition, would have weighed about 800
                    lb each or so, worth about 24 cents per the gross. I have never been paid for
                    the property, &amp; have never applied for pay before. I received nothing in
                    exchange. I am the sole owner of the claim. And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">B.T. Bagby</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 5th day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>M.B. Smart</byline>
                <p>Deposition of M.B. Smart to prove the taking, furnishing &amp; value of the
                    property.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says I am 33 years old I reside in Augusta Co. Va. I am a
                    speculator in horses. I was not present &amp; did not see the property taken
                    mentioned in the claimants petition. I was there the day the property was taken.
                    Saw the horses removed to the woods, &amp; cattle also, the property was on
                    the farm of the claimant when it was taken, it was there when Genl. Averills men
                    came on the farm it was not there when they left there was no one else to take
                    them. I think this was in June 1864. Mr. Bagby's Colored men were present when
                    the property was taken. The whole of Genl. Averills command passed through the
                    claimants farm, &amp; must have taken the horses, there was no one else to
                    take them. The horses were all in first rate condition. I don't know their ages,
                    but they were all young horses. I boarded with the claimant &amp; knew the
                    property well &amp; had owned &amp; used some of them. They were worth
                    $150 to $200 each, &amp; would bring that now. He had 3 beef cattle taken at
                    the same time were 2 or 3 years old, don't know their weights or value. All this
                    property belonged to the claimant. He has never been paid for it so far as I
                    know and nothing was left in exchange.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">M. Smart</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Matthew Tisdale</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Mathew Tisdale to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says I am 33 years old, reside in Augusta Co. Va. am a farmer.
                    Lived near him during the war, &amp; saw him nearly every day. I had many
                    talks with him about the war. He seemed to be opposed to the war. He was more
                    opposed to going into the war than any man I ever saw. Said he would spend all
                    the money he had rather than go in the Confed. Army He always said he was
                    opposed to the ordinance of secession. He said, I was as good a Union man. I
                    heard his neighbors curse him &amp; say he ought to be in the Confederate
                    Army. He did nothing for the Confederate Army voluntarily so far as I know he
                    was compelled to go in the home guard. I know he had a detail to make horse
                    shoes for the Confederate Government, to keep him out of the army. He told me he
                    furnished a substitute to keep out of the Rebel army. He was out in the home
                    guard only a short time, &amp; <hi rend="underline">then he was Quarter
                        Master</hi>. He did nothing for the U.S. Govt. so far as I know. I don't
                    know how he voted on the ordinance of secession. I don't know that he owned any
                    Confederate bonds, nor did anything to support Confederate credit. I don't know
                    that he gave any information to Union officers as to the movements of the
                    Confederate armies. I the witness was a Union man all the war. He helped a
                    deserter from the rebel army to avoid detection, by the provost guard. I suppose
                    he would have stayed here had the South gained its independence. And further
                    this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">M M Tisdale</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>Hardy Shaw</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Hardy Shaw Colored to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says, I am 47 years old, reside in Augusta Co. I am a laborer. I
                    was a slave before the war &amp; belonged to the claimant. Was emancipated
                    by Presdt. Lincoln. I lived with the claimant during the war, saw him every day,
                    &amp; he talked to me about the War. He told me to stay with him, that I
                    would be free. He was opposed to the war. He kept all his Colored people away
                    &amp; would not let them work on Confederate fortifications. The Rebel men
                    said he ought to be sent in the rebel army. I know he didn't want to go in the
                    rebel army. He said he was sick, to keep out. All he did for the rebels he was
                    made to do, &amp; that you know he couldn't help. He kept Mr Tisdale
                    &amp; Mr Garrison out of the rebel army. If he owned any Confederate bonds I
                    didn't know it. The claimant was always kind to the colored people, he always
                    said we would be free. I don't know that he told the Union men where the rebels
                    were. I the witness was a Union man. Don't know how he voted on the ordinance of
                    secession. I don't know what he would have done had the rebels whipped. And
                    further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Hardy Shaw</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 5th day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>H. Risk</byline>
                <p>Staunton, Va., Feb. 24 1873</p>
                <p>Hon <abbr expan="Commissioners">Comm'rs</abbr> of Claims</p>
                <p>Gentlemen</p>
                <p>I learn from Jacob Stover &amp; Joseph M. Brown, two good loyalists during
                    the War, and who were residents of the neighborhood in which Benjamin T. Bagby
                    lived, whose claim No. 15503 is non file in your Office, was by no means
                    regarded as a Union man, but on the contrary, he would regarded as a rebel and
                    was extremely tyrannical in the executions of his functions as an officer or
                    attache of the Quarter Master's department. Messers Stover &amp; Brown, are
                    reputable farmers, near Fisherville P.O. on the L. &amp; O. R.R. midway
                    between this City Waynesboro. From all I can gather this case was kept secret,
                    and the sub-agent (Mr. H. Ken) of Howmer &amp; Smith was the clerk in
                    recording the testimony. Mr. Bagby is a gentleman of wealth, and he and I are
                    members of the same church. I mention this last to show that I am not activated
                    by any feeling of hostility to him.</p>
                <p>
                    <del hand="h1">John J. Christian, a colored man of this City, whose claim is likewise
                        filed &amp; No. 7987</del>
                    <del hand="h1">is considered by the colored men here as being the Agent of disloyal
                        whites. They say that it was rumored that a good deal of Tobacco, Etc. was
                        deposited with him, thinking that as he being a colored man, the Union
                        Officers and soldiers would not molest them.</del>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <del hand="h1">I shall make more enquiries and keep you posted.</del>
                </p>
                <p>Very Respectfully</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">H. Risk</name>
                </p>
                <p>Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Commr</abbr>.</p>
                <p>P.S. I am almost daily receiving letters of enquiry in regard to the preparation
                    of claims. I think it a great pity that the limit for the presentation of claims
                    had not been a later date than the 3<hi rend="super">d</hi> March. A great
                    man worthy me will fail to get their petitions in by that day.</p>
                <p>Respectfully</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">H.R.</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>Treasury Department</byline>
                <p>Treasury Department, Office of the Secretary, Washington, D.C. April 25, 1892</p>
                <p>The Honorable The Attorney General.</p>
                <p>Sir:</p>
                <p>In answer to your request of the 8th instant in the case of Benjamin T. Bagby
                    against the United States, No. 8544 Congressional, I have the honor to state
                    that the name of Benj. T. Bagby appears in a list of those voting for the
                    ordinance of secession in Augusta County, Virginia.</p>
                <p>It is presumed that the original poll list of Augusta County is in the custody of
                    the county clerk.</p>
                <p>There is herewith transmitted a duly authenticated copy of a certificate issued
                    at Staunton, Virginia, to Benjamin F. Bagby, endorsed Benjamin T. Bagby. See 341
                    Virginia Certificate, B.</p>
                <p>Respectfully yours,</p>
                <p><name type="other">OL <unclear>Gouldy</unclear></name>, Acting Secretary</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>Confederate States of America Depository Office</byline>
                <p>Confederate States of America Depository's Office</p>
                <p>Staunton Apr 1, 1864</p>
                <p>This will certify, That Benjamin F. Bagby has paid in at this office Thirty two
                    hundred dollars, for which amount Registered Bonds, of the Confederate States of
                    America, bearing interest from this date, at the rate of four percent per annum,
                    will be issued to him under the "Act to reduce the currency and to authorize a
                    new issue of notes and bonds," approved February 17, 1864, upon the surrender if
                    this certificate at this office.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">A.F. Kinney</name>
                </p>
                <p>Depository</p>
                <p>For value recd. I, B. T. Bagby assign unto Mr. H H Lynn Coll in Payment of Taxes
                    the within certificate of stock of the Confederate States of America and hereby
                    authorize the Register of the Treasury to transfer said stock on the Books of
                    the Department.</p>
                <p>May 27, 1864</p>
                <p>Executed before me <unclear>A Lynn</unclear> D.C. 14 District</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">B.T. Bagby</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
