<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0532"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0532">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Waller Odor,
                    1875, Claim No. 8999</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of waller odor, 1875 claim no 8999</title>
        <author>Odor, Waller</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 14 kilobytes</num>
      </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0532</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498419</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Waller Odor, 1875,
                            Claim No. 8999</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of waller odor, 1875 claim no 8999</title>
            <author>Waller Odor</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, Claim #8999</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1875">1875</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Enlistment, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0532T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Waller Odor filed this claim in 1875 for $175, claiming Union forces under
                    General Sheridan took one horse in 1864. Waller was a 62 year old blacksmith in
                    Mossy Creek. His son served in the Confederate Army. He was threatened for his
                    Union sentiments during the war and served as a postmaster after the war's
                    conclusion. The commission allowed $150.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Horse</cell>
                            <cell>$175.00</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The claimant is now about 65 years of age and a farmer. During the war he resided
                    in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>.
                    The evidence shows that he was loyal to the Union cause. Did not vote on the
                    ratification of the ordinance of secession. His son was in the Confederate army.
                    Mr. Odor tried to keep him out. He was denounced by the Confederates on account
                    of his Unionism. Since the war he has been postmaster and has taken the test
                    oath. Inquiries have been made by our special agent. This report confirms the
                    claimant, allegations of loyalty. We find him loyal.</p>
                <p>In 1864 a fine horse was taken from the claimant by <abbr expan="United States"
                        >U. S.</abbr> troops and for army use. No voucher was given &amp; no
                    claim has before been presented for payment.</p>
                <p>We recmomend the payment of $150.00</p>
                <p><name type="other">A. O. Aldis</name>, <name type="other">Orange Ferris</name>,
                        <name type="other">J. B. Howell</name></p>
                <p><abbr expan="Commissioners">Commrs.</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Waller Odor</byline>
                <p>Answer to first Interrogatroy: I am 62 years old and reside in
                    <del hand="h1">Rockingham</del> Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>. <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi>.</abbr> I am a blacksmith,
                    Have lived where I now am for 20 years.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Witness says. I never passed the military or naval lines of the US
                    &amp; entered the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4. Witness says. I never took an oath of allegiance to the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr>. <abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>5. Witness says. I took the amnesty oath in 1865 at Harrisonburg have not been
                    pardoned.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6. Witness says. I never was directly nor indirectly connected with the
                    civil service of the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> States. never had
                    any connection whatever with any department of the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed</abbr>. <abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>. Never was in its Army
                    or Navy &amp; never furnished a substitute for either.</p>
                <p>14. Witness says. I never was engaged in blockade running or illicit traffic
                    between the lines.</p>
                <p>15. Witness says. Did not leave the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr>.
                    States at any time during the war.</p>
                <p>17. Witness says. Never was arrested by either the <abbr expan="United States"
                    >US</abbr> or <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr>. <abbr expan="Governments"
                        >Govts</abbr>.</p>
                <p>18. Witness says. Had no property taken by the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                    >Confed</abbr>. <abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>19. Witness says. I was told I ought to be shot on account of my Union
                    sentiments.</p>
                <p>22. Witness says. I did nothing for the <abbr expan="United States">US</abbr> its
                    army or Navy. I had no opportunity.</p>
                <p>23. Witness says. I had a son and several nephews in the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr>. army. I did nothing to supply them with
                    money or equipment they were in the Confederate army against my wish. My son
                    went in against my protest. I wanted him to enter the Union lines.</p>
                <p>24. Witness says. I never owned any <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr>.
                    bonds. Never did anything to support the credit of the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed</abbr>. States.</p>
                <p>32. Witness says, I am not and never have been under any disabilites imposed by
                    the 14th amendment to the constitution. I have been <abbr expan="United States"
                        >U. S.</abbr> postmaster since the war, took the <hi rend="underline">"iron
                        clad"</hi> oath to qualify.</p>
                <p>33. Witness says. At the beginning of the war I sympathized with the Union. I did
                    not vote either for or against the ordinance of secession. After its adoption I
                    adhered to the cause of the Union and did not go with my State.</p>
                <p>34. Witness says, I have always and constantly sympathized with the cause of the
                    Union. I have never done anything to injure its cause and was ready at all times
                    to aid it to the extent of my ability &amp; further this deponent saith not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Waller Odor</name>
                </p>
                <p><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr>. 26th 1871</p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 26th day of <abbr expan="October"
                    >Oct</abbr>. 1871</p>
                <p>W. G. Riley, United States Commissioner and a special <abbr expan="Commissioner"
                        >Com</abbr>. for the State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super"
                            >a</hi></abbr>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Isaac Miller</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Isaac Miller to prove property</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Witness says. I am 69 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super"
                        >a</hi></abbr>. I am a laborer. I saw the horse of the claimant in
                    possession of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> troops.</p>
                <p>4. Witness says. The property was taken from the premises of the claimant in 1864
                    by officers and Soldiers of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> army
                    under the command of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Sheridan.</p>
                <p>6. Witness say. Officers were present when I saw the horse taken in the service
                    of the <abbr expan="United States">U. S.</abbr> Army and a United States soldier
                    on him.</p>
                <p>10. Witness says. I think the horse was taken for the use of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U. S.</abbr> army.</p>
                <p>15. Witness say. The horse was a very fine one in good condition he was about 5
                    years old. I think he was worth $200.</p>
                <p>19. Witness says. I think the horse was taken for the necessary use of the <abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>. and the <abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt</abbr>. should pay for it, and further this deponent saith not</p>
                <p><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr>. 26th 1871</p>
                <p>Isaac X <add hand="h1" place="inline">his mark</add> Miller</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 26th day of <abbr expan="October"
                        >Oct</abbr> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com</abbr>. for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>George Craun</byline>
                <p>Deposition of George Craun to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Witness says. I am 57 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super"
                        >a</hi>.</abbr> I am a farmer. I have known the claimant 40 years. Lived
                    near him. Saw him nearly every day and talked with him about the war. I regarded
                    him as a truly loyal man and he was regarded by this neighbors. He did nothing
                    for the <abbr expan="United States">U. S.</abbr><abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt</abbr>. He had no opportunity. he did not do anything for the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr>. States. Never knew him molested or
                    threatened on account of him Union sentiments. I think he was too loyal to the
                        <abbr expan="United States">U. S</abbr>. <abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt.</abbr> to have remained in the South had the Confederates succeeded
                    &amp; further this deponent sayeth not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">George Craun</name>
                </p>
                <p>Oct. 26th 1871</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 26th day of <abbr expan="October"
                        >Oct</abbr> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com</abbr>. for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>William Evers</byline>
                <p>Deposition of William Evers to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1. Witness says. I am 48 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co</abbr>. <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>. I
                    am a farmer. I have known the claimant 15 years. Lived near him. Saw him often
                    and talked to him about the war. I regarded him as a loyal man to the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U. S.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr>
                    &amp; he was so regarded by his neighbors. Never knew him to do any thing
                    for the <abbr expan="United States">U.S</abbr>. <abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt.</abbr> &amp; he never did anything for the Confederate <abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>. Never knew him threatened or molested on
                    account of his Union sentiments. I have heard him swear he did not want to live
                    here if the South <orig reg="seceded">suceeded</orig>. he was too loyal to have
                    stayed here &amp; further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Oct. 26th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">William Evers</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 26th day of <abbr expan="October"
                        >Oct</abbr>. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a.</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>S.E. Chamberlin</byline>
                <p>Harrisonburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr><abbr expan="September"
                    >Sept</abbr>. 25<hi rend="super">th</hi>, 1874</p>
                <p>Commissioners of Claims</p>
                <p>Gentlemen<lb/>Waller Odor claimant No. 8999 of Mossy Creek, Long Glade, Augusta
                        <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>., is a blacksmith by occupation and is now
                    carrying on business there. After careful inquiry of those knowing him well I
                    feel satisfied that he was a Union man during the war, he is a quiet man and as
                    far as I am able to learn, he would not put in a claim against government unless
                    he believed it just.</p>
                <p>Very Respectfully Yours</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">S. E. Chamberlin</name>
                </p>
                <p>Special Agent</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
