<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0528"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0528">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Christian
                    Landes, 1877, Claim No. 17,923</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of christian landes, 1877 claim no 17 923</title>
        <author>Landes, Christian</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">33</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0528</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498415</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Christian Landes,
                            1877, Claim No. 17,923</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of christian landes, 1877 claim no 17 923</title>
            <author>Christian Landes</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #17923</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1877">1877</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Enlistment, Family, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0528T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Christian Landes filed this claim in 1877 for $444, claiming Union forces under
                    General Sheridan took 3 horses, 2 bushels of hay, 2 cattle, and sheep in 1865.
                    Christian was a farmer in Mount Sidney and a member of the Dunker Church. He had
                    two sons forcefully conscripted into Confederate service. Included is testimony
                    on the Dunkers political and pacifist beliefs as well as testimony from John
                    Yates, the local Postmaster and an "Ironclad Oath" taker. The commission allowed
                    $300.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 Horses &amp; 2 bus hay</cell>
                            <cell>$360.00</cell>
                            <cell>$300.00</cell>
                            <cell>$60.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 Cattle &amp; 2 Sheep</cell>
                            <cell>$84.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$84.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimant belongs to the fraternity of Dunkards who eschew Politics and war. He
                    was opposed to secession and in favor at the Union. He did not go to the
                    Election when the Ordinance of <orig reg="secession">succession</orig> was
                    submitted. He advised his son and sons in law to go North and aided them to do
                    so. His neighbors testify to his loyal conversation &amp; reputation. We
                    find him loyal. Two of the Horses were taken by Gen Hunter's <unclear>forces
                    in</unclear> 1864, and the other by Gen Sheridan's Command in 1865. He abandons
                    the claim for the Cattle, on the ground that although he had bargained for them
                    he had not paid for them and they had not been delivered.</p>
                <p>We allow $300.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name>, <name
                        type="other">O. Ferris</name><abbr expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of
                    Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Christian Landes</byline>
                <p>In answer to the First General Interrogatory, the Deponent says: My name is
                    Christian Landes, my age 64 years, my residence Augusta County, in the State of
                    Virginia, and my occupation a Farmer; I am the claimant, and have beneficial
                    interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>2 I lived all the time on my own farm at Mount Sidney in Augusta County.</p>
                <p>3 &amp; 4 No sir.</p>
                <p>5 Yes sir. I went to Staunton and took it after the war.</p>
                <p>6 to 24 inclusive No sir. I had nothing at all to do with them in any way. My age
                    exempted me from military duty and saved me much trouble.</p>
                <p>25 Yes, the Confederates camped on my place at Mount Sidney for 4 or 5 days in
                    the fall of 1864 and used a quantity of corn from my fields. They never paid me
                    anything for it.</p>
                <p>26 Yes. When I have been asked by the Confederate soldiers to feed their horses
                    and have told them I could not do it, they have threatened to burn my barn down.</p>
                <p>27 to 29 inclusive no sir</p>
                <p>30 Yes, I have one nephew named Levi Landes, two sons named Jacob and Daniel
                    Landes. Jacob was <unclear>in the second</unclear><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del><unclear>he carried to
                        the county in a sick bed</unclear> after he denied the Confederate cause and
                    carried him away by force. He was 19 years old when he went. He was forced to go
                    both times. Daniel was conscripted in 1865. He was living near my residence at
                    the time, he was about 30 years old. I gave neither of them any
                        <unclear>equipment</unclear> nor assistance when in the service, and would
                    have kept them out if I could have done so.</p>
                <p>31 to 39 inclusive No Sir</p>
                <p>40 I sympathized with the Union Cause. I thought the rebellion was wrong. I did
                    not vote on the question of Secession. Our church held that the brethren might
                    not meddle with politics, and recommended that we abstain from voting or
                    attending elections. After the state <orig reg="seceded">seceeded</orig> I still
                    held for the union.</p>
                <p>41 I was for the Union from first to last. I could never see any good cause for
                    the rebellion. I never did anything against the cause of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> and was always glad of its success. I am a
                    member of the Dunkard Church.</p>
                <p>44 I am a native born Citizen of the United States and I have not <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> through
                    Bankruptcy.</p>
                <p>In answer to the interrogatories as to the Property deponent says</p>
                <p>I was present and saw my property taken, all except the cattle.</p>
                <p>1 &amp; 2 The Black horse and bay mare were both taken <hi rend="super"
                        >at the same time one</hi> from a boy I had plowing with them. He was
                    plowing with two and one of them was taken and another from the field. They were
                    taken by the army of <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Hunter in the summer of
                    1864, when they were passing through here towards Staunton. The main body had
                    passed along and two soldiers came back while other portions of the army were
                    passing. There was some 20 or 30 men stopped while the horses were being taken
                    and they all passed on taking horses from other persons on the way. The black
                    horse I valued at $125 and the bay mare at $135. They were both good animals and
                    in good condition.</p>
                <p>The cattle were taken from the farm of Mr Searight about 4 miles from my place. I
                    had purchased them from him for to butcher, and was to take them at a certain
                    day, but did not get them away and they were driven away by a portion of the
                    army of <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Sheridan in <abbr expan="September"
                        >Sept</abbr> 1864 as I am informed and expect to prove. The cattle were
                    purchased by weight and I forget the exact amount, but think it was about $80 or
                    $85 for the two.</p>
                <p>The dark brown horse was taken from the stable on my farm at Mount Sidney, by a
                    portion of Gen Sheridans army in March 1865 while going towards Staunton.</p>
                <p>The Stable was locked and the men broke the door open while I was in my yard,
                    across the road from the farm.</p>
                <p>I urged them not to take him, but they told me the less I said, the better for
                    me. There was a large company of men in the party, probably 100 or more. I
                    valued him at $100. He was an excellent farm horse.</p>
                <p>There were officers with the party who knew of the taking. I spoke to one of them
                    about it, but it did no good, and further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Christian Landes</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Elizabeth Garber</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Elizabeth Garber as to the taking of Property</p>
                <p>I am 33 years old, I live in the same house with the claimant. I am his daughter.
                    During the war, I lived in the <hi rend="super">same</hi> place where I do
                    now until August 1864 when I went west where my husband was.</p>
                <p>In the summer of 1864 when the Army of <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Hunter
                    passed through this place I saw some of the soldiers go to a field near the
                    house where a boy was plowing corn and take the harness from one of the horses
                    and put a <orig reg="saddle">sadle</orig> on him and ride him away another party
                    next into a field on the other side of the road and took the bay mare from the
                    field saddled her and rode her away. Also, both of them were taken along with
                    the army. They did not leave any other horses in places of them.</p>
                <p>The army was a portion of them passing through here at the time the horses were
                    taken. My father was at the house on the porch at the time. It was the first
                    union army that had passed this way during the war. And further deponent saith
                    not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Elizabeth Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>John M. Perry</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John M Perry as to the taking of Property</p>
                <p>I am 50 years old, a farmer, live near Banks Mill in Augusta County <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p><del hand="h1">D</del> I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in this claim.</p>
                <p>During the war I was present and saw a lot of cattle driven from the farm of John
                    and George Searight by a portion of the Army of Gen Sheridan, in the fall of the
                    year 1864. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know how many cattle were in the lot
                    driven away. I supposed they were Mr Searights cattle. I did not know that Mr
                        <orig reg="Landes">Landis</orig> had purchased any of them. I heard Mr
                    Searight talking about them afterwards, and he said he had sold two or three
                    head to Mr <orig reg="Landes">Landis</orig>, I forget which, and that they were
                    left there at his Mr <orig reg="Landes'">Landis</orig> risk, and that he should
                    hold him responsible for them.</p>
                <p>I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know what kind of cattle Mr <orig reg="Landes"
                        >Landis</orig> had bought. Some of those driven away were cows. Some were
                    dry and in good order. The troops were gathering up stock all about the
                    neighborhood at the time and these were driven away with the rest. And further
                    deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John M. Perry</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Lydia Miller</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Lydia Miller as to the taking of Property</p>
                <p>I am 37 years old. I live 4 miles from Mt Sidney in Augusta County <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>. During the war I lived on my fathers farm. The
                    claimant is my father.</p>
                <p>I was present and saw all his property taken except the cattle.</p>
                <p>The black horse was taken from before the plow while plowing corn in the summer
                    of 1864, by a portion of <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr><orig reg="Hunter's"
                        >Hunters</orig> command while passing on the Pike towards Staunton. One of
                    the men put a saddle on him and rode him away with the rest of the Army. Our
                    farm is immediately on the pike and the horse was plowing close by when taken.
                    He was a good sized animal and an excellent saddle horse. He was valued at $125
                    when taken.</p>
                <p>The bay mare was taken at the same time from a pasture field across the road by
                    some of the same troops who went into the field and caught her. And one of them
                    rode her away with the rest of the army. She was a medium sized animal, a good
                    worker and rider. She was worth rather more than the horse.</p>
                <p>The brown horse was taken in the spring of the year 1865 a short time before the
                    surrender of Gen Lee by a party of Union cavalry, passing up the Pike toward
                    Staunton. There was a large party of them; they were from 1 <abbr
                        expan="O'clock">Oclk</abbr> until after dark in passing, marching close to
                    each other.</p>
                <p>The horse was taken from our stable and rode away by one of the party.</p>
                <p>I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know who was in command of the troops. I
                    understood they belonged to <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr><orig
                        reg="Sheridan's">Sheridans</orig> army.</p>
                <p>He was very good horse, was valued at about 125.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Lydia Miller</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Abner Shumate</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Abner <orig reg="Shumate">Shumake</orig> as to the Loyalty of
                    Christian Landes</p>
                <p>I am 50 years old a merchant in M<hi rend="super">t</hi> Sidney. I am not
                    related to the claimant, and have no interest in his claim.</p>
                <p>I have known the Claimant 45 years, have lived within half a mile of him nearly
                    all the time, was near him during the whole period of the war. I have heard him
                    talk many times on matters connected with the rebellion. He was opposed to
                    secession and spoke against it as long as it was safe to do so. He <orig
                        reg="always">alway</orig> held that the rebellion was wrong and that it
                    could not succeed. Said he was certain the south would be overrun and the
                    rebellion crushed. He regarded me as a union man and spoke freely with me;
                    sometimes we were alone and sometimes in company with other loyal men, but not
                    publicly.</p>
                <p>Whenever the Union forces were victorious in battle, the claimant was rejoiced
                    and would express it when I saw him.</p>
                <p>He was generally known and regarded as a union man all through the war. And
                    further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Abner Shumake</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>John Yates</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Yates as to the Loyalty of Christian Landes</p>
                <p>I am 65 years old. I am Postmaster at Mt. Sidney. I am an "Iron Clad" Union man.
                        <hi rend="super">I</hi> was imprisoned in Castle Thunder for aiding
                    refugees across the lines, and was sent form there to Staunton for trial and
                    before the time came on, I was released by the Army of <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen</abbr> Sheridan. I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in
                    his claim.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant 30 years lived about half a mile from him, during the
                    whole period of the war, except when a prisoner. I had frequent conversations
                    with him about secession and the war and all such matters, and he always
                    expressed union sentiments when talking with me. he was opposed to secession and
                    the war. He thought as I did about it, that it was an unrighteous affair, and
                    that it could not prosper. He was a decided union man at heart but like most of
                    us was obliged to be very prudent and cautious in his expressions. <hi
                        rend="super">In consequence of his union sentiments, his barn was not
                        burnt by Sheridan.</hi> And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Yates</name>
                </p>
                <p>Claimant is a very simple minded and peacable old Dunker. Never meddles with
                    public affairs. Is perfectly <orig reg="harmless">harmles</orig> and innocent.</p>
                <p>Isaac P. Baldwin Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>Christian Landes</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Claimant</p>
                <p>1 My name is Christian <orig reg="Landes">Landis</orig>. I am 68 years old, a
                    farmer and live at M<hi rend="super">t</hi> Sidney where I have resided 26
                    years.</p>
                <p>2 I am the claimant.</p>
                <p>3 I was born and raised in this county.</p>
                <p>4 Where I now live</p>
                <p>5 I sympathized with the north all the time from beginning to end.</p>
                <p>6 I never did.</p>
                <p>7 &amp; 8 I was willing and I did give all the aid in my power. I sent my son
                    and two sons in law to the north through the mountains, and one of my daughters
                    down the valley and they all <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> north until the war
                    closed.</p>
                <p>9 Two cousins of my first wife named Wenger and several others one a David <orig
                        reg="Landes">Landis</orig>.</p>
                <p>10 No Sir</p>
                <p>11 I gave the union troops when camped near me at the time of the burning hay,
                    Oats, bacon and provisions, and my wife cooked for them all day.</p>
                <p>12 I stood by the union all the time. I am no <orig reg="politician"
                    >polititian</orig>. I belong to the Dunker Church. I did not do anything.</p>
                <p>13 I adhered to the union all the time.</p>
                <p>14 I was always sorry for the defeat, and glad of the success of the union forces
                    as I believed that was the only way to peace, and because the union cause was
                    right. Of course I was sorry for so much slaughter and suffering.</p>
                <p>15 I never asked for any</p>
                <p>16 I never had occasion to take it.</p>
                <p>17 John Yates, Abner Shumate, Daniel and John Miller, John Wampler &amp;
                    Joseph Click were all union men living within one to two miles of here. Some of
                    them wil testify to my loyalty.</p>
                <p>18 They threatened various things if I did not feed their horses, for nothing. I
                    did <hi rend="super">not</hi> want to do it.</p>
                <p>19 No sir.</p>
                <p>20 They took from me 100 bushels of wheat I had at Klines Mill, they never paid
                    me a cent. They made me give them a tenth of my crop one year.</p>
                <p>21 to 35 No Sir, to each and every question.</p>
                <p>36 My youngest son was conscripted the second year of the war. He was taken by
                    armed men from my house and was killed in the Wilderness. He was taken against
                    my will: I went to M<hi rend="super">t</hi> Jackson and also to Staunton
                    to try to get him off, but could not succeed. His name was Jacob <orig
                        reg="Landes">Landis</orig>. I had two <hi rend="super"
                        >cousins</hi><del hand="h1">Nephews</del> in the service also, one named Henry and one
                    Daniel <orig reg="Landes">Landis</orig>. They lived about 2 miles from me. I had
                    nothing to do with their going, and contributed nothing towards their support
                    while in the service.</p>
                <p>37 &amp; 38 No Sir</p>
                <p>39 I took some kind of an oath after the war in Staunton. I reckon it was the
                    amnesty oath.</p>
                <p>40 to 43 No Sir, to each question.</p>
                <p>44 I have no recollection of voting during the war. There was no union
                    candidates. I did not vote at all on the secession question at eather election.
                    Our church advises us to take no part in elections.</p>
                <p>45 to 51 No Sir to each question.</p>
                <p>Concerning the property deponent says During the war I carried on buchering and
                    had purchased the <del hand="h1">three</del><hi rend="super">two</hi> cattle charged
                    in my claim from a man named George Searight who had agreed to deliver to me
                    three head, but butchered one of them himself, and before the others were
                    delivered to me they were taken by the Union forces, and Searight charged them
                    to me and insisted that I should pay for them because I had not taken them away
                    at the time agreed on, so I charged them to the government. I have since been
                    advised that he cannot compel me to pay for them, and I therefore have thought
                    it best to abandon the claim for the cattle, <orig reg="although">altho</orig> I
                    have had no settlement with him.</p>
                <p>The charge for the cattle is Abandoned.</p>
                <p>The last horse that was taken from me, was a dark brown, or some would say a
                    black horse. He was taken by a party of Union Cavalrymen from my stable. They
                    broke the door of the stable open, and one of the men rode him away with the
                    others going towards Staunton. This was in the spring of 1865. He was a good
                    horse worth at least $100. And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Christian Landes</name>
                </p>
                <p>Isaac P. Baldwin Special Comm<hi rend="super">r</hi></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                
                <byline>Elizabeth J. Landes</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Claimants wife concerning property.</p>
                <p>My name is Elizabeth J. <orig reg="Landes">Landis</orig> I am 40 years old. I am
                    the wife of claimant and live with him. I was married to him in 1871.</p>
                <p>In the Spring of 1865 I was living with my own family keeping house about one
                    mile from the claimant on the pike towards Staunton. Claimants <hi
                        rend="super">first</hi> wife was then living, and my sister was living
                    with them where <del hand="h1">where</del> we now live. Claimant had at that time a dark
                    brown or black horse which my sister used to ride when she came to see me, and
                    which I used to see at claimants place very often, and knew the horse well.</p>
                <p>In the spring of 1865, I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> remember the month, a
                    party of union cavalry, said to be a part of <orig reg="Sheridan's"
                    >Sheridans</orig> Army passed up the pike going towards Staunton; and in passing
                    my residence, I saw the brown or black horse of claimants with them, rode by one
                    of the men in uniform, and called the <pb n="19"/> attention of one of my
                    sisters who was visiting with me to the horse, saying "there is Mr <orig
                        reg="Landes">Landis</orig>'s black horse that you have rode many a time."
                    She looked and immediately recognized the horse as belonging to claimant. There
                    were probably two or three hundred in the party, and they all passed on towards
                    Staunton which was the last I ever saw of them. He was a veery fine looking
                    horse, and was called a good one by those who knew him. I saw no other of
                    claimants property taken.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Elizabeth J. <orig reg="Landes">Landis</orig></name> her
                    mark</p>
                <p>Isaac P. Baldwin Special Commr</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                
                <byline>John Miller</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Miller</p>
                <p>1 My name is John Miller. I am 64 years old. I am a farmer and a preacher in the
                    Dunker Church and live near Mount Sidney in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> where I have lived for 30 years
                    past.</p>
                <p>2 I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in the success of his
                    claim</p>
                <p>53 to 55 I have known him for 30 years or more, have lived within about 1 1/2
                    miles of the Dunker Church. I frequently saw him during the war, sometimes at Mt
                    Sidney sometimes at church and elsewhere.</p>
                <p>56 I had some conversation with him <hi rend="super">on</hi> matters
                    relating to war but not much. He is not much of a talker at anytime, is more
                    than ordinary quiet. When I did talk with him he generally expressed union
                    sentiments, but was rather reticent except when in the company of well known
                    union men.</p>
                <p>57 I was not a witness to any acts of his that would indicate his sentiments I
                    have understood that he favored the going north of several members of his family
                    and that they did escape and remained away until the close of the war.</p>
                <p>58 &amp; 59 I do not. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> believe he did any
                    thing in aid of the rebellion that he was not of need to do.</p>
                <p>60 I have never heard him spoekn of a great deal he did not meddle with politics.
                    If all were like him there would have been no war. He was generally regarded as
                    a union man by those who knew him as far as I know. And I think he was in favor
                    of the Union cause. I am quite sure he had no sympathy with the Confederate
                    cause.</p>
                <p>61 Abner Shumate John Yates, Joseph Glick John Wampler &amp; Daniel Miller
                    were all good union people.</p>
                <p>62 I have had a claim allowed by the commrs of claims. I was a decided Union man
                    at all times.</p>
                <p>63 to 65 At the time of the burning his barn was spared.</p>
                <p>And further saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Miller</name>
                </p>
                <p>Attest Isaac P. Baldwin Special Commr</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                
                <byline>John Wampler</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Wampler</p>
                <p>1 My name is John Wampler I am 49 years old, a farmer and live near Mt Sidney
                    where I have resided over 20 years.</p>
                <p>2 I m not related to the claimant and have no interest in the success of his
                    claim.</p>
                <p>53 to 55 I have known him about 30 years, part of hte time intimately. We are
                    members of the same church and often met during the war.</p>
                <p>56 We had some considerable talk about the war and such matters. He was opposed
                    to the war and spoke against it, and against secession. I <orig reg="can't"
                    >cant</orig> relate conversation, but from his language I always took him to be
                    a union man. When the news of a battle came, it was most always in favor of the
                    rebels. I remember his saying you <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> believe that
                    side, I expect when we get the news it will be that the Confederates were
                    whipped. He expressed union sentiments when speaking of these things. He is not
                    much of a talker at any time, and we all had to be on our guard in those days.</p>
                <p>He had one son and two sons in law and one daughter who went north during the war
                    and remained there until the war closed. Some of them started from claimants
                    home and he helped them away. I know this because <orig reg="they">the</orig>
                    were started on horseback but found they could not make it, and sent the horses
                    back to claimants house and then took to the mountains.</p>
                <p>58 &amp; 59 No Sir</p>
                <p>60 He was regarded generally by those who knew him as a union man. I have heard
                    him called a union man by the secesh and probably by others I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> remember; the members of our church were generally union
                    people. There were some secesh among them.</p>
                <p>61 John Yates, Abner Shumate, John Miller, Daniel Miller, Joseph Click were all
                    union people.</p>
                <p>62 I profess to have been one.</p>
                <p>65 Claimants farm was spard during the burning. And further saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Wampler</name>
                </p>
                <p>Attest Isaac P. Baldwin Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Commr</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d17">
                
                <byline>Commissioners' Note Regarding Claim</byline>
                <p>In the absence of any special commissioner, the Commissioners authorize the
                    taking of further testimony in this case by the clerk of the nearest court of
                    record, but strictly in conformity to the rules for taking testimony for the
                    uses of the Commissioner.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Charles">Chas</abbr> F. Benjamin Clerk.</p>
                <p>Commissioners Office, Harrisonburg Virginia, November 22<hi rend="super"
                    >d</hi> 1876</p>
                <p>Depositions taken, sworn to, and subscribed before the undersigned G. F. Compton,
                    a Commissioner in and for the County Court of Rockingham County Virginia to be
                    used as evidence for, and in behalf of, Christian Landes, upon <del hand="h1">a</del>
                    Claim No. 17923, before The Commissioners of Claims, under Act of Congress of
                    the Untied States of date March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>Christian Landes, a witness of lawful age, introduced in behalf of himself, being
                    first duly sworn by Affirmation, deposes, and says,</p>
                <p>Answer To Question No. 14, on annexed printed Sheet.</p>
                <p>I was always in favor of peace, and while I was grieved to see so many persons
                    killed or wounded, I believed in sustaining the Union, and rejoiced in the final
                    termination of the War, but I was too old to take arms, and remained quietly at
                    home.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent says not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Christian Landes</name>
                </p>
                <p>Attest G. F. Compton Com<hi rend="super">r</hi>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d18">
                
                <byline>Andrew M. Yates</byline>
                <p>At the same time and place. Andrew M. Yates, a witness introduced in behalf of
                    Christian Landes, being first duly sworn <hi rend="super">by
                    Affirmation</hi> deposes says.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 52, on annnexed printed Sheet. In Christian Landes' farm.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 53. I have known him about 20 years, and have been intimate
                    with him during the whole time.</p>
                <p>Answer to <abbr expan="Question">Quest.</abbr> 54. I lived one fourth of a mile
                    from him during the late war and still live at the same place.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 55. I met him a number of times, perhaps once in every two
                    months, or oftener.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 56 I had frequent conversations with him during the war, about
                    the war, and he always expressed himself as a Union man. I can remember his
                    exact words but he always spoke in favor of Union Cause, and desired that there
                    should be no separation.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 57. I know of no particular act done by the Claimant he was an
                    old man, and stayed at home.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 58. I do not.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 59 I have heard John Yates, Peter Sheets + Abner Shumate speak
                    of his being a Union man.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 60 People in the neighborhood said he was a Union man.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 61. John Yates, Abner Shumate &amp; Peter Sheets were all
                    Union men during the War.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 62 Not at first, I lent that way toward the close of war.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 63 No Sir I do not.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 64 I know his language was laways against the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Answer to Question 65 No Sir, I do not</p>
                <p>And further this deponent says not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">A. M. Yates</name>
                </p>
                <p>Attest G. F. Compton Com<hi rend="super">r</hi>.</p>
                <p>I G. F. Compton do hereby certify that the foregoing depositions were taken sworn
                    to and subscribed before me at the time, and place named in the Caption. Given
                    under my hand as Commissioner of the County Court of Rockingham County, this
                        22<hi rend="super">nd</hi> day of November 1876.</p>
                <p><name type="other">G. F. Compton</name>, Com<hi rend="super">r</hi><abbr
                        expan="Chancery">Chy.</abbr><abbr expan="Court">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Circuit">Ct</abbr><abbr expan="Rockingham">Ro.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr></p>
                <p>Virginia, Rockingham County, to wit-</p>
                <p>I, Joseph F. Logan Clerk of the County Court of Rockingham County a Court of
                    Record, for said County &amp; State do hereby certify that G. F. Compton the
                    person before who the foregoing depositions were taken, and whose name is signed
                    to the foregoing Certificate, is a Commissioner of the County Court of
                    Rockingham County duly authorized, empowered, and sworn, to perform the duties
                    of such Commissioner.</p>
                <p>Given under my hand and the Seal of my said County Court of Rockingham County
                    this 22<hi rend="super">d</hi> day of November 1876, and the year of the
                    Commonwealth.</p>
                <p><name type="other">J. F. Logan</name>, Clerk of the County Court of Rockingham
                    County</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
