<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0537"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0537">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of David Wampler,
                    1871, Claim No. 2559</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of david wampler, 1871 claim no 2559</title>
        <author>Wampler, David</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 17 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0537</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498424</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of David Wampler, 1871,
                            Claim No. 2559</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of david wampler, 1871 claim no 2559</title>
            <author>David Wampler</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #2559</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0537T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>David Wampler filed this claim in 1871 for $350, claiming Union forces under
                    General Sheridan took two horses and two cows in 1864. David was a 70 year old
                    farmer. He helped his son furnish a substitute to avoid Confederate service. He
                    was also threatened with arrest and imprisonment because of his Union
                    sentiments. The commission allowed $275.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bay Horse</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One grey Horse</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Two cows</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimants loyalty is established by his own testimony and that of Daniel Long. He
                    is 70 years of age. He talked a great deal against the Confederates, and took
                    care of wounded soldiers of the Union Army, and was regarded as a Union man by
                    all of his neighbors.</p>
                <p>The property for which he claims compensation was taken in 1864, from Claimant
                    farm, by soldiers of Sheridan's command.</p>
                <p>We allow the sum of two hundred and seventy five dollars.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>David Wampler</byline>
                <p>I am 70 years old reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>. I am a farmer. I
                    have lived where I now do for forty years.</p>
                <p>Ques 3. Witness says: I never passed the military or Naval lines of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> &amp; entered the rebel lines</p>
                <p>4. Witness says, I never took an oath of allegiance to the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr> States.</p>
                <p>5. Witness says: I took the amnesty oath in 1865 at New Hope. Have not been
                    pardoned</p>
                <p>6. Witness says: I never was directly nor indirectly connected with the civil
                    service of the Confederate service</p>
                <p>7. Witness says, I never held any place of honor profit or trust under the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr> States</p>
                <p>8. Witness says: I never held any clerkship agency or employment of any kind
                    under the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr> States</p>
                <p>9. Witness says, I never was in any capacity in the military or Naval service of
                    the Confederate States</p>
                <p>10. Witness says, I never was an officer soldier sailor or marine in either the
                    army or navy of the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>. never furnished a substitute for either. I
                    helped my Son to furnish a substitute to keep out of the army. I never was in
                    any way connected with any department of the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>11. Witness says, I never was in any service employment or business of any Kind
                    for the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr><abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt.</abbr> its army or navy</p>
                <p>12. Witness says I never was in any manner engaged in the manufacture of
                    munitions of war, clothing boots shoes or goods of any kind for the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>13. Witness says, I never was directly nor indirectly employed in the collection
                    or impressment of stores or supplies, or goods of any kind for the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> States, &amp; had no interest therein</p>
                <p>14. Witness says, I never was engaged in blockade running or illicit traffic
                    between the lines</p>
                <p>15. Witness says, I did not leave the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr>
                    States between the 19th of April 1861 &amp; 19th of April 1865</p>
                <p>16. Witness says, I never was the owner nor part owner of any vessel engaged in
                    navigating to or from any part of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17. Witness says: I never was arrested by the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> nor the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>18. Witness says: I had horses &amp; grain taken by the Confederates. Some
                    paid &amp; some did not it was taken for the use of the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr> Army.</p>
                <p>19. Witness says: I was threatened with arrest &amp; imprisonment on account
                    of union sentiments</p>
                <p>21. Witness says, I did nothing for the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr>
                    during the war. I fed the wounded union soldiers</p>
                <p>23. Witness says, I had no near relatives in either the Union or <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr> Armies</p>
                <p>24. Witness says, I never owned any <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr>
                    bonds, &amp; never did anything to support <abbr expan="Confederate"
                    >Confed.</abbr> credit</p>
                <p>25. Witness says, I have never given aid or comfort to the rebellion</p>
                <p>26. Witness says: I never engaged in making raids into the United States or in
                    destroying its commerce.</p>
                <p>27. Witness says, I never was engaged in holding in custody persons taken as
                    prisoners of war by the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>28. Witness says, I never was a member of any society for the persecution or
                    imprisonment of persons on account of union sentiments</p>
                <p>29. Witness says, I never was a paroled prisoner of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr></p>
                <p>30. Witness says: I never held any office in the Army or Navy of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> was not educated either at West Point or
                    the Naval Academy</p>
                <p>31. Witness says, I never <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> any pass from any
                    officer of the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr> States</p>
                <p>32. Witness says, I am not &amp; never have been under any disabilities
                    imposed by the 14th amendment of the Constitution, have not held any office
                    under the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> since the war</p>
                <p>33. Witness says, At the beginning of the war I <orig reg="sympathized"
                        >sympathised</orig> with the Union. I did not vote either for or against the
                    ordinance of secession. After its adoption I adhered to the Union Cause
                    &amp; did not go with my State.</p>
                <p>34. Witness says, I was ready at all times to do all I could for the Union
                    &amp; its cause &amp; further this deponent sayeth not. Oct 4th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">David Wampler</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 21st day of September 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Benjamin F. Wampler</byline>
                <p>Deposition of <abbr expan="Benjamin">Benj.</abbr> F. Wampler to prove taking of
                    the property</p>
                <p>Ques 1. Witness Says: I am 37 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>. I am
                    a farmer. I was present &amp; saw the property mentioned in claimants
                    petition taken.</p>
                <p>4. Witness says, The property was taken in 1864 from the farm of the claimant, by
                    officers &amp; soldiers of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> under
                    the <abbr expan="command">Comd.</abbr> of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr>
                    Sheridan, it was in <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr>. of <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Sheridan, it was in <abbr expan="September"
                        >Sept.</abbr></p>
                <p>6. Witness says, I suppose there were officers present. I saw some I took to be
                    officers, did not know their name, <abbr expan="regiment">regt.</abbr> or rank,
                    they said they had orders to take the property.</p>
                <p>7. Witness says: The property was taken from the farm, the horses were taken from
                    the stable, &amp; the cattle were driven from the field, &amp; all taken
                    along with the Army. I think the horses were led.</p>
                <p>9. Witness says, The army was on the march, &amp; the cattle were taken
                    along. The army encamped that night at Middle River</p>
                <p>10. Witness says, The property was taken for the use of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">US</abbr> Army <unclear>not</unclear> for private use</p>
                <p>11. Witness says: No complaint was made as I know, on account of such taking.</p>
                <p>12. Witness says, No receipt was asked for &amp; none given</p>
                <p>13. Witness says, The property was taken in the day. It was not taken secretly</p>
                <p>14. Witness says, When the property <hi rend="super">was taken</hi> the
                    army was on the march, there had not been any battle or skirmish near</p>
                <p>15. Witness says: Item #1. one bay horse in fine condition, he was 8 or 10 years
                    old, he was worth $150.00 item #2 one fine grey horse, in good condition was six
                    years old, worth $150.00 Item #3. 950 lbs beef was worth 14 cents per lb. I saw
                    all the above property taken in 1864. I think I have put it at its fair market
                    value at the time</p>
                <p>19. Witness says: I believe the property was taken for the use of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Army, &amp; not for private use.</p>
                <p>22. Witness says: I think the property was taken for the necessary use of the
                        <abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> &amp; the <abbr expan="Government"
                        >Govt</abbr> should pay for it</p>
                <p>23. Witness says: Those who took the property said they had orders to take,
                    &amp; further this deponent sayeth not</p>
                <p>Oct 4th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Benjamin F Wampler</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 21st day of September 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Daniel Long</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Daniel Long to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1. Witness says: I am 61 years old. I reside Rockingham <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>. I
                    am a farmer. I have known the claimant 40 years. Lived near him during the war.
                    Saw him pretty often during the War. I regarded him as loyal to the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> &amp; he was so regarded by his
                    neighbors. Never knew him to do anything for the <abbr expan="United States"
                        >U.S.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> Do not know that he did
                    anything for the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> he talked a great deal against it. I do not
                    know that he was ever threatened, molested or <unclear>injured</unclear> on
                    account of his union sentiments. I think he was too loyal to the
                        <del hand="h1">Confed</del><abbr expan="United States">US</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr> to have made a loyal citizen to the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> had
                    it succeeded, &amp; further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Oct. 4th 1871 <name type="witness">Daniel Long</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 4th day of Oct. 1871</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Samuel Glick</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Samuel Glick to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1. Witness says, I am 47 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>. I am
                    a farmer. Have known the claimant all my life. Lived near him during the war.
                    Saw him often. Talked with him about the war. I regarded him as loyal to the
                        <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>
                    &amp; he was so regared by his neighbors. Never knew him to do anything for
                    the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> except he fed soldiers of the Union
                    Army. Never knew him to do anything for the Confederates except to feed
                    soldiers. Do not know that he was ever molested threatend or injured on account
                    of union sentiments. I think he was too loyal to the <abbr expan="United States"
                        >U.S.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> to have made a loyal
                    citizen to the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government"
                        >Govt.</abbr> had it succeeded. Oct 4th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Samuel Glick</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 4 day of Oct 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
