<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0304"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0304">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John Bumgardner,
                    September 5, 1871, Claim No. 9293</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john bumgardner, september 5 1871 claim no 9293</title>
        <author>Bumgardner, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 17.5 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0304</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498371</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John Bumgardner,
                            September 5, 1871, Claim No. 9293</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john bumgardner, september 5 1871 claim no 9293</title>
            <author>John Bumgardner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche # 438</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism,</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0304T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John Bumgardner filed this claim September 5, 1871, for $210, claiming that Union
                    troops confiscated 1 horse with saddle and bridle, 1 patch of corn, and 1 hog
                    from his farm in 1864. A witness, Humphrey Ware, testified that 2 horses were
                    taken; one sheet within the claim includes a second horse in a varying claim of
                    confiscated property: 2 large bay horses, both 5 years old, one valued at $250
                    and one at $200; also, 40 bushels of corn, valued at $40.00. Why the lists vary
                    is unclear. The claim was disallowed December 9, 1872.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>one horse with saddle and bridle</cell>
                            <cell>$170.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$170.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>one patch of corn</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>one hog</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>This claimant is a farmer 31 years of age, resided in Augusta Co. Va. was
                    employed in 1863 to haul flour for the Confederates - says he was "impressed" to
                    that work - says he was never threatened injured or molested on account of his
                    union sentiments - This testimony on the question of loyalty is weak &amp;
                    uncertain - all the important printed questions between No 19 &amp; 29 are
                    omitted or not answered at all by the Claimant -</p>
                <p>The proof is not satisfactory &amp; the claim is rejected -</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>John Bumgardner</byline>
                <p>United States of America</p>
                <p>State of Virginia</p>
                <p>I, W.G. Riley, a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioner of
                    Claims appointed under the Act of Congress of March 3, 1871 to take and record
                    testimony Do hereby certify that the reason for takng the following depositions
                    is and the fact is the matter of Claim of John Bumgardner vs. the United States
                    of America and other witness herein named being the first duly sworn answereth
                    as follows.</p>
                <p>Question 1 Witness says - I am thirty-one years I reside in Augusta County Va. My
                    occupation a farmer. I resided in Augusta County six months prior to April 1st
                    1861</p>
                <p>2 I resided from April 1st 1861 to April 1st 1865 in Augusta County Virginia.</p>
                <p>3 Witness Says I never passed beyond the Military and naval lines of the United
                    States and entered the Rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4 Witness Says I never took an oath of allegiance to the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5 Witness Says I have taken the Amnesty Oath. I took it after the War, in Augusta
                    County Virginia. I have never been pardoned by the President. I have never done
                    a thing to be pardoned for.</p>
                <p>6 Witness Says I was impressed to haul Flour by the Confederate States, they said
                    if I did not go, they would take my team and put another driver with it. In the
                    year 1863 in the State of Virginia, no oath was required.</p>
                <p>7 Witness Says. I never held any office under the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>8 Witness Says. I never held any clearkship or any agency whatever under the
                    Confederate Government, I have never of my own free will done anything directly
                    or indirectly for the Confederate States, or any State in Rebellion thereto.</p>
                <p>9 Witness Says. I was never in any Military or Naval capacity or any way
                    connected with the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>14 Witness Says. I was never engaged in running the blockade.</p>
                <p>15 Witness Says. I did not leave the Confederate States between the 19th of April
                    1861 and the 19th of April 1865.</p>
                <p>16 Witness Says. I was never <unclear>interested</unclear> in any Vessel used in
                    navigation the Ocean to or from any part of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17 Witness Says. I was never arrested by the confederate Government. I was never
                    arrested by the United States Government.</p>
                <p>18 Witness Says. I never had any property taken by the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>19 Witness Says. I was never threatened, injured or molested on account of my
                    Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>29 Witness Says. I was never a <unclear>paroled</unclear> prisoner of the United
                    States.</p>
                <p>30 Witness Says. I have never held any office under the United States Government.
                    I was not educated at West Point or at the Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>31 Witness Says. I never received any pay from the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>32 Witness Says. I never was under disabilities <unclear>imposed</unclear> by the
                    14th Amendment.</p>
                <p>33 Witness Says. At the beginning of the War I was for the Union and not for the
                    Rebellion. I voted neither for nor against the Ordinance of Secession. After the
                    Ordinance was passed I adhered to the Union and did not go with my State.</p>
                <p>34 Witness Says. I was from the beginning of the War for the Union, and was at
                    all times ready and willing to render any assistance for the Union in my power
                    at all times.</p>
                <p>And further the deponent says not.</p>
                <p>Sept 5th 1871</p>
                <p>X (his mark)</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Humphrey Ware</byline>
                <p>Humphrey Ware a witness introduced to prove the taking of the property charged in
                    the claimants petition being duly sworn answers as follows</p>
                <p>Question I Witness Says; I was present, when the articles mentioned in the
                    claimants petition were taken, I saw all the articles taken.</p>
                <p>IIII Witness says: The property was taken in 1864 from the claimants farm by
                    soldiers of the Union Army.</p>
                <p>6 Witness Says: There was an officer present at the taking of the claimants
                    property, do not know his rank.</p>
                <p>8 Witness Says: Property was removed by Soldiers. The horses were <orig
                        reg="ridden">rid</orig>, the other property was carried on horses.</p>
                <p>10 Witness Says: The property was taken for the use of the United States Army.</p>
                <p>11 Witness Says: Claimant complained.</p>
                <p>12 Witness Says: There was no receipt asked for &amp; none given.</p>
                <p>13 Witness Says: The property was taken in the day time, none of it was taken
                    secretly.</p>
                <p>14 Witness Says: When the property was taken the Army was encamped in the
                    vicinity about four miles off.</p>
                <p>15 Witness Says: The horses were in fine condition, the large bay horse was five
                    years old &amp; worth three hundred dollars, another bay horse five years
                    old was worth two hundred dollars, they took about forty bushels of shelled
                    corn, worth one dollar a bushel.</p>
                <p>19 Witness Says: The property was taken for the use of the United States Army
                    &amp; not for individual use.</p>
                <p>22 Witness Says: The property was taken for the use of the Army &amp;
                    therefore the <abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> is justified in paying for
                    it.</p>
                <p>23 Witness Says: Those who took the property had authority to take it or to order
                    it taken.</p>
                <p>24 Witness Says: I am 32 years old, I live in Augusta Co Va by occupation a
                    farmer, &amp; further the deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 5th 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Humphrey Ware</name> his x mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Humphrey Ware</byline>
                <p>Humphrey Ware a witness introduced by the claimant to prove his loyalty to the
                    U.S. Govt. being duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>Question 1 Witness says: I am 32 years old, I reside in Augusta Co. Va. &amp;
                    am by occupation a farmer. I have known the Claimant 17 years. I lived with him
                    15 years &amp; saw him every day during the war &amp; talked with him
                    repeatedly about the war. He cursed the rebel army. He was loyal to the U.S.
                    Govt during the war &amp; was so regarded by his neighbors. He fed the
                    soldiers of the Union Army free of charge while he was in reach of them. He did
                    nothing for the rebel army except what he was forced to do. his wagon was
                    impressed twice by the rebels. He was too loyal to have stayed in this country
                    if the rebel Govt. had succeeded, &amp; further deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 5th 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Humphrey Ware</name> his x mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>William Stickley</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>William Stickley a witness by the claimant to prove his loyalty to the U.S. Govt.
                    being duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1 Witness says: I am 59 years old, reside in Augusta Co. Va. by occupation
                    a farmer. I have known the claimant 20 years. I reside near him, I saw him often
                    during the war, talked often with him about the war. I regarded him as a
                    perfectly loyal man to the U.S. Govt. &amp; he was so regarded by his
                    neighbors. Never knew him to do anything for the U.S. Army, nor to do anything
                    for the rebel govt. He was too loyal to the U.S. govt. to have been loyal to the
                    rebel Govt. had it succeeded &amp; further the deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 5th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">William Stickley</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn &amp; subscribed before me this 5th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">W.G. Riley</name> (seal)</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for
                    State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>H. Risk</byline>
                <p>Deposition of H. Risk to prove the loyalty of Jno. Bumgardner</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says I am 55 years old reside in the City of Staunton. I am U.S.
                    Deputy Marshall. I have known Mr. Jno. Bumgardner about 10 years. I lived about
                    4 miles from him during the war &amp; saw him frequently. I had no
                    conversation with him about the War, during the war. Anything I heard during the
                    war, or since, impresses me with the idea that he was during the War, since, a
                    strong Union man &amp; loyal to the U.S. Government. He was threatened with
                    arrest during the War for expressing Union sentiments. I have never heard from
                    any of his neighbors that he was not regarded as a Union man. I don't know that
                    he did anything for either Government. Don't know that he owned any Confederate
                    bonds or did anything to support Confederate credit. Don't know that he ever
                    rejoiced over any victory on either side. Don't know that he gave any
                    information to any Union Officers as to the movements of the Confederate armies.
                    I don't know that he could have stayed here had the Confederacy gained its
                    independence. And further this Deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">H. Risk</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn before me this 5th day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>Samuel D. Stover</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Saml. D. Stover to prove the loyalty of Jno. Bumgardner</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness Says I am 54 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a farmer. I
                    have known Mr. Bumgardner 20 years. Lived near him during the war &amp; saw
                    him often, and talked to him about the war during the War. I have heard him say
                    that if he were under age &amp; liable to military duty, that he would leave
                    the country before he would go in the Army that he believed the was to be unjust
                    &amp; uncalled for. I always considered him a good Union man. I think he was
                    so regarded as a Union man by his neighbors. I heard him say he was threatened
                    because he was a Union man, don't know the threats. I believe he advised all
                    persons to leave the country rather than go into the Confederate Army. He has
                    told me he never wanted the South to gain its independence that he could not
                    stay here if it did. So far as I know he did not own any Confederate bonds
                    &amp; did nothing to support the credit of the Confederate Govt. Don't know
                    that he ever gave any information to any Union Officer in regard to movements of
                    the Confederate Armies. And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Samuel D. Stover</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 2nd day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>
                    <seg type="postscript">Dec. 1872 Disallowed</seg>
                </p>
                <p>ARCHIVE OFFICE, WAR DEPARTMENT</p>
                <p>June 30, 1874</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 28</p>
                <p>Case of No 9293 &amp; 2134</p>
                <p>John Bumgardner</p>
                <p>Augusta County Virginia</p>
                <p>Oct 12 1861 A man of the above name sold one Stamping machine and one Stamp to
                    the Ordnance Department for twenty dollars</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>
                    <seg type="postscript">Rejected Dec 9/72 - Disallowed</seg>
                </p>
                <p>ARCHIVE OFFICE, WAR DEPARTMENT</p>
                <p>March 14, 1874</p>
                <p>
                    <seg type="postscript">Petition for rehearing filed</seg>
                </p>
                <p>Book 2, Letters sent, page 494</p>
                <p>Case of John Bumgardner</p>
                <p>Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>(Nos 9293 and 2134.)</p>
                <p>The above claimants name is found signed to the petition of citizens of Augusta
                    Co. praying discharge of one McClung who is a miller and "who volunteered in the
                    Confederate service rather than go in the militia." has three brothers in the
                    Army two of which have been in ever since the war began.</p>
                <p>(W.D.S. 1862.M.No. 256. In file)</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>ARCHIVE OFFICE, WAR DEPARTMENT</p>
                <p>Jan 2nd, 1879</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 369</p>
                <p>Case of J. Bumgardner</p>
                <p>Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>Bill &amp; voucher for hire of one 4 horse team 9 days March 28 to April 5<hi
                        rend="underline">th</hi> at $4.<hi rend="underline">50</hi> per day. Also
                    for 184 lbs hay at $2.<hi rend="underline">30</hi> perbushel amounting to
                        $36.<hi rend="underline">20</hi></p>
                <p>paid Apl. 18<hi rend="underline">th</hi> 1862 by A.O.M.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W.H. Peyton</name>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <seg type="postscript">1872 Rejected</seg>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>. . .that said supplies were Taken by the United States troops under the command
                    of General <unclear>Averill</unclear> when he with General Hunter made his march
                    through the valley of Virginia in the month of June 1864 - That he is unable to
                    give the name or names of any officer or soldier engaged in the taking of said
                    property</p>
                <p>Witness to prove Loyalty<lb/>John English Arbor Hill Augusta County
                    Va.<lb/>Porterfield Porter <unclear>Summerdeau</unclear> " " "</p>
                <p>Witnesses to prove Loss of property &amp; value thereof<lb/>Porterfield
                    Porter <unclear>Summerdeau</unclear> Augusta Co Va<lb/>John English Arbor Hill</p>
                <p>Post-office Address of Claimant is Arbor Hill<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Virginia</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
