<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0503"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0503">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Hannah M.
                    Hanger, 1879, Claim No. 19933</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of hannah m hanger, 1879 claim no 19933</title>
        <author>Hanger, Hannah M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 16 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0503</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498390</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Hannah M. Hanger,
                            1879, Claim No. 19933</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of hannah m hanger, 1879 claim no 19933</title>
            <author>Hannah M. Hanger</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C. RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8943 </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1879">1879</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Family, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0503T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Hannah M. Hanger filed this claim in 1879 for $760, claiming the Union army took
                    horses, corn and bacon in June 1864 by General Hunter's Union troops. The
                    property belonged to John Brown Hanger, her deceased husband who died in 1866.
                    Hannah was a 42 year old farmer who resided in Arbor Hill. The claim was
                    disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amount of Claim</cell>
                            <cell>$760.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$760.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>Claimant is a widow whose husband died in 1866. The property was his when taken.
                    Her only evidence of her loyalty of claimant and her husband to the same
                    statement of Claimant and one witness that they were loyal. There are no facts
                    or indications tending to support claim statements. She had a brother in the
                    Confederate Army.</p>
                <p>We are not satisfied with the sufficiency of the evidence in support of loyalty.
                    We there therere refuse this claim.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name>, <name
                        type="other">O. Ferriss</name></p>
                <p><abbr expan="Commissioners">Com.</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>Hannah M. Hanger</byline>
                <p>My name is <hi rend="underline">Hannah M. Hanger</hi>, my age <hi
                        rend="underline">42</hi> years, my residence <hi rend="underline">Arbor Hill
                        Augusta Co.</hi>, in the State of <hi rend="underline">Virginia</hi>, and my
                    occupation a <hi rend="underline">farmer</hi>; I am <del hand="h1">related to</del> the
                    claimant, and have beneficial interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>Ques. 2. Ans. I reside where I now do. There are 169 acres in the tract 100
                    cleared to the balance timber. I did not change my residence or business.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Ans. I never passed the lines.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4. Ans. I took no oath at all.</p>
                <p>Ques. 5. Ans. I never too an amnesty oath nor asked for a pardon.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6. Ans. I never was connected with the civil service of the Confederate
                    Government.</p>
                <p>Ques. 7. Ans. I held no office or place of any kind.</p>
                <p>Ques. 8. Ans. I never was a clerk or had any agency or employment for or under
                    the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9. Ans. I belonged to no militia.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10. Ans. Was never a soldier.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11. Ans. I never was in the militia.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12. Ans. I had nothing to do with home guards, or committees of any kind.</p>
                <p>Ques. 13. Ans. Of course no conscript.</p>
                <p>Ques. 14. Ans. I furnished no substitute.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15. Ans. Never in no way connected or employed in any branch of the
                    service.</p>
                <p>Ques. 16. Ans. I had nothing to do with railroads or in transporting soldiers or
                    anything else.</p>
                <p>Ques. 17. Ans. I never had charge of stores or supplies or anything else for the
                    Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 18. Ans. I never was in service of any kind nor furnished nothing of any
                    kind.</p>
                <p>Ques. 19. Ans. I never engaged or was employed in the manufacture of goods or
                    articles of any kind.</p>
                <p>Ques. 20. Ans. I had nothing to do with the Confederate Government in any way.</p>
                <p>Ques. 21. Ans. I ran no blockade nor had interest in goods of any kind.</p>
                <p>Ques. 22. Ans. I remained at my house all the time.</p>
                <p>Ques. 23. Ans. I never owned any vessel or boat.</p>
                <p>Ques. 24. Ans. I never was arrested by either Government.</p>
                <p>Ques. 25. Ans. I had no property taken by the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>Ques. 26. Ans. I never was threatened.</p>
                <p>Ques. 27. Ans. I was not molested.</p>
                <p>Ques. 28. Ans. I made no contribution had no chance.</p>
                <p>Ques. 29. Ans. I did all I could for Union men.</p>
                <p>Ques. 30. Ans. My brother George F. Smith. he resides near Churchville, Augusta
                        <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> I give him nothing.</p>
                <p>Ques. 31. Ans. I owned no Confederate bonds. I did nothing to support the credit
                    of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 32. Ans. I give no aid and comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>Ques. 33. Ans. I never engaged in making raids.</p>
                <p>Ques. 34. Ans. I held no one in custody for any cause.</p>
                <p>Ques. 35. Ans. I belonged to no society or association of any kind or for any
                    purpose.</p>
                <p>Ques. 36. Ans. I never was a paroled prisoner.</p>
                <p>Ques. 37. Ans. I never held any office.</p>
                <p>Ques. 38. Ans. I never had a pass.</p>
                <p>Ques. 39. Ans. I was under no disabilities.</p>
                <p>Ques. 40. Ans. My sympathies were with the Union being a lady I could not vote.</p>
                <p>Ques. 41. Ans. I do solemnly declare that from beginning of hostilities against
                    the United States to the end thereof: my sympathies were constantly with the
                    Union and that I never by word or deed did anything or sought, offered, or
                    attempted to do anything to injure said cause or retard its success and I was at
                    all times ready and willing to aid and assist the cause of the Union or its
                    supporters so far as my means and power permitted.</p>
                <p>Ques. 42. Ans. I was married to John B<add hand="h1" place="inline">rown</add> Hanger in 1850. My husband
                    was a loyal man to the cause of the United States. He is dead, died <abbr
                        expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 1866. I have nine children Mary C. is 21 years.
                    Jacob F. is 20 years. George G. is 18 years. John H 16. Theodore R. 15. Charles
                    14 years. William Y. is 13. James B is 12 years. Edwin is 10 years. After the
                    death of my husband all property fell into my hands as his widow and
                    representative of my children. My husband was not in the Confederate Army and
                    was never in the civil service.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Ans. I was not present and did not see all the property taken.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Ans. I was not at home at the time being out on business.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4. Ans. The property was taken in June 1864 by soldiers belonging to the
                    Command of General Crook &amp; Averall.</p>
                <p>Ques. 5. Ans. David Dull <abbr expan="junior">jr.</abbr> was present with my
                    children.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6. Ans. I do not know whether there was an officer present or not.</p>
                <p>Ques. 7. Ans. I do not know.</p>
                <p>Ques. 8. Ans. I did not see, not being at home.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9. Ans. I do not know.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10. Ans. I cannot say.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11. Ans. I made no complaint.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12. Ans. I got no receipt.</p>
                <p>Ques. 13. Ans. There was no camp near than Staunton about 6 miles distant. There
                    had been a battle at Piedmont a few days before. <abbr expan="Generals">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">ls.</hi></abbr> Hunter Crook &amp; Averall united
                    with <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Hunter at
                    Staunton.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15. Ans. The horses were all in good condition all well broken to ride and
                    work. I believe there were 6 <abbr expan="bushels">bushl.</abbr> corn and 3 or 4
                    pieces of Bacon. I think my property worth all its charged.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Hannah M. Hanger</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>David Dull Jr.</byline>
                <p>Deposition of David Dull jr.</p>
                <p>Answer to 1<hi rend="super">st</hi><abbr expan="general">gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> question. My name is David Dull <abbr
                        expan="junior">jr.</abbr> My age is 47 years. My occupation a Cooper. My
                    residence near Arbor Hill in Augusta County. I am not related to the Claimant
                    and have no interest in the claim. I was present and saw the property taken.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Ans. The Stallion was in the stable and the others in a field adjoining
                    the barn. The Corn was in the granary and the Bacon in the Smoke house and also
                    the flour.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4. Ans. It was about the 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> of June 1846. I
                    have no idea of the number of Soldiers. I suppose two companies of Cavalry.
                    There was an officer present whom the soldiers called Captain. I did not hear
                    any name.</p>
                <p>Ques. 5. Ans. Mrs. Hanger's (the claimant) children were present.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6. Ans. The soldiers called one man Captain. I heard no name. He the
                    Captain told me that they needed the property.</p>
                <p>Ques. 7. Ans. The Stallion was taken out of the stable and the other horses out
                    of a field the Bacon &amp; flour from the Smoke house &amp; the Corn out
                    of the granary.</p>
                <p>Ques. 8. Ans. The horses were led except the Stallion he was rode a soldier
                    getting off his horse and mounted him. The Corn was shelled and carried away in
                    three bags by Soldiers on horse back. The Flour was carried in Sacks, and the
                    Bacon (3 pieces) carried in hand.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9. Ans. The Command was then en route towards Staunton. I did not follow
                    after.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10. Ans. I never saw the property after they left claimants house.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11. Ans. I made complaint to the Captain stating that the owner of the
                    property was a Union man and he replied that they needed the property but for me
                    to keep a list of the articles and that they would be paid for after awhile.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12. There was no receipt given nor asked for.</p>
                <p>Ques. 13. Ans. The property was taken in the day time about 10 A.M. and 3 P.M.</p>
                <p>Ques. 14. Ans. There was no camp nearer than Staunton. <abbr expan="General"
                            >Gen<hi rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Hunter had a battle at
                    Piedmont on the Sunday before the property was taken. <abbr expan="Generals"
                            >Gen<hi rend="super">ls.</hi></abbr> Crook and Averall were on
                    their way to Staunton where they united with <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Hunter. Then camped at that place and
                    remained in Camp until the Friday after the Piedmont battle. I knew no Quarter
                    Master.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15. Ans. The Stallion was in fine order 4 years old of good size near 16
                    hands high, well broken. The large bay mare was 6 years old, large and in fine
                    order. The next 4 years old was a good animal. The horse (bay) 9 years old, was
                    a noble good horse. All the horses were sound and I think <add hand="h1" place="inline">worth</add> all
                    that is charged. There 3 sacks filled with Corn. 3 pieces of Bacon, which I
                    judged would weigh 40 pounds and two barrels of flour emptied into bags. I do
                    not think any of the charges are too much.</p>
                <p>Deposition of Same witness as to the loyalty of Claimant.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant for 20 years and her deceased husband from his boyhood.
                    I lived about 200 yards from them during the War. I was very intimate with both.
                    I saw one or the other every day. I never heard either of them express
                    themselves but the bitterest terms against the rebellion. I have heard them
                    converse frequently in the presence of others and were always and invariably in
                    favor of the Union. And whenever the rebels gained a victory the claimant and
                    her husband were depressed and sorry. I often heard them wish the Union Army
                    would come. I think his Union neighbors believed him to be a sincere friend of
                    the Union. I was a Union man and I had full confidence in the claimant and her
                    husband. I heard the claimant advise her brother to go through the lines to the
                    Union Army. I never knew them to do anything for the United States. The only
                    thing that claimants husband did was to burn Charcoal a short time. The claimant
                    did nothing he did not vote for the Ordinance of Secession, nor put in a
                    substitute. I am satisfied that if the South had gained its independence, they
                    could not have <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> in it.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">David Dull Jr.</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>David Thornton</byline>
                <p>Deposition of David Thornton</p>
                <p>Answer to first general question. My name is David Thornton, my age is 64 years.
                    My occupation is a farmer. I am not related to the claimant and have no benefit
                    in the claim. I have known the claimant for 10 years or more and her husband 15
                    years. After the first year of the War I lived about 1/4 mile from claimant. We
                    were intimate during the War. I saw him very often and talked about the War and
                    his sympathies were constantly with the Union and I think the claimant was
                    always loyal to the United States. I <add hand="h1" place="inline">think</add> the Union men of the
                    neighborhood regarded them both as good and loyal to the United States. I never
                    knew them to do anything to aid the rebellion. The claimant and her husband both
                    knew me to be a Union man. If the South had been successful I do not believe
                    they could have <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> in the South at all.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">David Thornton</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
