<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0516"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0516">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Joseph M. Cline,
                    1871, Claim No. 2578</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of joseph m cline, 1871 claim no 2578</title>
        <author>Cline, Joseph M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 17 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0516</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498403</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Joseph M. Cline,
                            1871, Claim No. 2578</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of joseph m cline, 1871 claim no 2578</title>
            <author>Joseph M. Cline</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #2578</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Patriotism, Prisons/Prisoners</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0516T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Joseph M. Cline filed this claim in 1871 for $330, claiming the Union army took
                    two horses and one cow in 1864. Joseph was a 34 year old minister of the Dunker
                    church and a farmer. He was arrested by the Confederate Government attempting to
                    reach Union lines. He also helped others reach Union lines and escape
                    Confederate service. The commission allowed $275.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bay Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Iron Gray Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Milk Cow</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                            <cell>$5.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimant testifies that he was a Union Man, and was arrested by Rebels while
                    attempting to escape into the Union lines in 1863, and was released on taking
                    the Oath not to do anything against Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>Christian Cline testifies that he knew Claimant well and had no doubt of his
                    loyalty during the War. He was <orig reg="recognized">recognised</orig> as a
                    loyal man by his neighbors and assisted persons to escape into the Union lines,
                    and made an attempt to escape himself, but was caught by the Rebels.</p>
                <p>The property was taken in 1864 by soldiers of <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr>
                    Hunter's Command except cow which was taken by soldiers of <abbr expan="General"
                        >Gen</abbr> Sheridan's Command.</p>
                <p>We allow Two hundred and seventy five dollars.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name><name type="other">JB Howell</name><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Joseph M. Cline</byline>
                <p>I am 34 years, I reside in Augusta Co. Va. I am by occupation a farmer.</p>
                <p>Deposition of Joseph M. Cline, claimant.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Answer. Witness Says-I resided in Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> prior to April 1
                    1861, and was there in person during the 6 months prior to that time.</p>
                <p>2. Witness says-I resided in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> from the
                        1<hi rend="super">st</hi> April 1861 to June 1865. I never changed my
                    residence.</p>
                <p>3. Witness says-I never passed beyond the Military or Naval lines of the United
                    States and entered the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4. Witness Says-I took an oath at Harrisonburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                    in 1862 or 1863.</p>
                <p>5. Witness says-I never took the Amnesty Oath.</p>
                <p>6. Witness says-I never was directly or indirectly connected with the civil
                    service of the So called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>7. Witness says-I never held any office or place of trust profit or honor in the
                    Confederate Government, State or territory.</p>
                <p>8. Witness says-I held no clerkship, Agency or employment of any kind for the
                    benefit of the So Called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>9. Witness Says-I never was in any capacity in the Military or Naval service of
                    the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>10. Witness Says-I was never a Officer, soldier, sailor or Marine of the
                    Confederate army or Navy. I never furnished a Substitute, or in any way
                    connected with any department, bureau or branch of the Confederate Government. I
                    never had charge of stores, supplies or trains, teams, wagons, vessels or
                    munitions of war for the use of the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>11. Witness Says-I was never in the employment of the So called Confederate
                    States, nor furnished anything for the use of the Confederacy. I never give any
                    information to any of the Confederate Authorities.</p>
                <p>12. Witness Says-I never was employed in the Manufacture of anything whatsoever
                    for the use of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>13. Witness Says-I never was employed in any way in the collection, impressment
                    or purchase of any article for the use of the Confederate States. I had no
                    interest of share in any contract whatever.</p>
                <p>14. Witness Says-I never was <orig reg="engaged">enged</orig> in blockade running
                    or illicit traffic or intercourse between the lines. I had no interest in any
                    Goods, or Merchandise, brought into or exported from the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>15. Witness Says-I did not leave the Confederate States between the 19<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> April 1861 and the 19<hi rend="super"
                    >th</hi> April 1865.</p>
                <p>16. Witness Says-I was not the owner or part owner of any vessel used for
                    navigation any where at all.</p>
                <p>17. Witness Says I was arrested by the Confederate Government in 1862 or 1863. I
                    was arrested while making an effort to get into the Union lines, by a Captain of
                    the Confederate Army whose name I have forgotten. I took an Oath to get my
                    release. The oath was that I was not to do any thing against the Confederacy. I
                    never was arrested by the United States Government.</p>
                <p>18. Witness Says-I had two horses taken. I was paid for them.</p>
                <p>19. Witness Says-I never was threatened for my Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>20. Witness Says, I never was molested except my arrest, when on my way to the
                    Union lines.</p>
                <p>21. Witness Says, I never contributed anything in aid of the United States
                    Government or the Union cause except in aid of persons getting to the Union
                    lines.</p>
                <p>22. Witness says-I never had any <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> to do
                    anything.</p>
                <p>23. Witness says-I had a cousin in the Confederate Army, and several in the Union
                    Army. I never made a contribution to any of them.</p>
                <p>24. Witness Says I owned no Confederate Bonds, and did nothing to support the
                    Credit of the Confederacy. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> aid and comfort
                    to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26. Witness Says-I never was engaged in making raids into the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> from Canada, nor in the destruction of the
                    Commerce of the United States.</p>
                <p>27. Witness Says I never aided in the holding of any person or persons taken from
                    the Confederate Government as prisoners of War, or for political causes.</p>
                <p>28. Witness Says-I never was a member of any society for the imprisonment or
                    prosecution of any person on account of his union sentiments.</p>
                <p>29. Witness Says, I never was a paroled prisoner of the United States.</p>
                <p>30. Witness Says-I never held any office in the Army or Navy of the United
                    States. Nor educated at any of its schools.</p>
                <p>31. Witness Says, I received No pass from the Confederate Government or any of
                    its officrs.</p>
                <p>32. Witness Says, I was under no disabilities imposed by any amendment to the
                        <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Constitution. I have held no office
                    since the War.</p>
                <p>33. Witness Says, At the beginning of the rebellion, I <orig reg="sympathized"
                        >sympathised</orig><orig reg="with">withe</orig> the Union. I did not vote
                    at all, and after the Ordinance of Secession was adopted I still adhered to the
                    Union and against the State.</p>
                <p>34. Witness Says, I do declare that at the beginning of the hostilities against
                    the United States to the end thereof, my sympathies were constantly in favor of
                    the Union, and its causes and that I never did anything of my own free will and
                    accord to injure said cause or retard its progress and success, and that I was
                    ready and willing at all times, to do all <hi rend="super">in</hi> my
                    power (except to bear arms, which my profession, a minister in the Dunkard
                    Church, forbid me to do) to aid and assist the said Cause.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><name type="claimant">Joseph M Cline</name><lb/>Sworn to and subscribed before me
                    this 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of September 1871.</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name><abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super">r</hi>.</abbr> and Special
                        <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super">r</hi>.</abbr> for the
                    State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Christian Cline</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Christian Cline, to prove the taking of property charged in <orig
                        reg="claimant's">claimants</orig> petition.</p>
                <p>1. Witness Says, I am 62 years old, I reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I am a farmer. I was present
                    when all the articles named in the petition were take. I saw them taken-two
                    Horses, and saw the Cow in their possession.</p>
                <p>4. Witness says, The property was taken in 1864-the horses in June and the Cow in
                    Sept. Taken from the <orig reg="Claimant's">Claimants</orig> farm. The horses
                    were taken by Officers and soldiers belonging to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunters Army, and the Cow by <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan's.</p>
                <p>5. Witness Says-I suppose the family were present. The Claimant was I know.</p>
                <p>6. Witness Says, When the Cow was taken there was a Captain present, but do not
                    recollect about when the horses were taken. I do not <hi rend="super"
                    >know</hi> the regiment to which the Captain belonged, but it was <abbr
                        expan="General'">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan's
                    command. I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> say whether the Captain ordered the
                    taking or not.</p>
                <p>7. Witness Says-The horses were taken from the premises of claimant. There was a
                    conversation between the claimant and soldiers, but I do not know its nature or
                    substance.</p>
                <p>8. Witness Says-The horses were led off by the soldiers, and the Cow drove off.</p>
                <p>9. Witness Says-The horses were taken to Piedmont, where the Army was encamped,
                    and the Cow was drove with Sheridan's Army down the Valley. I did not follow the
                    property or see it after it was taken.</p>
                <p>10. Witness Says-I do not know, but suppose the horsees were taken for the use of
                    the Army, and the Cow likelise. I saw none used.</p>
                <p>11. Witness Says, I do not know that there was any complaint made.</p>
                <p>12. Witness Says, I do not know that any receipt was asked or given.</p>
                <p>13. Witness Says, The property was taken in the day time-afternoon. It was taken
                    publicly.</p>
                <p>14. Witness Says-The Army was encamped at Piedmont about one mile from Claimant.
                    The Army was only there one day and night. The battle of Piedmont took place the
                    same day the horses were taken, but had been no battle or skirmish when the Cow
                    was. I knew no Quartermaster.</p>
                <p>15. Witness Says, The horses were in serviceable order, so was the Cow. The
                    horse, was about 9 or 10 years old and worth $150. The Mare was 4 or 5 years,
                    and worth $150. The Cow worth $25 or $30. The property was all good. The
                    property was taken in 1864.</p>
                <p>19. Witness Says-I believe the property was taken for the use of the Army and not
                    to gratify any one.</p>
                <p>20. Witness Says, I suppose they had need of horses, and beef, and that there was
                    a necessity for them.</p>
                <p>22. Witness says, I think there was such a necessity, as to justify the
                    Government in paying for it.</p>
                <p>23. Witness Says, I think the property was taken by orders.</p>
                <p>General Interrogatory</p>
                <p>Do you know of other matter <hi rend="super">relative to</hi><del hand="h1">of</del>
                    this claim? If so state it fully. Answer. I do not know of anything else.
                    Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Christian Kline</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 18 day of Sept. 1871.</p>
                <p><name type="other">W.G. Riley</name><abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super">r</hi>.</abbr> and Special
                        <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super">r</hi></abbr>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Christian Kline</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Christian Kline, to prove the loyalty of claimant to the<abbr
                        expan="United States"> U.S.</abbr> States.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness Says I am 62 years old. I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and am
                    a farmer. I have known the claimant all his life. I live very near him, and knew
                    him intimately during the rebellion. I have no doubt of his loyalty to the
                    Union, and he was generally regarded so by his neighbors. He assisted persons in
                    getting to the Union lines, and made the attempt to go himslf but was caught by
                    the rebels. He never did anything voluntarily for the Confederacy. Nor for the
                    United States except to aid persons to get through the Union lines. I do not
                    think he could have had any claim <hi rend="super">of loyalty</hi> to the
                    Confederacy had it succeeded. He would have had to leave.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Christian Kline</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of
                    September 1871.</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name><abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super">r</hi>.</abbr> And Special
                    Commissioner</p>
                <p>I hereby cer</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
