<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0110"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0110">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Peter Ellinger,
                    September 16, 1871, Claim No. 6477</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of peter ellinger, september 16 1871 claim no 6477</title>
        <author>Ellinger, Peter</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 15 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0110</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498335</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Peter Ellinger,
                            September 16, 1871, Claim No. 6477</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of peter ellinger, september 16 1871 claim no 6477</title>
            <author>Peter Ellinger</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #6811</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0110T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Ellinger's claim for over $200 worth of property was disallowed because he voted
                    in favor of secession and had two sons in the Confederate Army. He filed an
                    unsuccessful appeal with the Congressional Court of Claims in 1890.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Two Barrels Flour @ $10</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Eight Hundred lbs Bacon @ 25c</cell>
                            <cell>200.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>200.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Thirty gallons molasses @ 75c</cell>
                            <cell>22.50</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>22.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Twenty Bushels Potatoes @ $1</cell>
                            <cell>20.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Ten Bags @ 50c</cell>
                            <cell>5.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>5.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Barrel vinegar</cell>
                            <cell>10.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>10.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Twenty five pounds Beef @ 12c</cell>
                            <cell>9.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>9.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$286.50</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$286.50</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>Claimant swears that he voted for the Ordinance of Secession under threats of
                    being driven away from his property, and that he was Compelled to serve in the
                    "Reserves", and had two sons in the Rebel Army and gave them a little money.</p>
                <p>These acts are all more or less inconsistent with <orig reg="loyal">loyall</orig>
                    adherence to the Cause of the Union, and the Government of the United States;
                    and we therefore reject the claim.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>Peter Ellinger</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Peter Ellinger Claimant</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says, I am 54 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a farmer. I
                    resided six months prior to April 1861 in Augusta Co.</p>
                <p>2 Witness says: I resided in Augusta Co from April 19th 1861 to April 19th 1865.</p>
                <p>3 Witness says, I never passed the military or naval lines of the United States
                    to enter the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says: I never took an oath of allegiance to the Confederate States. I
                    took an amnesty oath in 1865 at Staunton, it was required of all. Have not been
                    pardoned by the <abbr expan="President">Presdt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says: I never was directly nor indirectly connected with the civil
                    service of the Confed. States.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says: I never had any office or place of honor, profit or trust under
                    the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>Witness says, I never held any clerkship or agency of any kind under the Confed
                    States.</p>
                <p>9 Witness says: I was out in the reserves by compulsion.</p>
                <p>10 Witness says, I never was an officer soldier, sailor or Marine in the Army or
                    Navy of the Confed. States. Never furnished any substitutes. Never was connected
                    with any Dept or bureau, branch or service of the Confed Govt. Did not at any
                    time have charge of any store or supplies for the Confed. Army or Navy.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says: I never was at any time in any service or employment of any kind
                    for the Confed. Govt. its Army or Navy. Never furnished any stores of any kind.
                    Never gave any information to any officer or soldiers. Did nothing for the
                    Confed. Govt. except what I was compelled to do.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says, I never was engaged in blockade running, or illicit traffic.
                    Never had any interest in any goods of any kind, brought into the Confed States.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says, I did not leave the Confed States between the 19th of April 1861
                    &amp; 14 of April 1865</p>
                <p>16 Witness says, I never was interested in any vessel engaged in navigating to or
                    from any port of the Confed. States.</p>
                <p>17 Witness says, I never was arrested by the Confed. Govt. never was arrested by
                    the U States Govt.</p>
                <p>18 Witness says: I had grain &amp; meat taken by the Confed. Govt. in 1863, I
                    suppose for Govt. use, <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> no pay for it</p>
                <p>19 Witness says: I never was threatened with damage or molested in any way by the
                    Confed. Govt. on account of union sentiments</p>
                <p>21 Witness says: I did nothing to aid the United States Govt.</p>
                <p>23 Witness says: I had some cousins in the Confed Army, &amp; had two sons in
                    the Army by detail &amp; conscription. I gave them some little money while
                    in the Confed. Army</p>
                <p>24 Witness says: I never owned any Confed States. Never did any thing to support
                    the credit of the Confed Govt.</p>
                <p>25 Witness says, I have never given aid or comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26 Witness says, I never was engaged in the United States from Canada or in
                    destroying its commerce.</p>
                <p>27 Witness says, I never was engaged in holding in custody any persons taken as
                    prisoners of war by the Confed Govt.</p>
                <p>28 Witness says, I never was a member of any society for the imprisonment or
                    expulsion of any person on account of loyalty to the U.S. Govt.</p>
                <p>29 Witness says, I never was a paroled prisoner of the U.S.</p>
                <p>30 Witness says, I never held any office in the Army or Navy of the U.S. Was not
                    educated at West Point or the Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>31 Witness says: When I was in the conscript service I got a pass to go home. I
                    got them from different officers to go home to see my family, lasted only a few
                    days. Did not take an oath to get the pass.</p>
                <p>32 Witness says: I am not &amp; never was under any disabilities imposed by
                    the Constitution of the United States Have not held any office under the US Govt
                    since the War.</p>
                <p>33 Witness says, At the beginning I sympathized with the Union. I voted for the
                    Ordinance of Secession under threats of being driven away from my property.
                    After the adoption of the ordinance of secession I adhered to the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>34 Witness says, I solemnly declare that from the beginning to the end of the war
                    my sympathies were with the Union Cause, &amp; I was ready at all times to
                    aid its Cause, to the extent of my ability, &amp; so far as the
                    circumstances permitted, &amp; further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 16th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Peter Ellinger</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; Subscribed before me this 16th day Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr.</abbr>
                    for State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Elizabeth Stone</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Miss Eliz. Stone to prove taking &amp; furnishing of the
                    property.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 27 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a
                    housekeeper. I was present &amp; saw the property taken mentioned in the
                    claimants petition.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says: The property was taken in June 1864, by Soldiers &amp;
                    Officers of the Union Army, of Genl. <del hand="h1">Sheridans</del> Crook &amp;
                    Averill <abbr expan="command">Com'd</abbr>.</p>
                <p>5 Witness says, The family of the house &amp; myself.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says, There was no officers present when the property was taken.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says: The flour was hauled away in ambulances, bacon, molasses,
                    &amp;c were taken in the same way</p>
                <p>8 Witness says, The property was removed by Soldiers, in wagons.</p>
                <p>9 Witness says, The property was taken to camp. I did not follow it &amp; did
                    not see it again.</p>
                <p>10 Witness says: The property was taken to feed soldiers of the Union Army they
                    told me they were hungry &amp; must have it to eat.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says, There was no complaint made on account of such taking</p>
                <p>12 Witness says, There was no receipt given &amp; none asked for</p>
                <p>13 Witness says, The property was taken about 9 O'clock in the day.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says, When the property was taken no part of the Army was encamped
                    near. Had been a skirmish about 5 miles off Did not know any of the quarter
                    Masters or any of the officers.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says: The bacon &amp; flour was of the very best quality.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says, I am confident it was taken for the use of the Army, &amp;
                    not for private use</p>
                <p>20 Witness says, I believe it was taken because the Soldiers were not supplied
                    with rations by the Govt.</p>
                <p>21 Witness says, I believe it was taken on account of some necessity</p>
                <p>22 Witness says, I believe it was taken for the necessary use of the Govt.
                    &amp; that they ought to pay for it</p>
                <p>23 Witness says: I do not think they were ordered to take, but they had no
                    rations &amp; were not supplied by the Govt.</p>
                <p>General Interrogatory</p>
                <p>Do you know of any other matter relative to said claim? If you do state it fully</p>
                <p>Answer. The soldiers took every thing he had on the place, inside the house, and
                    outside. Nothing was left except a poke of Flour which I hid &amp; further
                    this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 16th 1871 <name type="witness">Eliz. Stone</name> her mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 16th day of Sept 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for
                    State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Henry Mish</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Henry Mish to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 58 years I reside in Augusta Co. I am a farmer. I have
                    lived in Augusta Co. 36 years. Have known the claimant 36 years. Lived near him
                    during the war. Saw him often, &amp; talked with him often about the War. I
                    believed him to be a loyal man. I think the most of his neighbors regarded him
                    as loyal. Never knew him threatened on account of loyalty. Never knew him to do
                    anything for the United States Govt. did not have the chance. Never knew him to
                    do anything for the Confed Govt. I think he was too loyal to the U.S. Govt to
                    have been loyal to the Confed. Govt. had it succeeded, &amp; further this
                    deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 16th 1871 <name type="witness">Henry Mish</name></p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; Subscribed before me this 16th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">Wm G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for
                    State of Va</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>William Glover</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Wm Glover to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 67 years old I reside in Augusta Co. I am a farmer.
                    Have lived in Augusta 47 years. Have known the claimant 20 years. Live near him.
                    Saw him often during the war. Talked with him about the war. Regarded him as a
                    loyal man, he was so regarded by his neighbors Never knew him threatened on
                    account of his union sentiments. Never knew him to do anything for the US Govt.
                    he was forced in the reserves of the Confed States. I do not think he could have
                    stayed here, if the South had succeeded, he was too loyal to the U.S. Govt.
                    &amp; further this deponent sayeth not</p>
                <p>Sept 16th 1871 <name type="witness">Wm. Glover</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 16th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for
                    State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>Archive Office, War Department, Nov 3, 1877</p>
                <p>Peter Elinger, Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>A man by the above name was Paid $30.00 for arresting John Wilson a Deserter from
                    Co. H. 52 Va. <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr>. Staunton Va Sept 17<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> 1862.</p>
                <p>His signature on voucher on file in this office</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>Assistant Adjutant General</byline>
                <p>June 10, 1892</p>
                <p>Respectfully returned to the Department of Justice, by authority of the Secretary
                    of War, inviting attention to the following report, viz:</p>
                <p>There are on file in this office two vouchers in favor of Peter Elinger &amp;
                    signed P. Elinger at Staunton, Va. one, for arresting a deserter &amp; the
                    other for beef.</p>
                <p>One Peter Elinger was a private in Co. D. 3<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">d</hi>
                    </hi><abbr expan="Battalion">Battn</abbr>, Va. Reserves, organized in Augusta
                    Co. Va.</p>
                <p>No further information found.</p>
                <p><name type="other">J. O. <unclear>Eilmore</unclear></name><abbr expan="Assistant"
                        >Ass't</abbr> Adjutant General</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
