<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0111"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0111">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Samuel Garber,
                    September 5, 1872, Claim No. 2508</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of samuel garber, september 5 1872 claim no 2508</title>
        <author>Garber, Samuel</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 20 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0111</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498336</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Samuel Garber,
                            September 5, 1872, Claim No. 2508</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of samuel garber, september 5 1872 claim no 2508</title>
            <author>Samuel Garber</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8646</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0111T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Garber's claim for horses and livestock was disallowed because he voted in favor
                    of the ordinance of secession. He unsuccessfully appealed this decision to the
                    Congressional Court of Claims in 1892.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Black Horse 5 year Old</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>55 bushels oats partly measured 50c</cell>
                            <cell>27.50</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>27.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>6 sheep (good Order) valued $3</cell>
                            <cell>18.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>18.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 Milch Cows Valued at (large, good &amp; grain fed)</cell>
                            <cell>120.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>120.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Steer 3 year Old Valued at (fat)</cell>
                            <cell>40.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>40.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Heifer 3 year Old valued at (good)</cell>
                            <cell>35.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>35.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 Heifers 2 year Old valued at (good order)</cell>
                            <cell>40.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>40.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Small Bull, 2 years Old (good order)</cell>
                            <cell>15.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>15.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$445.50</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$445.50</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>The Claim Consists of 8 items valuation to 445.00</p>
                <p>Amount Disallowed 445.00</p>
                <p>Claimant swears to his loyal sympathies and that he aided refugees. He says he
                    voted for the Ordinance of Secession through compulsion and against his
                    sentiments. He does not give the circumstances of the compulsion of which he
                    speaks, and we presume it was only the fear of public opinion.</p>
                <p>We regard a vote to dissolve the Union, inconsistent with loyal adherance to it,
                    and we therefore reject the Claim.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>Samuel Garber</byline>
                <p>My name is Samuel Garber, my age is 68 years, my residence New Hope, in the State
                    of <del hand="h1">Augusta</del> Va, and my occupation a farmer.</p>
                <p>To question No. 2, Residence near New Hope, Augusta Co. Va. I was a farmer and
                    did not change my residence or occupation during the war.</p>
                <p>To question No. 3 &amp; 4 he answers no in full to each question separately
                    put</p>
                <p>To question No. 5 he answers, I took the amnesty oath at New Hope, Va, directly
                    after the War.</p>
                <p>To questions Nos. 6 to 24 inclusive he answers no in full to each.</p>
                <p>To question No. 25 he answers, The rebels took my corn &amp; potatoes during
                    the war. I cannot remember dates or amounts. I never received any pay for it.</p>
                <p>To question Nos. 26 to 28 inclusive he answers no in full to each.</p>
                <p>To question No. 29 he answers, I aided Union refugees, my four sons and others to
                    escape to the North. I contributed supplies to the Union Hospital near New Hope
                    Va when others would not.</p>
                <p>To question No. 30 he answers, I had a nephew, Eli Garber, in the Confederate
                    army. He now lives near New Hope, Va. I never gave him any money or clothes
                    while he was in the army.</p>
                <p>To question Nos. 31 to 39 inclusive he answers no in full to Each question
                    separately put</p>
                <p>To question No. 40 he answers, At the beginning of the rebellion I sympathized
                    with the Union. I talked in favor of the Union Cause. I voted for Union
                    candidates. I voted for the ratification of the ordinance of secession. I did it
                    through compulsion and for self-preservation. It was not my sentiments. After
                    the ordinance of secession was adopted I still adhered to the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>To question No. 41 he says, I do so solemnly declare.</p>
                <p>The claimant is here examined by the Commissioner concerning property taken. I
                    saw the black horse with the 55 bushels of oats recorded in my account taken. I
                    did not see the other property taken. The horse and oats were taken at the day
                    of the battle of Piedmont, by <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Hunters army.
                    The horse was in the stable and a great many soldiers were in the yard and one
                    of them took the horse and rode him away. I heard an officer present <hi
                        rend="super">talking</hi> that he had better not take the horse as I
                    was a Union man, but the soldier took him. The soldier said he needed the horse
                    and would have to take it. It was in the evening after the battle. I did not ask
                    for a receipt and he did not give me one. The horse was 5 years old, sound and
                    in good order &amp; was worth $150. The oats were in the barn and was
                    carried off by the soldiers in bags on their horses. I think there were some
                    officers present. They did not say anything about the oats, nor did I say
                    anything to them. I asked for no receipts and they did not give me any. I
                    estimated the amount of oats I had put in the barn at 55 bushels, &amp; it
                    was all taken by the soldiers. It was not measured when taken. Oats were worth
                    at least fifty cents per bushel in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>. The cattle were taken at the time of
                    the Burning Raid, but I did not see them taken although was assured by others
                    they were taken. <del hand="h1">He saw</del> There were eight head of them. There were 3
                    cows in good <del hand="h1">in good</del> order &amp; I could have sold them for $40
                    each. They were in good order. The balance were young cattle, from three to four
                    years old each, and were worth from $15 to $20 Each, except one fat steer which
                    was worth $40. The sheep were taken by <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Hunters
                    army at the time of the Piedmont fight in the night time. There were six taken.
                    They were good mutton and would have averaged 50 pounds net. I do not know what
                    mutton was then worth. The sheep were worth $4 or $5 each.</p>
                <p>I never saw any thing of any of the property afterward. The sheep were inside the
                    Union lines when taken. I went to get the sheep the evening before they were
                    taken, but the soldiers would not let me get them, and the next morning when I
                    went for them they were gone. The army was then encamped on my farm.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Samuel Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Annie Garber</byline>
                <p>Annie Garber, witness to prove property taken, being affirmed and examined by the
                    Commissioners, says:</p>
                <p>I am <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> years old and live near New Hope, Augusta County Va. I am the wife of
                    the claimant &amp; have no money interest in his claim. I saw one horse, 3
                    cows and five young cattle and some oats taken from my husband by the Union army
                    during the war. The horse was taken at the time of the Piedmont fight, by <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Hunter's army. The horse was in the stable and
                    was taken by the soldiers and rode away. I heard the soldier who took the horse
                    say that he did not like to take the horse, but he was compelled to have him. It
                    was <del hand="h1">the</del> a black horse, about five years old. I do not know his value.
                    He was a good riding horse. I never saw the horse after he was taken. The oats
                    were taken the same day by some soldiers of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr>
                    Hunter's army. The oats were in the barn &amp; some were fed on the ground
                    and some carried away by soldiers in bags. I do not know how much oats there
                    was. I do not know its value. I did not hear any conversation at the time. I saw
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Sheridan's army take three cows and five
                    young cattle from my husband at the time of the Burning Raid in September 1864.
                    They were in the field and I saw the soldiers drive them away. The soldiers who
                    took the cattle told my daughter in my presence that they had orders to take the
                    cattle and that if we were Union people we would get paid for them. I had been
                    offered $18 each for two of the heifers in the spring before they were taken. I
                    do not know the value of any of the others. The cows were first-rate ones. At
                    the time <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Hunters army was there in June 1864.
                    The soldiers who were with it told me that they had killed six of my husband's
                    sheep, that they did not take any more than they were obliged to have. It was
                    the night succeeding the fight that the sheep were taken. I saw the sheep hides
                    on the ground in the camp &amp; recognized the hides from a private mark. I
                    do not know their value.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Annie Garber</name> her mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>George Garber</byline>
                <p>George W. Garber, witness to prove <del hand="h1">loyalty of claimant</del>, property
                    taken, being sworn by the Commissioner, deposes and says:</p>
                <p>I am 25 years old reside near New Hope &amp; am a son of the claimant and
                    have no money interest in this claim. I saw one horse 8 head of cattle and a lot
                    of oats--55 or 60 bushels of oats--taken from my father by the Union army during
                    the war. The horse and oats were taken by <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr>
                    Hunters army in the year 1864. The horse was in a old house in the yard used as
                    a stable, and a soldier saddled him up in the yard and rode him away. My father
                    told him we were Union people &amp; the soldier said he did not like to take
                    the horse but he needed a horse and must take him. An officer was present who
                    told him not to take the horse, but the soldier said he needed him and must take
                    him. The horse was five years old and was worth $150. The oats were taken at the
                    same time by the same command. Part were fed on the groud and part carried away
                    in bags. I put the oats away in the barn &amp; am satisfied there were from
                    55 to 60 bushels. It was all taken. I did not hear any conversation. There were
                    several officers present. The sheep were taken the night after the Piedmont
                    fight by <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Hunters army &amp; the soldiers
                    told me that they had taken the sheep and eaten them. They said they had not
                    taken any more than they wanted to make use of. I saw the hides laying on the
                    ground and recognized them from a private mark, as having been my fathers sheep.
                    The sheep were in good order and would have made good mutton. At the time of the
                    Burning Raid I saw the soldiers belonging to <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr>
                    Sheridans army take three cows and five head of young cattle belonging to my
                    father. I saw the soldiers driving the cattle away, but did not hear any
                    conversation. The army was at that time taking all the stock in the
                    neighborhood. I do not know their value as I was a boy when they were taken.
                    This is all I know about it and further say not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">George W Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>Noah Beard</byline>
                <p>Noah Beard, witness to prove loyalty of claimant, being sworn and examined by the
                    Commissioner, deposes and says:</p>
                <p>I am 51 years old &amp; reside at New Hope, Augusta Co. Va. &amp; am a
                    saddler. I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in his claim. I
                    lived about four miles from him during the war and saw him once or twice during
                    the war. I did not have any conversation with him in regard to the war. I knew
                    his reputation for loyalty; it was that of a thoroughly loyal man. He was
                    regarded a loyal man by his loyal neighbors. I never knew him to render any aid
                    or assistance to either army. I never knew him to own any Confederate Bonds. I
                    never knew him to be molested or injured on account of his Union sentiments. I
                    know of no acts done or language used, but I believe his public reputation for
                    loyalty during the war would have rendered it impossible for him to prove his
                    loyalty to the Confederacy if it had been successful.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Noah Beard</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>Daniel Probst</byline>
                <p>Daniel Probst a witness for <abbr expan="claimant">clt.</abbr> being duly
                    affirmed and examined by <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com<hi rend="super"
                        >r</hi></abbr> deposes and says:</p>
                <p>I am 75 years, 11 months and 5 days old, a resident of Augusta County, at New
                    Hope. I am unable to work at anything now. I am not related to Mr Garber, the
                        <abbr expan="claimant">Clt</abbr>, and have no interest in his claim. I have
                    known him about 25 years, I was intimately acquainted with him during the war,
                    lived within about a mile of him. I saw him at least twice a month during the
                    war. I often talked with him about the war. I know his political sympathies and
                    opinions from his talk. He was a strong Union man. I was a Union man, I knew the
                        <abbr expan="claimant's">clt's</abbr> reputation in the community for
                    loyalty. The rebels <orig reg="didn't">did'nt</orig> like him but the Union men
                    did. I never knew him to be molested or threatened with injury on account of his
                    Union sentiments. I never knew him to contribute anything in aid of either cause
                    during the war. I never knew him to contribute anything to sustain the credit of
                    the Confederate <abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr> or to own any Confederate
                    bonds. I have heard him express Union sentiments in the presence of others. All
                    that I know is, that he was a Union man and could not have proved his loyalty to
                    the Confederate <abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr> if <del hand="h1">he</del> it had
                    been able to maintain a <orig reg="separate">seperate</orig> one, but I don't
                    remember anything he said or done that would prevent it</p>
                <p>Further saith not</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Daniel Probst</name> his mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>John Yates</byline>
                <p>We the under-signed citizens of Augusta Co Va being acquainted with Samuel Garber
                    know him to have been a union man during the late rebellion and believe that the
                    matters certified to in the foregoing affidavit is in all respects true and
                    would most earnestly and Respectfully recommend its payment</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Yates, Henry K Eakle, Charles Batis</name>
                </p>
                <p>This is the original Account that was presented to to the Government at
                    Washington in the year 1869 &amp; no action taken but Returned to me.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Samuel Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>Abraham Garber</byline>
                <p>We the undersigned Loyal citizens of Augusta County Virginia do hereby certify on
                    oath that we have known the claimant Samuel Garber for many years and know him
                    to have been Loyal to the Government of the United States, before and at the
                    time and since the taking of the property and supplies in the claimants petition
                    mentioned.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Yates, Abraham D. Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>Archive Office, War Department, Sept 15, 1874</p>
                <p>Case of Samuel Garber of Augusta Co Va</p>
                <p>Bill &amp; voucher for 1220 lbs. Hay amt $36.60 Sold to Maj HM Bell <abbr
                        expan="Quarter">Q.</abbr><abbr expan="Master">M.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Confederate">C.</abbr><abbr expan="States">S.</abbr> army</p>
                <p>Paid at Staunton <abbr expan="December">Decr</abbr> 19<hi rend="super"
                    >th</hi> 1864</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                <byline>United States Treasury Department</byline>
                <p>Treasury Department, Office of the Secretary, Washington, D.C. April 27, 1892</p>
                <p>The Honorable The Attorney General</p>
                <p>Sir:</p>
                <p>In answer to your question of the 9th instant in the case of the estate of Samuel
                    Garber against the United States, No. 8646 Congressional, I have the honor to
                    state that the following named persons voted for the ordinance of secession in
                    Augusta County, Virginia, as appears from a copy of the poll list on file in
                    this Department, the original of which is presumed to be in the custody of the
                    clerk of the court of said county, viz: Samuel Garber, <abbr expan="Senior"
                    >Sen.</abbr>, S. Garber, <abbr expan="Senior">Sen.</abbr>, and Samuel M. Garber.</p>
                <p>The name of Samuel Garber of Jacob is found in the list of certificates issued by
                    the Bank of Rockingham, Confederate States Depository Page 10.</p>
                <p>Respectfully yours,</p>
                <p><name type="other">Charles <unclear>Forten</unclear></name> Secretary</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>War Department, Adjutant General's Office, April 30, 1892</p>
                <p>There are on file in this office fifteen (15) vouchers signed <hi
                        rend="underline">Samuel Garber</hi>, in Augusta &amp; Rockingham Cos.
                    Va., for forage, flour, bacon, horse, &amp;c.</p>
                <p>One <hi rend="underline">S. Garber</hi>, New Hope, Augusta Co., Va., petitioned
                    for the discharge of a soldier fromm C.S.A.</p>
                <p>One <hi rend="underline">Samuel Garber</hi>, of Augusta Co., Va., petitioned for
                    the discharge of a blacksmith from C.S.A.</p>
                <p>No further information found.</p>
                <p><name type="other">
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>
                    </name><abbr expan="Assistant">Ass't</abbr> Adjutant General</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
