<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0531"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0531">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of David Myers,
                    1874, Claim No. 12,113</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of david myers, 1874 claim no 12 113</title>
        <author>Myers, David</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 40 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0531</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498418</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of David Myers, 1874,
                            Claim No. 12,113</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of david myers, 1874 claim no 12 113</title>
            <author>David Myers</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #12,113</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1874">1874</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Enlistment, Home Front, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0531T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>David Myers filed this claim in 1874 for $929, claiming Union forces under
                    General Hunters Army took five horses, corn, grain, flour, and sorgham molasses
                    in 1864. David was a 53 year old farmer in New Hope who helped neighbors escape
                    to the Union lines. He hired a substitute for his son and then sent his son to
                    the Union to avoid Confederate service. David served as a Justice of the Peace
                    after the war was over. Included is testimony of John A. Stover of Augusta who
                    joined the 6th Ohio Regiment. The commission allowed $615.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Bay horse 6 years old</cell>
                            <cell>$175.00</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Brown Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$110.00</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Cob Ham Mare 3 yrs old</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$110.00</cell>
                            <cell>$15.0</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bay Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Sorrel Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>25 Bushels of Corn</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                            <cell>$5.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>21 acres grain in head - 15 bus per acre</cell>
                            <cell>$315.00</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>$215.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Barrel Flour</cell>
                            <cell>$8.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$8.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bbll Sorgham Molasses</cell>
                            <cell>$6.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$6.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The claimant is about 55 years of age and a farmer. He resided in Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> during the war.
                    When this case was first submitted the testimony was so badly taken that we
                    required an investigation and further testimony. The testimony has been
                    furnished. Mr. Myers was opposed to secession, and when the ordinance of
                    secession was submitted to the people he did not vote on the question. His son
                    was conscripted and being sick he purchased a substitute for him and sent him
                    north into the federal lines to escape conscription. He rejoiced at Union
                    victories and is regarded by all his Union neighbors as having been a constant
                    and consistent Unoin man. The rebels took his property but paid him nothing.</p>
                <p>The battle of Piedmont occured June 5, 1864 about one mile from claimants
                    premises. The next day June 6 the claimants property was taken. The horses and
                    the corn clearly for army use. The quantity of corn is not certain. The field of
                    grain was wheat which was just heading out and the cavalry horses were turned
                    into the field and trampled it down. For the pasturing we can make a small
                    allowance. The flour and molasses must be charged to depredation. No vouchers or
                    receipts were given.</p>
                <p>We recommend the payment of $615</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>David Myers</byline>
                <p>United States of America</p>
                <p>State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> S. S. </p>
                <p>J.W.G. Riley a commissioner selected and designated by the <abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr>. of Claims, appointed under the act of
                    Congress of March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi>. 1871. To take and record
                    testimony. Do hereby certify that the reason for taking the following
                    depositions is and the fact is, the matter of claim of David Myers vs. the
                    United States of America and the witness herein named being material and
                    necessary, being first duly sworn deposeth as follows.</p>
                <p>Question. Where do you reside. What is your age, and what is your occupation,</p>
                <p>Ans. I reside at New Hope, in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> My age is 53 years and my occupation a farmer.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says. Same place, New Hope Augusta
                        <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and was
                    there during the war.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Witness says. He did not pass beyond the military or Naval lines of the
                        <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> and enter the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. He never did take an oath of
                    affirmation to bear allegiance to the so called Confederate States or to aid or
                    support them in any way.</p>
                <p>Ques. 5<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says, <del hand="h1">Have you ever
                    taken</del> I have taken the am<add hand="h1" place="inline">n</add>esty oath. I have not been pardoned
                    by the President I have done nothing to be pardoned for.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. That he was never directly
                    or indirectly connected with the civil service of the so called Confederate
                    States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 7<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. That he never held any
                    office <add hand="h1" place="inline">or</add> place of trust under the Confederate Government or under
                    any of the States or territories subordinate thereto.</p>
                <p>Ques. 8<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. He held no agency or
                    employment of any kind for or under or for the benefit of the so called
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. He never was in the Military
                    or Naval service of the so called Confederate States or of any of State or
                    territory subordinate thereto.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10. Witness says. I never was in the Confederate Army or Navy myself, but I
                    did furnish a substitute for my son. My son was sick, and being about to force
                    him into the service, I hired a substitute for him he being under age at the
                    time, and as soon thereafter as he was well, I sent him into the Federal lines,
                    where he remained until after the close of the war. I was never directly or
                    indirectly connected with employed for either the Commissary department, Quarter
                    Master department, Medical department, Engineers department, the Ordinance
                    department impressment service, the Provost Marshal department, or any other
                    Bureau, or branch or department of the Confederate service. Nor did I at any
                    time have charge of any stores, or supplies for the use of the Confederate Army,
                    Navy or Government, or the charge of trains, teams or teams Wagon or Wagons,
                    Vessels, Boats, or other crafts, or munitions of War for the use of the
                    Confederate Army or Navy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11. Witness says. He was never in any service of any kind for the
                    Confederate service of any kind for the Confederate Governmnet, Army or Navy. I
                    never furnished any supplies, stores or property of any kind volunatrily to the
                    Confederate States or any State in rebellion, or to the Army, Navy militia, home
                    guards, armed forces, or military organizations thereof, or for any officer,
                    soldier or sailor thereof, that he never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> any
                    information to any officer, soldier, or sailor of the Confederate Army or Navy,
                    or to any person employed by of for the so called Confederate States, or acting
                    on their behalf, or for their benefit which might aid in any way any military or
                    naval <orig reg="operations">apperations</orig> carried on against the United
                    States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. I was never employed in the
                    manufacture of the munitions of war, of clothing, Boots, Shoes, Saddles Harness
                    or leather, for soldiers of the Confederate Army or Navy, or aid or assist
                    others, engaged in such manufacture.</p>
                <p>Ques. 13<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. That he never was directly
                    or indirectly employed in the collection, impressment, or purchase or the sale
                    of Stores, supplies, or any property for the use or benefit of the Confederate
                    Government or any state in rebellion or the Army Navy, or other forces thereof.
                    And that he never had any interest or share in contracts with, or purchases for,
                    the Confederate Government or its Army or Navy, or any state in rebellion or its
                    forces.</p>
                <p>Ques. 14<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. That he never was engaged
                    in blockade running or illicit traffic or intercourse between the lines nor
                    never was in any way interested therein. Nor did he have any interest or share
                    in any goods, wares, merchandise, stores or supplies brought into or exported
                    from the so called Confederate States during the war.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. That he did not leave the
                    so called Confederate States between the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> April
                    1861 and the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> April 1865.</p>
                <p>Ques. 16<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. That he was not the owner
                    or any way interested in any vessel used in navigating the ocean, to or from any
                    port in the Confederacy or upon any waters in the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 17<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. I never was arrested by the
                    Confederate Government or any one having authority or professing to have
                    authority therefor. Nor was I ever arrested by the United States Government.</p>
                <p>Ques. 18<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. He had grain taken by the
                    Confederate authorites, but received no compensation for the same.</p>
                <p>Ques. 19<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. I was never threatened with
                    damage to person, family, or property on account of my Union sentiments, to my
                    own knowledge.</p>
                <p>Ques. 20<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. I believe it was on account
                    of my Union sentiments that they took my grain.</p>
                <p>Ques. 21<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Witness says. I contributed nothing in
                    aid of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Government, or in aid of the
                    Union Army or cause.</p>
                <p>Ques. 22<hi rend="super">nd</hi>. Witness says. That the soldiers of the
                    Union Army after the battle of Piedmont came to my house and got provisions of
                    various kinds, same being commanded by <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi>.</abbr> Hunter.</p>
                <p>Ques. 23<hi rend="super">d</hi>. Witness says. He had no near relatives in
                    the Confederate or Union Armies. I did have nephews in the Confederate
                    Government and a brother in law in the Union Army. I did not supply them with
                    any military equipment or with money.</p>
                <p>Ques. 24. Witness says. I never owned any Confederate bonds, nor any share or
                    interest therein, or did in any way contribute to support the credit of the so
                    called Confederate States, during the rebellion.</p>
                <p>Ques. 25<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. He never <orig reg="gave"
                        >give</orig> any aid and comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>Ques. 26<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. I never was engaged in
                    making raids into the United States from Canada, nor engaged in the destruction
                    of Commerce of the<abbr expan="United"> U.</abbr> States in the rivers adjoining
                    Canada.</p>
                <p>Ques. 27<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. I was never engaged in
                    holding in custody directly or indirectly any persons taken by the rebel
                    Government as prisoners of War.</p>
                <p>Ques. 28<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. I never was <add hand="h1" place="inline">a member
                        of</add> any society for the imprisonment, expulsion or execution of any
                    persons, on account of their loyalty to the United States, or did ever assist in
                    such acts.</p>
                <p>Ques. 29<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. That he was
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">never</add> a paroled prisoner of the United States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 30<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. I have never held any
                    office in the Army or Navy of the United States. I was never educated in the
                    Military Academy at West Point or at the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr>
                    Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 32<hi rend="super">d</hi>. Witness says. That he was not under any
                    disabilities imposed by the 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Amendment to the
                    Constitution of the <abbr expan="United">U.</abbr> States. That he held the
                    office of Registrar by Military appointment and took the so called "Iron Clad"
                    oath.</p>
                <p>Ques. 33<hi rend="super">d</hi>. Witness says. that at the beginning of the
                    rebellion he did sympathise with the Union cause, and did not vote for or
                    against the ordinance of secession and that he adhered to the Union cause during
                    the war.</p>
                <p>Ques. 34<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. That I did from the
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">beginning of</add> hostilities against the United States to the end
                    thereof sympathise with the cause of the same and never of my own free will
                    injured the said cause, and were at all times willing when called upon to aid
                    the cause of the Union or its supporters so far as my means and power and the
                    circumstances of the case permitted.</p>
                <p>Further this witness sayeth not, August 7<hi rend="super">th</hi>, 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">David Myers</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Samuel P. Garber</byline>
                <p>Samuel P. Garber, a witness introduced by David Myers, being first duly sworn
                    answereth as follows.</p>
                <p>Question. How old are you. Where do you reside and what is your occupation?</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Ans</hi>. I am twenty four years old, I reside near New
                    Hope, Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>. <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>.
                    my occupation is a farmer.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Witness says. I was present when the
                    horses were taken belonging to the claimant. I saw them taken. I saw nothing
                    else taken.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. They were taken by <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter's Army, on the 6<hi rend="super"
                        >th</hi> day of June 1864, on the farm of Elizabeth Garber, about 1/4 mile
                    from claimant</p>
                <p>Ques. 5<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. that my mother, Elizabeth
                    Garber, was present.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. that they were taken by
                    soldiers under <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter's command. I did not
                    know the rank or regiment.</p>
                <p>Ques. 8<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says that some were rode and some
                    led off.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says That they were removed to
                    Staunton, I did not follow it.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says I do not know, for what use
                    they were taken.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says there was no complaint made
                    at the time of taking</p>
                <p>Ques. 12<hi rend="super">th.</hi> Witness says there was no receipt taken
                    for the property</p>
                <p>Ques. 13<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. They were taken the day
                    time on the 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> June 1864.</p>
                <p>Ques. 14<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says. They were coming to
                    Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, where they remained not more than
                    week, there was a battle fought at Piedmont on the 5<hi rend="super">th
                    </hi>of June 1864.</p>
                <p>Ques 15<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says that the horses were in
                    pretty good condition and I think the charges made by the claimant are
                    reasonable and fair. They were all young horses. </p>
                <p>Ques. 19<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says that they were taken for the
                    Army, that they the soldiers said they wanted them for the Artillery service.</p>
                <p>Ques. 20<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says they were taken for the use
                    of the Army and not for the soldiers private use.</p>
                <p>Ques. 21<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Witness says. I suppose they were ordered
                    to take them.</p>
                <p>Ques 22<hi rend="super">nd</hi>. Witness says. I do think the Government
                    ought to pay for them.</p>
                <p>Ques 23<hi rend="super">rd</hi>. Witness says. I suppose they had authority
                    to take them.</p>
                <p>Questions asked by the Commissioner</p>
                <p>Question 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. How long have you known the claimant?</p>
                <p>Ans. Ever since my infancy and I have known him to be a loyal man. I saw him
                    often during the war, and lived near him and know that his <orig
                        reg="sympathies">sympathys</orig> were with the Union all the time. He fed
                    the Union soldiers during the time they were about his house, I never knew him
                    to aid the Confederate Government, I never knew him threatened on account of his
                    Union sentiments. He never owned any Confederate bonds. He was regarded a Union
                    man by his neighbors.</p>
                <p>Ques. 2<hi rend="super">d</hi>. Do you know any act done, or language used
                    by the claimant, which would have prevented him from establishing his loyalty to
                    the Confederacy if it had been maintained as a <orig reg="separate"
                    >seperate</orig> Government. If so, state the same particularly.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Ans</hi>. He was such a good Union man that he could not
                    have maintained his loyalty to the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not</p>
                <p>August 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Saml. P. Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Sallie J. Kerr</byline>
                <p>Sallie J. Kerr, a witness is introduced by David Myers, being duly sworn
                    answereth as follows</p>
                <p>Questions by the Commissioner</p>
                <p>Ques. 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Do you know the condition and value of the
                    horses, of the claimant when taken by the United States Army?</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Ans</hi>. The horses were in good condition and I think
                    worth all charged for them. I know that the army took corn. I suppose about the
                    quantity specified, but I do not know what Corn was worth by the bushel, they
                    pastured their horses on the wheat and carried Corn from the barn and fed it in
                    the wheat field--but I do not know how much. I think they took a barrel of flour
                    from the barn.</p>
                <p>Ques. 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi>. How long have you known the claimant?</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Ans</hi>. I have known him all my life and think if there
                    was a loyal man in the Confederacy he was to the United States Government and
                    was so regarded by all his neighbors.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. How old are you? Where do you reside and what is your occupation?</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Ans.</hi> I am 28 years old, I reside near New Hope, Augusta
                        <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>. <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>. by
                    occupation a housekeeper.</p>
                <p>Further this witness saith not,</p>
                <p>August 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Sallie J. Kerr</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>William H. Myers</byline>
                <p>William H. Myers, a witness introduced by David Myers, being duly sworn answereth
                    as follows.</p>
                <p>Questions by the <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super"
                    >r</hi>.</abbr></p>
                <p>Ques. 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. How long have you known the claimant, and
                    do you know him to have been loyal to the United States during the War?</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Ans</hi>. I have known the claimant all my life, he was
                    loyal during the war to the <abbr expan="United States">U. S.</abbr> Government
                    and so regarded by his neighbors. I have heard him to a certain extent defend
                    the Union cause</p>
                <p>Ques. 2<hi rend="super">d</hi>. Do you know of any act done, or language
                    used by the claimant, which would have prevented him from establishing his
                    loyalty to the Confederacy if it had maintained as a <orig reg="separate"
                        >seperate</orig> Government? If so, state the same particularly. How old are
                    you?</p>
                <p>Ans. I think he was too good a Union man to have established his loyalty to the
                    Confederacy had it succeeded. I am 26 years, I reside in New Hope, Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co</abbr>.</p>
                <p>Further this witness saith not.</p>
                <p>August 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Wm. H. Myers</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 7th day of August 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi>.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>David Myers</byline>
                <p>My name is <hi rend="underline">David Myers</hi>, my age <hi rend="underline"
                    >54</hi> years, my residence <hi rend="underline">Augusta County</hi>, in the
                    State of <hi rend="underline">Virginia</hi>, and my occupation a <hi
                        rend="underline">Farmer</hi>; I am <del hand="h1">related to</del> the claimant,
                        <del hand="h1">and have beneficial interest in the claim.</del></p>
                <p>I did not see any of the horses charged taken. I did see the Corn grain, Flour,
                    and sorgham molasses taken. These items were all taken on the 6<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> day of June 1864 from my farm near this place.
                    The Corn was taken out of my granary, by a portion of <abbr expan="General"
                        >Genl.</abbr> Hunter's Army. They were going towards Staunton. <del hand="h1">They
                        said</del> I was at the house an officer came and
                    <del hand="h1">told</del><add hand="h1" place="inline">asked</add> me <del hand="h1">that</del> if I had Corn. I told him I
                    had a little; he said they were obliged to have grain for their horses, and they
                    turned their horses into my wheatfield and came to the barn and carried the corn
                    out. They fed it right there, I saw then they had been feeding it. They left no
                    receipt for it. They got 25 <abbr expan="bushels">bus</abbr>. I knew I had put
                    25 <abbr expan="bushels">bus</abbr> into the granary and I had used none of it
                    and they took it all, the last grain. I was there and insisted on their leaving
                    us some, but they didn't do it. They carried the corn away in my sacks. They
                    took 12 or 15 sacks to carry it away. They did not return the sacks. The sacks
                    were cotton and were not worth more than 25 cts a piece. Corn was worth at that
                    time $1.- per bus in specie.</p>
                <p>The grain charged was growing wheat, just out of bloom. they turned the cavalry
                    horses in on it and pastured it there some 21 acres in the field and it was
                    pretty full of them. It looked to me like it was full. They were in the field
                    about 2 hours, I don't know the number of horses. There must have been a
                    regiment at least. The wheat was good. It was a good season. It would have made
                    at least 15 <abbr expan="bushels">bus</abbr>, to the acre. Wheat standing in the
                    condition mine was at that time was worth $1 per bushel. I cut the corner a
                    small portion of one of the fields about an acre. The horses were hungry and
                        <orig reg="ate">eat</orig> rapidly. they destroyed by tramping about one
                    third <del hand="h1">of</del> as much as they eat.</p>
                <p>The flour charged was taken out of a barrel in my corn cub. They carried the
                    flour away in their Horses sacks. It was a full barrel. They knocked the head of
                    the barrel in an took it all. They stopped <add hand="h1" place="inline">then</add> but for a short time.
                    They carried the flour away with them. I don't know where they took it. The
                    flour <del hand="h1">where</del> was then worth $8 per barrel. They said they were hungry
                    and were obliged to have the flour to eat.</p>
                <p>The sorgham they took at the same time. I think they filled their Canteens with
                    it. <del hand="h1">They took some of the molasses.</del> They said they were obliged to
                    have something to eat. The molasses was in a <unclear>finkin</unclear> in my
                    spring house. There was 12 <abbr expan="Gallons">Galls</abbr> in the
                        <unclear>Finkin</unclear> and they took it all. <orig reg="It">I</orig> was
                    worth $(50 cts) fifty cents per gallon. The battle <del hand="h1">was</del> of Piedmont
                    was fought the day before about a mile from my house. I got no receipts for any
                    of the property charged. I never thought about a receipt. Officers said the saw
                    the soldiers taking the property. I don't think they tried to prevent them from
                    taking it. No one <orig reg="has">is</orig> interest in this claim
                    <del hand="h1">from</del> but me. Further saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">David Myers</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Samuel P. Garber</byline>
                <p>Samuel P. Garber a witness for claimant being duly affirmed and examined by
                    Commissioner deposes and says</p>
                <p>I am 25 years old a resident of Augusta County a farmer by occupation, I am not
                    related to the claimant and have no interest in his claim. I was before examined
                    by Judge W. G. Riley at Staunton in this case. I was present and saw 5 horses
                    taken from the <abbr expan="claimant">clt</abbr>, one was good size Bay horse 6
                    years old and was worth $200--two hundred dollars. One was a brown mare 9 years
                    old worth about $130. One Cobham mare worth $150. One Bay mare worth $130. One
                    sorrel mare worth $75 she was about 12 yrs old. They <del hand="h1">they</del> were all
                    round--in good condition, large, they had no brands on them. I don't think any
                    officers were present when the horses were taken, the horses were taken from my
                    mother's Barn yard, I heard the soldiers tell my mother that they were good
                    horses and that they wanted them for the artillery and that the owner would get
                    paid for them. They took the horses toward Staunton, they said their horses had
                    broken down, It was the day after the battle of the 5<hi rend="bold">th</hi> of
                    June 1864 at Piedmont, I never saw them afterward.</p>
                <p>Further saith not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Saml. P. Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>William H. Myers</byline>
                <p>William H. Meyers, a witness whose testimony was taken and certified by Judge Wm.
                    G. Riley at Staunton on the 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of August 1871
                    in the claim of Daniel Meyers N<hi rend="super">o</hi>. 12113 being
                    recalled at the request of claimant makes the following additional statements
                    and correction of the testimony heretofore taken.</p>
                <p>I do know of acts and language both done and used by the Claimant that might have
                    prevented him from proving his loyalty to the Confederacy if it had been
                    maintained as a <orig reg="separate">seperate</orig><abbr expan="Government"
                        >Govt</abbr>. I know that he assisted me and others to go throught lines
                    north, to keep the rebels from getting us into their Army, He assisted me with
                    money and sent me in a buggy to about 5 miles to the left of Harrisonburg in
                    Rockingham County, a distance of about 27 miles from my home, I know that in his
                    conversations concerning the war he always upheld the north--the Union cause,
                    and to me he denounced the rebellion, I don't remember whether he ever expressed
                    an intention to change his residence in case the confederacy was successful.
                    Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Wm. H. Myers</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                
                <byline>John D. Garber</byline>
                <p>John D. Garber, witness to prove property being affirmed and examined by the
                    Commissioner, deposes and says: I am 22 years old and reside near New Hope, Va.
                    I am a farmer. I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in this
                    claim. I saw five horses belonging to the claimant taken by General Hunter's
                    army in the month of June 1864. The horses were in the barnyard of the stable
                    where they were taken. There were several soldiers present--but I don't know
                    whether there was an officer with them. I heard them say they wanted the horses
                    for the artillery service. One horse was a bay about six years old and worth
                    $200. One was a black mare. I don't know how old, worth about $130. One was a
                    bay mare about three years old, worth about $130. One was a brown mare. I don't
                    recollect how old worth about $120. The claimant was not present when the horses
                    were taken. The soldiers said they had a fight the day before and their horses
                    were broken down and that they needed these horses to supply their place. I knew
                    the horses well and worked them and knew their condition and am thus able to
                    state their value. The fifth horse was a sorrel mare, <del hand="h1">about</del> I do not
                    recollect how old, and was worth $130. Further deponent saith not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">J. D. Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                
                <byline>Samuel P. Garber</byline>
                <p>At the request of the claimant, The <abbr expan="commissioner">commr.</abbr>
                    recalls <abbr expan="Samuel">Saml</abbr>. P. Garber and examines him concerning
                    the pasturage of the wheat charged in the 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> item.</p>
                <p>I did not see the cavalry horses of the Army turned into the field of the <abbr
                        expan="claimant">Clt.</abbr> I did not see them while they were in there, I
                    saw the day after that the field had been pastured off, I know the field well, I
                    know the number of acres, There were two fields. They contained 21 acres. The
                    wheat was growing in the head and didn't lack much of being ripe. It was a good
                    crop, I think it would have made 20 bushels to the acre. I saw it the day after
                        <del hand="h1">the day</del> after the <del hand="h1">Ar</del> the <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi>.</abbr> Hunter's army moved by, It was
                    trampled down and eat off. I suppose about the half of it was eat and nearly all
                    the balance was destroyed. The claimant cut a little of it about an acre or two,
                    which they didn't get over so much--it was pretty tolerable good. The wheat was
                    worth, I think, in that condition a $1 per bushel. And further saith not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Saml. P. Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                
                <byline>Isaac Coffman</byline>
                <p>Depositions of Isaac Coffman, and John A. Stover taken on behalf of David Myers,
                    claimant in the city of Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> said
                    witnesses being duly sworn by me H. Risk, Special Commissioner.</p>
                <p>Deposition of Isaac Coffman</p>
                <p>Answereth</p>
                <p>My name is Isaac Coffman, my age is 46 years, residence near New Hope, Augusta
                    County, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, occupation a farmer. I am related to
                    the claimant by marriage on his wife's side but have no beneficial interest in
                    the cliam. I lived about one mile from the claimant during the war and saw him
                    frequently and talked with him about the war and I always regarded him as a true
                    Union man doubted or questioned by any of his neighbors. I do not recollect any
                    language used by claimant, but have no hesitation in saying that he was a strict
                    union man. I never knew him to do anything to aid the Confederacy except he was
                    compelled to do. The rebels had no confidence in him. I was a Union man myself
                    and the claimant knew it. I am satisfied that had the rebels succeeded in
                    gaining an independent government, the claimant never could have proven any
                    loyalty to that government.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Isaac Coffman</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d17">
                
                <byline>John A. Stover</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John A. Stover</p>
                <p>Answereth--</p>
                <p>My name is John A. Stover, my age is 31 years, my residence near New Hope Augusta
                    County. occupation a farmer. I am not related to the claimant. I resided about
                    ten miles from the claimant during the war. I saw him frequently, but cannot say
                    how often during the time. I heard him talk frequently and always in favor of
                    the Union and its cause. I remember when I was about starting through the lines,
                    that he advised and encouraged me to go, and concealed me at his house until
                    everything could be fixed for my departure. I left in 1864. had never been in
                    the rebel service. I joined the 6th Ohio Regiment, Co. M, under command of
                    General Sheridan. To the time I left I never had heard of the claimants unionism
                    doubted. I believe he was strictly and truly a Union man and he was so regarded
                    by his neighbors. I know that he has acted with the Union party since the
                    surrender and acted as a Justice of the Peace under military rule in this
                    county.</p>
                <p>I have heard him express himself since, and know that he has worked and voted for
                    the Republican party.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John A. Stover</name>
                </p>
                <p>The foregoing depositions were taken by me at the time and place named in the
                    caption.</p>
                <p>H. Risk</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Special">Spe</abbr>. <abbr expan="Commissioner">Commr</abbr>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d18">
                
                <byline>Henry K. Eakle</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Henry K. Eakle, taken in Staunton,<abbr expan="Virginia">
                    Va.</abbr> November 5th, 1874, in behalf of David Myers of Augusta County
                    Virginia who being duly sworn answers as follows. My name is Henry K. Eakle, my
                    age is 55 years, my residence near New Hope in Augusta county, and occupation a
                    farmer. I have known the claimant, David Myers, all my life. I lived one mile
                    from him during the war and saw him very frequently during the war, and talked
                    frequently about the war with him, and am satisfied that his sympathies were
                    always with the Union. He appeared to be pleased when news would reach us of the
                    probability of the Union Army coming to our section, and when General Hunter's
                    did come, he seemed delighted and was <orig reg="relieved">releaved</orig> and
                    pleased with the result of the battle at Piedmont. I never heard his loyalty
                    doubted by the Union men of the neighborhood, and was regarded as a Union man my
                    the rebels of the neighborhood. The prominent Union men of that neighborhood,
                    were Charles Batis, Martin and Saml. Garber, Isaac Coffman and myself, with
                    others. I never knew the claimant to do anything for the Confederacy, except
                    what he might have been compelled. I have no hesitation in saying that I believe
                    he was strictly loyal during the war, and that since he has sustained the
                    Government by his votes and influence. He served as a Justice of the Peace,
                    under the military rule, which none but union men could do. My own record as a
                    Union man was and is well known in my section of the county.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Henry K. Eakle</name>
                </p>
                <p>I certify that the foregoing deposition of Henry K. Eakle was taken by me at the
                    place and on the day named in the caption. And I further certify that the
                    witness is a gentleman of undoubted veracity and loyalty to the Union.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">H. Risk</name>
                </p>
                <p>Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super">r.</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d19">
                
                <byline>H. Risk</byline>
                <p>Staunton, Va., Nov 13<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1874.</p>
                <p>Hon. Comm<hi rend="super">r</hi>. I am satisfied that Mr. David Myers is
                    and was a true Union man, and believe from all I have heard of him that his
                    claim should be allowed.</p>
                <p>Respectfully, <name type="witness">H. Risk</name></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
