<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0500"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0500">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John W. Landis,
                    1875, Claim No. 17922</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john w landis, 1875 claim no 17922</title>
        <author>Landis, John W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 24 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0500</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498387</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John W. Landis, 1875,
                            Claim No. 17922</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john w landis, 1875 claim no 17922</title>
            <author>John W. Landis</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8617</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1875">1875</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Church/Religious Activity, Death Casualties, Economy,
                        Patriotism, Prisons/Prisoners, Slavery, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0500T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John W. Landis filed this claim in 1875 for $595, claiming the Union army took
                    three horses and nine cattle in 1864 during Sheridan's burning of the Shenandoah
                    Valley. John was a 41 year old farmer who resided near Mount Sidney and was a
                    member of the Dunker church. The claim was disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Black Horse 3 years old</cell>
                            <cell>125.00</cell>
                            <cell>0.00</cell>
                            <cell>125.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Bay Mare 8 years old</cell>
                            <cell>100.00</cell>
                            <cell>0.00</cell>
                            <cell>100.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Sorrel mare 3 years old</cell>
                            <cell>100.00</cell>
                            <cell>0.00</cell>
                            <cell>100.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>9 head of Cattle 600 lb each 5400.#505</cell>
                            <cell>270.00</cell>
                            <cell>0.00</cell>
                            <cell>270.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>The Claimant was a resident of Augusta Co. Va. He voted to ratify the ordinance
                    of secession. Was a soldier in both the militia &amp; Confederate Army.
                    Furnished a substitute - paid $500 to be Exempted &amp; his horses and
                    cattle were taken in Sheridan's "burning raid". Not for the use of the army.</p>
                <p>The claim is disallowed.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name>, <name type="other">Orange Ferris</name>,
                        <name type="other">JB Howell</name></p>
                <p><abbr expan="Commissioners">Conmmrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>John W. Landis</byline>
                <p>My name is <hi rend="underline">John W. Landis</hi>, my age <hi rend="underline"
                        >41 years</hi>, my residence <hi rend="underline">Augusta County</hi>, in
                    the State of <hi rend="underline">Virginia</hi>, and my occupation a <hi
                        rend="underline">Farmer</hi>; I am <del hand="h1">related to</del> the claimant, and
                    have beneficial interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>Interrogatory 2. I lived on my fathers farm about 2 miles from Mount Sidney all
                    the time</p>
                <p>3 &amp; 4. No Sir</p>
                <p>5. Yes I went to Staunton and took it after the war.</p>
                <p>6 to 10. inclusive No Sir.</p>
                <p>11 to 15. I was enrolled in the militia and when they were ordered to meet at
                    Staunton I met up there for a week or so. When the quota of our county was made
                    up and I remained at home. In March 1862 I was ordered out again and hired a
                    subsitute who went and served for me until 1863 when I paid my fine of $500 and
                    got a discharge altogether. I was compelled to go myself or get some one in my
                    place. I paid my substitute $800 to go for me during the war. This was done
                    before the law was passed allowing members of our church to pay the fine and
                    after I had put in my subsitute and he had served over a year they conscripted
                    me again and then I paid the fine of $500. I am a member of the Dunkard church.</p>
                <p>16 to 24. inclusive No Sir.</p>
                <p>25. Yes. They took one tenth of my crops for two years. They did not pay me
                    anything for it.</p>
                <p>26 to 29. inclusive No Sir.</p>
                <p>30. Yes. I had one brother named Jacob who was conscripted the same time I was in
                    March 1862. He was shot in the Chancellorsville fight and died soon after. I had
                    another named Daniel who was conscripted at the same time I was in March 1862.
                    He hired a substitute to serve during the war but was conscripted again in 1863
                    and was not allowed to pay the fine; not being a member of the church and he was
                    put in the home guards or reserves as some called them. He was never in any
                    battle. I did not encourage them in any way. They were in the army contrary to
                    their own wishes and mine too.</p>
                <p>31. I had one loan of $500 which I got to pay off my substitute.</p>
                <p>32 to 39. inclusive No Sir.</p>
                <p>40 to 41. I sympathized with the union cause all the time. I thought it wrong for
                    the South to <orig reg="secede">seceed</orig>. I never believed in Slavery. I
                    wanted the North to whip and the union to be preserved. After the state seceded
                    I held for the union. I voted for secession under threats of being put in the
                    army if I did not.</p>
                <p>44. I am a native born citizen of the United States. I have not passed through
                    Bankruptcy.</p>
                <p>In answer to interrogatories as to the Property deponent says - I was present and
                    saw all my property taken. It was all taken at one time by a portion of the Army
                    of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Sheridan at the time of the burning on the
                        28<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of <abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr>
                    1864.</p>
                <p>There were some 8 or 10 men in the party taking the property. They were all taken
                    from a field near the house where they were grazing.</p>
                <p>Item 1. Blk horse. The Black horse was a young animal about three years old well
                    brok to ride but not in the harness. He was a good sized animal nice and fat and
                    was worth $125.</p>
                <p>Item 2. Bay Mare. The bay mare was 8 years old of medium size, an easy keeper
                    kind and gentle and an excellent family horse. She was the favorite of my wife
                    and was in splendid order. She was worth $100.</p>
                <p>Item 3. Sorrel Mare. The sorrel <add hand="h1" place="inline">mare</add> was rising 3 years old. She was
                    broke to ride but not to work. She was about the same size of the black I valued
                    at about $100.</p>
                <p>Item 4. Cattle. The cattle were <del hand="h1">2</del>4 of them <orig reg="milk"
                    >milck</orig> cows and 5 of them young cattle averaging about 2 years old.</p>
                <p>THe cows were first rate ones; good milkers and were in first rate order. I could
                    have sold them all for $25 a head in gold. I did sell one for $25 in gold and
                    was offered $30 in gold for another but would not sell.</p>
                <p>The young cattle were in good order for beef; those that were large enough. I was
                    intending to sell some of them for beef. The five were worth about $20 a head in
                    gold. There was considerable gold in circulation at that time and I had no use
                    for Confederate money.</p>
                <p>The horses were led away and the cattle were driven away. They were all taken
                    from the farm where I was living belonging to my father, about 2 miles from
                        <abbr expan="Mount">Mt.</abbr> Sidney.</p>
                <p>and further deponent saith not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John W. Landes</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Anna Landes</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Anna Landes as to the Property. I am 43 years old. I live with the
                    claimant; he is my husband.</p>
                <p>I was present and saw all the property named in the petition when taken.</p>
                <p>It was taken by a portion of Gen. Sheridans Army in the fall of the year 1864 at
                    the time of the burning; our barn was burnt the same day. There were some 8 or
                    10 men in the party taking the property. When I first saw them coming I went to
                    the lot where the horses were and <orig reg="caught">cought</orig> one who was a
                    favorite of mine and brought him to the yard by the door and held him by the
                    bridle until he was taken from me by some of the party while the others went to
                    the field and got the other two and drove our cattle away also at the same
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">time.</add>We had 9 head of cattle taken at this time 4 of them were
                        <orig reg="milk">milck</orig> cows and 5 were young cattle of different
                    ages, would average about 2 years old.</p>
                <p>The cows were splendid milkers, we never had any before no since like them. and
                    further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Anna Landes</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Sarah E. Grove</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Sarah E. Grove as to the Property. I am 19 years old. I live with
                    the claimant; he is my father.</p>
                <p>I was present and saw our property taken. It was all taken on one day, by the
                    same party, at the time of the burning of the barns in the fall of the year.
                    There were 8 or 10 soldiers on horses came to our place and took all three of
                    our horses and 9 head of cattle and led and drove them all away. They were all
                    in the meadow but one horse which was in the yard my mother had brought one into
                    the yard and was holding the bridle when the men came and took the horse from
                    her and soon after left with all the horses and cattle too. They drove away 10
                    head of cattle, but one of them a cow came back home. I was young, but I
                    recollect distinctly about the taking of the stock and of the burning of the
                    barn.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Sarah E. Grove</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>John Wampler</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Wampler as to the Loyalty of John W. Landes</p>
                <p>I am 46 years old, a farmer, live near <abbr expan="Mount">Mt.</abbr> Sidney. I
                    am not related to the claimant and have no interest in his claim.</p>
                <p>I have known claimant since my childhood. Lived about a mile from him during the
                    war. Saw him many times and heard him speak in favor of the union and against
                    the rebellion. I dont recollect any conversation with him on the subject of
                    secession. I dont recollect how he voted. It is so long since, I have forgotten.
                    He uniformly spoke against the war. He belongs to the church whose principles
                    are opposed to the war and who as a church were loyal to the United States
                    during the war. I think he was generally regarded as a loyal man so far as he
                    could be. We all had to do some things we did not wish to do. Many of us had to
                    pay a fine of $500 to keep from serving in the Army. We were compelled to do it,
                    or go in the army.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Wampler</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>John A. Critzer</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John A. Critzer as to the Loyalty of John W. Landes</p>
                <p>I am 46 years old, a wagon maker, live at <abbr expan="Mount">Mt.</abbr> Sidney,
                    Augusta County, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I am not related to the
                    claimant and have no interest in his claim.</p>
                <p>I have know the claimant about 15 years. I lived about 1 1/2 miles from him
                    during the war until I went north in <abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 1864. I
                    had frequent dealings with Claimant before I went north; he would refuse to take
                    confederate money, said it was of no account. I was at work at my trade in
                    Gordonsville one time when Claimant came to me and offered me 10 bushels of
                    wheat for a cradle that cost me about $3 saying he would rather I would have it
                    than for the rebels to get it. When I went north he knew I was going, and told
                    me if he got in a tight place he should go too. In all my conversations with
                    him, he spoke as if he thought the south was wrong and I was confident he was a
                    loyal man, or I would not have told him I was going through the lines. And
                    further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John A. Critzer</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>Daniel Miller Sr.</byline>
                <p>Q. Where did you reside before and during the war?<lb/>A. Where I now live about
                    one and one fourth miles from where Mr. Landes then lived.</p>
                <p>Q. Were you acquainted with Mr. Landes during said war, and if so was it intimate
                    or otherwise?<lb/>A. Yes I knew him very well.</p>
                <p>Q. About how often on an average did you see and converse with him during said
                    war, and when you did see him and converse with him did you speak on the
                    question of the war, and if so how did he express himself?<lb/>A. I suppose I
                    saw him as much as once every two weeks on an average. We did not talk much
                    about the war, only the trouble we were in, that is we did not know when one
                    army or the other might come in on us.</p>
                <p>Q. From your knowledge of Mr. Landes and his conduct during said war was he
                    opposed or in favor of the Union cause. Also state if you know what his
                    reputation in his neighborhood was on the question of the war during said war,
                    loyal or disloyal to the union?<lb/>A. I <orig reg="always">allways</orig>
                    thought he was a union man, he and I were both in the same company in the
                    militia, and were carried to Staunton. I was sent home for my team which was
                    impressed and took it to Staunton <add hand="h1" place="inline">and made one trip to Monteay</add> and
                    then went back home, and afterwards heard that Mr. Landis <add hand="h1" place="inline">had</add> gotten
                    a substitute, and he afterwards came home. Then afterwards we both paid $500
                    each to keep out of the Confederate army, all members of the <orig
                        reg="Mennonite">menonite</orig> and <orig reg="Dunker">dunkard</orig>
                    churches paid money to keep out of the confederate army, at least his neighbors
                    treated him as a union man.</p>
                <p>Q. What if any thing did the claimant do to aid the union cause during the
                    war?<lb/>A. I can not say.</p>
                <p>Cross Examination</p>
                <p>Q. Did you ever hear the claimant express himself on the question of the war
                    during the war?<lb/>A. Not that I recollect of.</p>
                <p>Q. Then you think he was a union man because he was a member of the <orig
                        reg="Mennonite">Menonite</orig> church, do you not?<lb/>A. Yes.</p>
                <p>Q. Were all the members of that church in your neighborhood union people or union
                        <orig reg="sympathizers">sympathisers?</orig><lb/>A. I think they were as
                    far as I know.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Daniel Miller <abbr expan="Senior">Sen.</abbr></name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>John Wampler</byline>
                <p>Quest. 1 Where did you reside in 1861 and throughout the civil war?<lb/>A. I
                    lived during the war where I now live, about one mile from where the claimant
                    lived.</p>
                <p>Q. 2. Were you acquainted with the claimant during the war and if so was it
                    intimate or otherwise, and if you knew him about how often on an average, did
                    you see him <del hand="h1">him</del> during that period?<lb/>A. I knew him well, and saw
                    him a number of times during the war, but I can not say how often. I think
                    though as often as I saw any other of my neighbors.</p>
                <p>Q. When you saw him during the war did you converse with him on the subject of
                    the war and if so how did he express himself on the subject of the war?<lb/>A. I
                    talked to him and he was like I was we were both in favor of the Union, he <orig
                        reg="always">allways</orig> was opposed to the war, I dont remember what he
                    said, but I do remember that he and I were of the same opinion, both opposed to
                    the war from the beginning to the end.</p>
                <p>Q. How did the claimant vote on the ordinance of secession, if you know?<lb/>A. I
                    dont know how he voted, I did not vote at all. I came to the polls to vote for
                    the union, but there was such a warm time I decided not to vote.</p>
                <p>Q. What if anything did the claimant do during the war to aid the Union
                    cause?<lb/>A. I dont know that he did any thing, we did not dare to do anything,
                    we had to keep low. because they made threats that if a union man did any thing
                    he was threatened with arrest, and it was not safe for him to express his
                    sentiments. I know some who did express union sentiments and were arrested.</p>
                <p>Cross Examination</p>
                <p>Q. Name some of those that you know were arrested on account of Union <orig
                        reg="sentiments">sentaments</orig><lb/>A. Joseph Beery and his son Solomon,
                    and John Cline, and John Yates were arrested during the war by the Confederates
                    and carried to Richmond, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> except Mr. Cline, who
                    was taken to Harrisonburg. and put in jail, but he was afterwards released. He
                    was a preacher.</p>
                <p>Q. Was claimant ever in the Confederate army?<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>with the militia.</p>
                <p>Redirect Examination</p>
                <p>Q. Of what church was Mr. Landes a member of if any during the war? And state
                    what their position was on going to war if they had any?<lb/>A. He was a member
                    of the <orig reg="Mennonite">Menonite</orig> church, that church was like the
                        <orig reg="Dunker">Dunkard</orig> church opposed to war.</p>
                <p>Q. Did you ever testify in this case before?</p>
                <p>A. I can not say. I think I testified for his father, but as for the claimant I
                    can not say.</p>
                <p>Q. From your knowledge of the warm time there was at the voting place on the day
                    of the orindnace of secession was voted upon, was it safe or unsafe for a man on
                    that day to vote against the ordinance of secession.<lb/>Q. We thought it was
                    unsafe, that is the reason I did not vote.</p>
                <p>Recross Examination</p>
                <p>Q. Was any one hurt at the voting place on that day on account of his union <orig
                        reg="sentiments">sentaments?</orig><lb/>A. Not that I know of, I did not
                    stay there long after I found out how things were.</p>
                <p>Q. How many votes were <orig reg="polled">poled</orig> at precinct on that day
                    against the ordinance of secession?<lb/>A. I dont think there were any.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Wampler</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                <byline>John Landes</byline>
                <p>Q. Where did you reside during the civil war?<lb/>A. About two miles east of
                        <abbr expan="Mount">Mt.</abbr> Sidney <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> was
                    a farmer during the entire war.</p>
                <p>Q. Did you ever take an oath to support the Confederacy<lb/>A. No Sir.</p>
                <p>Q. Were you ever connected with the civil or military service of the
                    confederacy?<lb/>A. No sir, except in the Virginia Militia, and they took us to
                    Staunton and drilled us without arms for a while, I had to go or they would have
                    arrested me and taken me to Richmond. I did not want to go, but <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Shumake came for me and said I had to go. After
                    getting to Staunton I got a substitute, I had to do this or be taken to Richmond
                    or go into the Confederate army myself. I did not want to hire a substitute, as
                    it cost me $800 part of it borrowed money, I was told I had to get a substitute
                    or go into the army myself.</p>
                <p>Q. State if you ever gave any aid to the Confederacy <orig reg="voluntarily"
                        >volentarily</orig>?<lb/>A. No sir I did not. They pressed a team from me
                    and my father together <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Wilson was the
                    Quartermaster who pressed the teams in thsi neighborhood, they might have gotten
                    some supplies from my place, but the Confederate army was not in my neighborhood
                    often.</p>
                <p>Q. There seems to be a petition <add hand="h1" place="inline">for exemption of a potter</add> in the
                    archives of the Confederacy signed by John W. Landis, state if you are the same
                    man who signed said petiiton? State also if you ever signed a petition to be
                    exempted from conscription? This last petition was to the Confederate States
                    Congress.<lb/>A. I have <add hand="h1" place="inline">no</add> recollection of signing a petition for the
                    potter, there was a pottery in <abbr expan="Mount">Mt.</abbr> Sidney during the
                    war and I may have signed a petition for one of the Watsons. I can not say about
                    the petition to the Confederate congress. It has been so long that I can not
                    remember about it.</p>
                <p>Q. Were you ever arrested by either side or were you ever threatened on account
                    of your <orig reg="sentiments">centiments</orig>?<lb/>A. I was never arrested by
                    either side, and was never threatened by either side.</p>
                <p>Q. How did you vote on the ordinance of secession?<lb/>A. I can not remember just
                    how I voted or certainly whether I voted, but whatever I said in my former
                    testimony was the fact as I then remembered it.</p>
                <p>Cross Examination</p>
                <p>Q. What relatives did you have in the Confederate Army?<lb/>A. I had one brother
                    in the Confederate Army and one in the home <orig reg="reserve">recerve</orig>,
                    he paid his fine and came home. one brother went north and three brothers-in-law
                    went north.</p>
                <p>Q. What if any thing did you do during the war to aid the Union <del hand="h1">cause</del>
                    cause, state fully.<lb/>A. I did not do much. I had very little opportunity to
                    do any thing.</p>
                <p>Q. After your state <orig reg="seceded">seceeded</orig> did you go with the state
                    of did you remain loyal to the Union?<lb/>A. I remained loyal to the Union.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John W. Landes</name>
                </p>
                <p><name type="other">JB Kagey</name> N.P.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
