<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0523"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0523">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Martin Garber,
                    1871, Claim No. 2537</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of martin garber, 1871 claim no 2537</title>
        <author>Garber, Martin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 21 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0523</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498410</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Martin Garber, 1871,
                            Claim No. 2537</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of martin garber, 1871 claim no 2537</title>
            <author>Martin Garber</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #2537</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Home Front, Patriotism</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0523T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Martin Garber filed this claim in 1871 for $799, claiming Union forces during
                    General Hunter's raid of the Valley took four horses, bacon, cattle, wheat, and
                    a harness in 1864. Martin was a 54 year old farmer near New Hope who did not
                    vote on the Ordinance of Secession question. The commission allowed $557.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Grey horse</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Grey mare</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Bay horse</cell>
                            <cell>$130.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Black horse</cell>
                            <cell>$60.00</cell>
                            <cell>$300.00</cell>
                            <cell>$140.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>50 pounds Bacon</cell>
                            <cell>$7.00</cell>
                            <cell>$7.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>8 Cattle</cell>
                            <cell>$320.00</cell>
                            <cell>$240.00</cell>
                            <cell>$80.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>8 bush. wheat</cell>
                            <cell>$12.00</cell>
                            <cell>$10.00</cell>
                            <cell>$2.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Saddle &amp; harness</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The claimants loyalty is established by his own Statement and that of his
                    neighbors, who testify in his behalf.</p>
                <p>The property for which he asks Compensation was taken by Gen Hunters Command in
                    June 1864.</p>
                <p>We allow the sum of five hundred and fifty seven dollars.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Martin Garber</byline>
                <p>United States of America, State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>. SS</p>
                <p>JWG Riley a commissioner selected and designated by the commissioners of Claims,
                    appointed under the act of Congress of March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi> 1871
                    to take and record testimony. Do hereby certify that the reason for taking the
                    following depositions is, and the fact is, the matter of claims of Martin Garber
                    vs the United States of America and the witness herein named being natural and
                    necessary, being first duly sworn deposed as follows.</p>
                <p>Question, Where do you reside.</p>
                <p>Answer, I reside near New Hope Augusta <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>, by
                    occupation a farmer, age fifty four.</p>
                <p>2 The witness says, Same place.</p>
                <p>3 The witness says, No.</p>
                <p>4 The witness says, I never did take an oath of allegiance to the so called
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5 The witness says, I have never taken any amnesty oath. I have never been
                    pardoned by the President. I have done nothing to be pardoned for.</p>
                <p>6 The witness says, He says he never was directly or indirectly connected with
                    the civil service of the so called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says, He held no office of honor or profit under the Confederate
                    Government.</p>
                <p>8 Witness says-No</p>
                <p>9 Witness says-No</p>
                <p>10 Witness says-He never aided the Confederate Government in any way whatever.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says-No nothing except that which was impressed the witness says he
                    nver rendered any aid whatever to the so called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says-He never was employed in any way for the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>13 Witness says-No he never was employed by the Confederate Government in any
                    way.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says-He never was Engaged in Blockade running never had any interest
                    or share in any goods or wares, brought into or exported from the so called
                    Confederate States during the war.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says-I did not leave the Confederate States between the 19<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> April 1861 and the 19<hi rend="super"
                    >th</hi> April 1865.</p>
                <p>16 Witness says-I never was an owner or part owner or in any way interested in
                    any vessel used in navigating the Ocean to or from any port in the Confederacy
                    or upon any waters in the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17 Witness says-I never was arrested by the Confederate Government or by any
                    Officer, soldier or other person professing to act therefor or for any State in
                    rebellion &amp; never was arrested by the United States Government.</p>
                <p>18 Witness says-I had a good deal of property taken by the Confederate
                    authorities, some was <orig reg="paid">payed</orig> for and some was not.</p>
                <p>19 Witness Says-I never was threatened to my face with damage or injury to my
                    person, family or property on account of my union sentiments, but I was
                    threatened behind my back.</p>
                <p>20 Witness says-I was molested and somewhat injured on account of my Union
                    sentiments more than I otherwise would have been.</p>
                <p>21 Witness says-I never contributed anything to the Union Cause until <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter made a raid
                    through our Valley, and then they gathered up my property that way viz: horses
                    &amp; cattle for the use of the Army.</p>
                <p>22 Witness says-No sir I do not recollect that I did unless by talking in favor
                    of it.</p>
                <p>23 Witness says-I had two nephews in the Confederate Army until they run off. I
                    had no relations in the Union Army that I know of. I contributed nothing to
                    supply them with military equipments or with money.</p>
                <p>24 Witness says-I did own one Confederate bond which I used to pay taxes</p>
                <p>25 Witness says-I have never given aid or comfort to the Rebellion</p>
                <p>26 Witness says-I never was engaged in making raids into the United States from
                    Canada, or engaged in destroying the Commerce of the United States</p>
                <p>27 Witness says-I never was engaged in holding in custody any person taken by the
                    Rebel Government as prisoners of war</p>
                <p>28 Witness says-No sir I never was</p>
                <p>29 Witness says-I never was a parolled prisoner of the United States</p>
                <p>30 Witness says-I have never held any office in the Army or navy of the United
                    States I was not educated by the United States at the Military Academy at West
                    Point or at the United States Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>31 Witness says-I received no pass from the Confederate Government, except to go
                    home from town.</p>
                <p>32 Witness says-I was under no disabilities imposed by the fourteenth article of
                    the amendments to the Constitution of the United States. I have held no Office
                    under the United States Government since the war</p>
                <p>33 Witness says-I sympathized with the Union Cause and not with the Rebellion. I
                    did not vote for or against the ordinance of Secession. I went to the polls to
                    vote against the ordinance of Secession, but the excitement was so great that I
                    came away without voting at <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
                <p>34 Witness says-I from the beginning of hostilities against the United States to
                    the end of thereof my sympathies were with the cause of the United States and
                    that I was at all times ready and willing when called upon to aid the cause of
                    the Union or its supporters so far as my means and power and the circumstances
                    of the case permitted.</p>
                <p>Questions by the Commissioner</p>
                <p>What was the condition of the property charged in your petition when taken by the
                    Government?</p>
                <p>All the stock mentioned in the petition was in good condition when taken by the
                    United States Government. I think that the prices charged in the petition are
                    fair, they would have brought that before the war. The rest of the articles were
                    good and were sold at fair prices. Further this deponent saith not. August the
                        8<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Martin Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Jacob Stover</byline>
                <p>Jacob Stover a witness introduced by Martin Garber, being duly sworn answereth as
                    follows</p>
                <p>Questions by the Commissioner</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> How old are you, where do you reside, and what is
                    your occupation? Answer I am fifty three years old. I reside in Augusta County
                    Virginia, by occupation a farmer</p>
                <p>2 How long have you known the Claimant in this petition Answer I have known him
                    twenty or twenty five years. I reside seven miles from him. I knew him during
                    the war. I saw him often during the war. I took him to be strictly loyal to the
                    United States Government during the war. I did not know any man more so in
                    Augusta County Virginia. He was so regarded by his neighbors. I never heard him
                    threatened on account of his union sentiments but Union people were generally
                    threatened. I never knew him to do anything to aid the Confederate Government,
                    nor do I believe he would have done it voluntarily.</p>
                <p>3 Do you know of any act done or language used by the Claimant which would have
                    prevented him from establish his loyalty to the Confederacy if it had been
                    maintained as a separate Government if so state the same particularly. Answer He
                    was so loyal to the United States Government he could not have been loyal to the
                    Confederate Government if it had been maintained as a separate government.</p>
                <p>Further the witness saith not. August the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Jacob Stover</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>David Perry</byline>
                <p>David Perry a witness introduced by Martin Garber being duly sworn answereth as
                    follows</p>
                <p>1 By Commissioner How old are you where do you reside, and what is your
                    occupation. Answer I am forty nine years old. I reside in Augusta County
                    Virginia by occupation a farmer.</p>
                <p>2 Are you acquainted with the Claimant in this petition Answer I have known him
                    for eleven years. I saw him often during the war. So far as I know and believe
                    he was loyal to the United States Government during the war and so regarded by
                    his neighbors.</p>
                <p>3 Were you acquainted with the property or any part of it mentioned in the
                    Claimants petition Answer I was acquainted with his horses and cows they were in
                    good condition when I saw them last. I saw one of his horses in the posession of
                    the Army of the United States then being commanded by <abbr expan="General"
                            >Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr> Hunter, and from my knowledge
                    of his stock I do not think he has charged the Government too much in his
                    petition.</p>
                <p>4 Do you know any act done, or language used by the Claimant which would have
                    prevented him from establishing his loyalty to the Confederacy if it had been
                    maintained as a separate Government if so state the same particularly. Answer he
                    was too loyal to the United States Government to have been considered a loyal
                    man to the Confederacy if it had been maintained as a separate Government.</p>
                <p>Further this witness saith not. August the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">David Perry</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Martin Garber</byline>
                <p>Martin Garber the Claimant having been duly sworn deposes as follows.</p>
                <p>Witness says-I was present when the cattle were taken. When the horses were taken
                    which was by another portion of the Army, the Cavalry. I was a quarter of a mile
                    distant, they being in the pasture meaning my horses.</p>
                <p>3 Witness says-I saw the grain, the bacon and the harness taken.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says-I say that they were taken the day after the battle of Piedmont
                    which I think was the 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> of June 1864 they were
                    taken from my house by Officers and soldiers under the command of <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter</p>
                <p>6 Witness says-I saw the cattle taken by the Quartermaster, he gave me a receipt
                    for the same which is filed with my petition, he said the army was making a raid
                    and that they had orders to take horses and cattle and flour and bacon and
                    everything else necessary for the use of the army that the Army <hi
                        rend="super">had</hi> lost a good many horses the day before, and that
                    cattle they must have that they had to get their living in the country they
                    passed through.</p>
                <p>8 Witness says-The property was removed by the soldiers. The horses were rode and
                    the cows driven</p>
                <p>9 Witness says-It was removed to Staunton I followed it there. I saw the saddle
                    and one horse the property of Isaac Coffman which was in the pasture with mine
                    at the time they were taken.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says-I complained to the Provost <orig reg="Marshal">Marshall</orig>
                    as they had taken all my horses he told me to come on to Staunton and as they
                    had taken all my horses he would do what he could for me. I went to Staunton the
                    next day and found the Provost Marshal, he told me he was very busy and the
                    Cavalry was all scattered about, and if he would give me an order to hunt my
                    horses unless I was a deity I could not find them he told me to come back some
                    other day. The reason I did not come back, both armies were in the neighborhood
                    and the pickets were fighting.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says-A receipt was given for the Cattle without being asked for which
                    receipt is filed with the petition. There was no other receipt given for any
                    other articles mentioned in the Claimant's petition no other receipt was asked
                    for</p>
                <p>13 Witness says-The property was taken in the day time about ten O'clock and none
                    of the property was taken secretly.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says-It was taken the day after the battle of Piedmont when the Army
                    was on its way to Staunton where it was encamped for several days</p>
                <p>15 Witness says-The horses and cattle were in good condition the cattle were good
                    beef, they were worth what the Claimant has charged the Government in his
                    petition and the Quartermaster's receipt that was given me corresponds precisely
                    with the amount charged by the Claimant in his petition the age of the horses is
                    state in the petition. The wheat mentioned in the Claimant's petition ws
                    threshed and in the barn and was worth at that time what I have charged the
                    Government, as well as the bacon and all other articles mentioned in the
                    Claimant's petition</p>
                <p>16 Witness says-I knew what was in the barn they did not take all. I measured
                    what was left behind which enabled me to know what was taken.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says-I am satisfied that the property which was taken, was taken for
                    the use of the government and for no other purpose.</p>
                <p>20 Witness says-The property was taken for the use of the Government</p>
                <p>21 Witness says-the articles were taken for the use of the Government because the
                    Government needed them</p>
                <p>22 Witness says-I know that it was taken for some purpose so necessary useful
                    beneficial or justifiable as to require the Government to pay for it</p>
                <p>23 Witness says-I do believe that the persons that took the property were
                    authorized, empowered, and justified in taking it or ordering it to be taken.</p>
                <p>Further the deponent saith not Aug 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Martin Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Isaac Coffman</byline>
                <p>Isaac Coffman a witness introduced by Martin Garber being duly sworn answereth as
                    follows.</p>
                <p>Questions by Commissioner</p>
                <p>1 How old are you where do you reside and what is your occupation? Answer I am
                    forty three years old I reside in Augusta County Virginia by occupation a
                    farmer.</p>
                <p>2 Do you know the claimant? Answer I have known him all my life time I reside in
                    a half mile of him. I saw him often during the war, he was loyal to the United
                    States during the war, he was so regarded by his neighbors. He <hi
                        rend="super">always</hi> spoke in favor of the United States
                    Government</p>
                <p>3 Do you know any act done, or language used by the claimant which would have
                    prevented him from establishing his loyalty to the Confederacy, if it had been
                    maintained as a separate Government if so state the same particularly. Answer He
                    was too good a Union man to have been considered loyal to the Confederacy if it
                    had been maintained as a separate government</p>
                <p>And further this witness saith not August the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Isaac Coffman</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 8th day of August 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
