<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0140"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0140">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Daniel Miller,
                    September 3, 1872, Claim No. 2541</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of daniel miller, september 3 1872 claim no 2541</title>
        <author>Miller, Daniel</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 11 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0140</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498365</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Daniel Miller,
                            September 3, 1872, Claim No. 2541</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of daniel miller, september 3 1872 claim no 2541</title>
            <author>Daniel Miller</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington
                            D.C., fiche #482</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0140T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>The Commissioners disallowed Miller's claim for the value of one horse because he
                    voted in favor of the Ordinance of Secession.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Horse</cell>
                            <cell>140.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>140.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimant swears that he went to the Polls with the intention of voting against
                    Secession but was persuaded into voting for it, by the argument that if the
                    State went unanimously the North would not go to war.</p>
                <p>The act of voting for disunion under whatever pretence is inconsistent with loyal
                    adherence to the Union, and we therefore reject the Claim.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Daniel Miller</byline>
                <p>In answer to the First General Interrogatory, the Deponent says: My name is
                    Daniel Miller, my age 53 years, my residence Mt. Sidney, in the state of
                    Virginia, and my occupation a farmer; I am the claimant.</p>
                <p>To question No 2 he answers, I resided where I now live near Mt. Sidney, Augusta
                    Co. Va. on my own farm. It contained 140 acres - one hundred of which were under
                    cultivation. I didn't change my residence or occupation during the war.</p>
                <p>To questions No 3 to 24 inclusive he answered no in full to each question
                    separately and fully put.</p>
                <p>To question No. 25 he answers Myself, two horses and wagon were pressed into
                    service in the year 1863, by a rebel officer whose name or command I did not
                    know, to haul baggage from Staunton to Monterey Va. I was absent four days. I
                    came directly home &amp; got paid in Confederate money.</p>
                <p>To question Nos. 26 to 39 he answers no in full to each question separately put.</p>
                <p>To question No. 38 he answers, I received a pass from a Confederate officer to
                    return home with my team when I was press in 1863. I took no oath to obtain the
                    pass.</p>
                <p>To question No. 39 he answers no</p>
                <p>To question No. 40 he answers At the beginning of the rebellion I sympathised
                    with the Union cause. I never said much about it. I felt that the Union army
                    ought to come through and stop the rebellion. I did not vote upon sending
                    delegates to Richmond to frame the ordinance of secession. When I went to the
                    polls it was with the intention of voting against the ordinance, but they made
                    me believe that the strongest front we presented to the North the less danger
                    there would be of war. <add hand="h1" place="inline">I was sorry after I had cast the vote for the
                        Ordinance that I had done so.</add> After the Ordinance of Secession was
                    adopted I still adhered to the Union cause and did not go with my state.</p>
                <p>For question No. 4 he answers, I do solemnly declare.</p>
                <p>The claimant was here examined by the Commissioner as to property taken.</p>
                <p>I did not see my horse taken. The horse was taken out of the orchard near the
                    house. I was in the house at the time. He was from five to six years old, and
                    was worth $140. He was in good order. Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Daniel Miller</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Christian Kline</byline>
                <p>Christian Kline, witness to prove loyalty of claimant, being sworn by the
                    Commissioner, deposed and says:</p>
                <p>I am 62 years old and reside near New Hope Augusta Co. Va. I am a farmer and
                    miller. I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in his claim. I
                    lived about three miles from him during the war and saw him every few days. I
                    had frequent conversations with him in regard to the cause and progress of the
                    war &amp; knew what his political sympathies and opinions were. I knew he
                    was a union man. I knew what his reputation was for loyalty. It was that of a
                    loyal man. He was regarded a loyal man by his loyal neighbors. I was a loyal man
                    and the claimant so regarded me. I never knew knew him to do anything for the
                    U.S. Army during the war. I never knew him to own any Confederate Bonds, I never
                    know him to be injured or molested on account of his union sentiment. I know no
                    act done or language used that would prevent him from proving his loyalty to the
                    confederate Government if it had maintained a separate existence. Further
                    deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Christian Kline</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>John Wampler</byline>
                <p>John Wampler, witness to prove loyalty of claimant, being affirmed by the
                    Commissioner, deposes and says:</p>
                <p>I am 44 years old and reside at Mt. Sidney, Va. - about half mile from the
                    claimant. I am not related to him and have no interest in this claim. I saw him
                    once or twice a week during the war. I often talked with him in regard to the
                    cause and progress of the war. He always expressed himself in favor of the Union
                    cause. I heard him so express himself in the presence of other persons. I was a
                    loyal man and the claimant so regarded me. I know what his reputation was for
                    loyalty. It was that of a loyal man. His loyal neighbors regarded him a loyal
                    man. I know that he contributed provisions to the Union Hospital near New Hope
                    and at other places. I never knew him to be injured or molested on account of
                    his Union sentiments. I never knew him to own any confederate Bonds. He always
                    said if the Confederates gained their independence we could not live here - he
                    was always for the Union cause and could not have proved his loyalty to the
                    Confederate government if it had suceeded in Maintaining a separate existence.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Wampler</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Barbara Wampler</byline>
                <p>Barbara Wampler, witness to prove property being affirmed by the Commissioner,
                    says:</p>
                <p>I am 39 years old and reside near Mt. Sidney, Va. I am not related to the
                    claimant and have no interest in his claim. I was present and saw his horse
                    taken by the yankee army at the time of the Burning Raid. I don't remember what
                    year it was in or what officer was in command at the time. The horse was in the
                    yard at the house when two soldiers came and took the horse away. It was in
                    day-time. I did not hear anything said at the time. The army was encamped about
                    a mile off. It was a bay <del hand="h1">horse</del> mare. I do not know how old it was. I
                    think it was worth about $140. I don't know whether any officer was with the
                    soldiers when they took the horse - and I don't know an officer from a soldier.
                    I never saw the horse afterward. This is all I know about it.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Barbara Wampler</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>John Miller</byline>
                <p>John Miller, witness to prove property being affirmed by the Commssioner deposes
                    and says:</p>
                <p>I am 58 years old, and reside near Mt. Sidney Va. I am a brother to the claimant.
                    I have no interest in this claim. At the time of Sheridan's Raid - September
                    1864 - I saw a bay mare which I recognized as the claimant's, in the posession
                    of the troops who were on the Burning Raid. They came to my house &amp; had
                    the mare. A Union soldier was riding the mare. No conversation passed in regard
                    to the mare. The mare was a good one, and was worth $100 or $150 at that time. I
                    recognized the mare from her general appearance - having known her from a calf.
                    She was not branded.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Miller</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>John Wampler and Joseph Click</byline>
                <p>We the undersigned Loyal citizens of Augusta County Virginia, do certify on oath
                    that we have known Daniel Miller for many years and know him to have been Loyal
                    to United States Government before, and at the time of and since the taking of
                    the property in the claimants petition mentioned.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">John Wampler</name>, Mt. Sidney <name type="witness">Joseph
                        Click</name>, Mt. Sidney</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 29th day of April 1871 <name
                        type="other">H.M. McCausland</name> N.P.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
