<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0108"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0108">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John R.
                    Buchanan, September 14, 1871, Claim No. 6893</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john r buchanan, september 14 1871 claim no 6893</title>
        <author>Buchanan, John R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 12 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0108</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498333</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John R. Buchanan,
                            September 14, 1871, Claim No. 6893</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john r buchanan, september 14 1871 claim no 6893</title>
            <author>John R. Buchanan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #6857</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0108T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Buchanan's claim for one horse was disallowed because the Commissioners believed
                    that Buchanan, as a minor during the war, could not have owned the horse
                    outright.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bay Horse</cell>
                            <cell>$175.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$175.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>If he gives his age correctly, the claimant was born in 1844 &amp;
                    consequently was but 20 years of age when the horse was taken in 1864. In the
                    year 1863 he left as he says to avoid the rebel conscription &amp; went to
                    Ohio &amp; remained until after the war. The horse was taken by Gen. Hunters
                    command while the Claimant was in Ohio. He says nothing about ownership.</p>
                <p>David Buchanan is called as a witness - says he is 68 years of age resides in
                    Augusta Co. &amp; the property was taken from his farm in June 1864. He says
                    nothing about the claimant's owning the horse nor whether he is any way related
                    to the claimant. How this claimant then a boy became the owner of the horse
                    should have been shown by the most conclusive proof. We suspect David Buchanan
                    is the father of the claimant &amp; that he was the real owner of the horse.
                    We are not willing to report favorably upon the claim as the proofs now stand.
                    It is rejected.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>John R. Buchanan</byline>
                <p>Before the Commissioners of Claims, under the Act of March 3<hi
                        rend="super">d</hi> 1871. Jno. R. Buchanan vs. The United States</p>
                <p>On this fourteenth day of Sept. 1871 at Staunton in the County of Augusta and
                    State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi> personally came Jno. R. Buchanan
                    claimant, and David Buchanan and David Sansibaugh his witnesses, in a cause now
                    pending before the commissioners of claims in the name Jno. R. Buchanan vs. the
                    United States, before me a U. States Commissioner and also Special Commissioner
                    appointed by the Commissioner of Claims. Present Jno. R. Buchanan claimant and
                    Attorney for said claimant. The said claimant, and each of said witnesses, were
                    first, before any questions were put to them, properly &amp; duly sworn to
                    tell the truth, the whole truth, &amp; nothing but the truth, relative to
                    the matters in which they were to testify; and the testimony of the
                        <unclear>claimant</unclear> and said witnesses were taken down by me, or in
                    my presence, and I read over to said claimant and to each of said witnesses
                    their respective depositions; and the said depositions were duly signed in my
                    presence.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">Wm G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>U.S. Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for State of
                        V<hi rend="super">a</hi></p>
                <p>Deposition of Jno. R. Buchanan</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 28 years old. I reside in Augusta. I am a farmer. I
                    resided six months before the war in Augusta, <orig reg="have">hav</orig> lived
                    in Augusta all my life, except when I was in Ohio. I went there in Dec. 1863,
                    &amp; remained until after the War. Was farming while there.</p>
                <p>3 Witness says, Never passed the Military or Naval lines of the U.S. &amp;
                    enter the rebel lines</p>
                <p>4 Witness says: I never took an oath of allegiance to the Confed. States</p>
                <p>5 Witness says: I took an amnesty oath in 1865, in Staunton Va.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says: I never was indirectly nor directly in any manner connected with
                    the Civil Service of the Confed States.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says, I never held any office or place of honor, profit, or trust under
                    the Confed. States.</p>
                <p>8 Witness says: Held no office or clerkship of any kind under the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>9 Witness says: I was in no way in the military or Naval service of the Confed
                    States.</p>
                <p>10 Witness says: I never was an officer soldier sailor or marine in either the
                    army or Navy of the Confed. had nothing whatever to do with them.</p>
                <p>11 Witness Says: I never was in any service or employment of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says: I never was engaged in the manufacture of any goods of any kind
                    for the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>13 Witness says: I never was engaged in the purchase of any stores for the
                    Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>14 Witness Says, I never was engaged in <orig reg="blockade">blocade</orig>
                    running.</p>
                <p>15 Witness Says: I left the Confederacy in Dec. 1863 &amp; went to Ohio. I
                    left to keep out of the rebel army, &amp; stayed away until after the war.
                    Was engaged in farming while there. I came back to Augusta Co.</p>
                <p>16 Witness says, I never was engaged in a vessel navigating to or from any port
                    of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17 Witness says, I never was arrested by either the Confederate or U. States
                    Govt.</p>
                <p>18 Witness says: I had one cow taken by the Confederates <abbr expan="received"
                        >recd.</abbr> no pay for it. Was taken by Frank Hite for the use of the
                    Confederate Govt. he was impressment officer</p>
                <p>19 Witness Says: I was threatened, to be shot, by Confederates, &amp; to burn
                    my property.</p>
                <p>20 Witness says, I never was molested or injured in person, except my health was
                    injured by laying out in the woods, to avoid Confederate service</p>
                <p>21 Witness says: I never contributed any thing to aid the Union Cause</p>
                <p>22 Witness says: I never did anything for the US Army</p>
                <p>23 Witness says: Had near relatives in both armies. Contributed nothing to supply
                    them with either equipment or money.</p>
                <p>24 Witness says, I have never done anything to support the cause of the
                    Confederate Govt. Have never owned any bonds.</p>
                <p>25 Witness says: I have never given aid or comfort to the Confederacy in any way</p>
                <p>26 Witness says: I never engaged in making raids into the US, or in obstructing
                    its commerce.</p>
                <p>27 Witness Says: I never was engaged in any manner, in holding in custody any
                    persons, taken as prisoners of war by the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>28 Witness Says: I never was a member of any society for the imprisonment or
                    execution of any person on account of Union sentiments</p>
                <p>29 Witness says: I never was a paroled prisoner of the United States</p>
                <p>30 Witness Says, I never held any office in either the Army or Navy of the U.S.
                    Was not educated either at West Point or the Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>31 Witness says, I never received any pass of any kind from any officer of the
                    Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>32 Witness Says: I am not &amp; never have been in any degree under any
                    disabilities imposed by the 14th Amendment of the Constitution of the U.S. Have
                    not held any office under the U.S. Govt. since the war.</p>
                <p>33 Witness Says: At the beginning of the War I sympathized with the Union Cause,
                    &amp; continued to do so during the war. I exerted my influence for the
                    Union. Did not vote either for or against the ordinance of secession, had no
                    vote. After its adoption I adhered to the Union Cause, &amp; did not go with
                    my state.</p>
                <p>34 Witness Says: I do solemnly declare, that from the beginning to the end of the
                    war my sympathies were with the Union Cause, &amp; I was at all times ready
                    &amp; willing to aid it so far as the circumstances permitted, &amp;
                    further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 14th 1871 <name type="claimant">Jno. R. Buchanan</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 14th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>U. States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for the
                    State of V<hi rend="super">a.</hi></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>David Buchanan</byline>
                <p>Deposition of David Buchanan to prove taking &amp; furnishing property.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 68 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a farmer.
                    Have lived in Augusta during my life I was present when the property mentioned
                    in this petition was taken.</p>
                <p>Ques 2 Witness says: I saw the horse mentioned taken</p>
                <p>Ques 3 Witness says, Did not see anything else taken</p>
                <p>4 Witness Says, The property was taken by Union Soldiers, from my farm, June
                    1864, Hunters <abbr expan="Command">Comd</abbr>.</p>
                <p>5 Witness says: Myself &amp; wife</p>
                <p>6 Witness says, No U. States officers were present</p>
                <p>7 Witness says: The horse was taken, &amp; ridden away by Union Soldiers.</p>
                <p>9 Witness says: The property was taken to the Army. Did not see it again.</p>
                <p>10 Witness says, I suppose it was taken for the use of the army</p>
                <p>11 Witness says: No complaint was made.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says: No receipt was given none asked for.</p>
                <p>13 Witness says, The property was taken in the day time.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says, No part of the Army was encamped near. No battle or skirmish
                    near. Did not know any of the Officers.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says: The horse was in tolerable condition, a large bay worth One
                    Hundred &amp; fifty Dollars in Cash.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says, Taken for the use of the Army. Not for private use</p>
                <p>22 Witness Says, I think it was taken through necessity, &amp; therefore the
                    Govt. should pay for it.</p>
                <p>23 Witness Says: I believe it was taken by proper authority &amp; further
                    this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 14th 1871 <name type="witness">David Buchanan</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me, this 14 day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W G Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>U. States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for the
                    State of V<hi rend="super">a.</hi></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
