<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0120"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0120">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Abraham Lavell,
                    September 12, 1871, Claim No. 2638</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of abraham lavell, september 12 1871 claim no 2638</title>
        <author>Lavell, Abraham</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 25 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0120</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498345</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Abraham Lavell,
                            September 12, 1871, Claim No. 2638</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of abraham lavell, september 12 1871 claim no 2638</title>
            <author>Abraham Lavell</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8616</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0120T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Lavell's claim for the value of two horses was disallowed for lack of evidence of
                    active loyalty. His widow appealed this decision to the Court of Claims in
                1893.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Horse (Bay)</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Gray Horse</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$300</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$300</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Giving full weight &amp; credit to the statement under oath of claimant
                    himself, he was at best, but a neutral He does not remember whether he took the
                    oath of Allegiance to the Confederate government. He says he had no sympathy
                    with the Confederate government, only wanted the war to cease. His sympathies
                    were with the whole human family &amp; he did not take rides with either
                    party. This is doing pretty well considerig he had two sons in the Confederate
                    army &amp; no relatives in the Union Army, but it is not enough to entitle
                    him to renumeration upon the recommendation of this Commission. The two
                    witnesses called to prove his loyalty testify to nothing material. The claim is
                    rejected</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Abraham Lavell</byline>
                <p>United States of America State of Virginia L.L.</p>
                <p>I, W.G. Riley a commissioner selected &amp; designated by the commissioners
                    of claims appointed under the act of March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi> 1871
                    to take &amp; record testimony do hereby certify that the reason for taking
                    the following deposition is &amp; the fact is the matter of claim of <orig
                        reg="Abraham">Abram</orig> Lavell of Augusta Co. vs: The United States of
                    America &amp; the witnesses herein being named first duly sworn, answer as
                    follow.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 76 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. V<hi
                        rend="super">a</hi>. I am a gentleman. I resided in Augusta Co. V<hi
                        rend="super">a</hi> six months <orig reg="before">befor</orig> April
                    1861</p>
                <p>2 Witness says, Resided in Augusta Co V<hi rend="super">a</hi> &amp;
                    did not leave at any time</p>
                <p>3 Witness says, I never passed the Military or Naval lines of the U.S. &amp;
                    entered the rebel lines</p>
                <p>4 Witness says, Do not remember to have taken an oath of Allegiance to the Confed
                    Govt.</p>
                <p>5 Witness says: I took an amnesty oath in 1865 at Staunton V<hi
                        rend="super">a</hi>. it was required of every one. Have never been
                    pardoned</p>
                <p>6 Witness says: I never was in any way directly or indirectly in the civil
                    service of the Confed States.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says, I never held any office of honor, profit or trust under the
                    Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>8 Witness says, Never held any clerkship or office of any kind.</p>
                <p>9 Witness says, I never was in any capacity in the Military or Naval service of
                    the Confed. Govt. Never was a soldier or sailor in either the army or Navy or
                    connected with any dept. of the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>10 Witness says: Never was employed in any of the Departments of the Confed Govt.
                    Never had charge of any trains, teams or wagons of the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says: I never did anything but feed the soldiers of both armies.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says: Was never engaged in manufacturing munitions of War for the
                    Confed Govt. or anything used by them</p>
                <p>13 Witness says: I never was directly nor indirectly employed, in the collection
                    or impressment of supplies for the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says: I never was engaged in blockade running, &amp; had no share
                    nor interest in any goods brought into the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says: I did not leave the Confed. States, between the 19 of April
                    1861, &amp; the 19 of April 1865</p>
                <p>16 Witness says: I never was engaged or interested in any <orig reg="vessel"
                        >vesall</orig>, employed in navigating to or from any port of the
                    Confederacy</p>
                <p>17 Witness says, I never was arrested by either the U.S. or Confed Govt.</p>
                <p>18 Witness says: I had no property taken by the Confed. Govt. except what was
                    stolen, when I was asleep</p>
                <p>19 Witness says: I never was threatened injured nor molested on account of my
                    Union sentiments</p>
                <p>21 Witness says: I contributed nothing for the U.S. Govt. during the war either
                    for the Army nor Navy</p>
                <p>23 Witness says: I had two sons in the Confed. Army. Had no relations in the
                    Union army. I did nothing to supply them with military equipment or money.</p>
                <p>24 Witness Says, I owned 8% bonds of the Confed. Govt I did nothing else to
                    support the credit of the Confed Govt.</p>
                <p>25 Witness says: I have never given aid nor comfort to the rebellion</p>
                <p>26 Witness says: I never was engaged in making raids from Canada, nor in
                    destroying the commerce of the U.S.</p>
                <p>27 Witness says: I never was in any manner engaged in holding in custody persons
                        <orig reg="taken">taking</orig> as prisoner by the Confed Govt.</p>
                <p>28 Witness says: I never was a member of any society for the expulsion or
                    persecution of any person on account of loyalty to the U States</p>
                <p>29 Witness says, Never was a paroled prisoner of the U.S.</p>
                <p>30 Witness says: Never held any office in the Army or Navy of the U.S. Was not
                    educated either at West Point or the Naval Academy</p>
                <p>31 Witness says: Never had any pass from any one during the war</p>
                <p>32 Witness says: I am not &amp; never have been under any disabilities
                    imposed by the fourteenth amendment of Constitution of the United States.</p>
                <p>33 Witness says: I had no sympathy with the Confederate Govt. only wished the war
                    to cease. I neither voted for nor against the ordinance of <orig reg="secession"
                        >cesession</orig>. My sympathies were with the <orig reg="whole">whol</orig>
                    human family. I did not take sides with either party.</p>
                <p>34 Witness Says: The fact is, as I said before my sympathies were with the whole
                    human family &amp; further this deponent sayeth not</p>
                <p>Sept. 12th 1871 <orig reg="Abraham">Abram</orig> Lavell his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 12th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com:
                    for State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Jacob Steele</byline>
                <p>Jacob Steele a witness introduced by the claimant to prove the taking &amp;
                    furnishing of the property, being duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 27 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a Farmer I
                    was present when the claimants horses were taken I saw them taken. Saw nothing
                    else taken. They were taken in June 1864 from claimants farm, by soldiers of the
                    Union Army under command of Genl. Hunter.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says: I don't know that any officer <orig reg="was">were</orig>
                    present.</p>
                <p>8 Witness says, The horses were led away by the soldiers, they were removed to
                    Staunton, did not see it again</p>
                <p>10 Witness says: I suppose it was taken for the use of the Army</p>
                <p>11 Witness says: No complaint made</p>
                <p>12 Witness says: No receipt given &amp; none asked for.</p>
                <p>13 Witness says: The property was taken about 12 O'clock in the day it was not
                    taken secretly.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says, When the property was the army was encamped about 2 miles off.
                    They had been there about a week. Had been no battle or skirmish near. Did not
                    know either of Nor any of them.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says: The horses, were in good condition. One brown horse, about 9
                    years old, was worth One Hundred &amp; fifty dollars. One grey mare about 5
                    years old worth One Hundred &amp; thirty dollars</p>
                <p>22 Witness says: I think the property was taken for some purpose so careful
                    &amp; necessary, as to warrant the Govt. in paying for it, &amp; further
                    this deponent sayeth not</p>
                <p>Sept 12th 1871 Jacob Steele his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 12th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com:
                    for State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>James W. Beard</byline>
                <p>James W. Beard, a witness introduced to prove the loyalty of the claimant, being
                    duly sworn answers as follows:</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says, I am 43 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. V<hi
                        rend="super">a</hi>. I am a tanner. Have known the claimant 20 years.
                    I have lived about 3 miles from him. Saw him often during the war. Talked with
                    him about the War. He was loyal to the US Govt. &amp; was so regarded by his
                    neighbors so far as I know. Never knew him to do anything for either the U.S. or
                    rebel govts. during the war. I think he was too loyal to the U.S. govt. to have
                    been loyal to the Confed. Govt. had it succeeded, &amp; further this
                    deponent sayeth not</p>
                <p>Sept 12th 1871 <name type="witness">J.W. Beard</name></p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 12th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com:
                    for State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>N.K. Trout</byline>
                <p>N.K. Trout a witness introduced by the claimant to prove his loyalty, to the
                    Govt. of the U.S. being duly sworn, answers as follows.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 52 years, reside in Staunton, V<hi rend="super"
                    >a</hi>. &amp; by profession a Lawyer. Have known the claimant 30 years, he
                    has lived within 5 miles of Staunton since I have known him frequently during
                    the war. Had no doubts as to his loyalty to the US Govt. during the war. He was
                    opposed to the war in the beginning, &amp; desired the restoration of the
                    Govt. I think he was too loyal to the U.S. to have been loyal to the Confed.
                    Govt. had it succeeded &amp; further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept 12th 1871 <name type="witness">NK Trout</name></p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 12th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com:
                    for State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi>.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Charles Forter</byline>
                <p>Treasury Department Office of the Secretary Washington, D.C. May 3, 1892.</p>
                <p>The Honorable The Attorney General.</p>
                <p>Sir: In answer to your request of the 9th ultimo in the case of the estate of
                    Abraham Lavell against the United States, No. 8616 Congressional. I have the
                    honor to state that the name of A. Lavell is found in a copy of a list of those
                    who voted for the ordinance of secession in Augusta County, Virginia, the
                    original of which is presumed to be in the custody of the clerk of the court of
                    said county.</p>
                <p>Respectfully yours, <name type="witness">Charles Forter</name> Secretary.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Claimant's Brief on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS. DECEMBER TERM 1892-93.</p>
                <p>Abraham Lavell vs. The United States No. 8616 Cong.</p>
                <p>STATEMENT</p>
                <p>The claimant in this case resided in Augusta Co., Va. during the late war of the
                    Rebellion. He presented his claim to the Commissioners of Claims, and it was
                    disallowed by said Commissioners, and under the head of remarks they state:--</p>
                <p>"Giving full weight and credit to the statement under oath of claimant himself,
                    he was at best but a neutral. He does not remember whether he took the oath of
                    allegiance to the Confederate Government. He says he had no sympathy with the
                    Confederate Government, only wanted the war to cease. His sympathies were with
                    the whole human family and he did not take sides with either party. This is
                    doing pretty well considering he had two sons in the Confederate army and no
                    relatives in the Union army, but it is not enough to entitle him to renumeration
                    upon the recommendation of this Commission. The two witnesses called to prove
                    his loyalty testify to nothing material. The claim is rejected." Signed by none
                    of the Commissioners.</p>
                <p>The claim was referred to the Court by the Committee on War Claims, Feb. 26th,
                    1892.</p>
                <p>BRIEF ON LOYALTY.</p>
                <p>The following testimony was taken while the claim was pending before the
                    Commissioners of Claims. This testimony was taken in Sept. 1871.</p>
                <p>ABRAHAM LAVELL, the claimant, testifies age 76; residence Augusta Co., Va. I
                    resided in Augusta Co., Va. six months before April '61. I never passed the
                    Military or Naval lines of the U.S. and entered the Rebel lines. Don't remember
                    to having taken the oath of allegiance to the Confederate Government. Took the
                    amnesty oath in '65 at Staunton, Va. It was required of every one. Have never
                    been pardoned. (P. 1). Questions 6 to 10 inclusive answered in the negative
                    favorable to loyalty. I fed the soldiers of both armies. Questions 12 to 17
                    inclusive answered in the negative favorable to loyalty. (p. 2). Had no property
                    taken by the Confederate Government except what was stolen when I was asleep.
                    Never was threatened on account of my Union sentiments. Contributed nothing for
                    the U.S. Govt. during the war, either for the army or navy. I had two sons in
                    the Confederate army. Had no relatives in the Union army. Did nothing to supply
                    them with military equipments or money (P. 3.) I owned 8% bonds of the
                    Confederate Government; did nothing else to support the credit of the
                    Confederate Government. I have never given aid or comfort to the Rebellion.
                    Questions 26 to 32 inclusive answered in the negative favorable to loyalty. (P.
                    4.) I had no sympathy with the Confederate Government; only wished the war to
                    cease. I neither voted for nor against the ordinance of secession. My sympathies
                    were with the whole human family. I did not take sides with either party. The
                    fact is as I said before my sympathies were with the whole human family (P. 5).</p>
                <p>JAS. W. BEARD testifies age 43; residence Augusta Co., Va.; farmer. Live about
                    three miles from claimant Saw him often during the war. Talked with him about
                    the war. He was loyal to the United States Government and so regarded by his
                    loyal neighbors, so far as I know. Never knew him to do anything for either the
                    U.S. or Rebel Governments during the war. Think he was too loyal to the U.S.
                    Government to have been loyal to the Confederate Government, had it succeeded.
                    (P. 8).</p>
                <p>N.K. TROUT testifies age 52; residence Staunton, Va. Lawyer. Have known the
                    claimant 30 years He has lived within five miles of Staunton since I have known
                    him. Saw him frequently during the war. Had no doubt as to his loyalty to the
                    U.S. Government during the war. He was opposed to the war in the beginning and
                    desired the restoration of the Government. I think he was too loyal to the
                    United States to have been loyal to the Confederate Government, had it
                    succeeded. (P. 9).</p>
                <p>The following testimony has been taken since the reference of the claim to the
                    Court. This testimony was taken Oct. 12th, 1893.</p>
                <p>LUCY A LAVELL, testifies housekeeper; age 47; residence Staunton, Va. Interested;
                    widow of the deceased claimant. (P. 1). I was married to Mr. Lavell in 1862.
                    Knew him about four years before I was married. Didn't live very far from him.
                    About a mile and a half. He was sixty years old when I married him. I heard him
                    talk a good deal about the war. He was against it. He talked with Mr. Myers and
                    Mr. Beard about the war. They were neighbors of ours and came to see us right
                    often. They were against the war; Union people. (P. 2.) They said they had
                    better let the war alone; it would be a bad day's work. I heard them talking
                    sitting on the porch at my house. Mr. Lavell was not in favor of his two sons
                    going into the Confederate army. He told them it would be a bad day's work if
                    they went into that army. They had families at the time. He told them that he
                    would not take care of their families; they would have to do the best they
                    could. My husband did not vote for secession. He was at home on election day.
                    (P. 3.) He did not go to the election at all. He was not in the Confederate
                    army. He had two sons in the Rebel army and he was opposed to it. Their names
                    were David Lavell and Abraham Lavell. The Confederates got property from my
                    husband. They came and took the hay out of the barn and a barrel of flour and
                    killed some shoats. They took seven sheep skins. They took two horses. One was a
                    dark bay and the other an iron gray. My husband did not tell them they might
                    have the horses and the other property. (P: 4.) They did not take any of this
                    property at his request. They came in the fore part of the day and took the
                    horses and at night they took the hay and flour. Mr. Lavell did not allow them
                    to have this property for the purpose of helping the war along. He did not want
                    to help the war along. From what I know of my husband's feelings and sentiments,
                    I can say that he was in favor of the United States Government from the
                    beginning to the close of the war. The people in our neighborhood in favor of
                    the U.S. Government, thought he was all right in believing what he did. His son
                    enlisted April 18th, '61 at Lexington, Va., in Co. "C", First Va. Cavalry,
                    Confederate Troops. (P. 5).</p>
                <p>CROSS-EXAMINATION.</p>
                <p>I was married on Sept. 8th, 1862. The matters I have related to and conversations
                    with him occurred after we were married. The sons enlisted in the army after we
                    were married. They were both married. They were living away from home when they
                    went into the war. (P. 6). One lived about 36 miles and the other three miles.
                    (P. 7):</p>
                <p>SUMMARY.</p>
                <p>Abraham Lavell the claimant, was 66 years of age at the commencement of the war.
                    He resided during the war in Augusta Co., Va. He did not vote for nor against
                    secession. Did not take sides with either party. He owned 8% bonds of the
                    Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>His witnesses testify that he expressed loyal sentiments during the war. He had
                    two sons in the Confederate army. It appears however, that they had families and
                    were living by themselves. One of his sons was named Abraham.</p>
                <p>It is very evident from the testimony that it was his son and not himself that
                    voted for secession.</p>
                <p>Respectfully Submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> ATTY FOR <abbr
                        expan="CLAIMANT">C'L'M'T</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>Defendant's Brief on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS.</p>
                <p>Estate of Abraham Lavell, dec'd vs. The United States. No. 8616--Cong.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="underline">Defendant's Brief on Loyalty.</hi>
                </p>
                <p>This claim is for two horses, valued at $300, alleged to to have been taken from
                    the decedent near Min<del hand="h1">o</del>t Spring, just south of Staunton, Augusta Co.,
                    Va. by United States troops on June 6, 1864.</p>
                <p>It was rejected by the Commissioners of Claims for lack of proof of loyalty.</p>
                <p>The decedent, who testified before a special commissioner in Sept. 1871, did not
                    claim to have been more than neutral, explaining his neutrality by the statement
                    that his sympathies were with "the whole human family". As a portion of that
                    family the people of the Confederate States necessarily came in for their share
                    of that sympathy. In answer to the 34th interrogatory, he utterly failed to
                    respond to the searching questions as to loyalty, therein propounded, and merely
                    repeated his former statement as to his sympathy with the human family. The
                    decedent did not vote on the question of secession, but did not claim that it
                    would have been dangerous for him to vote against it. He <hi rend="underline"
                        >did not remember</hi> having taken an oath of all allegiance to the
                    Confederacy. He took the amnesty oath in 1865. He owned some 8% bonds of the
                    Confederate Government, and had two sons in the Southern army.</p>
                <p>The Confederate Archives contain two vouchers for payments to A. Lavell at
                    Staunton, viz.: $28. for two dozen sheep skins, June 14, 1862, and $55O. fora
                    bay mare, Dec. 1. 1863. The signatures appear to have been written by the
                    decedent. In his testimony in 1871, the decedent said, "I had no property taken
                    by the Confederate Government except what was stolen when I was asleep"; and
                    hence the property mentioned in tne vouchers must have been sold to the
                    Confederacy and not "taken" by it. The decedent's widow, in her recent
                    depositions, states that the Confederates took two horses, seven sheep skins,
                    and some other articles, the latter at night, but the horses in the day time. As
                    he did not himself say that any horses were impressed it cannot be presumed that
                    they were so taken.</p>
                <p>The Archives also <del hand="h1">present</del><hi rend="super">contain</hi> a voucher
                    for the services of two slaves paid for near Lexington, Va., but although the
                    signature resembles that of the decedent it may be his son's. A quartermaster's
                    return of hay purchased of A Lavell near Lexington, Va, June 24, 1864, but not
                    paid for, may also refer to the son.</p>
                <p>In conclusion it is submitted that the depositions in favor of the decedent's
                    loyalty (that of J.W. Beard and N.K. Trout in 1871, and of the decedent's widow
                    in 1893) would be too meagre and indefinite to prove loyalty even if they were
                    not completely refuted by the decedent's own admissions of mere neutrality, and
                    of ownership of Confederate bonds, and by the evidence of his dealings with the
                    Confederacy.</p>
                <p><name type="other">Charles C. Binney</name> Assistant Attorney.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
