<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0521"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0521">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Lydia Fishburn,
                    1876, Claim No. 17000</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of lydia fishburn, 1876 claim no 17000</title>
        <author>Fishburn, Lydia</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 26 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0521</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498408</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Lydia Fishburn, 1876,
                            Claim No. 17000</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of lydia fishburn, 1876 claim no 17000</title>
            <author>Lydia Fishburn</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim # 17000</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1876">1876</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Death/Casualties, Enlistment, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0521T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Lydia Fishburn filed this claim in 1876 for $1105.50, claiming Union forces under
                    General Hunter took two horses, corn, sheep, butter, hogs, bacon, lard, salt
                    beef, apple butter, sorgham, vinegar, and hay in 1864. Lydia was the widow of
                    Philip Fishburne. One of her sons residing in Staunton, George, was in the
                    Confederate Army. She had one son and two grandsons in the Union Army. The
                    commission allowed $714.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 Horses</cell>
                            <cell>$400.00</cell>
                            <cell>$280.00</cell>
                            <cell>$120.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>50 bushels Corn</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 Sheep</cell>
                            <cell>$12.00</cell>
                            <cell>$6.00</cell>
                            <cell>$6.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>50 lbs Butter</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>6 Sheep</cell>
                            <cell>$36.00</cell>
                            <cell>$18.00</cell>
                            <cell>$18.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>6 Hogs</cell>
                            <cell>$120.00</cell>
                            <cell>$60.00</cell>
                            <cell>$60.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>550 lbs Bacon</cell>
                            <cell>$137.00</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>$37.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>75 pounds Butter</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>50 pounds Lard</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>300 pounds Salt Beef</cell>
                            <cell>$45.00</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>20 Galls. apple Butter</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>30 " Sorgham</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>40 " Vinegar</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>100 bush Corn</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 1/2 tons Hay</cell>
                            <cell>$70.00</cell>
                            <cell>$70.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The claimant is the <hi rend="super">widow of</hi> Philip <orig
                        reg="Fishburn">Fishburne</orig> who died in 1865 and left all his personal
                    property to her. She is a very old Lady and they have a very large family of
                    sons and daughters. Some of the sons and Grandsons were in the Rebel Army but
                    more in the Union Army. Claimant swears to her own and her husbands loyalty, and
                    two or three witnesses give decided testimony to the loyal conversation and
                    reputation of both as well as <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> most of the family connection, part of whom
                    had moved to Iowa before the war.</p>
                <p>The Horses were taken by soldiers of Hunter's Command three days after the Battle
                    of Piedmont, and seem to have been needed for the use of the Commad, as many
                    were dismounted. The corn and sheep seem also to have been needed for Army use
                    and were taken by Sheridan in Sept.</p>
                <p>Items five to 15 in claim were taken by Sheridan's Command in March 1865 by
                    Sheridan's Command. We do not allow for Pantry stores usually as Supplies for
                    the Army.</p>
                <p>We allow in full of Claim the sum of Seven Hundred and fourteen dollars on the
                    testimony of Claimant and her daughter.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name>, <name
                        type="other">O. Ferris</name><abbr expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of
                    Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Lydia Fishburn</byline>
                <p>In answer to the First General Interrogatory, the Deponent says: My name is Lidia
                    Fishburn, my age is 77 years, my residence Clines Mill Augusta, in the State of
                    Va., and my occupation a ; I am the claimant, and have beneficial interest in
                    the claim.</p>
                <p>2 Ans. I have resided where I now do for fifty years. I have 196 acres of land,
                    about 100 cleared.</p>
                <p>3 Ans. I never passed any military lines.</p>
                <p>4 Ans. I never took any oath.</p>
                <p>5 Ans. I have taken no amnesty oath.</p>
                <p>6 Ans. No.</p>
                <p>7 Ans. No.</p>
                <p>8 Ans. No.</p>
                <p>9 Ans. No.</p>
                <p>10 Ans. No.</p>
                <p>11 Ans. I never had anything to do with any services.</p>
                <p>12 Ans. No sir.</p>
                <p>13 Ans. I was not conscripted.</p>
                <p>14 Ans. I furnished no substitute.</p>
                <p>15 Ans. Never.</p>
                <p>16 Ans. Never at all.</p>
                <p>17 Ans. I had charge of nothing.</p>
                <p>18 Ans. I never was in service at all.</p>
                <p>19 Ans. I made no cloth or anything else nor interested in any manufacture for
                    the benefit of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>20 Ans. Never.</p>
                <p>21 Ans. I no way.</p>
                <p>22 Ans. I did not.</p>
                <p>23 Ans. I was not.</p>
                <p>24 Ans. I was never arrested by either the Confederates or the United States.</p>
                <p>25 Ans. Nothing except they stole Bee hives and butter.</p>
                <p>26 Ans. I never was threatened.</p>
                <p>27 Ans. No, not seriously.</p>
                <p>28 Ans. I never contributed anything.</p>
                <p>29 Ans. I done nothing except to feed some of the soldiers.</p>
                <p>30 Ans. My son George Fishburn, was in the Confederate Army, he resides near
                    Staunton. I never furnished him any thing at all.</p>
                <p>31 Ans. I never owned any bonds, and done nothing to support the credit of the
                    Confederate Army or Government.</p>
                <p>32 Ans. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> aid or comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>33 Ans. I never made raids.</p>
                <p>34 Ans. No.</p>
                <p>35 Ans. Never</p>
                <p>36 Ans. No.</p>
                <p>37 Ans. No. No.</p>
                <p>38 Ans. I never had a pass.</p>
                <p>39 Ans. I had no disabilities.</p>
                <p>40 Ans. My sympathies were with the Union all the time.</p>
                <p>41 Ans. I do solemnly declare that from the beginning of hostilities against the
                    United States to the end thereof, my sympathies were constantly with the cause
                    of the United States, and I never of my own free will and accord did anything,
                    or offered, or sought, or attempted to do anything by word or deed, to injure
                    said cause or retard its success and was at all times ready and willing if
                    called upon to aid and assist the cause of the Union, or its supporters, so as
                    my means and power and the circumstances would permit.</p>
                <p>42 Ans. husband Phillip Fishburn, died in July 1865. I was married in 1818. My
                    husband was thoroughly a Union man, I have nine children living. My oldest Abram
                    Fishburn, is about 60 years old, he resides in the State of Illinois, one of his
                    sons was in the Union Army. William Fishburn, is about 58 years old, he resides
                    in South West Virginia. I do not know his Post Office. Ezra Fishburn, lives in
                    Iowa, he is about 54, his son was in the Union Army. Daniel Fishburn, is about
                    52 he resides near Staunton. Levi Fishburn about 49, resides near Staunton.
                    David Fishburn, lives in Iowa, about 46, he was in the Union Army. George
                    Fishburn, about 40, he resides near to Staunton. Elizabeth M<hi
                        rend="super">c</hi>Leod, resides in in Rockingham <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> is about 59, and Sarah L. A.
                    Fishburn, is about 35 years, and resides with me. My son George was in the
                    Confederate Army, he was there against his own consent. I hold the real estate
                    in virtue of my father Abram Silling's <del hand="h1">Will</del><hi rend="super"
                        >deed</hi>, and the personalty by the Will of my husband, both
                        Will<del hand="h1">s</del><hi rend="super">&amp; Deed</hi> are on record in
                    the County Clerks Office at Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> My
                    children are only interested as my heirs, or at my own disposal. An extract of
                    the will is hereto attached.</p>
                <p>Taken in the Property</p>
                <p>Deposition of Same.</p>
                <p>1 Ans. I was present and saw the property taken.</p>
                <p>3 Ans. One of the horses was in the field and the other in the Stable, and the
                    Sheep were in the field, and the hogs were in the pen. The other articles
                    specified were taken from the house, granary &amp;c.</p>
                <p>4 Ans. The horses were taken in June 1864 by soldiers belonging to <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter's Army. I
                    suppose there <hi rend="super">were</hi> two at the Stable and three in
                    the field, but quite a number near by. I do not know whether there was an
                    officer present or not. The two Sheep and Corn <hi rend="super">&amp;
                        butter</hi> was taken in September 1864 by soldiers belonging to <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan. I suppose
                    there were 60 or 70 present. And from item 5 to 15 were taken in March 1865, by
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan's
                    Command.</p>
                <p>5 Ans. My daughter Sarah L. A. Fishburn was present.</p>
                <p>6 Ans. I do not know whether there was an officer present or not.</p>
                <p>7 Ans. The property was all taken by soldiers.</p>
                <p>8 Ans. One of the horses was rode and the other was led away. The Sheep were in
                    part butchered on my farm and the others drove off. Same as to the hogs. The
                    Corn was carried off in Sacks and the Bacon &amp; Beef was taken in sacks
                    the Butter &amp; Lard was carried away in Cans in which it was packed. The
                    Apple butter was in Jars &amp; Crocks, and the molasses and vinegar, in
                    buckets, and the hay was carried in bundles. I think too they had a wagon and
                    hauled some hay.</p>
                <p>9 Ans. I suppose the horses were taken to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter's Camp at Staunton, and in
                    September 1864. The Command marched on in the direction of Staunton, and in
                    March 1865, the Army camped in about 1/2 mile of my house for one night. I did
                    not follow and I saw nothing after it was taken away.</p>
                <p>10 Ans. I only saw them take the horses + all the other articles, but do not know
                    how or for what they were used. A part of the sheep &amp; hogs were killed
                    and the meat carried off.</p>
                <p>11 Ans. I complained about my horses and the other articles, but the reply was
                    that they needed the horses for Army purposes, and the Corn to feed and also the
                    hay, and the provisions to eat, as they were out and needed provisions. They
                    told <hi rend="super">me</hi> I would be paid for everything taken.</p>
                <p>12 Ans. I did not ask for a receipt.</p>
                <p>13 Ans. The horses were taken from 10 A.M. to 2 P.M. Items 2, 3 &amp; 4 were
                    taken about 2 P.M. and the balance all taken between 3 P.M. &amp; night.</p>
                <p>14 Ans. <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter was
                    camped at Staunton, and had had a fight at Piedmont a few days <hi
                        rend="super">before</hi>. In Sept. <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan was on a raid, and in March
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan
                    camped on night near my house. I knew no officer.</p>
                <p>15 Ans. The horses were very fine, young 8 &amp; 6 years old, of good size
                    and well broken. The sheep were fat and also the hogs. The Bacon &amp; Beef
                    sound and good, and all the articles were good. The most of the Corn was on the
                    Cob. I did not measure it. From the quanitity of Bacon &amp; beef I think
                    there must have been the weight specified. I judged the quantity of hay by the
                    amount put into the Mow. Every article was very valuable to me and I think worth
                    all that is charged.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Lydia Fishburn</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Sarah L. A. Fishburn</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Sarah L. A. Fishburn</p>
                <p>Answer to first question</p>
                <p>My name is Sarah L. A. Fishburn, my age is 35, my residence near Clines Mill. The
                    claimant is my mother. I have no interest in the claim, except by her disposal.
                    I was present and <hi rend="super">saw</hi> the articles specified in the
                    claimants petition taken.</p>
                <p>3 Ans. The Horses were taken, one out of the Stable and the other from the field.
                    the items 2, 3 &amp; 4. The Corn was in the Crib. The sheep in the field,
                    and the butter in the Spring house, and the other articles named were taken, the
                    sheep out of the field, hogs from pen, hay from Stable Mow, Corn from the Crib
                    and Bacon, Beef &amp; Lard from the Smoke house and the other articles from
                    the house.</p>
                <p>4 Ans. The horses were taken in June 1864, by soldiers belonging to <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter's Army. The
                    2 Sheep, 50 <abbr expan="bushels">bush.</abbr> Corn &amp; 50 <hi
                        rend="super">lbs</hi> butter, in Sept 1864, by Union soldiers. The
                    commander's name I have forgotten, and the other items were taken in March 1865,
                    by <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Sheridan's
                    Command. There were 4 Soldiers engaged in taking the horses. There were a large
                    number of soldiers, a short distance away. When the items 2, 3 &amp; 4 were
                    taken there <hi rend="super">were</hi> 200 or 300 soldiers around the
                    house, and when the last items taken in March 1865. I do not know whether there
                    was an officer present or not. I suppose each time they remained two or three
                    hours.</p>
                <p>5 Ans. My mother was present.</p>
                <p>6 Ans. I do not know that there was any officer present or not.</p>
                <p>7 Ans. The property was taken as I have described. They said that they <hi
                        rend="super">had</hi> orders to take the property, and they needed all
                    they took. They also told me to keep an account of everything taken, and we
                    would be paid for all after awhile.</p>
                <p>8 Ans. One of the horses was rode away and the other led. The two sheep were
                    killed and the Meat carried off on horses, and the 50 <abbr expan="bushels"
                            >bush<hi rend="super">ls</hi>.</abbr> Corn taken off in bags, and
                    the butter carried in Cans. The 6 Sheep were also killed and also the hogs
                    killed too, and the Meat carried away, and every thing else was carried a short
                    distance where they camped for the night.</p>
                <p>9 Ans. I did not follow, but could see them going with the articles to the camp.
                    I mean all items from No. 5 to 15.</p>
                <p>10 Ans. I did not see them use any thing at all. Only saw them taken and carried
                    away.</p>
                <p>11 Ans. I asked them not <hi rend="super">to</hi> take the property, and
                    they replied they needed all, ad must take it.</p>
                <p>12 Ans. There was no receipt asked for.</p>
                <p>13 Ans. The horses were taken from 12 to 3 P.M. and items 2, 3 &amp; 4, were
                    taken in the afternoon, when they were on March, and the balance taken in March
                    1865, was in the afternoon. They camped for the night in sight of claimants
                    house.</p>
                <p>14 Ans. When the horses were taken <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter had his camp at Staunton. He
                    had a battle at Piedmont on Sunday before. The horses were taken on a Wednesday
                    of the same week, and when the 2 Sheep, 50 <abbr expan="bushels">bus.</abbr>
                    Corn &amp; 50 <hi rend="super">lbs</hi> butter was taken the command
                    was marching in the direction of Staunton, and then the last army camped one
                    night in sight. I did not hear the name of any Quarter Master.</p>
                <p>15 Ans. The horses were in splendid condition, good sized horses, one 6 and the
                    other 8 years, both of them good riding horses and also worked anywhere. The
                    sheep were No. 1, very fat + large. The hogs were good size and order. The hay
                    sound and good, and from the amount put into the Stable I should think there was
                    3 1/2 Tons. We guessed at the quantity of Corn, by the bulk in the Crib, it was
                    on the Cob. I do not think there was a pound less than 550 <hi
                        rend="super">lbs</hi> Bacon, and 300 Beef. The Butter was in Cans, and
                    also the Lard, Apple Butter in Jars &amp; Crocks, and the Molasses and
                    Vinegar in <abbr expan="barrels">Blls</abbr>. I do not think that there <hi
                        rend="super">is</hi> a charge or item in excess of its actual
                    quantity, and horses and every article worth all and more than the prices
                    charged. I did not weigh any thing or count pieces, but judged the quantity by
                    bulk.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Sallie A. Fishburn</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Samuel Landes</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Samuel Landes</p>
                <p>Answer to 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> general question</p>
                <p>My name is Samuel Landes, my age is 50 years. My residence near Spring Hill,
                    Augusta County and my occupation is a Miller. I am not related to the claimant,
                    nor have any interest in the claim. I become acquainted with the claimant and
                    her deceased husband in 1857. At the commencement of the War and until May 1862
                    I lived adjoining farms, and then I removed about 3 miles off. We were intimate
                    and I saw her and husband frequently. I saw her husband Philip Fishburn, at
                    least twice a month. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think we ever met without
                    conversing about the War. I was an adherent to the Union, and he was aware of
                    that. I do not recollect any particular expression or language that he used, but
                    I distinctly remember that I could always express myself freely and in
                    confidence in his presence, and I have no doubt of his being a true Union man,
                    and utterly opposed to the war. His reputation in the neighborhood, amongst the
                    Union men, was that of a Union man. I never knew him to do anything in aid of
                    the rebellion. I never knew him to do anything for the Union cause, except that
                    he harbored and helped men to keep out of the rebel service. I do not believe
                    that if the South had succeeded in gaining its independence, Philip Fishburn,
                    could if alive, proven loyalty to it.</p>
                <p>His widow, the claimant, was quite an old lady, seldom from home. I do not know
                    anything about her sympathies, but in my own mind I believe she was in sympathy
                    with her husband. I never heard anything to the contrary.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Samuel Landes</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Erasmus L. Houff</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Erasmus L. Houff</p>
                <p>Answer to 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> general question</p>
                <p>My name is Erasmus L. Houff, my age is 44 years. My residence near Mt. Sidney,
                    Augusta County. My occupation a farmer &amp; a <abbr expan="United States"
                        >U.S.</abbr> Store Keeper.</p>
                <p>I knew Philip Fishburn, the deceased husband or the claimant, for about 15 years
                    prior to his death, and resided about 3 miles from him during the war. We were
                    intimate I saw him frequently during the war, probably two or three time a
                    month, frequently spent the night with him. We talked about the War, its cause
                    and progress, and he invariably expressed his devotion to the United States
                    Government. That he at no time expressed any <hi rend="super">wish</hi> or
                    used any language in favor of the rebellion or its success. He said frequently
                    in my presence that he had witnessed the War of 1812, and in that he could have
                    fought with good conscience, but that he could not in the rebellion, for that
                    was to destroy what the other was to defend. His wife, the claimant always
                    agreed with her husband in his sentiments, stating what the people had suffered
                    to maintain the Government, and the rebels were now trying to break it down.</p>
                <p>I do not now recollect that there were any persons present (except their daughter
                    Sarah) when we had conversations, but they were always very bold and positive in
                    expressing themselves.</p>
                <p>The Union men of the neighborhood, had full confidence in their loyalty to the
                    Union cause. I was a strictly Union man myself, and consequently visited them
                    because they were true, and I could converse freely and fully with them. I never
                    knew them to do anything for the rebellion, but on the contrary they harbored
                    Union men and helped to keep them concealed.</p>
                <p>If the south had been successful they could not have proven by their neighbors
                    any loyalty to the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">E.L. Houff</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>William A. Burnett</byline>
                <p>Philip Fishburn's Will Recorded in Clerk's Office of Augusta County Court in Will
                    No 40 page 275, dated March 27th 1865, &amp; admitted to record November
                    27th 1865.</p>
                <p>"2nd. I give and bequeath to my beloved wife Lydia Fishburn all my personal
                    property consisting of all the household &amp; kitchen furniture, cattle,
                    hogs, sheep, horses and all the farming utensils to her sole use and purpose and
                    to be disposed of during her life time as she may think best."</p>
                <p>An Extract Teste</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">William A. Burnett</name>
                    <abbr expan="Clerk">Clk</abbr>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
