<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0508"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0508">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of David Buchanan,
                    1872, Claim No. 6892</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of david buchanan, 1872 claim no 6892</title>
        <author>Buchanan, David</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 17 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0508</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498395</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of David Buchanan, 1872,
                            Claim No. 6892</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of david buchanan, 1872 claim no 6892</title>
            <author>David Buchanan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #6818</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Desertion/Leave, Family, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0508T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>David Buchanan filed this claim in 1872 for $350, claiming General Hunter's Union
                    troops took two horses in 1864. David was a 68 year old farmer, residing near
                    Walker's Creek, who had two sons in the Union Army and one son in the
                    Confederate Army who deserted. The claim was disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Bay Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$200.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$200.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Sorrel Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>Mr. Buchanan resided in Augusta County. He says he did not vote on the question
                    of secession, but we find his name on the poll list as having voted for
                    ratifying the ordinance fo secession</p>
                <p>Mr. Buchanan had two sons in the Union Army, and one in the Confederate who <orig
                        reg="stayed">staid</orig> only a short time &amp; deserted. Several
                    circumstances stated in the testimony present Mr. Buchanan's conduct in a loyal
                    &amp; favorable light: but his vote for secession is a disloyal act
                    &amp; forbids the allowance of his claim.</p>
                <p>Claim rejected.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis.</name><abbr expan="Commissioners">Commrs.</abbr>
                    of Claims.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>David Buchanan</byline>
                <p>Before the Commissioners of Claims Under Act of Congress March 3<hi
                        rend="super">d</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>David Buchanan vs. The United States. No.</p>
                <p>On this 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of September 1871 at Staunton,
                    Augusta County and State of Virginia, personally came David Buchanan, the
                    claimant, and John Price and John Troxall his witnesses, in a cause now pending
                    before the Commissioners of Claims, in the name of David Buchanan vs. The United
                    States, before me a U.S. Commissioner, and also a special appointed by the <abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Comm'<hi rend="super">rs</hi>.</abbr> of Claims.</p>
                <p>Present David Buchanan, claimant.</p>
                <p>The said claimant, and each of said witnesses, were first, before any questions
                    were put to them, properly and duly sworn to tell the truth, the whole truth,
                    and nothing but the truth, relative to the matters in which they were to
                    testify; and the testimony of the claimant and said witnesses were taken down by
                    me, or in my presence; and I read over to said claimant and to each of said
                    witnesses their respective depositions; and the said depositions, were duly
                    signed in my presence.</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> US Commissioner and Special Commissioner</p>
                <p>Deposition of David Buchanan</p>
                <p>Ques. 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Answer. Witness says. I am 68 years old, I
                    reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr> I am a farmer by occupation, I resided at the same place prior to
                    the war or April 1<hi rend="super">st.</hi> 1861 and at the same place
                    from April 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1861 to June 1<hi rend="super"
                        >st</hi> 1865 never changed my residence or occupation.</p>
                <p>3<hi rend="super">d.</hi> Witness says. I never passed beyond the Military
                    or Naval lines of the United States and entered the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4. Witness says. I never took any oath to the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5. Witness says. I never took any Amnesty Oath. I never asked for a pardon from
                    the President.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th.</hi> Witness says. I never was in any way connected
                    with the civil service of the so called Confederacy.</p>
                <p>7. Witness says. I never held any office or place of trust, honor, or profit
                    under the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>8. Witness says. I never held a clerkship or agency or employment of any kind for
                    the benefit of the Confederate States. Nor was I, in any capacity in the
                    Military or Naval service of the so called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>10. Witness says. I never was an Officer, Soldier, Sailor, or Marine in the
                    Confederate Army or Navy, nor in any way employed in any department or bureau of
                    the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> Government Army or Navy. I never
                    had charge of any thing whatsoever for the use of benefit of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>11. Witness says. I never was in the service or employment of the Confederacy
                    whatsoever, I never furnished any supplies or property of any kind for the use
                    and aid of the rebellion. I never gave any information.</p>
                <p>12. Witness says. I never was employed in any way in the manufacture of any
                    articles of good whatever for the use or benefit of the States.</p>
                <p>13. Witness says. I never was in any way employed in the Collection, empressment
                    or purchase of stores, supplies or any thing for the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>14. Witness says. I never was engaged in blockade running or illicit traffic or
                    intercourse between the lines nor had any interest in any goods brought into or
                    exported from the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>15. Witness says. I did not leave the Confederate States between the 19<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> April 1861 &amp; April 19<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> 1865.</p>
                <p>16. Witness says. I never was interested in the navigation of any vessel in any
                    waters of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17. Witness says. I never was arrested by the Confederate Government. Nor by the
                    United States Government.</p>
                <p>18. Witness says. I had five head of Cattle taken by the Confederates in 1863 for
                    the use of the Confederate Government I have never received any pay for it.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th.</hi> Witness says. I have been threatened on account
                    of my Union sentiments. I never otherwise molested.</p>
                <p>21. Witness says. I never contributed anything in aid of the United States to
                    Army or Navy during the War.</p>
                <p>23. Witness says. I had two (2) sons in the Union Army and One (1) a short time
                    in the Confederate Army but he left and went into the Union lines. I did nothing
                    to supply them with equipments or money.</p>
                <p>24. Witness says. I never owned any Confederate Bonds nor done anything to
                    support the credit of the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>25. Witness says. I never gave aid and comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26. Witness says. I never was engaged in making raids into the United States from
                    Canada, or in the destruction of its commerce.</p>
                <p>27. Witness says. I never was engaged in holding in custody any persons taken as
                    prisoners of war by the rebels.</p>
                <p>28. Witness says. I never was a member of any society for the persecution or
                    expulsion of persons on account of their loyalty to the United States.</p>
                <p>29. Witness says. I never was a paroled prisoner of the United States.</p>
                <p>30. Witness says. I never held any Office in the United States, nor educated at
                    any of its Military or Naval Schools.</p>
                <p>31. Witness says. I never received any pass from the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>32. Witness says. I never held any office and was under no disabilities.</p>
                <p>33. Witness says. At the beginning I was a Union man and continued so. I did not
                    vote at all on the Ordinance of Secession. After its adoption I adhered to the
                    Union.</p>
                <p>34. Witness says. I declare that from the beginning of the hostilities against
                    the United States to the end thereof, my sympathies were constantly with the
                    Union, and that I did not seek or attempt to do any thing injure said Cause or
                    retard its success, and that I was at all times ready and willing if called upon
                    to assist the Union, so as my means, power, and circumstances permitted.</p>
                <p>General Interrogatory.</p>
                <p>Ques. Do you know of other matter <del hand="h1">of</del> relative to said claim? If you
                    do, state it fully.</p>
                <p>Answer. I know of nothing else.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><name type="claimant">David Buchanan</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of
                    September 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p><abbr expan="United States">US</abbr> Commissioner<lb/>And Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comm.</abbr> for the State of <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>John Troxall</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Troxall introduced the furnishing and taking of property
                    mentioned in the petition.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Witness says. I am 27 years old, I reside in Augusta Co. Va. and a
                    farmer by occupation. I was present and saw the property taken, or at least one
                    horse, but did not see the other taken, but know the same troops took it.</p>
                <p>4. Witness says. The property was taken in June 1864 from the Claimants of field,
                    by soldiers belonging to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super"
                    >l.</hi></abbr> Hunter's Command. There were no Officers present.</p>
                <p>8. Witness says. The property was rode off by the soldiers.</p>
                <p>9t<hi rend="super">h.</hi> Witness says. They said they were on their route
                    to Lynchburg. I did not see it after removed.</p>
                <p>10. Witness says. It was taken for the Government use, and the soldiers said they
                    were taking all the horses they could get.</p>
                <p>11. Witness says. The claimants son complained to an Officer, and he told him if
                    he could find the horses to take them, but he did not get them.</p>
                <p>12. Witness says. There was no receipt asked for or given that I know of.</p>
                <p>13. Witness says. The property was taken at about 12 Oclock in the day time, it
                    was taken publicly.</p>
                <p>14. Witness says. There was no encampment. They were on the March. There had been
                    no battle or skirmish. I knew no Quarter master.</p>
                <p>15. Witness says. The bay Mare was in good condition and a fine animal. She was 7
                    or 8 years old and worth I suppose $200. The Sorrel Mare was a good animal. She
                    was I suppose about 10 years old, and worth $200.</p>
                <p>19. Witness says. I believe it was taken for the benefit of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Government. The soldiers said they needed
                    them and were taking all they could get.</p>
                <p>20. Witness says. I believe it was taken for the use of the Government.</p>
                <p>22. Witness says. I think it was taken for the use of the Government and
                    therefore it should be paid for.</p>
                <p>23. Witness says. The soldiers I think were ordered. They said they were ordered
                    to take all they could get.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Troxall</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me, this 13<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of
                    September 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p><abbr expan="United States">US </abbr>Commissioner And Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comm.</abbr> for the State of <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>John Price</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Price introduced to prove the loyalty of claimant.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Answer. Witness says I am 47 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and a Wagon Maker
                    by trade. I have known the claimant for 30 years. I live very near him. We were
                    a great deal together during the War, and talked about it and from all his words
                    and acts, I never doubted his loyalty to the Union, and his neighbors generally
                    so believed him. I never knew him to do anything of his own with for the
                    rebellion. I know he had two sons in the North.</p>
                <p>I do not think he could have established any claim of loyalty to the Confederacy
                    had it succeeded.</p>
                <p>General Interrogatory</p>
                <p>Do you know of other matter relative to said claim? If so state it fully.</p>
                <p>I know of nothing except that the rebels threatened him and took his property and
                    annoyed his family.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Price</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 13th September 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>US Commissioner And Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comm.</abbr> for the State
                    of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p>I hereby certify that the foregoing Eleven (11) pages of depositions (including
                    this certificate) of the claimant and his witnesses were taken by me the time
                    and in the manner before named.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Commr.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>John R. Buchanan</byline>
                <p>Petition</p>
                <p>To the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States in Congress
                    assembled:</p>
                <p>Your petitioner represents that he <hi rend="underline">John R. Buchanan, son of
                        David Buchanan, deceased, of Craigsville, Virginia</hi> a citizen of the
                    United States, has a claim against the United States for property taken and used
                    by the U.S. army during the late rebellion; that said claim was presented to the
                    Commissioners of Claims, who disallowed it on or about the day of 1872 and
                    reported it to Congress where the claim now is, being on file in the office of
                    the Clerk of the House of Representatives <hi rend="underline">much of the
                        testimony was expartie, wrong conclusions were reached; if the case was
                        referred to the Court of Claims I could fully prove his loyalty and his
                        rights to recover.</hi></p>
                <p>Wherefore, having no other remedy, your petitioner asks that said claim may be
                    referred to the Court of Claims, pursuant to the Act of Congress of March 3,
                    1883 (22 Stat. 485-6). And your petitioner ever prays, &amp;c.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John R. Buchanan</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>United States Treasury Department</byline>
                <p>Treasury Department Office of the Secretary Washington, D.C. July 23, 1892.</p>
                <p>The Honorable The Attorney General.</p>
                <p>Sir: In answer to your request of the 9th ultimo, in the case of the son of David
                    Buchanan against the United States, No. 6818 Congressional, wherein the loyalty
                    of the said David Buchanan is in question, I have the honor to state that his
                    name appears in a copy of a list of those who voted for the ordinance of
                    secession in Augusta County, Virginia, the original of which is presumed to be
                    in the custody of the clerk of the court of said county.</p>
                <p>Respectfully yours, <name type="other">Charles Forten</name> Secretary.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
