<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0517"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0517">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Alexander
                    Anderson, 1874, Claim No. 19562</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of alexander anderson, 1874 claim no 19562</title>
        <author>Anderson, Alexander</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 23 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0517</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498404</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Alexander Anderson,
                            1874, Claim No. 19562</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of alexander anderson, 1874 claim no 19562</title>
            <author>Alexander Anderson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #19562</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1874">1874</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Patriotism, Home Front, Reunification, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0517T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Alexander Anderson filed this claim in 1874 for $712.50, claiming the Union army
                    took three horses, corn, bacon, oats, and a rifle in 1864. Alexander was a 66
                    year old farmer. After the war and taking the Ironclad Oath he served as a
                    Magistrate in Augusta. Included is testimony by the Mayor of Staunton to prove
                    Alexander's loyalty. The commission allowed $175.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Ten bus corn @ 1.00 per bus</cell>
                            <cell>$10.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$10.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One black horse 5 yrs old</cell>
                            <cell>$250.00</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>390 lbs bacon @ .25 per lb</cell>
                            <cell>$97.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$97.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>75 bus oats @.60 per bus</cell>
                            <cell>$45.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$45.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>25 bags .60 each</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 rifle gun</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>60 bus Corn @ 1.00</cell>
                            <cell>$60.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$10.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>50 bus Corn in Ear</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Black horse</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Three year old Colt</cell>
                            <cell>$130.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$130.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Mr. Anderson resided on his farm near Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                    during the war. He had two sons in the Confederate service but he swears he did
                    his best to get them to leave the Confederacy. He swears strongly to his own
                    loyalty-&amp; is sustained by the testimony of Mr. N.K. Trout the Mayor of
                    Staunton &amp; by one Daniel O'Rourke. -At the close of the War he was
                    appointed by <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Canby <abbr expan="President"
                        >Pres.</abbr> of the <abbr expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Election
                    and Justice of the Peace for Augusta.</p>
                <p>On the whole we incline to hold him loyal; tho' not without hesitatation.</p>
                <p>The evidence to show taking is the <del hand="h1">Claiment</del> claimant's <del hand="h1">&amp;
                        his</del> daughter Mary. Mary seems like a fair &amp; honest witness,
                    but her testimony gives no amounts of articles taken. She testifies only to Corn
                    "taken in wagons," "bacon," "oats" The phrase "some Corn" is too indefinite to
                    found any allowance upon. The party must prove his case-all indefinite testimony
                    is to be taken <abbr expan="against">ag<hi rend="super">t</hi>.</abbr>
                    him. It is fair to presume he would prove a better &amp; more definite claim
                    if he could.</p>
                <p>The black horse, Item 2, seems to be proved. As corn was taken in wagons, we may
                    allow for two wagon loads-though it is very slender proof; but a voucher for
                    Corn in the Ear sustains it. "Bacon," "Oats" too indefinite for any allowance.
                    Rifle gun-probably stolen-no authority. Item 5. bags not proven. Items 9
                    &amp; 10-The horse seems to have been an old one &amp; not fit for
                    Cavalry service. Colt 3 yrs old &amp; not fit for Cavalry use. We can not
                    think such animals taken by Authority for the use of the Army.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name><abbr expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of
                    Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Alexander Anderson</byline>
                <p>United States of America, State of Virginia, SS</p>
                <p>J.M.G. Riley a Commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioners of
                    Claims appointed under the Act of Congress of March 3<hi rend="super"
                    >rd</hi> 1871 to take and record testimony do hereby certify that the reason for
                    taking the following depositions is and the fact is the matter of the Claim of
                    Alexander Anderson vs. the United States of America and the witness herein named
                    being first duly sworn answereth as follows witness says I am 66 years old, I
                    reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr> I am a farmer by occupation. I resided at the same place for 6
                    months previous to April 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1861, and at the same
                    from April 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1861 to June 1<hi rend="super"
                        >st</hi> 1865, occupation farming.</p>
                <p>3<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I never passed beyond the military
                    lines of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> and enter the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never took any oath to bear
                    allegiance to the Confederacy. I took an Amnesty oath, after the close of the
                    War in 1865, at Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I never pardoned by
                    the President, never asked for one.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says-I never connected in any way with
                    the civil service of the so called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says-I never held any office or place of
                    trust or honor or profit under the Confederate States. I never held a clerkship,
                    or agency or employment of any kind whatsoever.</p>
                <p>9<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was <orig reg="in">in
                    in</orig> any capacity in the military or naval service of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>10<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never held any office nor in, as
                    sailor, soldier or Marine in the Confederacy. I never furnished a substitute. I
                    was not connected with any department of the Confederate Government Army or
                    Navy. I never had charge of stores, supplies teams, Wagons, vessels, or done any
                    thing for the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>11<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was in the employment of
                    the Confederate States I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> any information to
                    the officers or soldiers of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>12<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never manufactured any thing for
                    the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>13<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was directly or indirectly
                    engaged in collectiong or impressing any stores or supplies for the use of the
                    Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was engaged in blockade
                    running or any interst in any goods or merchandise brought into or exported from
                    any port of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I did not leave the Confederate
                    states during the war.</p>
                <p>16<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I had no interest in any Vessel
                    used in navigation to or from any port of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says-I never was arrested by the
                    Confederate Government, nor by the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr>
                    Government.</p>
                <p>18<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says he took Cattle, and Wheat, for the
                    use of Confederate Army. I was paid for the Wheat. It was taken in 1863.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says-I never was threatened directly,
                    with damage, on account of my Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>20<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was molested except in the
                    property taken from me.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I never done anything for the
                    United States Government.</p>
                <p>23<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I had two sons in the Confederate
                    Army. I had no relations in the Union Army. I did nothing to aid them. I tried
                    my best to get my sons to leave the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>24<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says He never owned a Confederate Bond
                    or done anything to support the Credit of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>25<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says He never <orig reg="gave"
                    >give</orig> aid comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says He never was engaged in making
                    raids into the United States from Canada, nor in the destruction of the commerce
                    of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr></p>
                <p>27<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says-I never was engaged in holding any
                    prisoners of War.</p>
                <p>28<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never belonged to any society for
                    the purpose of the prosecution or persecution of any one.</p>
                <p>29<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never was a paroled prisoner of
                    the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr></p>
                <p>30<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never held any office, nor
                    educated at any Military or Naval school of the <abbr expan="United States"
                    >U.S.</abbr></p>
                <p>31<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I never received a pass.</p>
                <p>32 Witness says I never was under disabilities imposed by the 14<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi><abbr expan="Amendment">Am<hi rend="super"
                        >t</hi>.</abbr> of the Constitution. I was a Magistrate in Augusta by
                    Military appointment since the war. I took the "Ironclad" Oath. I was also
                    president of the Commissioners of election by appointment by <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Canby.</p>
                <p>33<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says my sympathies were entirely with the
                    United States. I did not vote at all on the secession. After the ordinance of
                    secession was adopted I adhered to my Government the United States.</p>
                <p>34<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I do declare that from the
                    beginning of the hostilities to the end thereof my sympathies were constantly
                    with the Union cause, and was <hi rend="super"
                    >always</hi><del hand="h1">al</del>ready and willing to aid and assist the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Government.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. Sept. 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Alexander Anderson</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me the day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Mary E. Huppman</byline>
                <p>Mary E. Huppman, a witness introduced to prove the taking of the property,
                    charged in Claimants petition and being duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I am 24 years old, I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                    Housekeeper by occupation.</p>
                <p>I was present when the articles named in the petition.</p>
                <p>2<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I saw the property taken. Some Corn,
                    One black horse, Bacon, Oats, One Rifle gun. I don't remember the Bags. I saw
                    Corn taken in the ear, &amp; one Colt.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the property was taken by United
                    States soldiers, in the command of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter, in
                    1864 from my father's (the claimant) farm.</p>
                <p>5<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says My mother and brother were present
                    when the property was taken.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says Officers and soldiers both present
                    at the taking.</p>
                <p>7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the Colt was taken out of the
                    stable, and one horse from the field and one out of the road. The soldiers
                    wanted to take all the horses on the farm but the Officers would not let them.</p>
                <p>8<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the Corn was carried in Wagons, and
                    the soldiers led the Horses.</p>
                <p>9<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the property was taken to Staunton,
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p>10<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I suppose the property was taken
                    for the use of the Army.</p>
                <p>11<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says My father and mother complained
                    about the taking. I do not remember the name of the officer present.</p>
                <p>12<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says there was no receipt asked or given
                    that I recollect.</p>
                <p>13<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the property was taken publicly in
                    the day time. The horses in the fore, and the other property in the afternoon.</p>
                <p>14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says When the property was taken the
                    Army was encamped at Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter was the Commandant. The Army encamped at
                    Staunton, on the 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> of June '65, and left the 10<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi>. There had been a battle at Piedmont a few days
                    previous.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the Corn was all good, The horse
                    (black) was in good condition, so were the other horses. The Bacon was good, as
                    was all the property. I think Corn, was worth a dollar a bushel, being a lady I
                    do not know the prices of such property, but I would think that the charges
                    named in the petition were fair and reasonable.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I think the property named in the
                    claimants petition was taken for the use of the Army and not for soldiers or
                    officers gratification.</p>
                <p>20<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I suppose the property was needed
                    by the Army, but do not know.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says the officers forbid the soldiers
                    from taking all the horses.</p>
                <p>22<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I think the Government ought to pay
                    for the property.</p>
                <p>23<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I think they had authority to take
                    the property and acted under orders.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. September 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Mary E. Hupman</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; Subscribed before me the day of September 1871.</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Samuel Jackson</byline>
                <p>Samuel Jackson, a witness introduced by claimant to prove the taking and the
                    value of the property named in the petition, being duly sworn answers as
                    follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says-I am 40 years old, I reside in
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I am a
                    Cooper by Trade. I was not present when the property was taken. There was a
                    black horse about 5 years old, worth $250.00. I know nothing about the Bacon,
                    nor Oats, nor Rifle Gun, nor Bags, nor Corn, the black horse old, but worth
                    $150.00. The <orig reg="filly">Filley</orig> 3 years old was worth about $200.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says the property was taken from the
                    Claimants farm, in 1864, by soldiers and officers of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Army <pb n="12"/> under the command of
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter, the horses were all in good
                    condition, and low at the prices charged by the claimant.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. September 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Samuel Jackson</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this day of September 1871.</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for
                    State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Daniel O'Rourke</byline>
                <p>Daniel ORorke a witness introduced by claimant to his loyalty to the United
                    States being duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says- I am about 45 years old, I reside
                    in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I am
                    a farmer by occupation. I have known the claimant 10 years or more, I saw him
                    frequently during the war, and talked with him about the war, and I had no doubt
                    of his loyalty to the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Government and so
                    far as I know his neighbors so regarded him. I regarded him as truly loyal to
                    the United States Government.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. Sept. 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Danl O Rourke</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this day of September 1871.</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for
                    State of Virginia</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Nicholas K. Trout</byline>
                <p>Nicholas K. Trout (Mayor of Staunton City) a witness introduced by the claimant
                    to prove his loyalty to the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Government
                    being duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I am 52 years old. I reside in
                    Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> By profession a lawyer and Mayor of
                    the City. I have known the claimant 30 years, I talked with him often during the
                    war, and he was an avowed Union <hi rend="super">man</hi>, never
                    concealing his sentiments to any one. And was so regarded by all who knew him
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> opinions in that he was so bold in expressing his sentiments that he
                    could not have established any claim of loyalty to the Confederacy, had it
                    succeeded. Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">N.K. Trout</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this day of September 1871.</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for
                    State of Virginia</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
