<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0104"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0104">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Thomas J.
                    Gilbert, September 19, 1871, Claim No. 7264</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of thomas j gilbert, september 19 1871 claim no 7264</title>
        <author>Gilbert, Thomas J.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 29 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0104</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498329</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Thomas J. Gilbert,
                            September 19, 1871, Claim No. 7264</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of thomas j gilbert, september 19 1871 claim no 7264</title>
            <author>Thomas J. Gilbert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8645</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0104T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Gilbert's claim was disallowed by the Commissioners because his wartime
                    experiences suggested neutrality rather than loyalty to the Union Government.
                    Gilbert appealed this decision to the Congressional Court of Claims in 1895; his
                    son filed a second appeal in 1898.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Sorrel Mare</cell>
                            <cell>100.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>100.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Saddle &amp; bridle</cell>
                            <cell>10.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>10.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>5 bushels of Corn</cell>
                            <cell>5.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>5.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 bushels of Corn Meal</cell>
                            <cell>2.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>2.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>7 bags at .20</cell>
                            <cell>1.40</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>1.40</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1/2 barrel flour</cell>
                            <cell>2.50</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>2.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$120.90</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$120.90</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>Claim rejected.</p>
                <p>Mr. Gilbert lived near or in Staunton. He had no property taken by rebels-was
                    never molested or threatened. Had no relatives in either Army. Did not vote on
                    secession. -In May 1864 he left Va. (probably to avoid conscription) &amp;
                    went to Maryland to work in the Coal mines. -He never did anything for either
                    side.</p>
                <p>All this indicates neutrality. -He says he was for the Union &amp; he was
                    willing to do all he could for the U.S. Gov<hi rend="super">t</hi>. -That
                    is all he says. -Jess Gilbert (probably a relative) says he regarded him as a
                    Union Man &amp; he was so regarded by the Union men.</p>
                <p>The taking is not sastifactorily proved. No officer present. Looks like
                    depredation. The testimony of W<hi rend="super">m</hi>. R. Gilbert who was
                    ten years old at the time of taking does not agree with Smith's &amp; is not
                    reliable.</p>
                <p>We must reject the claim.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name> Commrs of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>Thomas J. Gilbert</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Thos. J. Gilbert</p>
                <p>I am 55 years. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a Farmer. Have lived in Augusta Co.
                    40 years.</p>
                <p>Ques 2 Witness says: I lived in Augusta Co. until May 4th 1864. Went to Alleghany
                    Co. Md. &amp; remained until the war closed.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says, I never took an oath of allegiance to the Confed. States.</p>
                <p>5 Witness says: I took the oth of allegiance to the U.S. Govt. in May 1864 in
                    West V<hi rend="super">a</hi>. New Creek &amp; in May 1865 at Staunton
                        V<hi rend="super">a</hi>. Have never been pardoned by the <abbr
                        expan="President">Presdt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>6 Witness Says: I never was directly nor indirectly in any manner connected with
                    the civil service of the Confed. States.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says, I never held any office or place of honor, profit or trust under
                    the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>9 Witness says: I never was in any capacity in the military or naval service of
                    the Confed. Govt. I drove a <orig reg="wagon">wago</orig> to the army twice, for
                    my employer, to whom I was hired by the year.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says: I never was engaged in blockade running, or in illicit traffic
                    between the lines.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says, I left the Confederate <orig reg="States">Stats</orig> May 4th
                    1864 &amp; went to Md. Stayed until May 1865. I was at work at the Coal
                    mines</p>
                <p>17 Witness says, I never was arrested by the Confed. or United States Govts.</p>
                <p>18 Witness says, I don't know that I had any property taken by the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says, I never was threatened on account of my union sentiments.</p>
                <p>21 Witness says: I did nothing for the United States Govt. its Army or Navy</p>
                <p>23 Witness says: I don't think I had any near relatives in either the union or
                    Confed. armies.</p>
                <p>24 Witness says, I have never owned any Confederate bonds, or done anything to
                    support the credit of the Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>25 Witness says, I have never given aid &amp; comfort to the rebellion or to
                    aid it in any way. I never did anything to injure the U.S. or its cause.</p>
                <p>29 Witness Says, I never was a paroled prisoner of the United States</p>
                <p>30 Witness Says, I never held any office in either the Army or Navy of the U.S.
                    was not educated either at West Point or the Naval Academy</p>
                <p>31 Witness Says, I never <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> any pass from the
                    Confed. Govt.</p>
                <p>32 Witness says: I am not &amp; never have been under any disabilities
                    imposed by the fourteenth amendment of the Constitution of the United States</p>
                <p>33 Witness says, At the beginning of the war I was for the Union, have been for
                    the Union all the time &amp; expect to remain so. Did not vote at all on the
                    ordinance of <orig reg="secession">cesession</orig>. After its adoption I went
                    with the Union &amp; not with my State.</p>
                <p>34 Witness says: I was ready &amp; willing to do all I could for the United
                    States Govt. so far as I could, &amp; further this deponent sayeth not.
                    Sept. 19th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Thomas J. Gilbert</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 19th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">Wm G Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com.
                    for State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Overton Smith</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Overton Smith to prove taking of Property.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness Says: I am 63 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. V<hi
                        rend="super">a</hi>. I am a shoemaker.</p>
                <p>2 Witness Says: I saw the horse mentioned in the claimants petition taken from my
                    lot, I saw nothing else taken.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says: The property was taken by Genl. Hunters men in 1864.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says, I do not know that any Officers were present</p>
                <p>8 Witness says: The horse was ridden off by soldiers</p>
                <p>10 Witness says: I think the horse was taken for the use of the army.</p>
                <p>11 Witness says, There was no complaint made on account of such taking.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says, There was no receipt asked for none given</p>
                <p>13 Witness says, The property was taken in the day time.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says, When the property was taken the Army was not encamped in the
                    neighborhood.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says, The horse was in good condition. About six years old, worth from
                    One hundred &amp; twenty, to one hundred &amp; fifteen Dollars.</p>
                <p>22 Witness Says: I think it was taken for the necessary use of the Govt.
                    &amp; should be paid for, &amp; further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 19th 1871 <name type="witness">Overton Smith</name></p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 19th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">Wm G Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com.
                    for State of Virginia</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>William R. Gilbert</byline>
                <p>Deposition of W<hi rend="super">m</hi>. R. Gilbert to prove taking of
                    Property</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says: I am 18 years old. I reside in Augusta Co V<hi
                        rend="super">a</hi> I am a Farmer</p>
                <p>2 Witness says: I saw all the articles mentioned in the claimants petition taken</p>
                <p>4 Witness says The property was taken by Genl. Hunters <abbr expan="command"
                        >comd.</abbr> in 1864 from claimants form. I think there was one officer
                    present, did not know his rank, regt. or command.</p>
                <p>7 Witness says: The horse was ridden off. the other property was carried off on
                    horses.</p>
                <p>9 Witness says: The property was taken in the direction of Staunton</p>
                <p>10 Witness says: I suppose the property was taken for the use of the Govt. I saw
                    the mare in possession of the soldiers of the United States Army</p>
                <p>15 Witness says: The horse was in good order I think she was six years old. The
                    saddle &amp; bridle were worth seven Dollars. Five bus. corn was worth Two
                    50/100 Dollars. Two bus. corn meal One dollar &amp; sixty cents. Seven bags
                    were worth one dollar &amp; twenty five cents. One half bbl. flour was worth
                    Five Dollars.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says, The property was taken for the actual use of the Union Army
                    &amp; not for private use</p>
                <p>20 Witness says: I suppose the property was taken because the troops had not
                        <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> their regular supplies.</p>
                <p>21 Witness says: I think the property was taken for the necessary use of the
                    Govt. &amp; that the Govt should pay for it</p>
                <p>23 Witness says, I know the property was taken by <abbr expan="command"
                    >comd.</abbr> of the officer present &amp; further this deponent sayeth not.
                    Sept. 19th 1871 <name type="witness">William R. Gilbert</name></p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 19th day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">Wm G Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com.
                    for State of Virginia</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>Jesse N. Gilbert</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Jesse N. Gilbert to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness Says: I am 58 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. I am a farmer
                    Have lived in Augusta Co 52 years. Did not change my residence during the war.
                    Have known the claimant all my life. Saw him frequently during the war, until he
                    left this Co. &amp; went to Md. Talked with him about the war, &amp; I
                    regarded him as loyal to the U.S. Govt. he was so regarded by the Union men.
                    Never knew him to do anything for the US Govt. had no opportunity. I never knew
                    him persecuted or threatened on account of his union sentiments. He was ordered
                    to join the Confed. army &amp; rather than do so, left his home &amp;
                    went to Md. I believe he was too loyal to the <abbr expan="United">U.</abbr>
                    States to have been loyal to the Confed. Govt. had it succeeded. He could not
                    have stayed here without torture on account of his union sentiments, &amp;
                    further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept 19th 1871 <name type="witness">Jesse N. Gilbert</name></p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 19 day of Sept. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">Wm G Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com.
                    for State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>Claimant's Brief on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS. DECEMBER TERM 1894-95.</p>
                <p>Thomas J. Gilbert, vs. The United States No. 8645 Cong.</p>
                <p>STATEMENT</p>
                <p>The claimant in this case resided in Augusta Co., Va</p>
                <p>The Commissioners of Claims rejected his claim, and in their report to Congress
                    state:--</p>
                <p>"Mr. Gilbert lied near or in Staunton. He had no property taken by rebels. Was
                    never molested or threatened. Had no relatives in either army. Did not vote on
                    secession. In May '64 he left (probably to avoid conscription) and went to
                    Maryland to work in the coal mines. He never did anything for either side. This
                    indicates neutrality. He says he was for the Union and willing to do all he
                    could for the U.S. govt. That is all he says.</p>
                <p>Jesse Gilbert, (probably a relative) says he regarded him as a Union man and he
                    was so regarded by the Union men.</p>
                <p>The Commissioners proceed to comment upon the testimony as to merits, and in
                    conclusion state: we must reject the claim."</p>
                <p>The claim was transmitted to the Court by the Committee on War Claims March 3rd,
                    1892.</p>
                <p>BRIEF ON LOYALTY</p>
                <p>The following testimony was taken while the claim was pending before the
                    Commissioners of Claims.</p>
                <p>CLAIMANT testifies: Age 55; residence Augusta Co., Farmer Have lived in Augusta
                    Co., 40 years. (P. 1). Lived in Augusta Co., till May 4th, '64, went to
                    Alleghany Co., Md., and remained until war closed. I never took an oath of
                    allegiance to the Confederate states<orig reg=".">..</orig> Took the oath of
                    allegiance to the U.S. in May '64, at New Creek, W. Va., and in May '65 at
                    Staunton, Va., Have Never been pardoned<orig reg=".">..</orig> Never connected
                    with the civil service of the Confederacy. Never held any office or place of
                    trust or profit under the Confederacy. Never in any capacity in the military or
                    naval service of the Confederate Govt. Drove a wagon to the army twice for my
                    employer to whom I was hired by the year. Never engaged in blockade running or
                        <orig reg="illicit">elicit</orig> traffic between the lines. I left the
                    Confederate states May 4th, '64 and went to Md. <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig>
                    until May '65. Was at work at the coal mines. (P. 2). Never arrested by the
                    Confederate or U.S. Govt. Don't know that I had any property taken by the
                    Confederate Govt<orig reg=".">..</orig> Never threatened on account of my Union
                    sentiments. Did nothing for the U.S. Govt. its army or navy. I don't think I had
                    any near relatives in either the Union or Confederate armies. Never owned any
                    Confederate bonds, or did anything to support the credit of the Confederacy. I
                    have never given aid or comfort to the rebellion. Never did anything to injure
                    the U.S. or its cause<orig reg=".">..</orig> Never a paroled prisoner of the
                    U.S. Never held any office in either the army or navy of the U.S.. Was not
                    educated either at West Point or the naval academy. Never received any pass from
                    the Confederate Govt. (P. 3). I am not and never have been under any
                    disabilities imposed by the 14th amendment. (P. 3). At the beginning of the war
                    I was for the Union Have been for the Union all the time and expect to remain
                    so. Did not vote at all on the ordinance of secession. After its adoption I went
                    with the Union, and not with my state. I was ready and willing to do all I could
                    for the U.S. Govt. so far as I could. (P. 4).</p>
                <p>JESSE M. GILBERT testifies: Age 68; residence Augusta Co., Farmer: I have lived
                    in Augusta Co. 62 years. Did not change my residence durig the war. Have known
                    the claimant all my life. Saw him frequently during the war until he left this
                    county and went to Md. and talked to him about the war, and I regarded him as
                    loyal to the U.S. Govt. He was so regarded by the Union men. Never knew him to
                    do anything for the Confederate Govt. He did nothing for the U.S. Govt. had no
                    opportunity. I never knew him persecuted or threatened on account of his Union
                    sentiments He was ordered to join the Confederate army, and rather than do so
                    left his home, and went to Md. I believe he was too loyal to the U.S. to have
                    been loyal to the Confederate Govt., had it succeeded, he could not have <orig
                        reg="stayed">staid</orig> here without torture on account of his Union
                    sentiments. (P. 9).</p>
                <p>The following testimony has been taken since the reference of the claim to the
                    Court, in Aug. 1895.</p>
                <p>D.A. SNITEMAN testifies: Merchant; age 48; residence near Staunton, Va. Not
                    related or interested. (P. 1). I have known the claimant all my life. Lived
                    within a mile and a half of him and saw him off and on throughout the war. Saw
                    him under ordinary circumstances as neighbors. I had no direct conversation with
                    him on the subject of the war, but his reputation in the neighborhood was that
                    of a strong Union man. I was an adherent of the Union cause, and claimant knew
                    it. His public reputation was that of a Union man, opposed to secession. He was
                    so regarded by his loyal neighbors. (P. 2). I don't know of anything the
                    claimant did to aid the Union army. Or the Confederate Govt. I don't know how he
                    voted on secession, but I am satisfied his influence was with the Union side.
                    His views did not change so far as I know<orig reg=".">..</orig></p>
                <p>CROSS-EXAMINATION.</p>
                <p>Claimant did not have any sons in the Confederate army. I am the claimant in case
                    No. 8799. Haven't been called on to testify in that case. I was present when the
                    case was examined this morning. (P. 3) I never was in the Confederate army, my
                    oldest brother was. I did not own Confederate bonds. My father owned them, but
                    they belonged to the estate of my grand father on my mother's side, of which my
                    father was executor.</p>
                <p>RE-DIRECT</p>
                <p>I was ready and willing if called on to testify in my father's case. I came here
                    with the expectation of being called upon. I had no objections to testifying.
                    (P. 4).</p>
                <p>O.E. CLEVELAND testifies; Farmer; age 72; residence Augusta Co., Va. Not related
                    ar interested. (P. 5). My acquaintance with the claimant began in '57. Knew him
                    well during the war and lived three or four hundred yards from him. Sometimes I
                    saw him every day and sometimes not so often. He always expressed himself in
                    opposition to the war in frequent conversations. I suppose I was an adherent of
                    the Union cause, though I did not know it until the war came on, and I suppose I
                    was known as such to him, as we had frequent conversations. Everybody knew that
                    claimant was a loyal man, and I knew it too. Claimant did everything in his
                    power to aid the Union army. Early in '64 he went through the lines to keep from
                    aiding the Confederacy, and remained outside the Confederacy, and inside the
                    Union lines until the war closed. (P. 6). He did not belong to any church so far
                    as I know. He never contributed anything to aid the Confederate Govt. so far as
                    I heard. I can't be positive, from his reputation I haven't the least Idea that
                    he would under any circumstances. So far as he exerted his influences it was on
                    the side of what he thought which was on the side of the Union. So far as I know
                    he thought throughout the war that nothing ought to be done contrary to the
                    cause of the U. S. Govt.</p>
                <p>CROSS-EXAMINATION</p>
                <p>I was born and raised in Va. My father was a bred and born yankee from
                    Connecticut. During the war he was as good a secesh as any man in the state. I
                    was the only Union man in the family, and suppose I am yet. (P. 7). I didn't
                    particularly fancy seeing any body killed<orig reg=".">..</orig> I didn't care
                    who they whipped so they kept the U.S. in a solid situation. I don't know that
                    the Confederates ever bought anything from the claimant except in the ordinary
                    way, like they bought whenever they <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> here. I
                    don't know whether he ever got pay for anything or not. By the ordinary way, I
                    mean whenever he had anything to sell he would sell it to any one who would buy
                    it, but not with a view to help the army. Of course any man who raised anything
                    had to sell it to help his family along He didn't have anything much to sell at
                    that time, as he was most in general working by the day, or working sometimes by
                    the day and sometimes by the month and sometimes by the year, as well as I can
                    recollect. I don't think claimant worked for the army<orig reg=".">..</orig> I
                    couldn't positively say, because I did not see claimant <orig reg="take"
                    >tale</orig> a trip once or twice while working for Mr. Bell, and haul for about
                    a week or so for the Confederate army.. (P. 8). I couldn't say positively
                    whether Mr. Bell did or did not send Mr. Gilbert with his teams. While I heard
                    Mr. Gilbert, the present claimant, make the statement that the claimant went
                    with Bell's teams once or twice to haul for the Confederate army, I couldn't say
                    I knew it. Robt. L. Lee was in the Confederate army. I saw him there, and he was
                    one of the finest looking men I ever saw too, on his big horse. I saw Stonewall
                    Jackson in the Confederate army. Never saw Jubal Early there. I don't know much
                    about Gen. McClelland I don't think he was in the Confederate army, unless he
                    was surrounded by rebels and was in the middle of it<orig reg=".">..</orig>
                    David Bell said he was the employer of Mr. Gilbert by the year. I did not hear
                    Mr. Gilbert say that his father, the original claimant, was employed by the year
                    as overseer by Mr. Bell I made some such observation as that myself. I heard him
                    say it, of course. I just judge from Bell's conversations with me that he was on
                    the Southern side. Their is no doubt about that. (P. 10). I reckon I stated he
                    was a secesh and a good one. (P. 11).</p>
                <p>SUMMARY.</p>
                <p>The Commissioners rejected this claim partly on merits, as well as doubts as to
                    loyalty. They found that he had no relatives in either army; that he did not
                    vote on secession; that in May '64 he left Va. to avoid conscription, and went
                    to Md., and they add "all this indicates neutrality." Whereas upon the finding
                    of these facts the claimant should have been held loyal.</p>
                <p>The claimant resided in Augusta Co., Va., during the war engaged in farming,
                    until May 4th, '64 when he went to Md. and remained until the war closed. He
                    never aided the Confederacy. Owned no Confederate bonds. He was for the Union at
                    the commencement, and says he has been for the Union all the time and expects to
                    remain so. Did not vote for the ordinance of secession. His witnesses testify to
                    his loyal expressions during the war and his loyal reputation. Was regarded as
                    loyal by his loyal neighbors.</p>
                <p>Witness Cleveland states, that every body knew claimant was a loyal man. That
                    early in '64 he went through the lines to keep from aiding the Confederacy, and
                    remained inside the Union lines until the war closed.</p>
                <p>This testimony is certainly conclusive as to claimants loyalty throughout the war
                    and the Court should so find.</p>
                <p>Respectfully Submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> ATTY FOR <abbr
                        expan="CLAIMANT">C'L'M'T.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>Claimant's Motion for a New Trial on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>COURT OF CLAIMS. DECEMBER TERM 1896-97.</p>
                <p>David M. Kerr, <abbr expan="Administrator">Adm'r</abbr>. Thos. J. Gilbert, <abbr
                        expan="deceased">dec.</abbr>, vs. The United States No. 8645 Cong.</p>
                <p>MOTION FOR A NEW TRIAL ON LOYALTY.</p>
                <p>In this case petition and letters cf administration were filed on Jan. 15th,
                    1896.</p>
                <p>On Dec. 10th, 1896 the case was submitted on briefs.</p>
                <p>Jan. l8th, 1897 case dismissed, loyalty not found. This motion for a new trial is
                    based upon error of fact.</p>
                <p>Mr. Gilbert is shown to have been loyal throughout the war by the testimony.</p>
                <p>The following are the facts in proof:</p>
                <p>Claimant lived in Augusta Co., Va., during the war. up to May '64. Then he went
                    to Md. and remained until the war closed. He never gave any aid to the
                    rebellion. He was opposed to secession from the commencement to the close of the
                    war. He was regarded in the community where he lived throughout the war as a
                    Union man and loyal citizen. He was ordered to join the Confederate army, and
                    rather than do so he left his home and went to Md. His expressions throughout
                    the war were in favor of the U.S. Govt. The fact of his leaving home, and
                    seeking protection inside the Union lines in connection with the fact that he
                    never aided the rebellion should conclude the question of loyalty in his favor.</p>
                <p>Upon the foregoing facts not controverted loyalty should have been found.</p>
                <p>Affidavits are expected, and will be filed in support of this motion.</p>
                <p>Respectfully Submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> ATTY FOR <abbr
                        expan="CLAIMANT">C'L'M'T.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>Claimant's Brief on Motion for a New Trial on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>COURT OF CLAIMS, DECEMBER TERM 1898-99.</p>
                <p>THOMAS J. GILBERT, Executors, etc., vs. The United States No. 8645 Cong.</p>
                <p>Claimant's Brief on Motion for a new trial on Loyalty.</p>
                <p>In support of this motion there are filed affidavits of Robert W. Johnson and
                    Thomas J. Gilbert. R.W. Johnson, himself a secessionist, deposes that he had
                    frequent conversations with claimant during the war, and that claimant differed
                    with him widely, steadily declaring himself for the Union; that deceased
                    claimant bore the reputation in that community of a "loyal" Union man. This is
                    the first the Court has heard of these <del hand="h1">peculiar</del><add hand="h1" place="inline">particular</add>
                    conversations with deceased claimant. If a new trial should be allowed, formal
                    and full proof will be made of them, including all such particulars as the
                    Attorney for the Government may choose to bring out.</p>
                <p>The deponent Gilbert is a son of the deceased claimant and resided with him
                    during the War. Like the former witnesses, he tells of his father's leaving his
                    home and going within the Federal Lines in Maryland and remaining there until
                    the end of the War; also, in general terms, of <add hand="h1" place="inline">his</add> consistent
                    loyalty.</p>
                <p>Such evidence as was before the Court on the submission of the case was all in
                    claimant's favor. There was no conflict in it, no inconsistencies even.
                    Evidently it failed to satisfy the Court merely because there was not thought to
                    be enough of it. It appears now that on a new trial important new proof of new
                    facts would clearly show that the deceased claimant was loyal.</p>
                <p>On the former evidence, indeed, the loyalty of deceased claimant was not denied
                    by the Attorney for the Government. All that he said was that the testimony was
                    correctly presented in my brief.</p>
                <p>Respectfully submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> Attorney for
                    Claimant.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                <byline>Defendant's Brief on Claimant's Motion for a New Trial on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS OF THE UNITED STATES. December Term, 1898.</p>
                <p>Estate Thomas J. Gilbert v. The United States No. 8645, Congressional.</p>
                <p>Defendants' Brief on Claimant's Motion for a New Trial on Loyalty</p>
                <p>The claimiant in support of his motion files the affidavit of his local attorney
                    to the effect that the evidence submitted in the affidavits accompanying could
                    not have been obtained before the hearing of the case by the exercise of
                    ordinary diligence.</p>
                <p>Two other affidavits are filed, one by Robert W. Johnson who says that he had
                        <del hand="h1">three</del> conversations with the claimant on the subject of
                    secession, but does not say when. From the fact, however, that affiant says he
                    subsequently went into the Confederate army, it is presumed that the
                    conversation took place before the war, or at least at its outbreak. No new fact
                    is set forth in Johnson's affidavit.</p>
                <p>The third affidavit is supplied by the son of the claimant who says his father
                    was a Union man and that he went to Maryland to avoid conscription into the
                    Confederate army. This alleged fact was fully presented when the case was heard
                    before.</p>
                <p>It is respectfully submitted that the evidence presented in support of the motion
                    for a new trial is cumulative at best and that the motion should be denied.</p>
                <p><name type="other">George H. Walker</name>, Assistant Attorney.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
