<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0501"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0501">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Jacob Bowman,
                    1873, Claim No. 17165</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of jacob bowman, 1873 claim no 17165</title>
        <author>Bowman, Jacob</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 18 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0501</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498388</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Jacob Bowman, 1873,
                            Claim No. 17165</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of jacob bowman, 1873 claim no 17165</title>
            <author>Jacob Bowman</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jusidiction #8876</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1873">1873</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Church/Religious Activity, Desertion/Leave, Economy,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0501T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jacob Bowman filed this claim in 1873 for 4 items, including horses, corn, bacon,
                    and flour, amounting to $600. He claimed the property taken by General Averill's
                    Union troops in June of 1864. Jacob was a 37 year old farmer and miller and a
                    member of the Lutheran Church. He voted for the Ordinance of Secession. The
                    claim was disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>4 Items</cell>
                            <cell>600.00</cell>
                            <cell>0.00</cell>
                            <cell>600.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>Claimant swears to loyal Sympathies but not to loyal Conduct. On the contrary he
                    was over persuaded and voted for the disolution of the Union and the destruction
                    of the Government. He likewise furnished a Substitute for the Confederate
                    Serivce, having as he alleged been Conscripted and having no other way to Escape
                    personal Service. And he also received Vouchers from Confederate Officers for
                    supplies taken which would not have been given him had he been the reputation of
                    a Union Man. We therefore reject the Claim.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>Jacob Bowman</byline>
                <p>My name is <hi rend="underline">Jacob Bowman</hi>, my age <hi rend="underline">37
                        years</hi>, my residence <hi rend="underline">Augusta County</hi>, in the
                    State of <hi rend="underline">Virginia</hi>, and my occupation a <hi
                        rend="underline">farmer</hi>; I am <del hand="h1">related to</del> the claimant, and
                    have <hi rend="underline">a</hi> beneficial interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>2. Witness says: I resided on my farm &amp; cultivated my farm all the war;
                    my farm contains 500 acres, 350 cleared. I did not leave the State during the
                    war.</p>
                <p>3. No in full</p>
                <p>4. No in full</p>
                <p>Witness says: I took amnesty oath after the war, had nothing to be pardoned for.</p>
                <p>6. No in full</p>
                <p>7. No in full</p>
                <p>8. No in full</p>
                <p>9. No in full.</p>
                <p>10. No in full</p>
                <p>11. No in full</p>
                <p>12. Witness says: I was forced into the Home guard for 5 days in 1864.</p>
                <p>13. I was conscripted into the Rebel service &amp; furnished a substitute to
                    keep out of it. I had either to do that or go in myself; I had no other choice.</p>
                <p>15. No in full</p>
                <p>16. No in full</p>
                <p>17. No in full</p>
                <p>18. No in full</p>
                <p>19. No in full</p>
                <p>20. No in full</p>
                <p>21. No in full</p>
                <p>22. No in full</p>
                <p>23. No in full</p>
                <p>24. Witness says: He was arrested twice by the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                    >Confed.</abbr> authorities &amp; brought to Staunton, the first time
                        <del hand="h1">he</del><add hand="h1" place="inline">I</add> was parolled, then <del hand="h1">he</del><add hand="h1" place="inline">I</add> was
                    brought back &amp; released upon the ground that <del hand="h1">he</del><add hand="h1" place="inline">I</add>
                    was a miller. Was arrested after the law passed requiring principals to go into
                    Army notwithstanding had employed substitutes. I never was arrested by the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Gov<hi
                            rend="super">t.</hi></abbr></p>
                <p>25. The Confederate impressed <add hand="h1" place="inline">some</add> hay, oats, &amp;
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">flour</add> for which they gave me receipts.</p>
                <p>26. Witness says: I was never threatened as I kept as still I possibly could.</p>
                <p>27. No in full</p>
                <p>28. No in full</p>
                <p>29. No in full</p>
                <p>30. Witness says: I had no son, nephew or brother in <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr> Army.</p>
                <p>31. No in full</p>
                <p>32. No in full</p>
                <p>33. No in full</p>
                <p>34. No in full</p>
                <p>35. No in full</p>
                <p>36. No in full</p>
                <p>37. No in full</p>
                <p>38. No in full</p>
                <p>39. No in full</p>
                <p>40. Witness says: I was opposed to the war from beginning to the end. I voted for
                    the Ordinance of Secession against my conviction. I had determined to vote
                    against it, but was approached by D<hi rend="super">r.</hi> W<hi
                        rend="super">m</hi> S. M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Chesney, an
                    intelligent &amp; influential man, a warm personal friend of mine, who said
                    if I did not vote for it I would rue it the balance of my life as it was the
                    only way upon Earth to keep off a war and I yielded to his advice for &amp;
                    in consideration of my love of the country.</p>
                <p>41. Witness says: My sympathies were with the old <abbr expan="Government"
                    >Gov.</abbr> I wasted no change. Was opposed to a Separation, &amp; did
                    nothing for the rebel <abbr expan="Government">Gov.</abbr> but what I was
                    compelled. I was never gladder in my life than when the war ended &amp; as
                    it did.</p>
                <p>And further this Deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Jacob Bowman</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 17 day of October 1872.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Jacob Bowman</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Jacob Bowman recalled to prove taking &amp; value of his
                    property.</p>
                <p>1. Witness says: I saw all the property mentioned in my petition mentioned the
                    flour &amp; corn from the mill, one horse from a meadow &amp; the other
                    from the yard gate on my farm. The bacon was in my house. This was
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">all</add> taken in June 1864 by G<hi rend="super">en.</hi> Averill
                    &amp; Crooks soldiers of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Army.
                    There were about 150 soldiers engaged in takin the property. There were officers
                    present but I do not know their names or ranks. My family was present, &amp;
                        M<hi rend="super">r.</hi> W<hi rend="super">m</hi> Bosserman was
                    with me at the time near by. I had no conversation with any officer, the
                    officers <add hand="h1" place="inline">said</add> that they must have such property as this mentioned, it
                    was necessary to have it. They were driving off my young cattle, but at the
                    earnest request of my life to leave one special one, he said as that is the best
                    one I will leave all, which he did. The main body of the Army was at Staunton
                    about 7 miles, they took the property in direction of camp, except what they fed
                    on the ground. There were a great many sacks in mill, which they used in taking
                    property away. An officer rode one of my horses, &amp; told my wife it was
                    one of the best horses he had seen in <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a.</hi></abbr> the other was led off. No complaint
                    was made to any officer, no receipt was given or asked for, all was taken in day
                    time. The horses were 4 &amp; 6 years old respectively, in fine condition,
                    &amp; worth richly $200 each. The flour was in <abbr expan="pounds"
                    >lbls.</abbr> 10 barrels &amp; worth $10 per <abbr expan="pound">lb<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> There were 50 bushels of corn I had
                    measured it. it was all taken &amp; was worth $1 per bushel. There were 11
                    pieces of bacon, large hams weighing 20 <abbr expan="pounds">lbs.</abbr> each,
                    all taken from garret of the house to which it had been removed from the Smoke
                    house; was worth 25 cents per <abbr expan="pound">lb.</abbr> The officer was
                    very kind, &amp; would suffer no soldier to enter the house. he pitched the
                    bacon out of the window. he left about as much bacon as he took. I was the sole
                    owner of the property taken, nothing was left in exchange, &amp; I have
                    never been paid for it, nor has the claim ever been presented before to the Gov.</p>
                <p>And further the Deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Jacob Bowman</name>
                </p>
                <p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me this 17<hi rend="super">th.</hi>
                    day of October 1872.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>William Bosserman</byline>
                <p>Deposition of William Bosserman to prove the taking and value of the property
                    mentioned in Claimants petition.</p>
                <p>1. Witness says: I am 45 years of age, reside in Augusta County, and am a farmer.
                    Was on a hill near by <del hand="h1">his</del><add hand="h1" place="inline">Claimant</add> house &amp; mill,
                    &amp; saw the property taken, or rather saw the soldiers enter the mill
                    where the corn &amp; flour were, &amp; when they left it was gone. I saw
                    one horse taken out of the meadow, &amp; the other from the yard gate of
                    Claimants farm. I did not see the bacon actually taken, but know from
                    information of others that it was. This was <add hand="h1" place="inline">done</add> in June 1864, by
                    soldiers of <abbr expan="General">Gl.</abbr> Hunter. I thought there were 150
                    men engaged in taking the property. The place seemed alive with them. The
                    Claimants family were present. There were officers there, but I did not know
                    them. The main body of the Army was encamped at Staunton, a part of it about 4
                    miles from Claimants; soldiers took the property towards their camp. No
                    complaint was made that I know of to any officer, no receipt given or asked for,
                    nothing left in exchange, it has never been paid for or presented to any Dep
                    that I know of. It was all taken in the day time. The horses were in fine
                    condition, one 6 &amp; the other 4 years of age, they were remarkably fine
                    horses &amp; richly worth $200 each. They took 10 <abbr expan="pounds"
                    >lbls</abbr> of flour worth $10 each. it was in the mill. There were 50 bushels
                    of measured corn in the mill. it was taken. it was worth $1 per bushel. I did
                    not see the bacon, but am satisfied from what I saw &amp; heard it was
                    taken. it was worth 25 <abbr expan="cents">cts.</abbr><abbr expan="per">p<hi
                            rend="super">r.</hi></abbr><abbr expan="pound">lb.</abbr></p>
                <p>And further this Deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">W<hi rend="super">m.</hi> Bosserman</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 17<hi rend="super">th.</hi> day of
                    October 1872.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>William Bosserman</byline>
                <p>Deposition of W<hi rend="super">m.</hi> Bosserman recalled to prove the
                    loyalty of the Claimant.</p>
                <p>1. I have known the Claimant all his life, he was raised within two miles of my
                    fathers house. Saw him constantly during the war &amp; talked with him about
                    the war. He was the sickest man of the war I ever saw, he was opposed to the war
                    &amp; to secession. He advised every body to leave the South &amp; go to
                    the mountains. He aided all deserters, fed them &amp; concealed them. he
                    gave them while in the mountains, flour, bacon, &amp;. He said the day he
                    was parolled &amp; left Staunton that if he could not get off as a miller he
                    would certainly <add hand="h1" place="inline">run off &amp;</add> go North. I regarded him as a true
                    Union man &amp; he was so regarded by all his neighbors. I heard of no
                    threats against him. I am certain that he did nothing to aid the Confederate
                        <abbr expan="Government">Gov<hi rend="super">t.</hi></abbr> except as
                    stated above. The claimant is a member of high standing in the Lutheran Church.
                    I the witness was a Union man during the war, &amp; am also a member of the
                    Lutheran Church. He had no sons in <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr>
                    Army, was the owner of no <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> bonds to my
                    knowledge, &amp; did nothing to aid the credit of the Confederacy. He
                        <del hand="h1">was</del> rejoiced more than any man I ever saw at the conclusion of
                    the war &amp; at the sucess of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> I
                    do not think he would have done as he did about <del hand="h1">not</del> voting, had it
                    not been for the influence of D<hi rend="super">r.</hi> W<hi
                        rend="super">m.</hi> S. M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Chesney
                    &amp; for the reason assigned that it would keep off a war. D<hi
                        rend="super">r.</hi> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Chesney had great
                    influence and was regarded as a true friend. The D<hi rend="super">r.</hi>
                    was as much distressed as I ever saw a man when the war commenced - he wept
                    bitterly. The State of affairs was such, that a great many good
                    <del hand="h1">friends</del> citizens, &amp; Union men, were apt to be influenced by
                    men of more reading &amp; information than they possessed themselves, as to
                    what way proper to be done for the Country.</p>
                <p>And further the Deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Wm. Bosserman</name>
                </p>
                <p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 17<hi rend="super">th.</hi> day of
                    October 1872.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>George S. Arehart</byline>
                <p>Deposition of G. S. Arehart, to prove the Loyalty of Jacob Bowman.</p>
                <p>1. Witness says: I am 44 years old, reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                    >Co.</abbr> I am a farmer, I have known the Claimant all his life. Lived near
                    him during the war. Saw him often &amp; talked to him about the war. When we
                    went in the mountains hiding to keep out of the Confederate Army, the Claimants
                    sent us us six (6) <abbr expan="pounds">lbs.</abbr> of flour to use, when I
                    returned from the West in 1864. I told him how every thing prospered in the
                    North &amp; that the South was already whipped. he seemed delighted. Said he
                    wanted the thing to close. I regarded him as a Union man &amp; his neighbors
                    regarded him as such. Don't know how he voted on the ordinance of Secession. If
                    he had been a rebel he would not have supplied us as he did while we were hiding
                    in the mountains. Never heard him threatened by the rebels. He was in the home
                    guards a few days. <add hand="h1" place="inline">was</add> forced into it. Did nothing voluntarily for
                    the Confederate <abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> Had no son in the
                    Confederate Army. Owned no Confederate blonds, did nothing to support the credit
                    of the Confederate States. He is a member of the Lutheran Church. I am a member
                    of the same Church. Can't say what the claimant would have done had the South
                    gained its independence. And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">George S. Arehart</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 15th day of October 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
