<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0109"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0109">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of James F. Davis,
                    September 6, 1871, Claim No. 2135</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of james f davis, september 6 1871 claim no 2135</title>
        <author>Davis, James F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 14 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0109</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498334</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of James F. Davis,
                            September 6, 1871, Claim No. 2135</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of james f davis, september 6 1871 claim no 2135</title>
            <author>James F. Davis</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8649</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0109T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Davis' claim for one mule was rejected for the vagueness of testimony on both
                    loyalty and taking of property. He unsuccessfully appealed this decision to the
                    Congressional Court of Claims in 1892.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Mule</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>This claim is rejected.</p>
                <p>I. Mr. Davis says, "He was forced into the rebel service but only remained a
                    short time." How long? He does not say. He says "he was arrested, carried to
                    Richmond, kept in Castle Thunder, released and put into the service."</p>
                <p>For this we have nothing but his own statement, nothing to sustain him. The two
                    witnesses say nothing about it &amp; testify in a loose general way of no
                    value.</p>
                <p>II. The evidence of the taking is not satisfactory either as to the authority or
                    necessity of the taking, or as to the use by the Army.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A. O. Aldis</name><abbr expan="Commissioners">Comms</abbr> of
                    Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>James F. Davis</byline>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">United States of America, State of Virginia</hi>
                </p>
                <p>I, W. G. Riley, a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioners
                    appointed under the Act of Congress of March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi>
                    1871, to take and record testimony. Do hereby certify, that the reason for
                    taking the following depositions is, and the fact is, the matter of claim of
                    James F. Davis vs. the United States of America, and the witnesses herein named,
                    being first duly sworn, answers as follows,</p>
                <p>James F. Davis Claimant &amp; Witness</p>
                <p>Question 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says, I am 46 years old. I
                    reside in Augusta Co. Va. and an auctioneer by occupation. I resided for 6
                    months previous to April 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1861 in Augusta County,
                    Va.</p>
                <p>2. Witness Says, I resided in the same County until in 1864, I left and passed
                    the Union lines to the state of Indiana, where I remained for some five months;
                    employed <del hand="h1">by</del> as a hand on the Rail road, and then returned to my home
                    in Augusta Co. in June 1865.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says, I never took any oath of
                    allegiance to the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, I took an Amnesty oath in 1865, at
                    Staunton, Va. I never applied for pardon, I was not guilty of any <orig
                        reg="offense">offence</orig>.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says, I have never directly or
                    indirectly connected with the civil service of the Confederate States, except
                    when forced to do so.</p>
                <p>7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says I never held any office in the
                    Confederacy, Clerkship agency or employment of any kind.</p>
                <p>9<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, I was forced into the rebel Army,
                    but only remained a short time and never fired a gun or <orig reg="burst"
                        >bursted</orig> a cap.</p>
                <p>10<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, I never was an officer, soldier,
                    sailor or Marine, except as named in a previous answer.</p>
                <p>11<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says I never was in the rebel service
                    in any way except as herein named.</p>
                <p>14<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says I never was engaged in blockade
                    running.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says I did leave the <orig
                        reg="Confederacy">Confederate</orig> and went into the Federal lines and
                    remained there until June 1865.</p>
                <p>17<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, I was arrested by the Confederate
                    Government, and carried to Richmond, and kept in Castle Thunder and then
                    released and put into the service. I took no oath at all. I was arrested by the
                    United States Government, and held as a prisoner about 1 1/2 hours.</p>
                <p>18<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, I had <hi rend="super"
                    >no</hi> property taken by the Confederates.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, I have been threatened with
                    personal damage, because of my Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Witness Says, I never contributed any thing for
                    the support of the United States Government.</p>
                <p>23<hi rend="super">d</hi>. Witness Says, I had relatives in both the
                    Armies, I did nothing to supply them with equipments of any kind.</p>
                <p>24<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, I never owned a Bond or did
                    anything to support the credit of the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>25<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says I never give any aid or done
                    anything except what forced to do for the rebel Government.</p>
                <p>30<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, I never held any office in the
                    United States. Nor educated at any military or Naval school of the United
                    States.</p>
                <p>31<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Witness Says I did receive a pass from the
                    Confederates, to go from Staunton to my home in the Country.</p>
                <p>32<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, I was under no disabilities by the
                        14<hi rend="super">th</hi><abbr expan="Amendment">Amt.</abbr> of the
                    Constitution. I was a U.S. Inspector Internal Service since the War, and took
                    the "Iron clad" I have also held the Office of Constable and Notary Public</p>
                <p>33<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, At the beginning my sympathies were
                    with the Union. I don't think I voted at all on the adoption of the Ordinance of
                    Secession. After the adoption of Secession, my sympathies were for the Union.</p>
                <p>34<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I do solemnly declare that from
                    the beginning of hostilities against the United States to the end thereof, my
                    sympathies were constantly with the United States and that I never of my own
                    free will and accord did anything to injure the cause of the Union. And was at
                    all times ready and willing to <del hand="h1">do</del> aid the cause of the Union, so far
                    as my means and power and the circumstances would permit.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">James F. Davis</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>William Silor</byline>
                <p>William Silor a witness introduced by the claimant to prove the taking the Mule
                    named in the petition being duly sworn answers.</p>
                <p>Question 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Witness Say I am 50 years of age. I
                    reside in Augusta, Co. Va. and a farmer by occupation. I was present and saw the
                    property taken from the Claimant.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, The property was taken in June
                    1865, by soldiers under Command of <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi>.</abbr> Hunter, from the premises of claimants
                    brother in law.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says, The Mule was taken by soldiers of
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi>.</abbr> Hunter's
                    command, I did not know any names or rank.</p>
                <p>12<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says There was no receipt asked for
                    given</p>
                <p>13<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says, The property was taken in the day
                    time</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness Says The Mule was in first rate
                    condition, he was 3 or 4 years old, and worth $125. or $130<hi
                        rend="super">00</hi>.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I think the Mule was taken for the
                    use of the Army, they were marching at the time.</p>
                <p>22<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says I think that the Government having
                    taken the property ought to pay for it.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">William Silor</name> his mark</p>
                <p>The same witness introduced to prove the loyalty of the Claimant to the United
                    States.</p>
                <p>Answers as follows,</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Question">Quest.</abbr> 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Witness
                    says, I have known the claimant about 15 years. I saw him often during the War,
                    and I believe he was loyal to the United States and think he was so regarded by
                    his neighbors I don't know that he did any thing for the United States, except
                    to leave the Confederate States and go into the Union lines He done nothing for
                    the rebel Government voluntarily.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">William Silor</name> his mark</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>John Silor</byline>
                <p>John Silor, a witness introduced to prove the loyalty of Claimant, being duly
                    sworn, answers as follows,</p>
                <p><abbr expan="Question">Ques.</abbr> 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>. Witness
                    Says, I am 55 years old. I reside in Augusta Co. Va. and by occupation a farmer.
                    I have known the claimant for about 15 years I resided some distance from him
                    during the War, but saw him frequently, and believe that he was a loyal man to
                    the United States, and he was I think so regarded by his neighbors.</p>
                <p>He never done anything for the United States. Nor nothing for the Confederacy,
                    voluntarily. I think he was too loyal to the United States, to have been
                    regarded as loyal to the Confederacy, had it succeeded.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Silor</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 6th day of <abbr expan="September"
                        >Sept.</abbr> 1871.</p>
                <p><name type="other">W G Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for State of V<hi rend="super"
                >a</hi></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>United States Treasury Department</byline>
                <p>Treasury Department, Office of the Secretary, Washington, D.C. April 25, 1892</p>
                <p>The Honorable The Attorney General</p>
                <p>Sir:</p>
                <p>In answer to your request of the 11th instant in the case of James F. Davis
                    against the United States, No. 8649 Congressional, I have the honor to state
                    that Jas. F. Davis voted for the ordinance of secession in Augusta County,
                    Virginia, as appears in a copy of the poll sheets of said vote.</p>
                <p>It is presumed that the original list is in the custody of the county clerk of
                    Augusta County.</p>
                <p>Respectfully yours, <name type="other">
                        <unclear>G Stanley</unclear>
                    </name> Acting Secretary</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>War Department, Adjutant General's Office, April 30, 1892</p>
                <p>There are on file in this office six (6) vouchers signed <hi rend="underline">J.
                        F. Davis</hi>, four dated at Richmond, Va. for hospital supplies, one at
                    Marion, Va., for hay, and one other in Washington Co., Md., for bacon.</p>
                <p>One <hi rend="underline">Jas. F. Davis</hi>, of Staunton, Augusta Co., Va.,
                    petitioned the president of the C.S. not to proclaim martial law in that town.</p>
                <p>One <hi rend="underline">J. F. Davis</hi>, of Russell or Wise Co., Va.,
                    petitioned for a military force to be stationed in that vicinity. Various other
                    references are found to persons by the name of <hi rend="underline">J. F.
                        &amp; Jas. F. Davis</hi> in Ark., Ala., Miss., N.C., S.C., Tenn.,
                    &amp; Texas.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
