<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0315"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0315">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Eli A. Garber,
                    January 12, 1874, Claim No. 2560</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of eli a garber, january 12 1874 claim no 2560</title>
        <author>Garber, Eli A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 16 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0315</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498382</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Eli A. Garber,
                            January 12, 1874, Claim No. 2560</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of eli a garber, january 12 1874 claim no 2560</title>
            <author>Eli Garber</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche # 2194</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1876">1876</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Enlistment, Family, Home Front, Military Authority, National
                        Government, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0315T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Eli A. Garber filed this claim January 12, 1874, for $100, claiming that his two
                    milch cows were driven off by Union troops, being part of a larger herd owned by
                    his father, Samuel Garber. The confiscation occurred during the burning of the
                    Valley of Virginia in September 1864, and Samuel Garber's barn was burned as the
                    cattle were confiscated. Despite the Claims Commission's satisfaction that Eli
                    Garber was in fact loyal to the Union, the claim was disallowed on a
                    technicality: many of the cattle taken during the Valley burning were sold and
                    the money paid to the Treasury. Therefore, the cattle were not necessarily used
                    as army supplies. The claim was disallowed in 1876.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Two Milch Cows</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$100.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The Claimant files testimony to establish his loyalty. But it appears from the
                    proof in the case that Sheridan's troops were on the Burning Raid at the time
                    the cattle were driven off by them. The Barn was burned and the stock driven off
                    in order to cut off the supplies of the Rebel Army. As many of the cattle taken
                    at the time were subsequently sold and the money paid into the Treasury we
                    cannot therefore find without direct proof of the fact that these cows were
                    taken as supplies for the Army, We therefore reject the Claim.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name><name type="other">JB Howell</name><name
                        type="other">O. Ferris</name> Commrs of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Eli A. Garber</byline>
                <p>In answer to the First General Interrogatory, the Deponent says: My name is Eli
                    A. Garber, my age 36 years, my residence Augusta County, in the State of
                    Virginia, and my occupation a Farmer; I am the claimant, and have beneficial
                    interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>Interrogatory 2. I lived in Augusta County Va. until the 1<hi rend="super"
                        >st</hi> week of <abbr expan="January">Jany</abbr> 1864 when I in company
                    with 12 other young men including two of my brothers started for Penn<hi
                        rend="super">a</hi> and when we had gone about 26 miles we were
                    intercepted by some rebel pickets or scouts, and part of our party were
                    captured, I among them. While being taken to their head quarters we resisted and
                    compelled the guards to release us. I then went home and bewteen Saturday night
                    and Sunday night I raised 25 refugees, among them a number of rebel Soldiers,
                    and having armed ourselves we all started together and went through to New Creek
                    station on the B &amp; O <abbr expan="Rail">R.</abbr> Road and crossed over
                    into Maryland and <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig><add hand="h1" place="inline">in the
                        North</add><del hand="h1">since</del> until the War closed.</p>
                <p>3. No sir.</p>
                <p>4. Yes sir. In July 1861 when the militia were called out I was compelled to go
                    to with them to New Hope and to Staunton and when at New Hope, the oath of
                    allegiance or some kind of an oath was administered to us while standing in a
                    line. I think it was not to give any aid or comfort to the enemy. I did not sign
                    any paper. When the oath was first proposed I just refused to take it but was
                    threatened with being sent to Richmond if I refused, and I agreed to the form,
                    knowing there was no Confederacy and that it was not binding.</p>
                <p>5. Yes sir. I took it at Mt Sidney soon after the war. I took the oath of
                    allegiance to the U.S. at New Creek Station when I went north in <abbr
                        expan="January">Jany</abbr> 1864.</p>
                <p>6 to 10. No sir. I had nothing to do with them in any way.</p>
                <p>11 to 14 inclusive. When I was at Staunton, my Father &amp; Mother were so
                    exercised about my going in the militia that they came to Staunton every day
                    trying to get me off and I told the men and our Lieutenant I would not fight if
                    they took me, that I would leave the first opportunity I got. My father at last
                    hired a man in my place and I went home. The quota of volunteers was not then
                    made up and my parents were afraid I would have to go.</p>
                <p>15 to 21 inclusive. No sir.</p>
                <p>22. Yes. I went north early in 1864.</p>
                <p>23. No Sir.</p>
                <p>24. Yes. When trying to escape north.</p>
                <p>25. Yes. They took away my two horses after I had gone north. When they took my
                    horses they told my wife if I would come to Staunton I could get them. They knew
                    I was gone north. I was never paid for them.</p>
                <p>26 to 28 inclusive. No Sir. The Union Army never came through here until after I
                    had gone north.</p>
                <p>29 Yes sir. I assisted a large number of persons to escape from the confederacy.
                    I was engaged in this business about 18 months, and helped many citizens and
                    soldiers and put them on the route through the mountains to the Union lines.</p>
                <p>30. None nearer than one cousin, and I assisted him to escape north. I had
                    relatives in the Union army.</p>
                <p>I had three brothers here liable to do military duty and all four of us went
                    north. None of our family were in the rebellion in any way.</p>
                <p>31 to 39 No sir.</p>
                <p>40 &amp; 41 I sympathized with the Union Cause all the time. I did not
                    believe in Secession and spoke against it all I dared to do. I could not say
                    much in some <orig reg="crowds">crouds</orig> as it was not safe to express
                    Union sentiments. I don't think I voted for the candidates to the convention and
                    when the vote was taken on Secession my impression is that I was away from home
                    and that I did not vote. I am not perfectly clear on the subject.</p>
                <p>After the State Seceeded I adhered to the Union. My sentiments were Union all the
                    time, and I did all I could in aid of the Union cause.</p>
                <p>Property</p>
                <p>In answer to the interrogations as to the taking of the property</p>
                <p>Deponent says I was not present and did not see my cows taken. I was in
                    Pennsylvania at the time.</p>
                <p>They were taken from my fathers place and were with his stock when taken.</p>
                <p>The cows fine large Durham milch cows, excellent for milk and Butter. I
                    considered them worth not less than $50 a head.</p>
                <p>I am a native born citizen and have not passed through Bankruptcy.</p>
                <p>And further the deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Eli A. Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Anna Garber</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Anna Garber as to the Property.</p>
                <p>I am 62 years old, live in Augusta Co. Va. I am the mother of the claimant. I
                    have no interest in his claim.</p>
                <p>In the fall of the year 1864 while a body of cavalry men passing our farm at the
                    time of the burning a party of 25 or 30 men rode in to our barn and set it on
                    fire and drove off all the cattle on the place except three calves. I forget the
                    exact number of cattle we had, but think it was 11 head. Two of them belonged to
                    my son the claimant who was then in Penn<hi rend="super">a</hi></p>
                <p>The cattle belonging to the claimant were two very fine Durham milch cows that
                    were prized highly. They were excellent stock and good milkers and were in nice
                    order when taken away. The were young and of superior breed and were worth more
                    than ordinary cows.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Anna Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Samuel Garber</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Samuel Garber as to the Property</p>
                <p>I am 64 years old, a farmer, live near New Hope in Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>I am a father of the claimant. I have no interest in his claim.</p>
                <p>I was present at my house on my farm near New Hope when a portion of cavalry of
                    the Army of Gen Sheridan were passing my place in the fall of 1864 in Sept, and
                    I saw some 25 or 30 of the party ride in towards my barn and soon saw it in
                    flames. The same party drove off all our cattle but a few calves who were not
                    with the others. There were about a dozen in all driven away at that time. Among
                    them were two very <del hand="h1">very</del> fine Durham cows belonging to my son the
                    claimant who had gone across the lines and was in the north. The cows were not
                    ordinary ones, but were very fine ones in good order and excellent for milk and
                    butter. I consider such cattle worth any time $50 a head tho he paid more than
                    that for them and further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Samuel Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>John Yates</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Yates as to the Loyalty of Eli A. Garber</p>
                <p>I am 65 years old. I am Postmaster at Mt Sidney. I am an "Iron Clad" Union Man. I
                    was imprisoned in Castle Thunder for aiding refugees to escape and sent to
                    Staunton for trial but before the time came I was released by the forces of Gen.
                    Sheridan.</p>
                <p>I have no interest in the claim of the claimant and am not related to him.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant 10 or 12 years. During the War, until he went north I
                    lived within 1/2 mile of him and saw him very often, had frequent conversations
                    with him on matters relating to the war. He always expressed himself as opposed
                    to the confederacy. I have heard him speak strongly in favor of the Union cause
                    and the loyal party at the north. He started to go north once with a party of
                    refugees but returned and took a large party with him as I heard.</p>
                <p>He was well and generally known as a strong union man by the loyal element around
                    here. I have heard him spoken of as such by many and further the deponent saith
                    not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Yates</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Daniel Bowers</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Daniel Bowers as to the loyalty of Eli A. Garber</p>
                <p>I am 43 years old, a <unclear>Printer</unclear>, live at Mt Sidney Augusta County
                    Va.</p>
                <p>I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in his claim.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant about 20 years. During the war I did not see much of
                    him until <unclear>early</unclear> in 1863. When he came to Mount Sidney to work
                    on his father in laws farm and I became quite intimate with him. We had much
                    talk on the subject of the rebellion, and how to keep out of the army and about
                    the war. He said he was opposed to Secession and the War, and that he never
                    intended going into the Army. I cannot relate his conversation on the subject of
                    the Union, but I am positive he had no sympathy with the rebellion. I think he
                    sympathized with the Union cause; I think so because he left this county and
                    went north, and because he done a great deal to assist others to escape from the
                    confederacy. I know he was quite active in that business, and that through his
                    assistance a good many made their escape and went north. I was one myself of a
                    party of 25 or more who started from the vicinity of Mt Sidney and landed at New
                    Creek Station on the B &amp; O <abbr expan="Rail">R.</abbr> Road about 23
                    miles above Cumberland, who were got together mainly through Claimant's agency.
                    I don't remember hearing him say anything about fighting in the union army. His
                    main object appeared to be to keep out of the Army himself and to help as many
                    others to keep out as he could. I have heard the claimant spoken of as a true
                    Union man. I heard Mr. Yates say so for one. It was about the time the refugee
                    party were preparing to go away. I regarded the claimant as a union man myself,
                    and believed him loyal to the United States. The Union forces were never came to
                    this country until after the claimant had left.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Daniel Bowers</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Isaac P. Baldwin</byline>
                <p>No doubt about claimants sentiments being Union.</p>
                <p><name type="other">Isaac P. Baldwin</name> Special Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>John Yates and John C. Humbert</byline>
                <p>We the undersigned Loyal citizens of Augusta county Virginia do certify on oath
                    that we have known Eli A. Garber for many years and know him to have been Loyal
                    to the Government of the United States before and at the time of the and since
                    the taking of the property in the claim and petition mentioned.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">John Yates</name> Mt Sidney <name type="witness">John C.
                        Humbert</name> New Hope</p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 29<hi rend="super">th</hi> April
                        1871<lb/><name type="other">H.G. MCausland</name> N.P.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
