<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0124"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0124">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Kilburn H.
                    Rowsey, May 23, 1874, Claim No. 7650</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of kilburn h rowsey, may 23 1874 claim no 7650</title>
        <author>Rowsey, Kilburn H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 47</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0124</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498349</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Kilburn H. Rowsey,
                            May 23, 1874, Claim No. 7650</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of kilburn h rowsey, may 23 1874 claim no 7650</title>
            <author>Kilburn H. Rowsey</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8608</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1874-05-23">1874-05-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0124T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Kilbourn Rowsey filed his claim in Augusta County, where he resided at the time,
                    but during the war he lived in Rockbridge County. His claim for blacksmith tools
                    and a saddle was disallowed by the Commission in 1879 for lack of evidence. He
                    appealed this decision, apparently successfully, in 1903.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 sets Smiths tools complete</cell>
                            <cell>300.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>300.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell> 200 lbs <unclear>steel</unclear> at 30cts </cell>
                            <cell>60.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>60.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Horse shoes &amp; nails</cell>
                            <cell>20.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>set brace &amp; bits</cell>
                            <cell>6.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>6.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 screw plates</cell>
                            <cell>20.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>one large drill</cell>
                            <cell>10.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>10.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>300 lb Iron</cell>
                            <cell>30.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>30.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Drawing knives saw &amp; chains</cell>
                            <cell>10.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>10.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>saddle &amp; 2 bridles</cell>
                            <cell>15.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>15.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tools and other contents of a blacksmith shop</cell>
                            <cell>471.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>471.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>There is some evidence lending to the support of Claimants loyalty. But without
                    passing on the sufficiency of the evidence on that question we are constrained
                    to reject the Claim on defect of proof as to the property. The only evidence on
                    that point is Claimant's wife, who swears that the army stopped on the march and
                    the soldiers broke open the door at the shop and took the tools etc. and put
                    them into the wagons. She <orig reg="doesn't">don't</orig> know who commandant
                    was, and <orig reg="doesn't">don't</orig> testify what tools were taken nor to
                    their value. The evidence is too meagre and defective to justify an allowance.
                    We therefore reject the claim.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name>, <name
                        type="other">O. Ferriss</name> Com of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Kilburn H. Rowsey</byline>
                <p>Deposition of K.H. Rowsey</p>
                <p>My name is Kilburn H. Rowsey jr., my age 43 years, my residence Moffett's Creek,
                    Augusta Co., in the State of Va., and my occupation a Blacksmith; I am the
                    claimant, and have a beneficial interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>Ques. 2 Ans. I resided part of the time in Rockbridge County, Va. part in
                    Clarksburg &amp; Martinsburg W. Va. and a part in Augusta Co.</p>
                <p>3 Ans. I never passed beyond the lines of the U.S. into the rebel lines, but was
                    in the rebel lines when the war commenced.</p>
                <p>4 Ans. I was forced to take an oath as a citizen of Virginia. The <orig
                        reg="Militia">Malitia</orig> was called out, and required to take the oath
                    or be sent to Richmond. I do not recollect the purport of the Oath.</p>
                <p>5 Ans. I took the Amnesty Oath, at Clarksburg W. Va. Oct 28 1864, prescribed by
                    the Presidents Proclamation. (see Certificate herewith filed) I never asked any
                    pardon.</p>
                <p>6 Ans. I never was in any way connected with the civil service of the
                    Confederacy.</p>
                <p>7 Ans. I never held any office, or place of honor or trust in the Confederate
                    Government, State or Territory subordinate thereto.</p>
                <p>8 Ans. I held no clerkship, agency or employment of any kind.</p>
                <p>9 Ans. I was called out as a <orig reg="Militia">Malitia</orig>, and only
                    remained a few days at Lexington Va. and returned to my home.</p>
                <p>10 Ans. I never was an Officer or Soldier in the Confederate Army.</p>
                <p>11 Ans. Only as stated in question 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>.</p>
                <p>12 Ans. I never was in the Home Guard, or in any committee whatsoever.</p>
                <p>13 Ans. I was conscripted but did not go into service.</p>
                <p>14 Ans. I furnished no substitute.</p>
                <p>15 Ans. I never was in any way connected with the Quarter Master's, Commissary or
                    in any department of the Confederate Army or Government.</p>
                <p>16 Ans. I never was employed on a Rail road, nor aided in transporting soldiers
                    munitions of War or supplies for the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>17 Ans. I never had charge of any stores or supplies--trains, teams, <orig
                        reg="wagons">waggons</orig>, or Boats, for the use of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>18 Ans. I never was in any employment or business of any character, and never
                    furnished any supplies or stores whatsoever. I never <orig reg="gave"
                    >give</orig> any information.</p>
                <p>19 Ans. I never was employed in the manufacture of any thing for the use of the
                    Confederacy. Nor aided others.</p>
                <p>20 Ans. I never was directly or otherwise employed in any way whatsoever.</p>
                <p>Ques. 21 Ans. I never run the blockade, nor engaged in any trade between the
                    lines, and had no share or interest in such <orig reg="traffic">trafic</orig>.</p>
                <p>22 Ans. I left the Confederate lines on the 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> day
                    of October 1864, I went to Beverly W. Va. thence to Clarksburg W. Va. I left
                    because of my opposition to the rebel cause. I did not return until after the
                    War closed in 1865. I worked at my trade, in Martinsburg I was in the employment
                    of the U.S. Government.</p>
                <p>23 Ans. I never owned or had any share in any vessel.</p>
                <p>24 Ans. I never was arrested by either the Confederate or United States
                    authorities.</p>
                <p>25 Ans. I never had any property taken by the Confederate Authorities.</p>
                <p>26 Ans. There were some threats, made by citizens and neighbors, to send me to
                    Richmond to Castle Thunder.</p>
                <p>27 Ans. I never was molested.</p>
                <p>28 Ans. I never contributed anything in aid of the United States, or the Union
                    Army.</p>
                <p>29 Ans. I never did anything.</p>
                <p>30 Ans. I had a brother, Thomas J. Rowsey, he is dead. I <orig reg="gave"
                    >give</orig> him nothing at all. I had two brothers in the Union Army, W<hi
                        rend="super">m</hi>. L. Rowsey &amp; Sam<hi rend="super"
                    >l</hi>. J. Rowsey. W<hi rend="super">m</hi> is dead and Samuel lives in
                    Kanawha Valley W. Va.</p>
                <p>Ques. 31 Ans. I never owned any bonds nor had <orig reg="an">a</orig> interest in
                    them.</p>
                <p>32 Ans. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> any aid or comfort to the Rebellion</p>
                <p>33 Ans. I never engaged in making raids from any place or for any purpose.</p>
                <p>34 Ans. I never was engaged in holding any person as prisoners of War, for any
                    cause.</p>
                <p>35 Ans. I never belonged to any society or association for any purpose whatever.</p>
                <p>36 Ans. I never was a paroled prisoner.</p>
                <p>37 Ans. I never held any office, and was not educated in any Military or Naval
                    School.</p>
                <p>38 Ans. I never had a pass at all.</p>
                <p>39 Ans. I was under no disabilities. I have not held any Office since the War.</p>
                <p>40 Ans. My Sympathies were all the time with the Union cause. My feelings were
                    bitter toward secession. My influence was exerted against Secession. I did not
                    vote for the ratification of the Ordinance of Secession, after its adoption I
                    still adhered to the Union.</p>
                <p>Ques. 41 Ans. I do solemnly declare that from the beginning of hostilities
                    against the United States to the end thereof, my sympathies were constantly with
                    the cause of the United States; and that I never of my own free will and accord
                    did any thing, or offered or sought or attempted to do anything by word or deed
                    to injure said cause or retard its success, and I was ready at all times when
                    called upon, or if called upon to aid and assist the cause of the Union or its
                    supporters so far as my means and power and the circumstances of the case
                    permitted. I <add hand="h1" place="inline">have</add> never been in Bankruptcy.</p>
                <p>I was not present when my property was taken. I saw the Army when at my house. My
                    Shop was on the road leading from Staunton to Lexington. It was General Hunter's
                    Army. I think it was on the 11th day of June 1864, about 9 Oclock A.M. I did not
                    see anything taken. The only one present and saw them taking the property was my
                    wife, Amanda F. Rowsey.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Kilburn H Rowsey Jr</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Sidney M. Campbell</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Sidney M. Campbell.</p>
                <p>Answer to general question.</p>
                <p>My name is Sidney M Campbell, my age is 40 years. My residence Moffetts Creek
                    Augusta Co. Va. My occupation a School Teacher. I am not related to the claimant
                    and have no interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant since 1845. I did not know <add hand="h1" place="inline">him</add> during the
                    War, as I was in W. Va. most of the time. I never met with him during the War. I
                    met with him during the War. I met with him in 1868, and had a <orig
                        reg="conversation">conservation</orig> with him in reference to the war.
                    Subsequently I learned from him that he was a member of the "U.H. of K of A"
                    Society, and had taken the first degree in the society, and from that I knew
                    that he must have <add hand="h1" place="inline">been</add> a loyal man during the rebellion, as it was
                    conferred on no one but loyal men, and since my acquaintance with him, I have
                    found him acting invariably with the Republican party, when an <orig
                        reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> presented though surrounded with
                    difficulties, which prevented him from doing much.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Sidney M. Campbell</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Anderson Hutchens</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Anderson Hutchens.</p>
                <p>Answer to general Question.</p>
                <p>My name is Anderson Hutchens, my age is 40 years. My residence is Moffett's
                    Creek, Augusta Co. Va. by occupation a farmer.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant since the close of the War. I did not know him during
                    the War. I believe from what I have seen of him that he was a loyal man during
                    the War, and since my acquaintance with him, he has invariably cooperated with
                    the Union party in all elections, which satisifies me that he was <del hand="h1">a</del>
                    loyal during the war, for a man to cooperate with that party in the South, since
                    would have to have as strong a nerve as to be a Union man during the War. I have
                    never heard his loyalty doubted by any one, and is regarded by all the Democrats
                    in the neighborhood as an uncompromising Radical.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Anderson Hutchens</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Amanda F. Rowsey</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Amanda F. Rowsey.</p>
                <p>Answer to first general question.</p>
                <p>My name is Amanda F. Rowsey, my age is 43 years. I reside at Moffetts Creek. I am
                    the wife of the claimant.</p>
                <p>I was present <add hand="h1" place="inline">when</add> the property charged in claimants account was
                    taken. I saw the Articles taken by the Army. My husband had locked the door of
                    his shop, and when the Army stopped the soldiers broke the door down, and took
                    the tools from the Shop and put them into the Wagons. It was in the month of
                    June 1864. I do not recollect the day. I did not hear the name of the General.
                    It was a very large Army. There were a number of Soldiers engaged in carrying
                    the tools out of the Shop to the wagons, I suppose they were about half an hour
                    in removing the tools. I saw a number of Officers present but heard no names. I
                    did not hear any thing said, I did not hold any conversation with any one in the
                    Army. The Army was marching toward Lexington and coming from the direction of
                    Staunton. There had not been any battle in the neighborhood that I recollect of.
                    I made no complaint to any one, and did not ask for any receipt. There was no
                    one present except my children. The tools were taken about 10 Oclock A.M. All
                    taken openly as though it belonged to them. There was no encampment. The Army
                    merely halted a short time. The tools were all in good condition, so was the
                    Saddle and bridles.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Amanday F Rowsey</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Claimant's Brief on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS.</p>
                <p>KILBOURN H. ROWSEY, vs. THE UNITED STATES. 8608 Congressional.</p>
                <p>CLAIMANT'S BRIEF ON LOYALTY.</p>
                <p>This claim originated in Augusta County, Virginia. It was originally filed before
                    the Commissioners of Claims, who did not pass on the question of claimant's
                    loyalty but rejected the claim because the proof of the taking property was not
                    satisfactory.</p>
                <p>The testimony which was before the Commissioners, having been taken in May 1874,
                    on the question of loyalty was as follows:</p>
                <p>KILBOURN H. ROWSBY, the claimant, testifies: Residence Moffett's Creek, Augusta
                    County, Va. (Page l). Blacksmith. During the war resided part of the time in
                    Rockbridge County, Virginia, part of the time in Clarksburg and Martinsburg,
                    West Virginia, and part of the time in Augusta County, Virginia. Never passed
                    beyond the lines of the United States into the rebel lines, but was in the rebel
                    lines when the war commenced. Was forced to take an oath as a citizen of
                    Virginia. The Militia were called out and required to take the oath or be sent
                    to Richmond. Does not recollect the purport of the oath. Took the amnesty oath
                    prescribed by the President's proclamation at Clarksburg, West Virginia, October
                    28th 1864. Never asked for any pardon. (Questions 6, 7, 8, 10, 11 &amp; 12
                    answered favorably to loyalty). Was called out as a member of the Militia;
                    remained a few days only at Lexington, Virginia and returned to his home. (Page
                    2). Was conscripted but did not go into service. (Questions 14 to 21 inclusive,
                    answered favorably to loyalty Page 3). Left the Confederate lines on October
                    18th 1864. Went to Beverly, West Virginia, then to Clarksburg, West Virginia.
                    Left because of his opposition to the cause. Did not return until in 1865, after
                    the war closed. Worked in Martinsburg at his trade and was in the employment of
                    the United States Government. Was never arrested by either Confederate or United
                    States authorities. Never had any property taken by Confederate authorities.
                    Some threats were wade by citizens and neighbors to send him to Richmond
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">to</add> Castle Thunder; never was arrested on account of his Union
                    sentiments. Never contributed anything in aid of the United States or the Union
                    army. Never did anything in aid of the Confederate Government or army. Had a
                    brother, J. R. Rowsey now dead, who was in the Confederate army. Gave him
                    nothing at all. Had two brothers William L., and Samuel J. Rowsey in the Union
                    army. William L., is now dead. Samuel J. lives in Kanawha Valley, West Virginia.
                    (Page 4). (Questions 31 to 37 inclusive answered favorably to loyalty). Never
                    took passes from Confederate authorities. Asked for no pardons because he was
                    under no disabilities. Has not held any office since the war. His sympathies all
                    the time were with the Union cause. His feelings were bitter toward secession.
                    His influence was exerted against secession. Did not vote for the ratification
                    of the ordinance of secession. After the adoption of the ordinance, still
                    adhered to the Union. (Page 5). His sympathies were constantly with the cause of
                    the Union States, and he did not of his own free will do or attempt to do
                    anything against that cause but was ready at all times to aid it or its
                    supporters so far as his means and power and the circumstances permitted. (Page
                    6).</p>
                <p>SIDNEY M. CAMPBELL testifies. Age 40 years. Residence Moffett's Creek, Augusta
                    County, Virginia. Not related to the claimant or interested in the claim. Has
                    known claimant since 1845. Did not know him during the war, being in West
                    Virginia most of the time. Never met him during the war. Met him in 1868 and had
                    a conversation with in reference to the war. Subsequently learned from him that
                    he was a member of <add hand="h1" place="inline">the "U. H. of K. of A"</add> Society and had taken the
                    first degree in the Society. From that know he must have been a loyal man during
                    the <orig reg="rebellion">re-rebellion</orig>, as membership in this society was
                    conferred on none but loyal men. Since becoming acquainted with claimant has
                    found him invariably acting with the Republican Party when an opportunity
                        presented<orig reg=",">,.</orig> though surrounded with difficulties which
                    prevented <add hand="h1" place="inline">him</add> from doing much.</p>
                <p>ANDERSON HUTCHENS testifies. Age 40 years. Residence Moffett's Creek, Augusta
                    County, Virginia (Page 7). Has known claimant since the close of the war; did
                    not know him during the war. Believes from what he has seen of claimant that he
                    was a loyal man during the war. Since the deponent's acquaintance with him he
                    has invariably cooperated with the Union Party in all directions, which
                    satisfies deponent that he was loyal during the war, for to cooperate with the
                    Union Party in the South required as strong a nerve as to be a Union man during
                    the war. Has never heard claimant's loyalty doubted by any one. He is regarded
                    by all the Democrats in the neighborhood as an uncomprising radical.</p>
                <p>Under the rules of this Court, viz. in December 1899, claimant was again examined
                    and an additional deposition was taken in his behalf. This testimony is as
                    follows:</p>
                <p>WILLIAM H. KELLY testifies. Age 56 years. Residence Parkersburg, Virginia. Not
                    related or interested in the claim. (Page l). Resided during the war at Flumen,
                    Rockbridge County, Virginia. Was intimately acquainted with claimant; resided
                    half a mile from him; met him often. Claimant expressed himself in favor of the
                    Union all the time of the war. Cannot tell of anything claimant did in favor of
                    the Union cause except that he kept out of the Confederate army. (Page 2). The
                    public reputation of claimant was that he was a Union man. Witness was a Union
                    man and loyal to the United States. Does not know of claimant being arrested,
                    injured or threatened on account of his loyalty. Claimant exerted his influence
                    in favor of the Union. Does not know how he voted. (Page 3).</p>
                <p>KILBOURN H. ROWSEY, the claimant, testifies. Went through the Union lines in
                    October 1864 to Clarksburg, West Virginia. Never took an oath to support the
                    Confederacy. Was never connected with the civil or military service of the
                    Confederacy. Never furnished a substitute for the Confederate army. Never
                    voluntarily gave aid to the Confederacy. When conscripted went through the Union
                    lines to Clarksburg. Was threatened but was never arrested by Confederate
                    authorities. (Page 4).</p>
                <p>SUMMARY.</p>
                <p>This evidence <orig reg="is">in</orig> entirely in claimant's favor, just as the
                    Commissioners of Claims evidently thought that part of it was which was before
                    then. Claimant, according to his own testimony, was strongly opposed to
                    secession from the outset and during the war remained true to the Union, having
                    no part or lot with the rebellion. Presumably he did not have a vote at all on
                    the ratification of the ordinance of secession; he testifies that he did not
                    vote for the ordinance. (Page 4 sup.). The surroundings at his home in the
                    valley of Virginia were so uncongenial that in October 1864 he went through the
                    Federal lines into loyal territory, where he remained intil after the close of
                    the war. At Martinsburg, West Virginia, he was in the employ of the United
                    States Government. (Pages 2 &amp; 3 sup.).</p>
                <p>Of the two brothers of claimant two were in the Federal army and one in the
                    Confederate army, and he gave no assistance to this one who was in the
                    Confederate army. (Page 3 sup.).</p>
                <p>It appears that at the outbreak of the war claimant as a member of the State
                    Militia took some sort of oath either to the Confederacy or to Virginia, but he
                    was required to do this, it appears, in order that he might remain at home and
                    not be sent into the service at Richmond. (Page 2 sup.). The witnesses Campbell
                    and Hutchens testify that they knew claimant soon after the war and that at that
                    time and since he has belonged to the party of which the chief tradition, in
                    that part of the country, was loyalty to the Union. at the time of its struggle
                    for existence. Campbell states that claimant belonged to a society in which a
                    condition of membership was loyalty to the Union during the war.</p>
                <p>William H. Kelly, examined under the rules of this Court, testifies that he lived
                    within half a mile of claimant during the war and that claimant then often
                    expressed himself to him as in favor of the Union, and that he exerted his
                    influence in favor of the Union; also that his reputation was that of a Union
                    man.</p>
                <p>There was no jurisdictional need of any new evidence on loyalty in this case. The
                    new evidence, however, with the old, puts the case beyond doubt and calls for a
                    finding of loyalty.</p>
                <p>Respectfully submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> Attorney for
                    Claimant.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Defendant's Brief on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS OF THE UNITED STATES.</p>
                <p>Kilbourn H. Rowsey v. THE UNITED STATES. No. 8608 Cong.</p>
                <p>DEFENDANT'S BRIEF ON LOYALTY.</p>
                <p>The abstract of testimony prepared by claimant's counsel is substantially
                    correct. The records of the War Department do not shed any light on the question
                    of claimant's loyalty. He claims that his sympathies were at the time with the
                    Union fellows, and that he exerted his influence against secession, but says
                    nothing about how he voted at the first election. He says, however, that he did
                    not vote for the ratification of the ordinance of secession. (Page 4, claimant's
                    brief.) He had two brothers in the Union army and one brother in the Confederate
                    army. (Page 3, claimant's brief.) Was never arrested by either army. He claims,
                    however, that some threats were made by citizens and neighbors (whom he does not
                    name) to send him to Richmond. Says he never did anything in aid of the
                    Confederate government or army. (Page 3, claimant's brief.) That he was
                    conscripted, but did not go into the confederate service. (Page 2, claimant's
                    brief.) It will be noticed that he makes no explanation of his important matter.
                    How did he escape service after he was conscripted? According to the testimony
                    he left the confederate lines on October 18, 1864, and went to Beverly, W. Va.,
                    and thence to Clarksburg, in the same state. He claims to have left because of
                    his opposition to the cause, and that he did not return until after the war
                    closed in 1865. That while at Martinsburg he worked at his trade and was in the
                    employment of the United States government. He furnishes no particulars. This
                    portion of his testimony is not corroborated by any other witness, and rests
                    entirely upon the statements of the claimant.</p>
                <p>The claimant was a member of the Virginia militia at the time the war broke out,
                    and claims that he was forced to take an oath as a citizen of Virginia or be
                    sent to Richmond, but does not recollect the purport of the oath. It may be here
                    remarked that there can be little question but that the oath taken was an oath
                    of allegiance to the confederate government. He claims that he was called out as
                    a member of the militia, and remained a few days only at Lexington, Va., and
                    then returned to his home. (Page 2, claimant's brief.) He fails to state what he
                    and his comrades in arms were doing at Lexington, Va., during this time in which
                    the militia was called into service, and it is submitted that this service of
                    the claimant weighs somewhat against his loyalty. As to whether it is sufficient
                    to defeat jurisdiction, is for the court to say.</p>
                <p>The supporting testimony is not particularly strong or impressive. Witness Sidney
                    D. Campbell (pp. 4 &amp; 5) states that he has known the claimant since
                    1845, <hi rend="underline">but did not know him during the war</hi>, and never
                    met him during the war, and claims to have met him in 1868, and had a <orig
                        reg="conversation">conersation</orig> with <orig reg="him">im</orig> in
                    reference to the war, and that he subsequently learned from the clamant that he
                    was a member of the "U. H. of K. of A." society (whatever that may mean), and
                    had taken the first degree in the society. This witness claims that membership
                    in this society was conferred on none but loyal men. It may be remarked that the
                    testimony of the preceding witness sheds no light upon the subject of the
                    claimant's loyalty during the war, inasmuch as the witness admits that he did
                    not see him during the war or until after the war was over. The next witness is
                    in the same predicament. Anderson <orig reg="Hutchens">Hutchins</orig> (pp. 5
                    &amp; 6) claimant's brief, for he states that he did not know him during the
                    war, but believes that he was a loyal man during the war because he has
                    cooperated with the Union party since the war. The testimony of William H. Kelly
                    (p. 6, claimant's brief) is to the effect that he resided half a mile from the
                    claimant during the war and met him often, and that claimant expressed himself
                    in favor of the Union all the time during the war. That he cannot give anything
                    that the claimant did in favor of the Union, except to keep out of the
                    confederate army. He states that his public reputation was that of a Union man.
                    This witness claims to have been loyal. He does not know of claimant's being
                    arrested, injured or threatened on account of his loyalty; does not know how he
                    voted.</p>
                <p>The claimant, in his testimony under the rules, states that when he was
                    conscripted he went through the Union lines to Clarksburg. This seems to have
                    been, according to his first testimony, on Oct. 14, 1864. His status betwen 1861
                    and 1864 does not seem to be clearly or satisfactorily covered by the testimony,
                    which is scant and weak. And as stated before whether or not the imputation of
                    disloyalty which arises in the case, by reason of the claimant's having taken
                    the oath to support the confederacy and served for a time with the militia at
                    Lexington, is outweighed by the testimony favorable to the claimant's loyalty,
                    is left for the consideration and determination of the court.</p>
                <p>Respectfully submitted: <name type="other">Franklin W. Collins</name><hi
                        rend="super">Special</hi><del hand="h1">Assistant</del> Attorney.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>Reply to Defendant's Brief on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS.</p>
                <p>KILBOURN H. ROWSEY, VS. THE UNITED STATES. No. 8608 Congressional.</p>
                <p>REPLY TO DEFENDANT'S BRIEF ON LOYALTY.</p>
                <p>Defendant's counsel delas very fairly with the testimony in support of this case,
                    with the exception of his statement that the "status of the claimant between
                    1861 and 1864 does not seen: to be clearly or satisfactorily covered by the
                    testimony, which is scant and weak." This position is controverted. The
                    testimony of the claimant shows that from the commencement to the close of the
                    war his sympathies were constantly with the Union cause; that he never did
                    anything in aid of the rebellion. He further states that threats were made by
                    citizens and neighbors to send him to Richmond, to Castle Thunder. This shows
                    very clearly that he was considered a Union man by his disloyal neighbors. He
                    furthermore states that he never gave any aid or comfort to the rebellion. His
                    not voting for the ratification of the Ordinance of Secession is strong evidence
                    of loyalty.</p>
                <p>Mr. William H. Kelly, who was intimate with the claimant during the war, and
                    lived a near neighbor to him, only half a mile distant, says that the claimant
                    expressed himself in favor of the Union all the time throughout the war, and his
                    public reputation was that of a Union man. This witness was also a Union man and
                    loyal to the United States. Says that claimant at the outset exerted his
                    influence against secession and in favor of the Union, so there is some proof
                    and very convincing proof that the claimant was loyal from the commencement all
                    the way through.</p>
                <p>The defence relies mainly, however, on the testimony showing that the claimant
                    took some kind of an oath about the commencement of the war, but it is evident
                    that he was forced to take this oath as a citizen of the State of Virginia. The
                    militia it seems were called out and required to take the oath or be sent to
                    Richmond. For all that appears in proof this may have been, and in all
                    probability was, the "Non-combatants" oath, that is that he as one of the
                    militia would not take up arms against the Confederacy. Claimant states that he
                    never took an oath to support the Confederacy, (page 7, original brief). So it
                    appears that defendant's counsel is mistaken in asserting that claimant took an
                    oath to support the Confederacy. There is nothing in the testimony that
                    justifies such a conclusion.</p>
                <p>Respectfully Submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> Attorney for
                    Claimant.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                
                <byline>Claimant's Request for Findings of Fact</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS. December Term 1902-1903.</p>
                <p>KILBOURN H. ROWSEY, vs. THE UNITED STATES. No. 8608 Congressional.</p>
                <p>CLAIMANT'S REQUESTS FOR FINDINGS OF FACT.</p>
                <p>The Claimant considering the facts hereinafter set forth to be proven and deeming
                    them material to the due presentation of this case in the findings of fact,
                    requests the Court to find the same as follows, to-wit:-</p>
                <p>I. The Claimant, Kilbourn H. Rowsey, resided during the late war for the
                    suppression of the Rebellion in the County of Augusta, State of Virginia, and
                    remained throughout said war loyal to the Government of the United States. See:-
                    Loyalty finding, filed May 25, 1903.</p>
                <p>II. During said war, there were taken from the Claimant by the United States
                    Military forces, acting under proper authority, and converted to the use of the
                    United States Army, Quartermaster supplies of the kinds and values, below
                    stated, as follows, to-wit:-</p>
                <p>2 Complete Sets Blacksmith steel tools, good, $200.00.</p>
                <p>1 Complete Set of Blacksmith steel tools, old, 40.00.</p>
                <p>1 Lot of 100 horseshoes and 1000 nails, 20.00.</p>
                <p>1 Lot of Drawing Knives, Saws and Chisels, 4.50.</p>
                <p>2 Screw Plates, 20.00.</p>
                <p>200 lbs of Steel at 25 cents per lb, 50.00.</p>
                <p>300 lbs. Wrought Iron at 5 cents per lb, 15.00.</p>
                <p>1 Saddle and 2 Bridles, 15.00.</p>
                <p>Total, $364.50.</p>
                <p>See:-Testimony of Kilbourn H. Rowsey, P. 2, Abstract; Amanda F. Rowsey, Pg. 2
                    Abstract; Kilbourn H. Rowsey, Ps. 3 tp 5, Abstract; Amanda F. Rowsey, P. 6,
                    Abstracts; GENERAL REMARKS, Ps. 6 to 7.</p>
                <p>III. No payment appears to have been made for said property or any part thereof.</p>
                <p>Respectfully submitted, <name type="other">Moyers &amp; Consaul</name>
                    Attorneys for Claimant.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                
                <byline>Claimant's Brief on Merits</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS. December Term 1902-1903.</p>
                <p>KILBOURN H. ROWSEY. vs. THE UNITED STATES. No. 8608 Congressional.</p>
                <p>STATEMENT.</p>
                <p>This claim in the sum of $471.00 for blacksmith tools, steel, iron, etc., arose
                    in the County of Augusta, State of Virginia. It was presented to the
                    Commissioners of Claims and was by them rejected. It was referred to this
                    Honorable Court under the provisions of the Bowman Act by the Committee on War
                    Claims of the House of Representatives on May 26, 1892. On May 25, 1903, loyalty
                    was found and the case is now before the Court upon the issue of merits.</p>
                <p>CLAIMANT'S BRIEF ON MERITS.</p>
                <p>This claim is for the following property alleged to have been taken by the
                    Federal troops under command of General Hunter about June 10, 1864:-</p>
                <p>2 Complete Sets Blacksmith steel tools, $200.00.</p>
                <p>1 Complete Set of Blacksmith steel tools, old, 40.00.</p>
                <p>1 Lot of 100 horseshoes and 1000 nails, 20.00.</p>
                <p>1 Lot of Drawing Knives, saws and chisels, 4.50.</p>
                <p>2 Screw Plates, 20.00.</p>
                <p>200 lbs of Steel at 25 cents per lb, 50.00.</p>
                <p>300 lbs. Wrought Iron at 5 cents per lb, 15.00.</p>
                <p>1 Saddle and 2 Bridles, 15.00.</p>
                <p>Total, $364.50.</p>
                <p>The following testimony was taken at Staunton, Virginia, on May 23, 1874, while
                    the claim was pending before the Commissioners of Claims:-</p>
                <p>KILB0URN H. ROWSEY, JR., testified: Claimant. Age: 43 years. Residence: Moffett's
                    Creek, Augusta County, Virginia. Occupation: Blacksmith (P. 1). Resided part of
                    the time during the in Rockbridge County, Virginia; also in Clarksburg and
                    Martinsburg, West Virginia, and also in Augusta County, Virginia. (P. 2). Left
                    Confederate lines October, 1864, and went to Beverly, West Virginia; thence to
                    Clarksburg, West Virginia, thence to Martinsburg. Worked at my trade there in
                    employ of the United States Government. (P. 4). I was not present when my
                    property was taken. I saw the army when at my house. My shop was on the road
                    leading from Staunton to Lexington. It was General Hunter's army. I think it was
                    June 11, 1864, at about 9:00 A.M. I did not see anything taken. The only one
                    present who saw them taking the property was my wife, Amanda F. Rowsey. (P. 6).</p>
                <p>AMANDA F. ROWSEY testified: Age: 43 years. Residence: Moffett's Creek, Virginia.
                    Wife of Claimant. Was present when property charged for in claim was taken. I
                    saw the articles taken by the army. My husband had locked the door of his shop
                    and when the army stopped here the (P. 8) soldiers broke down the doors and took
                    the tools from the shop and put them into their wagons. It was in June, 1864; do
                    not recollect the day. Did not hear the name of the General. It was a very large
                    farm. A number of soldiers were engaged in carrying the tools out of the shop to
                    the wagons. Suppose they were about one-half hour in removing the tools. Saw a
                    number of officers present but heard no names. Heard nothing said and had no
                    conversation with any one of them. The army was marching toward Lexington and
                    came from Staunton. No battle in the neighborhood that I recollect. I made no
                    complaint and asked for no receipt. No one was present except my children. The
                    tools were taken about 10:00 A.M., openly, as though the property belonged to
                    them. There was no camp here; the army merely halted a short time. The tools
                    were all in good condition and so was the saddle and so were the bridles. (P.
                    9).</p>
                <p>The following testimony was taken at Greenville, Augusta County, Virginia,
                    September 15, 1903:-</p>
                <p>KILBOURN H. ROWSEY testified: Age: 71 years. Occupation: Blacksmith. Residence:
                    Greenville Virginia. Am the Claimant. I lived at Cedar Grove, Rockbridge County,
                    Virginia, during the late Civil war. Was engaged in blacksmithing when the
                    Federal troops came. I kept two hands. It was the only blacksmith shop in the
                    place. I had two sets of tools in my shop, which I bought in Baltimore about
                    1858. Had two sets of everything; bellows, anvils, vises, screw plates, sledges,
                    punches, hammers, tongs, (P. 2) in fact, everything for use in a regular
                    blacksmith shop.</p>
                <p>There was about 300 pounds of hammered iron in the shop at the time. Also about
                    200 pounds of steel.</p>
                <p>There was a lot of about 1000 horseshoe nails and fully 100 horseshoes. My rack
                    held that many and I think it was full. Do not remember anything else in the
                    shop except a pair of heavy steelyards.</p>
                <p>Besides the above, I had a saddle and two bridles at the house, hanging out on
                    the porch.</p>
                <p>The blacksmith tools I paid $200.00 and believe them to have been worth that when
                    the army came.</p>
                <p>The 200 pounds of steel cost and was worth 25 cents per pound, or $50.00 in all.</p>
                <p>The iron was worth 5 cents per pound, or $15.00. (P. 3). The saddle cost me
                    $20.00 and was worth at the time about $15.00. I had it about two years and had
                    used it but little. The bridles were nearly new and worth about $5.00 together.</p>
                <p>I had three sets of blacksmith tools, but one was an old set, not worth to exceed
                    $40.00.</p>
                <p>I had a set of drawing knives, saws and chisels, worth $4.50 all told.</p>
                <p>The Federal army came to Cedar Grove June 10, 1864. General Hunter was in command
                    and said to have about 25,000 soldiers. They had a battle there on the evening
                    of June 9, 1864. I was right between the two fires. McCauslin's troops engaged
                    Hunter's. The Confederates left that evening (P. 4) and the Federal army left
                    next day. I did not see my property taken. I <add hand="h1" place="inline">was</add> hunting for Dr.
                    Killory and L. M. Humphries, who had run away from the fight and had not
                    returned. They had been out all night and their wives wanted me to look them up.
                    That is why I was not present when my property was taken. I went away about
                    sunrise and came back about 7:00 A.M. The Federal troops had not gotten to my
                    shop when I went away. I locked it when I left. When I returned, I found nothing
                    there. The blacksmith tools above mentioned, were all gone, also the iron and
                    steel and saddle and bridles. (P. 5). The Confederates did not take any of the
                    property. I know this because I was right there when McCauslin went away. Nobody
                    but my wife saw the property taken, except the Federal soldiers themselves. (P.
                    6).</p>
                <p>AMANDA F. ROWSEY testified: Age: 71 years. Occupation: Housekeeper Wife of
                    Claimant. Was living with my husband, the Claimant, in Cedar Grove, Virginia.
                    The house was about 50 yards from the blacksmith shop. I was present, when the
                    Battle took place between the Union troops and Confederates,-on our porch. The
                    next day after the battle, our property was taken. I saw it taken. Think it was
                    in the afternoon. My husband was on the river, taking something to eat for two
                    who ran away when the Battle came on. He also wanted to get them to come home.
                    They were close neighbors of ours. I saw the property taken by the Yankees. They
                    took it all from the shop. They took a saddle and bridle; it seems to me they
                    took two bridles. The soldiers that came to the house had on blue clothes; also
                    those who took the property from the shop. No Confederates came to the house.
                    (P. 8).</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">GENERAL</hi><hi rend="underline">REMARKS</hi>.</p>
                <p>In view of the fact that all of this property charged for was taken at one time
                    and amounts all told to only $364.50, we do not deem it necessary to incorporate
                    in this brief, an itemized summary.</p>
                <p>Mrs. Rowsey, Claimant's wife, has testified positively to actually seeing the
                    property taken by the Federal troops. Mr. Rowsey knew that the property was
                    there an hour or two prior to the arrival of the Federal troops and was
                    painfully aware of the fact that it was gone after the Federal troops had left.
                    It is shown that no one else was present when this property was taken, save Mrs.
                    Rowsey. In view of this fact, we submit that the evidence adduced in this case,
                    should in reason be considered as sufficient to warrant an allowance as prayed.
                    It is obvious that the prices charged are very reasonable and there is
                    absolutely nothing in the record to cast the least suspicion upon the good faith
                    of the Claimant. It will be borne in mind that he presented this claim as soon
                    as possible to the Southern Claims Commission and has always exercised all
                    possible diligence in continuing the prosecution of his claim.</p>
                <p>We think that your Honors will agree with us that an allowance should be made in
                    this case as follows, to-wit:-</p>
                <p>2 Complete Sets Blacksmith steel tools, good, $200.00.</p>
                <p>1 Complete Set of Blacksmith steel tools, old, 40.00.</p>
                <p>1 Lot of 100 horseshoes and 1000 nails, 20.00.</p>
                <p>1 Lot of Drawing Knives, Saws and Chisels, 4.50.</p>
                <p>2 Screw Plates, 20.00.</p>
                <p>200 lbs of Steel at 25 cents per lb, 50.00.</p>
                <p>300 lbs. Wrought Iron at 5 cents per lb, 15.00.</p>
                <p>1 Saddle and 2 Bridles, 15.00.</p>
                <p>Total, $364.50.</p>
                <p>Respectfully submitted, <name type="other">Moyers &amp; Consaul</name>
                    Attorneys for Claimant.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                
                <byline>Defendant's Brief on Merits</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS OF THE UNITED STATES. DECEMBER TERM, 1902-1903.</p>
                <p>Kilbourn H. Rowsey v. THE UNITED STATES. No. 8,608, Cong.</p>
                <p>DEFENDANT'S BRIEF ON MERITS.</p>
                <p>The claimant herein asks the court for a finding in his behalf to the effect that
                    certain property was taken and appropriated by the Federal troops, under the
                    command of Gen. Hunter, about June 10, 1864, said property belonging to the
                    claimant, and taken from his blacksmith shop and house at Cedar Grove,
                    Rockbridge County, Virginia, said property consisting of the following items:</p>
                <p>2 Complete Sets Blacksmith steel tools, $200.00.</p>
                <p>1 Complete Set of Blacksmith steel tools, old, 40.00.</p>
                <p>1 Lot of 100 horseshoes and 1000 nails, 20.00.</p>
                <p>1 Lot of Drawing Knives, saws and chisels, 4.50.</p>
                <p>2 Screw Plates, 20.00.</p>
                <p>200 lbs of Steel at 25 cents per lb, 50.00.</p>
                <p>300 lbs. Wrought Iron at 5 cents per lb, 15.00.</p>
                <p>1 Saddle and 2 Bridles, 15.00.</p>
                <p>Total, $864.50.</p>
                <p>The proofs presented in support of the above claim are quite meagre in quantity,
                    they being confined to the testimony of the claimant and his wife. They are
                    correctly abstracted in claimant's brief.</p>
                <p>The claimant himself was absent from home at the time of the actual taking of the
                    property, and the proof as to the taking are confined to the testimony of his
                    wife, Amanda F. Rowsey. As corroborative of her statement, however, that the
                    Federal troops did take the property in question (which she claims to have
                    seen), the claimant himself states that the Confederates had been there before
                    the Federals came, but did not take any of the property; that he was there when
                    the Confederate General went away; that a battle had been fought near his place
                    between the Union forces and the Confederates (see pp. 4 and 5, claimant's
                    brief), on the evening of June 9, 1864, and that McCauslin's troops engaged
                    Hunter's; that the Confederates left that evening (p. 4, testimony), and that
                    the Federal Army left the next day. That he (claimant) was out hunting for two
                    neighbors who had run away from the fight and had not returned; that their wives
                    wanted him to look them up; that that is the reason he was not present when his
                    property was taken; that he went away about sunrise, and came back about seven
                    a.m., and that the Federal troops had not gotten to his shop when he went away;
                    that he looked it up when he left, and when he returned he found nothing there.</p>
                <p>The testimony of Amanda P. Rowsey, which is abstracted on pages five and six of
                    claimant's "brief, shows her presence there when the property was taken,
                    although her testimony is somewhat deficient in detail. She does not enter into
                    a description of the property which she saw taken, but corroborates her husband
                    with regard to the facts relating to his absence.</p>
                <p>It may be remarked, for the information of the court, that the reason the
                    testimony of this witness was not brought out in greater detail was due to the
                    fact that at the time her testimony was taken she was in very feeble health, and
                    probably undergoing her last illness. It was with great difficulty that her
                    testimony could be taken at all.</p>
                <p>The claimant testifies, however, as to the items of property which he had in his
                    shop, such <add hand="h1" place="inline">testimony</add> being that abstracted on pages three to five of
                    claimant's brief. The property in question had probably deteriorated somewhat by
                    reason of age and use, and, it may be, the values given by the claimant should
                    be scaled somewhat.</p>
                <p>Respectfully submitted. <name type="other">F.W. Collins</name> Special
                Attorney.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
