<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0512"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0512">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John A. Mann,
                    1874, Claim No. 20294</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john a mann, 1874 claim no 20294</title>
        <author>Mann, John A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 24 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0512</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498399</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John A. Mann, 1874,
                            Claim No. 20294</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john a mann, 1874 claim no 20294</title>
            <author>John A. Mann</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8614</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1874">1874</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Patriotism, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0512T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John A. Mann filed this claim in 1874 for $982.05, claiming the Union army under
                    General Sheridan's command took various goods (including corn, flour, hay,
                    tobacco, rye, bacon, beef, molassas, vinegar, coffee pots, kettles, buckets,
                    crocks, and bags) in 1865. John was a 45 year old merhcant in Waynesboro who was
                    totally blind. The claim was disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>10 Barrels of Flour</cell>
                            <cell>$80.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$80.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 tons of Hay</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>23 Bushels of Corn</cell>
                            <cell>$23.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$23.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 1/2 Bushels of Rye</cell>
                            <cell>$2.50</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$2.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>250 lbs. of Bacon</cell>
                            <cell>$31.50</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$31.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>200 lbs of Beef</cell>
                            <cell>$16.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$16.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>15 Gallons of Molasses (deducted)</cell>
                            <cell>our</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>out</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>55 Gallons of Vinegar</cell>
                            <cell>$18.33 1/3</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$18.33 1/3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>224 lbs of Tobacco</cell>
                            <cell>$168.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$168.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>4 boxes No. 98. 99. 101. 102 lbs in all 400 lbs</cell>
                            <cell>$340.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$340.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Box of 60 lbs</cell>
                            <cell>$48.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$48.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Box of 40 lbs of extra Grandey</cell>
                            <cell>$54.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$54.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Box of smoking 240 lbs</cell>
                            <cell>$144.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$144.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>4 Coffee Potts Tin</cell>
                            <cell>$3.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$3.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>3 Brass camp Kettles (2 1/2, 3, &amp; 4 Gates each)</cell>
                            <cell>$7.50</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$7.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 Tin pans &amp; 3 Tin Buckets</cell>
                            <cell>$3.12 1/2</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$3.12 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>28 New Crocks</cell>
                            <cell>$3.50</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$3.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>24 Bags</cell>
                            <cell>$9.60</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$9.60</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>The claimant resided in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> throughout the war, was totally blind. His
                    business was merchandising. The testimony fails to satisfy us that he remined
                    loyal to the union cause. There is no doubt whatever had the Confederacy
                    succeeded he could have proved his loyalty to it by scores of witnesses. He
                    voted to ratify the ordinance of secession. There was no necessity for this.
                    Nobody would have harmed this blind man if he had stayed at home &amp; not
                    voted at all. Such was the course pursued by many persons opposed to secession
                    and they were not harmed. One of his own witnesses says "I do not know whether
                    he was strictly a Union man or not." The claim is disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>John A. Mann</byline>
                <p>My name is <hi rend="underline">John A. Mann</hi>, my age <hi rend="underline"
                    >45</hi> years, my residence <hi rend="underline">Waynesboro Augusta <abbr
                            expan="County">Co</abbr></hi>, in the State of <hi rend="underline"
                        >Virginia</hi>, and my occupation a <hi rend="underline">Merchant</hi>; I am
                        <del hand="h1">related to</del> the claimant, and have beneficial interest in the
                    claim.</p>
                <p>Ques. 2. Ans. I resided in Waynesboro Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> during the whole of the war. My occupation was a
                    Merchant. Made no change in my residence or business.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Ans. I did not pass out or in.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4. Ans. I never took an oath of any description to the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 5. Ans. I took an amnesty oath in Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr> after the war closed. I never asked for a pardon.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6. Ans. I never was in any manner connected with the civil service of the
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 7. Ans. I never held any place of trust, honor or profit under the
                    Confederate government, State or territory.</p>
                <p>Ques. 8. Ans. I never held any clerkship, agency or employment of any kind.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9. Ans. I never was in any capacity in the military service of the
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10. Ans. I never was an officer or soldier in the Confederate Army.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11. Ans. I never belonged to the State <orig reg="Militia">Malitia</orig>.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12. Ans. I never was in the home guard, or vigilance Committee, or
                    committee of safety.</p>
                <p>Ques. 13. Ans. I was not conscripted.</p>
                <p>Ques. 14. Ans. I furnished no substitute.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15. Ans. I had no connection with any department of the Confederate
                    government or army.</p>
                <p>Ques. 16. Ans. I never was employed in any railroad, nor engaged in the
                    transportation of soldiers or anything also for the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 17. Ans. I never had charge of any supplies or stores, teams, Wagons, or of
                    any thing whatever.</p>
                <p>Ques. 18. Ans. I never was in any service, employment or business of any kind,
                    nor furnished any aid whatsoever for the Confederate States, or any Military
                    force or organization. Nor did I give any information.</p>
                <p>Ques. 19. Ans. I never was engaged or employed in the manufacture of any article
                    whatsoever, for the use of the Confederate Government or its army.</p>
                <p>Ques. 20. Ans. I had no employment of any kind, nor contracts for the Confederacy
                    or any State in rebellion.</p>
                <p>Ques. 21. Ans. I never ran the blockade, or engaged or interested in illicit
                    traffic nor of goods, wares, merchandise brought into or exported.</p>
                <p>Ques. 22. Ans. I never left the lines, during the time of the war.</p>
                <p>Ques. 23. Ans. I had no interest in any vessel on any waters, for any purpose.</p>
                <p>Ques. 24. Ans. I never was arrested by either the Confederate or the United
                    States Government.</p>
                <p>Ques. 25. Ans. I never had any property taken by the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>Ques. 26. Ans. I have no recollection of bein threatened and never was injured.</p>
                <p>Ques. 27. Ans. I never was molested or injured.</p>
                <p>Ques. 28. Ans. I never contributed anything for the United States. I never was
                    called on.</p>
                <p>Ques. 29. Ans. I never did anything for the United States Government, its army or
                    the Union cause.</p>
                <p>Ques. 30. Ans. I had one brother, Francis M. Mann, he is <orig reg="dead"
                    >ded</orig>. I furnished him nothing.</p>
                <p>Ques. 31. Ans. I bought a Confederate bond to pay Confederate tax. I made no
                    bones. Nor did anything to support the credit of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 32. Ans. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> any aid and comfort to the
                    rebellion.</p>
                <p>Ques. 33. Ans. I never made raids from Canada or elsewhere.</p>
                <p>Ques. 34. Ans. I never had anything to do with prisoners, in any way or for any
                    cause.</p>
                <p>Ques. 35. Ans. I never belonged to any society or association for the punishment
                    of persons for any cause.</p>
                <p>Ques. 36. Ans. I never was a parolled prisoner.</p>
                <p>Ques. 37. Ans. I never held an office, nor was educated at any Military school.</p>
                <p>Ques. 38. Ans. I had a pass from my home to Richmond and return. I went to
                    purchase goods. I took no oath.</p>
                <p>Ques. 39. Ans. I was under no disabilities.</p>
                <p>Ques. 40. Ans. At the beginning of the rebellion, my sympathies were with the
                    Union. I voted for Union Candidates to the State Convention I voted for the
                    Ordinance of Secession against my consent owing to threats that was made against
                    those who refused to do so and being totally blind and a family to support I
                    feared the consequences of a refusal on my part, but my feelings and sympathies
                    were all the time with the Union.</p>
                <p>Ques. 41. Ans. I do solemnly declare that from the beginning of hostilities
                    against the United States to the end thereof, my sympathies were constantly with
                    the cause of the United States that I never of my own free will and accord did
                    anything or offered or sought or attempted to do anything by word or dead to
                    injure said cause or retard its success and that I was at all times ready and
                    willing when called upon to aid and assist the cause of the Union or its
                    supporters, so far as my means and power and the circumstances would permit.</p>
                <p>Testimony of taking the property</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. &amp; 2. Ans. I was present when part of the articles were taken,
                    but being blind could not see.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Ans. The flour was at my residence and all the articles, except the
                    tobacco and Coffee Pots, which were at my store room.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4. Ans. The Flour, Corn, Rye, Bacon, Beef, Bags, Vinegar, Brass Kettles,
                    Crocks &amp; Hay were taken from my dwelling and the Tobacco &amp;
                    Coffee Pots from my store room. I think about the 2<hi rend="super">d</hi>
                    day of February or March, in 1865 by <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Sheridan's Command. There were a large
                    number of soldiers present and engaged in taking the articles.</p>
                <p>Ques. 5. Ans. There was a <orig reg="colored">colered</orig> woman by name of
                    Nancy Brock present.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6. Ans. I do not know whether there was an officer present or not, the
                    Command belonged to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super"
                    >l.</hi></abbr> Sheridan.</p>
                <p>Ques. 7. Ans. The Flour was rolled out, and then emptied into bags, and the
                    Vinegar in buckets, Coffee pots &amp; pans.</p>
                <p>Ques. 8. Ans. The property was removed to their camp by soldiers. I asked them
                    not take my provisions that they saw my condition being blind, and they replied
                    that they were obliged to have provisions that they had no prisoner train.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9. Ans. The property was taken to the camps, in and around the town.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10. Ans. They told me they wanted provisions. I did not follow.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11. Ans. I made no complaint to any officer.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12. Ans. I did not get a receipt, I did not apply for one.</p>
                <p>Ques. 13. Ans. The articles were all taken in the day time, in the afternoon.</p>
                <p>Ques. 14. Ans. The army was encamped in and around the town. They remained there
                    but one night. There was a skirmish, with <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Early. I knew no Quarter Master or
                    other officer.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15. Ans. The Flour was a first rate article, I had refused the day previous
                    ten dollars in gold per barrel. A portion of the corn was shelled and the
                    balance on the cob. The hay was good, sound good Bacon. The Vinegar was of an
                    excellent quality, the Kettles, Coffe Pots, Crocks &amp; pans all new. The
                    bags were all sound and good. I judged the quantity of hay, by the amount I knew
                    my house held. I had purchased the Corn only three days previously, and none of
                    it had been used. I made the Bacon and knew that that amount was taken. The
                    boxes of Tobacco were unbroken, except one which contained 40 pounds. One Case
                    of Smoking Tobacco, was unbroken and contained 200 pounds, and the balance was
                    in 1/2 pound packages. The flour was in barrels and 10 of them. Every article
                    taken was good and sound.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John A. Mann</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Susan A. Mann</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Susan A. Mann</p>
                <p>Answer to first general question. My name is Susan A. Mann, my age is 39 years. I
                    reside in Waynesboro. I am the wife of the claimant. I was present and saw the
                    property taken. I saw all the property taken, which was <add hand="h1" place="inline">from</add> the
                    dwelling, Flour, Corn, Rye, Bacon, Vinegar, hay, Crocks, Bags, &amp;
                    Kettles.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Ans. The flour was rolled out of the house into the garden. The Bacon
                    from the Smoke house, and hay and corn and everything taken from the dwelling
                    was from the places where such articles are usually kept by families.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4. Ans. The articles were taken to the camp, so far as I know. I have no
                    recollection of the time, I know the year was 1865. <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Sheridan I understood was the
                    Commander. There were a large number of soldiers present. I do not know whether
                    there was an officer present or not. Nancy Brock, a <orig reg="colored"
                    >colered</orig> woman was present. I know of no officer being present. I do not
                    recollect anything that was said except that I told them my husband was blind,
                    and asked them not to take my provisions, and the reply was that I "had better
                    go to the house." The flour was emptied from the barrels into bags. The bags
                    taken from us <orig reg="were">was</orig> used for that purpose. They hay was
                    carried by the soldiers. The Bacon was carried by the soldiers in their hands
                    and the Vinegar in Coffee Pots, Crocks pans &amp;c. to the camp. I never saw
                    the articles after <orig reg="they were">it was</orig> taken away. There was no
                    complaint made to any officer that I know of and no receipt given. The property
                    was taken in the day time in the Afternoon. The army was camped in different
                    places in and around the town. It remained one night.</p>
                <p>There had been a fight with <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super"
                        >l.</hi></abbr> Early. The day that <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Sheridan came to the town. The
                    property was sound and good as far as I know.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness"><abbr expan="Susan">S.</abbr>A. Mann</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Rufus M. Markwood</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Rufus M. Markwood.</p>
                <p>Answer to 1<hi rend="super">st</hi><abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Question. My name is Rufus M.
                    Markwood, my age is 53 years. I reside near Waynesboro. I am by occupation a
                    Carpenter. I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in the claim. I
                    have known the claimant some 12 or 15 years. I was intimate with him during the
                    war. I was in Waynesboro working at my trade most of the war. I saw him
                    frequently and had frequent conversations about the war, he always denounced the
                    south for going into the rebellion. I never heard him express himself in the
                    presence of others. he was very free to talk with me, as he knew me to be a
                    strong Union man. The Union men of the town and neighborhood regarded him as a
                    good Union man. I have heard him say to others that it was very unwise for the
                    South to rebel. There was a great many threats made against any who voted
                    against Secession. There were parties banded together to lynch any one who voted
                    against the Ordinance and my impression that alone caused the claimant to vote
                    for it, for owing to his situation being blind, he was in a dependant situation
                    and I do not believe that had he voted against Secession or refused to vote for
                    it, he could have gotten patronage to support his family. I do not believe from
                    what I knew of the claimant that he could have proven his loyalty to the
                    Confederate States, if they had succeeded.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness"><abbr expan="Rufus">R.</abbr> M. Markwood</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>Benjamin M. Lines</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Benjamin M. Lines.</p>
                <p>Ans. to 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> general question. My name is Benjamin M.
                    Lines, my age is 73 years. I reside near Waynesboro. My occupation is Post
                    Master, &amp; Shoemaker. I am not related to the claimant and have no
                    interest in the claim. I have known the claimant for over fifteen years. I lived
                    about 3 miles distant from the claimant during the war. I saw him frequently,
                    probably once a week. I do not recollect of talking with him about the War. The
                    claimant knew my sentiments to be in favor of the Union. I do not know whether
                    he was strictly a Union man or not. I think however, that he was so inclined,
                    but I had no particular conversation with him on the subject. It was not at all
                    prudent in that town (Waynesboro) and neighborhood for a man to express himself
                    against secession. The claimant being a blind man and having a small variety
                    store would have been in danger of losing his goods and reduced to want, if he
                    had expressed himself openly in favor of the Union. I know a part of his Union
                    neighbors regarded him as a Union man. I never heard of his giving anything to
                    aid the Confederates. When Stonewall Jackson, had a large number of prisoners
                    enroute to Richmond the claimant sent or carried provisions to the prisoners. I
                    do not know whether he could have proved his loyalty to the Confederacy or not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness"><abbr expan="Benjamin">Benj<hi rend="super"
                        >m.</hi></abbr> M. Lines</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
