<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0314"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0314">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of George W. Furr,
                    August 22, 1871, Claim No. 5710</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of george w furr, august 22 1871 claim no 5710</title>
        <author>Furr, George W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 13 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0314</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498381</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of George W. Furr,
                            August 22, 1871, Claim No. 5710</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of george w furr, august 22 1871 claim no 5710</title>
            <author>George Furr</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche # 459</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0314T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>George W. Furr filed this claim August 22, 1871, for $140, claiming that Union
                    troops confiscated one bay mare on June 8, 1864, from his farm near Staunton,
                    Augusta County, Virginia. The claim includes the voucher Furr received when his
                    horse was taken, signed by J. M. Wiggins of the 20th Ohio Cavalry. The Claims
                    Commission did not find J. M. Wiggins in its records and thereby determined that
                    the claimant was "imposed upon" by someone taking the horse for non-Army
                    purposes; the claim was disallowed in 1872.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Bay Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$140.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$140.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claim rejected.</p>
                <p>The receipt purporting to be given by J.M. Wiggins of the 20th Ohio Cavalry is in
                    an unusual form &amp; such as would excite suspicion - "The United States
                    Gov't will pay to the bearer $140 on demand for a bay horse taken this day."</p>
                <p>On inquiry of the Third Auditor we are informed that no account of returns of
                    J.M. Wiggins are on file - neither does his name appear - nor is the
                    organization to which he is reported to have belonged mentioned in the Official
                    Army Register."</p>
                <p>We have no doubt that the claimant was imposed upon by some one - &amp; that
                    the horse was not taken for the use of the Army.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>
                </p>
                <p>Commrs of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>George W. Furr</byline>
                <p>United States of America</p>
                <p>State of Virginia</p>
                <p>I W.G. Riley a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioner of
                    Claims, appointed under the Act of Congress of March 3rd 1871, to take and
                    record testimony Do hereby certify that the reason for taking the following
                    deposition is, and the fact is the matter of claim of George W. Furr vs. the
                    United States of America and the witness herein named being first duly sworn
                    answereth as follows:</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness says - I lived in Augusta County Virginia six months prior to the
                    1st of April 1861. I have never been out of the state.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says I never took any oath to the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5 I have never taken any amnesty oath.</p>
                <p>6 Witness says I never did anything for the Confederacy. I never aided or abetted
                    it in any way directly or indirectly.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says - I never was engaged in blockade running anywhere.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says - I did not leave the Confederate States between the 19th April
                    1861 and the 19th April 1865</p>
                <p>17 Witness says - I never was arrested by either the Confederate or United States
                    Governments</p>
                <p>21 Witness says - I never did anything for the United States Government.</p>
                <p>23 Witness says - I had a brother in the Confederate Army. I did not aid him
                    while he was in the army.</p>
                <p>30 Witness says - I never held any office in the Army or Navy of the United
                    States. I was never educated at West Point or at the Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>31 Witness says - I never received any pass from the Confederate Government. I
                    never held any office under the United States Government.</p>
                <p>33 Witness says - At the beginning of the War I was for the Union. I did not vote
                    for the Ordinance of Secession.</p>
                <p>34 Witness says - In the beginning of hostilities against the United States I was
                    for the Union Cause, and was ready at all times to aid it to the best of my
                    ability.</p>
                <p>35 Witness says - I am thirty five years old. I live in Augusta County by
                    occupation a farmer and further the deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>August the 22nd 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">George W. Furr</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Daniel Fishburn</byline>
                <p>Daniel Fishburn a witness introduced by the claimant George W. Furr for proof as
                    to his loyalty being first duly sworn answereth as follows:</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness says - I am fifty one years old. I reside in Augusta County Va.
                    by occupation a farmer. I have known the claimant from a little child the
                    claimant is very deaf. I reside near him and saw him often during the war. He
                    was loyal to the United States during the war and was so regarded by his
                    neighbors. I never knew him to do anything for the Rebel Government. I never
                    knew him to do anything for the United States Government he had no opportunity.
                    I think he was too loyal to the United States Government to have been considered
                    loyal to the Confederacy if it had succeeded he used to hide himself in the
                    brush to keep out of the Confederate service and further the deponent saith not
                    August 22nd 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Daniel Fishburn</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>John Bumgardner</byline>
                <p>John Bumgardner being introduced by the Claimant to prove the taking of the
                    property, being first duly sworn answereth as follows:</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness says - I am sixty one years old. I reside in the County of
                    Augusta Va. by occupation a farmer. I am certain that the horse mentioned in the
                    claimant's petition was taken by soldiers under the command of Genl Hunter I
                    think there was an officer present at the taking. The horse was carried off by
                    soldiers. I don't know but I suppose it was taken to Genl Hunter's Head
                    Quarters.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says - There was a receipt given for the horse.</p>
                <p>13 Witness says - The property was taken in the day time it was not taken
                    secretly.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says - When the horse was taken the army was encamped near Staunton
                    Virginia, about five miles from where the horse was taken</p>
                <p>15 Witness says - The horse was in good condition. I think she was five years old
                    and I think she was worth one hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
                <p>19 Witness says - I think the horse was taken for the use of the Army and not for
                    private use.</p>
                <p>21 Witness says - I think it was taken for the use of the Army because they gave
                    a receipt for it.</p>
                <p>22 Witness says - I think the Government after taking the horse for the use of
                    the Army ought to pay for it.</p>
                <p>23 Witness says - I think those that took the horse had authority or power to
                    take it and further the deponent saith not August 22nd 1871</p>
                <p><name type="witness">John Bumgardner</name> his mark</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 22nd day of August 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">W.G. Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and Special Com. for State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Charles F. Benjamin</byline>
                <p>November 5, 1872</p>
                <p>Commissioners of Claims</p>
                <p>Refers for verification, memorandum receipt of <hi rend="underline">J.M.
                    Wiggins</hi> Q2Mr. 20th Ohio Cavalry, in favor of Geo. W. Furr, Augusta Co, Va.</p>
                <p>Respectfully referred to the Adjutant General by the Commissioners of Claims
                    requesting information concerning the genuine or spurious character of the
                    within receipt.</p>
                <p><name type="other">Chas. F. Benjamin</name> Clerk of Claims Comm.</p>
                <p>Nov 5/72</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>War Department, Adjutant General's Office, November 11th 1872</p>
                <p>Respectfully returned.</p>
                <p>There is no such regiment as the 20th Ohio Cavalry known to the office, nor does
                    the name of J.M. Wiggins appear upon the Volunteer Register as a Commissioned
                    Officer of any Ohio organization.</p>
                <p><name type="other"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Vincent</name> Asst. Adjutant Genl.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>J. M. Wiggins</byline>
                <p>CASH ACCOUNT OCTOBER June 8th 1864</p>
                <p>The United States Gov't will pay to the bearer $140 on demand for a Bay Mare
                    taken this day</p>
                <p><name type="other">J.M. Wiggins</name> Q.M. 20th Ohio Cavalry</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>United States Treasury Department</byline>
                <p>Treasurer's Department, THIRD AUDITOR'S OFFICE, November 4th, 1872</p>
                <p>Sir, In reply to your communication of the 11th Sept. (herewith returned) I have
                    to inform you that there are no Accounts or returns on file in this office of
                    J.M. Wiggins Quartermaster, 20th Ohio Cavalry - neither does his name appear -
                    nor is the organization to which he is reported to have belonged mentioned in
                    the Official Army Register.</p>
                <p>Respectfully, <name type="other">AM Garyewer</name> Act'g Audr</p>
                <p><name type="other">Chas F. Benjamin</name> Esq. Clerk Commr. of Claims</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
