<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0522"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0522">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Elizabeth
                    Garber, 1871, Claim No. 2545</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of elizabeth garber, 1871 claim no 2545</title>
        <author>Garber, Elizabeth</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">17</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0522</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498409</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Elizabeth Garber,
                            1871, Claim No. 2545</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of elizabeth garber, 1871 claim no 2545</title>
            <author>Elizabeth Garber</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #2545</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0522T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Elizabeth Garber filed this claim in 1871 for $200, claiming Union forces from
                    General Hunters Army took two horses in 1864. Elizabeth was a 48 year old farmer
                    in New Hope. The commission allowed $110.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Bay horse 16 years</cell>
                            <cell>$80.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$80.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Large Bay 13 years</cell>
                            <cell>$120.00</cell>
                            <cell>$110.00</cell>
                            <cell>$10.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimants' loyalty is sustained by her own statement and the testimony of David
                    Myer and <abbr expan="Samuel">Sam<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr> P Garber.</p>
                <p>The horses for which she claims compensation were taken by <abbr expan="General"
                        >Gen</abbr> Hunters Cavalry for the Artillery Service. As they were 13 and
                    16 years old, respectively it is probable they were past
                    <unclear>hearing</unclear> and so well adapted to that special service
                    nevertheless as old horses are not very valuable in the market, we feel
                    constrained to cut the prices of these down a little, although like all other
                    horses in the South during the War, "they were fat and in fine condition when
                    taken".</p>
                <p>We allow one hundred and ten dollars.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Elizabeth Garber</byline>
                <p>United States of America, State of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p>I, W.G. Riley, a Commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioners of
                    Claims appointed under the act of Congress of March 3<hi rend="super"
                    >d</hi> 1871, to take and record testimony. Do hereby certify that the reason
                    for taking the following depositions is and the fact is the matter of Claim of
                    Elizabeth Garber vs. the United States of America, and the witnesses herein
                    named being material and necessary, being first duly sworn answereth as follows.</p>
                <p>Questions</p>
                <p>1 Witness says-New Hope Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> My occupation farming.</p>
                <p>2. Witness say-Resided at the same place.</p>
                <p>3 Witness says-I never passed beyond the Military or Naval lines of the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> &amp; entered the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says-I never took an oath or affirmation or allegiance to the
                    Confederate States, nor done nothing to aid in any way the Confederate
                    Government.</p>
                <p>5. Witness Says-I have never taken any amnesty oath, and never had everything to
                    pardoned of.</p>
                <p>6 Witness Says, I never held any office or place of trust under the Confederate
                    Government.</p>
                <p>7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I never held any office or place of
                    trust under the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>8 Witness Says-I never did hold any office under the Confederate Government
                    whatever.</p>
                <p>9<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never was in <hi
                        rend="super">in</hi> any capacity in the service of the so called
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>10 Witness Says-I never aided the Confederate Government in any matter.</p>
                <p>11 Witness Says-I never rendered any service to the Confederate Government or in
                    any State thereof in rebellion.</p>
                <p>12<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never did.</p>
                <p>13<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never did.</p>
                <p>14 Witness Says, I never was engaged in blockade running or illicit traffic
                    between the lines, never had any interest or share in any goods, wares
                    merchandise, brought into, or exported fromt the so called Confederate states
                    during the war.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says I did not leave the Confederate
                    States between the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> April 1861 and the 19<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> April 1865.</p>
                <p>16<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I never was an owner in any vessel
                    employed in navigating the ocean to or from any port in the Confederacy or upon
                    any waters in the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Say I never was arrested by the
                    Confederate Government, or any officer, or soldier, acting therefor, or for any
                    State in rebellion. I never arrested by the <abbr expan="United States"
                    >U.S.</abbr> Government.</p>
                <p>18<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I had property taken by the
                    Confederate Authorities, for which I received such money as they had. I could
                    not do otherwise as they would take it.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, I never was threatened with damage
                    to my person, family or property by the Confederate Government on account of my
                    Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>20<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never was injured or molested on
                    account of my Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness Say, I never contributed anything in aid
                    of the Union cause.</p>
                <p>22 Witness Says, I fed the soldiers when the come along.</p>
                <p>23<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, I had no relatives either in the
                    Union or Confederate Armies. I never contributed anything to supply with stores
                    or money.</p>
                <p>24 Witness Says, I never owned any Confederate bonds or any interest or share
                    therein, or had any share or loans to the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>25<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I never give any aid or Comfort to
                    the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I never was engaged in making
                    raids into the <abbr expan="United">U.</abbr> States from Canada, or engaged in
                    destroying the Commerce of the United States in the Lakes or rivers adjoining
                    Canada.</p>
                <p>27<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, I never was engaged in holding
                    directly or indirectly any persons in custody, any engaged by the rebel
                    Government taken as prisoners of War.</p>
                <p>28<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-I never did.</p>
                <p>29<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says I never was a paroled prisoner of
                    the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr></p>
                <p>30<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Say-No.</p>
                <p>31 Witness Says, I never received any pass from any officer of the Confederate
                    Government or from any person having authority to issue the same.</p>
                <p>32. Witness Says-I never was under any disabilities imposed by the 14<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> Amendment to the Constitution. I have never held
                    any office in the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Government since the
                    War.</p>
                <p>33 Witness Says I <orig reg="sympathized">sympathised</orig> with the Union Cause
                    and not with the rebellion at the beginning, being a lady I could not vote for
                    or against the ordinance of secession. And after the ordinance of Secession was
                    passed I adhered to the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>34th Witness Says, I do not solemnly declare that from the beginning of
                    hostilities to the end thereof. My sympathies were constant in the cause of the
                    United States. That <del hand="h1">and</del> was ready and willing at all times, to aid
                    the cause of the Union or its supporters so far as my means and power and the
                    circumstances of the case permitted.</p>
                <p>Questions by the Commission</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> How old are you, where do you reside, and what is
                    your occupation. Ans. I am 48 years old, I reside in New Hope, Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>
                    occupation is farming.</p>
                <p>2. What was the condition of the horses charged in your petition at the time they
                    were taken by the Government, and their Value? Ans. They were in good condition
                    and worth more to me than I have charged in my petition.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not. August 10<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Elizabeth Garber</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>David Myers</byline>
                <p>David Myers, a witness introduced by Elizabeth Garber, being first duly sworn
                    answereth as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I was not present. I <hi
                        rend="super">know</hi> nothing of the taking of the property.</p>
                <p>2<hi rend="super">d</hi><del hand="h1">Witness Says</del> Did you know the condition
                    and value of property when taken, mentioned in the claimants petition. Ans: The
                    horses were in fine condition. I think the charges made in the petition are
                    reasonable and fair. I have every reason to believe that they were taken by the
                    Government but I did not see it.</p>
                <p>Questions by the Commissioner</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> How old are you? Where do you reside and what is
                    your occupation? Ans. I am 54 years old, reside at New Hope, Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> My occupation is
                    a farmer.</p>
                <p>2 How long have you known Elizabeth Garber the Claimant? And were you itimate
                    during the War? Ans. I have known her 30 or 40 years. I live near her, and saw
                    her every few days during the war, and she was as loyal to the Union Cause as
                    any person could be, and so regarded by her neighbors, and she being a widow,
                    the Confederate authorities seemed disposed to oppress her. I never knew her to
                    aid the Confederate Government, its officers or soldiers.</p>
                <p>3<hi rend="super">d</hi> Do you know of any act done or language used by
                    the claimant which would have prevented her from establishing her loyalty to the
                    Confederacy, if it had been maintained <del hand="h1">by the Confederate</del> as a <orig
                        reg="separate">seperate</orig> Government. If so, state the same
                    particularly. Ans. She was too loyal to the Union to have been considered loyal
                    to the Confederacy if it had been maintained as a <orig reg="separate"
                    >seperate</orig> Government.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not. Aug<hi rend="super">t</hi>. 10<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">David Myers</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Samuel Garber</byline>
                <p>Samuel P. Garber a witness introduced by Elizabeth Garber, being first duly
                    sworn, answereth as follows.</p>
                <p>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness Says-That I was present when the Articles
                    of property specified in Claimants petition were taken.</p>
                <p>2<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, I saw them taken meaning all the
                    Articles mentioned in Claimants petition.</p>
                <p>4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says Taken the 6<hi rend="super"
                    >th</hi> June 1864 from the Claimants premises, by <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter's Army.</p>
                <p>5 Witness Says I was present and Elizabeth Garber, the Claimant.</p>
                <p>6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, They were taken by some of the
                    Cavalry, belonging to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super"
                    >l</hi></abbr>. Hunter's Army. I do not know whether they were Officers or not.
                    The Soldiers who took them said "here are two fine horses, the Claimant said if
                    they took them, she could not get along. They said they wanted them for the
                    Artillery and that the Claimant would be paid for them.</p>
                <p>8<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-The horses were removed by soldiers.</p>
                <p>9<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says-The horses were
                        <del hand="h1">brought</del><hi rend="super">taken</hi> to Staunton, I did not
                    see them afterwards. I believe the property was removed to Staunton because the
                    Army was marching in that direction.</p>
                <p>10<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I do not know for what use the
                    horses were taken but they said, they wanted them for the Artillery.</p>
                <p>12<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, There was no receipt asked for,
                    nor none given.</p>
                <p>13<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says-The property was taken in the day
                    time, about 9 Oclock A.M. on the 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> June 1864. It
                    was not taken secretly.</p>
                <p>14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, There was a battle at Piedmont,
                    the day before the property was taken, which was about one mile from Claimants
                    residence. <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter
                    was in command of the Union Army.</p>
                <p>15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says The horses were in good condition
                    when taken, and were worth all charged in the petition either to the Claimant or
                    Government.</p>
                <p>19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, The property was taken for the use
                    of the Army, and not for the mere gratification of Officers or soldiers.</p>
                <p>20<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, I believe they were taken for the
                    use of the Army.</p>
                <p>21<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says I suppose they were taken in
                    consequence of some necessity for the articles taken which justified the
                    officers or soldiers in taking them.</p>
                <p>22<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I believe they were taken for the
                    use of the Army, and that the Government would be justifiable in paying for
                    them.</p>
                <p>23<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, I suppose they were taken by the
                    authority of some one whose authority justified him in taking it, <del hand="h1">or
                    jus</del></p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not. August 10<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">S. P. Garber</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 10th day of August 1871.</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
