<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0100"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0100">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Jonas Wampler,
                    August 7, 1871, Claim No. 2561</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of jonas wampler, august 7 1871 claim no 2561</title>
        <author>Wampler, Jonas</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">33</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0100</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498325</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Jonas Wampler, August
                            7, 1871, Claim No. 2561</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of jonas wampler, august 7 1871 claim no 2561</title>
            <author>Jonas Wampler</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8808</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism, Religion, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0100T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Wampler's claim for $162 worth of property was disallowed by the Commission, and
                    he appealed this decision in 1892, when the Congressional Court of Claims found
                    him loyal to the United States.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Light B Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>10 bush. Oats &amp; corn &amp; chops</cell>
                            <cell>6.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>6.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Barrel Flour</cell>
                            <cell>6.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>6.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>162.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>162.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>Loyalty of Claimant established by his own Statement and the testimony of Martha
                    A. Myers and Silas Church, Sarah J. Clark</p>
                <p>It does not appear very clearly from the brief testimony of the witnesses whether
                    the property charged was taken legitimately, or whether it was mere depredation
                    by thugging soldiers or camp followers. It seems that the person who took the
                    horse, a soldier we presume, said that his horse was broken down and promised
                    that he would return Claimants if he could get another. That <orig reg="doesn't"
                        >dont</orig> seem very much like taking with due authority for the use of
                    the Army.</p>
                <p>Then as to the other articles the only shadow of evidence is this remark of the
                    witness Sarah J. Clark "I also the other articles taken." But the other articles
                    it is clear were not taken when the horse was taken, and to neither time place
                    or circumstances by whom or how taken appear in evidence. The Claim is not
                    sustained by the evidence and we reject it.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>Jonas Wampler</byline>
                <p>I W.G. Riley a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioner of Claims
                    appointed under the act of Congress of March 3, 1871 to take and record
                    testimony. Do hereby certify that the reason for taking the following
                    depositions is and the fact is the matter of claim of <hi rend="underline"
                        >Jonas Wampler</hi> vs. the United States of America and the witness
                    herein named being material and necessary, being first duly sworn deposeth as
                    follows,</p>
                <p>Ques 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Witness says, I resided in Augusta Co
                    Va. that he was at home. My occupation was farming.</p>
                <p>Ques 2<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, I resided in Augusta Co.
                    Va. I was at home all that time, farming. I did not change my residence from
                    Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness Says, That he never passed
                    beyond the military or naval lines of the United States to enter the rebel
                    lines.</p>
                <p>Ques 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, He never took an oath or
                    affirmation to the so called Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Ques 5<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, I have never taken any
                    amnesty oath</p>
                <p>Ques. 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, No.</p>
                <p>Ques. 33. Witness says, At the beginning of the rebellion I was a Union man and
                    continued so all the time. I did not vote for the ordinance of Secession.</p>
                <p>Ques. 34<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, I was, from the
                    beginning of the hostilities against the United States to the end thereof,
                    constantly with the cause of the United States, and never of his own free will,
                    do anything to injure said cause or retard its success, and was at all times
                    ready to aid and assist the cause of the Union so far as his means and power and
                    the circumstances of the case admitted.</p>
                <p>Question by the Commissioner Ques. How old are you, Where do you reside, and what
                    is your occupation?</p>
                <p>Ans. I am 57 years, reside in Augusta Co Va. A farmer.</p>
                <p>August 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Jonas Wampler</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Martha A. Myers</byline>
                <p>Martha A. Myers, a witness introduced by Jonas Wampler, being duly sworn
                    answereth as follows,</p>
                <p>How old are you, Where do you reside, and your occupation-</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Ans</hi>. I am 38 years of age, reside in Augusta Co.
                    Va. Housekeeper.</p>
                <p>1 <hi rend="underline">Ques</hi>: Witness says I did see the horse taken and
                    know that all the articles named in the claimants petition were taken.</p>
                <p>Ques 6<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Witness says, Says that the property
                    was taken by the Union Soldiers, under command of Gen<hi rend="super"
                    >l</hi>. Hunter.</p>
                <p>Ques. 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, I saw the horse rode off,
                    but do not know how the other articles were taken off.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says The horse was taken to
                    Staunton, Va.</p>
                <p>Ques 10<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness Says, They told me they took
                    the horse, because he needed him, his horse was broken down.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says There was complaint at
                    the time and the officer said that he thought if he would go to Staunton he
                    could get it, but he did not get it back.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says No receipt was given.</p>
                <p>Ques 13<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, The property was taken in
                    the day time between 10 &amp; 12 o'clock</p>
                <p>Ques 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says The army were not encamped
                    near. The day before the battle was fought at Piedmont.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15<hi rend="super">th</hi> Witness says, The horse was in good
                    condition, and I think well worth the price charged by the Claimant. And all the
                    articles at reasonable and fair prices.</p>
                <p>Ques 22<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says, I think it was taken for
                    some purpose so necessary that the Government ought to pay for it.</p>
                <p>Ques. 23<hi rend="super">d</hi> Witness says I believe it was taken by
                    the order of some officer, who was justified in ordering it to be taken.</p>
                <p>Questions by the <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super"
                    >r</hi></abbr>. <hi rend="underline">Ques</hi>. How long have you known
                    the Claimant?</p>
                <p>Ans. I have known him about 12 years and he was loyal all the War to the <abbr
                        expan="United">U.</abbr> States Government, and was so regarded by his
                    neighbors. I have heard him frequently speak for the Union cause during the War.
                    If all were as loyal as he was, it would be well for them in the day of
                    Judgment.</p>
                <p>Ques 2<hi rend="super">d</hi> Do you know of any act done or <orig
                        reg="language">languaged</orig> used by the Claimant which would have
                    prevented him from establishing his loyalty to the Confederacy if it had been
                    maintained as a separate Government. If so state the same particularly?</p>
                <p>Ans. He was too good a Union man, and said he would not remain in the south if it
                    succeeded.</p>
                <p>Further this witness saith not. August 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Martha A. Myers</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Sarah J. Clarke</byline>
                <p>Sarah J. Clarke a witness introduced by Jonas Wampler being duly sworn answereth
                    as follows.</p>
                <p>Question by the Commissioner. How old are you, Where do you reside</p>
                <p>Ans. I am 31 years old, I reside in Augusta Co. Va. Housekeeper.</p>
                <p>Ques 2 How long have you known the claimant?</p>
                <p>Ans. I have known him all my life. He was a loyal all the war to the United
                    States Government, and so regarded by all his neighbors. He did nothing in any
                    way to aid the rebels.</p>
                <p>Ques 3. Did you see the property mentioned in the claimants petition taken. If
                    so, what was its condition and value?</p>
                <p>Ans. The horse was in good condition, and fully worth what he has charged. I also
                    saw the other articles taken and believe the charges to be low enough.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Ques</hi> 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> Do you
                    know of any act done or language used by the claimant which would have prevented
                    him from establishing his loyalty to the Confederacy, if it had been maintained
                    as a <orig reg="separate">seperate</orig> Government. If so, state the same
                    particularly.</p>
                <p>Ans. He could not <add hand="h1" place="inline">have</add> established any claim of loyalty to the
                    Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Witness further saith not. August 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Sallie J. Clark</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 7th day of Aug. 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special Com.
                    for State of V<hi rend="super">a</hi></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>Claimant's Brief on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS, December Term, 1891-1892</p>
                <p>Jonas Wampler vs. the United States, No. 8808 Cong.</p>
                <p>STATEMENT</p>
                <p>The claimant in this case resided in Augusta County, Virginia during the late
                    war; he presented his claim to the Commissioners of Claims, amounting to
                    $162.00. Claim was disallowed by the said Commissioners and reported to
                    Congress.</p>
                <p>In their report, the Commissioners state that the "loyalty of the claimant is
                    established by his own testimony and the testimony of Martha A. Myers, Silas
                    Church and Sarah J. Clark". The Commissioners rejected the claim, because, as
                    they state, the claim is not sustained by the testimony. This claim was referred
                    to the Court of Claims by the Committee on War Claims of the House of
                    Representatives, on March 23, 1892, under the provisions of the Bowman Act.</p>
                <p>BRIEF ON LOYALTY</p>
                <p>The testimony in this case while pending before the Commissioners, was taken
                    before a Special Commissioner, in 1871, at Staunton Augusta, County, Virginia.</p>
                <p>JONAS WAMPLER, the claimant, testifies; residence, Augusta County, Virginia,
                    during the war; occupation, farmer.</p>
                <p>Was at home all the time; did not change my residence never passed beyond the
                    military or naval lines of the United States into the rebel lines; never took
                    any oath to the Confederate States; never took the Amnesty Oath. (p. 1).</p>
                <p>Never held any office under the Confederate States; never served the Confederacy
                    in any manner; never gave any information to the Confederacy; never aided the
                    Confederacy in any shape or form; was not arrested by the Confederate or the
                    United States Government.</p>
                <p>Says the Confederates took his grain for which he received nothing. (p. 2).</p>
                <p>That he nor his family were ever threatened by the Confederate Government on
                    account of his Union sentiments; never contributed any thing to the Union army;
                    had no near realtions in either the Union or Confederate army; contributed
                    nothing to them; never did any thing for the Confederate cause.</p>
                <p>Questions 26 to 31, inclusive, answered in the negative, favorable to loyalty.
                    (p. 3).</p>
                <p>At the beginning I was a Union man; continued so all the time; did not vote for
                    the ordinance of secession; was from the beginning of hostilities against the
                    United States to the end, never did any thing to injure said cause; was at all
                    times ready to aid and assist the cause of the Union, so far as in my means and
                    power.</p>
                <p>I am fifty seven years of age; reside in Augusta County, Virginia. (p. 4).</p>
                <p>MARTHA D. MYERS testifies, age 38; reside in Augusta County, Virginia;
                    occupation, housekeeper.</p>
                <p>Testifies as to property. (p. 5).</p>
                <p>I have known claimant about twelve years; he was loyal all the war to the United
                    States Government; so regarded by his neighbors; have heard him frequently speak
                    for the Union cause during the war. If all were as loyal as he was, it would be
                    well for them in the day of Judgment.</p>
                <p>He was too good a Union man to establish his loyalty to the Confederate
                    Government, if it had been maintained. Said he would not have remained in the
                    South, if the Confederacy had succeeded. (p. 7).</p>
                <p>SARAH J. CLARK testifies: Age, 31; residence, Augusta County, Virginia
                    occupation, housekeeper.</p>
                <p>Have known claimant all my life; he was loyal to the United States Government all
                    of the war; so regarded by all of his neighbors; did nothing in any way to aid
                    the rebellion. (p. 8).</p>
                <p>He could not have established a claim to loyalty to the Confederacy, had it been
                    maintained as a Separate Government. (p. 9).</p>
                <p>SUMMARY.</p>
                <p>The loyalty of this claimant seems to have been conceded by the Commissioners of
                    Claims and the proof would seem to be ample on that branch of the case, and the
                    claimant should be found to have been a loyal adherent of the United States
                    Government throughout the entire war.</p>
                <p>Respectfully submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> Attorney for
                    claimant</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>Defendant's Brief on Loyalty</byline>
                <p>COURT OF CLAIMS</p>
                <p>Jonas Wampler v. The United States-No. 8808-Cong.</p>
                <p>LOYALTY. <hi rend="underline">DEFENDANTS' BRIEF</hi>.</p>
                <p>The claimant resided at or near Staunton Va, and presented his claim to the
                    Commissioners of Claims who rejected it because of the failure of the proofs on
                    the merits of the claim. They seem to have been satisfied upon the question of
                    Loyalty and the claimant has not offered any further evidence upon that question
                    since it came into this court here from Congress under the Bowman Act.</p>
                <p>With all due deference to the Commissioners of Claims I cannot agree with them in
                    their Finding that the loyalty of Mr. Jonas Wampler is established. He offers
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">two</add><del hand="h1">2</del> good old women who at the very best only swear to
                    an opinion that Mr. Wampler was loyal. The only <hi rend="underline"
                    >fact</hi> sworn to was by the last witness and he says he claimant, said if
                    the Confederacy was established he would go North and live. But not one act is
                    testified to that showed his loyalty, without it was the vicarious one of his
                    son who, he says<orig reg=",">,,</orig> fought in the Union army.</p>
                <p>But the most difficult thing to believe is that this man could have remained a
                    loud-mouthed Union man in that part of Old Virginia. This makes too much of a
                    draft on my credulity.</p>
                <p>The Court's attention is called to the report from the Confederate Archives.
                    There are 2 vouchers mentioned-I have examined both. I think the one for hire of
                    wagon $3.15 was signed by claimant-the signatures to the receipt bears a
                    striking resemblance to that <add hand="h1" place="inline">made</add> by the claimant to his petition.</p>
                <p>Respectfully submitted, <name type="other"><abbr expan="William">Wm.</abbr> J.
                        Rannells</name>, Assistant Attorney.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>Claimant's Brief on Merits</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS. December Term 1892-93</p>
                <p>JONAS WAMPLER VS THE UNITED STATES, No. 8808 Cong.</p>
                <p>STATEMENT OF CASE</p>
                <p>The claimant in this case resided in Augusta Co. Virginia, during the war; he
                    presented his claim to the Commissioners of Claims amounting to one hundred and
                    sixty two dollars. The claim was disallowed by the Commissioners and reported to
                    Congress, for the reason that the Commissioners were not convinced of the taking
                    of the property.</p>
                <p>The claim was transmitted to the Court by the Committee on War Claims, House of
                    Representatives, under the provisions of the Bowman act.</p>
                <p>Claimant has been found loyal by the court.</p>
                <p>BRIEF ON MERITS:</p>
                <p>1 barrel of flour, $6.00; 1 bay horse, 150.00; 10 bushels of oats and corn, at 60
                    cts, 6.00; $162.00</p>
                <p>Taken by General Hunter, on or about June 1864.</p>
                <p>The following testimony was taken while the claim was pending before the
                    Commissioners of Claims.</p>
                <p>This testimony was taken in August 1871 before a Special Commissioner of the
                    Commissioners of Claims.</p>
                <p>JONAS WAMPLER Testifies resided in Augusta Co. Va. during the war; occupation
                    farmer; Did not change my residence from Augusta Co. Virginia during the war.</p>
                <p>Testifies as to loyalty. Page 1.</p>
                <p>Claimant does not testify as to the taking of his property.</p>
                <p>MARTHA A. MYERS Testifies age 38; residence Augusta Co. Virginia. Occupation
                    housekeeper; Saw the horse taken and know all the articles named in claimants
                    petition were taken. The property was taken by the union soldiers under command
                    of Gen. Hunter; saw the horse ridden away Do not know how the other articles
                    were taken off. The horse was taken to <orig reg="Staunton">Stanton</orig>; told
                    me they took the horse because they needed him.</p>
                <p>His horse was broken down; was complaint made at the time,and the officer said if
                    he would go to <orig reg="Staunton">Stanton</orig> he could get it; did not get
                    it. Page 5.</p>
                <p>No receipt was given. The property was taken in the day time between ten and
                    twelve o'clock; the army was not camped near there; the horse was in good
                    condition; well worth the price charged by claimant and the articles are at
                    reasonably fair prices. Thought if it was taken for some purpose necessary,the
                    government ought to pay for it. Think it was taken under order of some officer.</p>
                <p>Questioned by Commissioner as to loyalty. Pages 6 and 7.</p>
                <p>SARAH J. CLARK Testifies age 31; residence Augusta Co. Virginia; Housekeeper.
                    Known claimant all my life. The horse charged for was in good condition and
                    fully worth what claimant has charged. Also saw the other articles taken, and
                    the prices charged are low.</p>
                <p>The balance of this deposition relates to loyalty. Page 8</p>
                <p>The following testimony has been taken since the reference of the claim to the
                    Court. This testimony was taken on Feb. 18th, 1895.</p>
                <p>JONAS WAMPLER testifies: farmer; age 81; residence Augusta Co., Va. This property
                    was taken by the Federal army the 8th of June, I think, '64, the second day
                    after the battle of Piedmont. The soldiers that took my horse went to Staunton
                    after the battle, and then returned towards Piedmont, passing my house. My
                    horses were in the field in sight of my house, about one hundred and fifty yards
                    from my barn. They went into the field and took the horse named, and took it off
                    with them. I saw them take it, and watched them take it away as long as they
                    were in sight. One of the soldiers rode the horse off. A whole company, or a
                    number of soldiers of the Federal army, were passing along the road, and one of
                    them left the road, and went into the field and took the horse as I have stated.
                    (P. 1). It was a bay mare, I called doll, about six years old, in good
                    condition, and worth at least $150.00, in silver at that time. The flour was
                    taken at the same time by the soldiers of the same army, from my house,--a
                    barrel of flour, I was given a receipt for it at the time, which I still have,
                    and will file it with this deposition,and mark it exhibit "A". It is somewhat
                    mutilated, but that is the condition it was in when given to me. It was worth
                    $6.00 That is that Flour was selling for at that time. I got that for other
                    flour that I sold about that time. The oats and corn they took at the same time
                    out of my granery. They gathered it up and put it in sacks, and the size of the
                    sacks, they took about ten bushels. Ten bushels of oats and corn were wort at
                    least $6 at that time in that neighborhood.. I asked Gen. Hunter who commanded
                    at the battle of Piedmont, which was fought about five miles from my house, and
                    with whom I was in conversation about the time these things were taken, if I
                    could not get some protection against the soldiers taking my things, and
                    property. He asked me if I was not a member of the Dunkard Church. I told him I
                    was. He said he believed all the members of the Dunkard Church were Union men. I
                    told him I was a Union man. He sent me a guard to protect my property after
                    that. I never got any of this property back. Nor never got any pay for any of
                    it.</p>
                <p>CROSS-EXAMINATION. I can't tell at this time how many sacks of oats and corn I
                    saw taken, it has been so long. I just have to guess at the amount and value as
                    I can remember it now. (P. 2).</p>
                <p>JOS. NISEWANDER testifies: carpenter; age 77; residence Augusta Co., Va Not
                    interested or related. On June 6th, '64 I lived <del hand="h1">in</del> not a quarter of a
                    mile from where I live now, and about 3/4 of a mile from Jonas <orig
                        reg="Wampler's">Wamplers</orig>. I have seen the mare that the Federals took
                    from the claimant several times. She was a fine mare, and worth about $160 or
                    $150.</p>
                <p>CROSS-EXAMINATION WAIVED. (P. 3).</p>
                <p>THOS. R. MYERS testifies: Farmer; age 44; residence Augusta Co., Va. Not
                    interested or related. On June 6th, '64 I lived in Augusta Co., Va., and about a
                    quarter of a mile from Mr. <orig reg="Wampler's">Wamplers</orig>. I did not see
                    them take the mare from claimant's premises, but saw Gen. Hunter's men with her.
                    I saw one of the men riding her, I recognized her as Jonas Wampler's mare. He
                    rode her to my father's house. My mother recognized her too, and told the man he
                    ought not have taken her; that Mr. Wampler was a good Union man. The soldier
                    remarked that he would get well paid for her. That he had taken her because he
                    needed her. There was a large body of soldiers at the time passing my father's
                    house--several hundred, I should suppose, from whom the man in possession of the
                    mare rode off and came to the house. I saw officers among them, whom I
                    recognized by their uniforms as such. This was as they returned from Staunton
                    towards Piedmont, the second day after the battle. She was in good order, and a
                    good mare. I don't know her exact age, but know she was a young mare. From the
                    way horses were rating at that time she was worth from $150 to $175. (P. 4).</p>
                <p>CROSS-EXAMINATION WAIVED</p>
                <p>Exhibit "A" is to the following effect: "Curtin Creek, Va., June 6th, 1864. This
                    is to certify that I have taken from Jonas Wampler one barrel of flour by order
                    of Maj. Gen. Hunter, for the use of the U.S. Govt."</p>
                <p>This receipt <orig reg="is">os</orig> so badly mutilated that it is impossible to
                    make out the name signed to same.</p>
                <p>SUMMARY</p>
                <p>The barrel of flour charged for is shown to have been taken and appropriated to
                    the use of the army, not only by the testimony of the witnesses, but by the
                    receipt on file.</p>
                <p>That the horse charged for was taken and used by the army is shown by the
                    testimony of Martha A. Myers, who also details the circumstances under which the
                    horse was taken, that is to supply, the place of one broken down in service.</p>
                <p>Also by the testimony of Sarah J. Clark.</p>
                <p>The testimony of the claimant shows that the Federal soldiers took the horse from
                    the claimant's field one of the soldiers riding the horse off with the command
                    describes the animal, as about six years old, in good condition, and worth at
                    least $150.00</p>
                <p>Mr. Nisewander testifies that he saw the mare taken by the Federals by the
                    claimant, that she was fine, and worth about $150 or $160.</p>
                <p>Thos. H. Myers saw the mare in the use of the Federals, and recognized her, says
                    whe was in good order young, good animal, and from the way horses were rating at
                    that time was worth from $150 to $175.00</p>
                <p>The ten bushels of oats and corn is proven by the testimony of Sarah J. Clark,
                    who saw the corn and oats taken, by the testimony of the claimant, who estimates
                    the quantity by the size of the sack, says there was ten bus., worth at that
                    time 60 cts. per bu.</p>
                <p>It is submitted that the proof justifies a finding for 1 barrel flour, $6.00; 1
                    bay horse, 150.00; 10 bus. oats and corn, 6.00; Total $162.00</p>
                <p>Respectfully Submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> ATTY FOR <abbr
                        expan="CLAIMANT">CL'M'T</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>Defendant's Brief on Merits</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS</p>
                <p>Jonas Wampler v. The United States, No 8808 Cong.</p>
                <p>DEFENDANTS' BRIEF ON MERITS.</p>
                <p>The brief of claimant's counsel compiles the evidence fairly.</p>
                <p>The case is this: While General Hunter's army was passing along the road near
                    claimant's farm, some of the soldiers left the ranks, to steal a horse, and at
                    the same time stole a barrel of flour and ten bushels of corn and oats they
                    found in the barn.</p>
                <p>Claimant produced a mutilated receipt given for the flour, and states that it is
                    now in the same condition it was when he received it in 1864. It will be noticed
                    that the soldier was careful to tear his name off the receipt. This
                    circumstance, taken in connection with the fact that claimant states that the
                    corn and oats were taken off "in sacks," and does not suggest that the flour was
                    not also carried away in sacks, forces the conviction that he was visited by
                    stragglers, and suffered the usual depredations incident to living along the
                    line of a marching army. This was the view taken by the commissioners, who say:</p>
                <p>"It seems that the person who took the horse, promised that he would return it,
                    if he could get another. This does not seem very much like the taking was with
                    due authority for the use of the army."</p>
                <p>(The claimant had not then, himself, testified respecting his loss of property,
                    when the claim was before the Commission.)</p>
                <p>It is submitted that the proof is not sufficient to sustain a finding that any
                    property of the claimant was "taken for the use of the army."</p>
                <p>Respy Sub. <name type="other">Charles W. Russell</name></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                <byline>Claimant's Requests for Findings of Fact</byline>
                <p>IN THE COURT OF CLAIMS, DECEMBER TERM 1894-1895</p>
                <p>Jonas Wampler, vs. The United States No. 8808 Cong.</p>
                <p>CLAIMANT'S REQUESTS FOR FINDINGS OF FACT</p>
                <p>The claimant, considering the facts hereafter set forth to be proven, and deeming
                    them material to the due presentation of this claim in the finding of fact,
                    requests the Court to find the same as follows:</p>
                <p>I. That the claimant, Jonas Wampler, a citizen of the United States residing in
                    Augusta Co, Va., did not give any aid or comfort to the rebellion during the
                    late war, but was throughout that war loyal to the Government of the United
                    States:</p>
                <p>II. That during the said period there was taken from him by the military forces
                    of the United States for their use, the following stores and supplies, of the
                    values stated, to wit: 1 barrel of flour, $6.00; 1 bay horse, 150.00; 10 <abbr
                        expan="bushels">bus.</abbr> oats and corn, 6.00; Total $162.00</p>
                <p>III. That no payment has ever been made for said stores and supplies or any
                    portion thereof.</p>
                <p><name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name>, <abbr expan="Attorney">Atty.</abbr> for
                    Claimant</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                <byline>Reply to Defendant's Brief on Merits</byline>
                <p>COURT OF CLAIMS. DECEMBER TERM 1896-97.</p>
                <p>Jonas Wampler, vs The United states No. 8808 Cong.</p>
                <p>REPLY TO <abbr expan="DEFENDANT'S">DEFT'S</abbr> BRIEF ON MERITS</p>
                <p>The position of defendant's attorney that the stores and supplies in this case
                    were stolen, that the taking of the same was merely a matter of depredation is
                        <orig reg="totally">totaly</orig> at varience with the facts. On the
                    contrary the proof shows that the property charged for was regularly taken in
                    the usual way in which property was appropriated by an army on the march. The
                    horse is traced to actual use, being rode by a soldier in the ranks. How could
                    evidence be more conclusive?</p>
                <p>The other items are flour, corn and oats, what the army actually needed and the
                    presumption is that they were taken for the use of the army.</p>
                <p>To devote further time to the discussion of this question would seem absolutely
                    useless and unnecessary</p>
                <p>There is no defense, and no one knows this better than the attorney for the Govt.</p>
                <p>Respectfully Submitted, <name type="other">Gilbert Moyers</name> ATTY. FOR <abbr
                        expan="CLAIMANT">C'L'M'T.</abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                <byline>Findings of Fact</byline>
                <p>COURT OF CLAIMS (Congressional Case No. 8808.)</p>
                <p>Jonas Wampler, vs. The United States</p>
                <p>STATEMENT OF CASE</p>
                <p>The claim in the above-entitled case for supplies, or stores, alleged to have
                    been taken by or furnished to the military forces of the United States, for
                    their use during the late war for the suppression of the rebellion, was
                    transmitted to the Court by the Committee on War Claims of the House of
                    Representatives on the 23rd day of March 1892.</p>
                <p>On a preliminary inquiry the Court, on the 3rd day of January 1893, found that
                    the person alleged to have furnished the supplies or stores, or from whom they
                    were alleged to have been taken, was loyal to the Government of the United
                    States throughout said war.</p>
                <p>The case was brought to a hearing on its merits on the 8th day of February 1897.
                    Gilbert Moyers Esq., appeared for claimant, and the Attorney General, by Charles
                    W. Russell Esq., his assistant, and under his direction, appeared for the
                    defense and protection of the interests of the United States.</p>
                <p>The claimant in his petition makes the following allegations:</p>
                <p>That he is a citizen of the United States residing in Annex, Augusta County,
                    State of Virginia, where he resided during the late war of the rebellion; that
                    at different times during said period the United States forces, by proper
                    authority, took from him quartermaster stores and commissary supplies of the
                    value of $162.00, and appropriated the same to the use of the United States
                    Army, as follows:</p>
                <p>By command of Major General Hunter, June 1864. 1 barrel flour, $6.00; 1 light bay
                    mare 5 or 6 years old No.1, 150.00; 10 bus. oats and corn and chop, 6.00;
                    Aggregating in value $162.00</p>
                <p>The Court, upon the evidence and after considering the briefs and arguments of
                    counsel on both sides, makes the following Finding of Fact.</p>
                <p>There were taken from the claimant's farm in Augusta County, State of Virginia,
                    in June 1864, by the military forces of the United States, for the use of the
                    Army, stores and supplies of those above described which at the time and place
                    of taking were reasonably worth the sum of ($135) one hundred and thirty five
                    dollars.</p>
                <p>It does not appear that any payment has been made for any part thereof.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
