<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0539"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0539">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Medley Moore,
                    1874, Claim No. 12124</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of medley moore, 1874 claim no 12124</title>
        <author>Moore, Medley</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 13</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0539</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498426</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Medley Moore, 1874,
                            Claim No. 12124</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of medley moore, 1874 claim no 12124</title>
            <author>Medley Moore</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche #1486</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1874">1874</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Prisons/Prisoners, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0539T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Medley Moore filed this claim in 1874 for $184.57, claiming the Union army under
                    General Hunter's command took one horse,one cow and bacon in 1864. Medley was a
                    41 year old farmer who was arrested and detained nine months in 1862 by
                    Confederate officials. He went North to West Virginia and the Pennsylvania
                    afterwards only returning to Augusta in 1865. The claim was disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Sorrel Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$95.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$95.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One fat cow</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$50.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>315 pounds of bacon at 12 ct.</cell>
                            <cell>$39.57</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$39.57</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>None Given</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Medley Moore</byline>
                <p>United States of America State of Virginia</p>
                <p>I, W.G. Riley, a commissioner selected and designated by the <abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commis.</abbr> of Claims appointed under the Act of
                    Congress of March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi> 1871 to take and record
                    testimony. Do hereby certify that the reason for taking the following
                    depositions is and the fact is the matter of claim of Medley Moore, Vs. United
                    States of America and the witnesses herein named being material and necessary,
                    being first duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1st Witness says. I resided in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> my occupation was a farmer. I am 41 years old.</p>
                <p>2d Witness says I resided part of the time in <abbr expan="West Virginia"
                    >W.Va.</abbr> and part in Pennsylvania. I was part of the time a Butcher, and
                    part a Bar keeper.</p>
                <p>3d Witness says I never passed beyond the military lines of the <abbr
                        expan="United">U.</abbr> States or into the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4th Witness say. I never took any oath of allegiance to the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5th Witness says I have taken an Amnesty oath at Wheeling <abbr
                        expan="West Virginia">W.Va.</abbr> in 1864 I have not been pardoned by the
                    President</p>
                <p>6th Witness says I never was directly or indirectly engaged or employed in the
                    civil service of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>7th Witness says I never held any office of trust, profit or honor in the
                    Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>9th Witness says I never was in the military and Naval service of the Confederate
                    States in any manner</p>
                <p>10th Witness says I never had any thing to do with the Confederacy in any way
                    whatever.</p>
                <p>14th Witness says I never was engaged in blockade running or illicit traffic or
                    intercourse between the lines, nor never was interested, in any wares goods or
                    merchandise, brought into or exported from the so called Confederate States
                    during the war.</p>
                <p>15th Witness says I left the Confederate <del hand="h1">the 19th</del> States, and went to
                        <abbr expan="West Virginia">W.Va.</abbr> thence to Pennsylvania and returned
                    to <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> in the fall of 1865.</p>
                <p>16th Witness says I never was interested in any vessel used in navigating the
                    waters of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> or Confederacy.</p>
                <p>17th Witness say I was arrested by the Confederate Government in 1862, in <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and kept under arrest nine months, part of the
                    time in Jail. I took no oath to the Confederacy to get my release. I never was
                    arrested by the <abbr expan="United">U.</abbr> States.</p>
                <p>18th Witness says <del hand="h1">The</del> I lost a little property by the Confederates,
                    but never was paid for it.</p>
                <p>19th Witness says I never was threatened with damage to person family or property
                    on account of my Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>21st Witness says I was a teamster for the United States government during the
                    war.</p>
                <p>23d Witness says I had a brother in the Confederate Army, and an Uncle and
                    Cousins in the Union Army. I did contribute money to a Cousin in the Union Army.</p>
                <p>24th Witness says I have never owned any Confederate bonds, nor done anything to
                    support the credit of the Confederacy</p>
                <p>25th Witness says I never given any aid or comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26th Witness says I never was engaged in making raids into the United States from
                    Canada, or in the destruction of the Commerce of the United States.</p>
                <p>27th Witness says I never was engaged directly or indirectly in holding in
                    custody any prisoners of War taken by the rebel States or Government.</p>
                <p>28th Witness says I never persecuted any <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> on account of their loyalty to
                    the United States.</p>
                <p>29th Witness says I was a paroled prisoner at Harrisonburg, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> in 1862, by an officer of <abbr expan="General"
                        >Genl.</abbr> Bank's command. I was afterwards arrested by the Confederates,
                    and held for nine months, part of the time in prison.</p>
                <p>30th Witness says I never held an office in the United States, nor nor educated
                    at any of the Military or Naval schools of the <abbr expan="United States"
                    >U.S.</abbr></p>
                <p>31st Witness says I received no pass from the Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>32d Witness says I was under no disablities under the 14th <abbr expan="Article"
                        >Art.</abbr> Constitution of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> I
                    have held no office since the War.</p>
                <p>33d Witness says I sympathized with the Union and not for the rebellion, I voted
                    against the ordinance of Secession, and after secession was adopted I went for
                    the Union and not for the State.</p>
                <p>34th Witness says I declare that from the beginning of hostilities against the
                    United States, my sympathies were constantly with the Union and that I did
                    nothing by word or deed to injure said course, and that I felt at all times
                    willing, so far as my means and power and the circumstances permitted, to aid
                    the United States.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>August 24th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Medley Moore</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Margaret A. Pforr</byline>
                <p>Margaret A. Pforr, a witness interviewed by Claimant to prove the taking of the
                    property named in the petition, being duly sworn answers as follows.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1st Witness says, I am 33 years old. I reside in Staunton, Va. and am a
                    house keeper. I did not see the property taken, but the property of the claimant
                    was at his house when the Union troops came in, and was missing after they left
                    and not seen afterwards. I do not know, who took the property but believe it was
                    taken by the United States soldiers, then encamped at Staunton, and belonging to
                    the command of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter.</p>
                <p>15th Witness says, the horse was in <del hand="h1">a</del> good condition and fine looking.
                    I think he was worth what is charged in claimants petition. The Cow, was very
                    fat and worth fifty dollars. There must have been over three (300) hundred
                    pounds, I suppose it was worth twelve &amp; a half cents a pound.</p>
                <p>19th Witness says I think it was taken for the use of the United States soldiers.</p>
                <p>22d Witness says I think it would be right for the Government to pay for it, as I
                    have no doubt they needed it and used it.</p>
                <p>23d Witness says I cannot say that the property was taken by persons authorized
                    to do so.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>Aug. 24 '71</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">M A Pforr</name>
                </p>
                <p>Margaret A. Pforr introduced to prove the loyalty of claimant being duly sworn
                    answers as follows</p>
                <p>Ques. 1st Witness says I am 33 years old, I reside in Staunton, Va. by occupation
                    a housekeeper. I have known the claimant all my life. I live near him. I did not
                    see him often during the war, as he went to the North. I believe him to have
                    been <del hand="h1">a</del> loyal to the United States Government and he was so regarded
                    by his neighbors. He done nothing for the Confederacy except what he was obliged
                    to do, and was arrested by the Confederate Government for his Union sentiments
                    and kept in prison for 8 or 9 months. I am satisfied that he could not have
                    established any claim to loyalty to the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>August 24th 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">M A Pforr</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn &amp; subscribed before me this 24th day of August 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">W. G. Riley</name> (seal)<lb/>United States Commissioner and
                    Special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>N.K. Trout and A. Chapman <abbr expan="Esquires">Esqs.</abbr></byline>
                <p>Staunton July 9, 1876</p>
                <p>My dear Sir,</p>
                <p>Do you know any thing about the accompanying enquiry? See to it and as to its
                    merits. I have no recollection whatever about the case.</p>
                <p>Yours Truly</p>
                <p><name type="other">N K Trout</name><lb/><name type="other">A Chapman</name>
                Esq</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
