<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0300"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0300">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of James W. Beard,
                    August 21, 1871, Claim No. 15,991</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of james w beard, august 21 1871 claim no 15 991</title>
        <author>Beard, James W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 18 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0300</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498367</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of James Beard, August
                            21, 1871, Claim No. 15,991</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of james beard, august 21 1871 claim no 15 991</title>
            <author>James Beard</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche # 948</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1873">1873</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0300T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>James W. Beard of Mint Spring, Augusta Co., Va., filed this claim in August 21,
                    1871, for $108, claiming that Union troops confiscated 13 tanned calf skins, 2
                    saddles, and 8 bushels of corn. The claim was disallowed December 8, 1873.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <!--Enter Items here (using the tag in the toolbar) between the "table" tags-->
                        <row>
                            <cell> 13 tanned <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> calf skins </cell>
                            <cell>$55.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$55.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 saddle new</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 saddle nearly new</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>8 bushels of corn at $1</cell>
                            <cell>$8.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$8.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <!--Enter the Claim Summary here between paragraph ("&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;") tags (all of which should be between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>Claimant is forty three years old, and was within Conscript age during the War.
                    He seems to have been detailed as a tanner to prepare supplies for the
                    Confederate Army as well as we can gather from his answers to questions, and was
                    exempt therefore from service in the field. This employment was inconsistent
                    with loyalty in itself, but aside from that the evidence of loyalty is not
                    satisfactory. He had two brothers in the Rebel army and we see no clear
                    indication that his sentiments differed from theirs. Moreover there is no
                    evidence that the articles charged were taken as supplies for the Army or were
                    so used - One witness swears that thirteen tanned calf skins were taken by
                    soldiers of Hunter's Command but there is no evidence or inferences fairly
                    deducible from circumstances that they were taken for the use of the Army.
                        <del hand="h1">There</del> A boy, now 15 years old and then seven or eight swears that
                    some soldiers came in the night and took two saddles and eight bushels of Corn.
                    That is all the evidence in support of the claim and it is of course utterly
                    insufficient and unsatisfactory and we therefore reject it.</p>
            </div1>
            <!--Enter each person's testimony here!-->
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>James W. Beard</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>United States of America</p>
                <p>State of Virginia</p>
                <p>I W.G. Riley a commissioner selected and designated by the Commissioners of
                    Claims appointed under the Act of Congress of March 3<hi rend="super"
                    >rd</hi> 1871 to take and record testimony Do hereby certify that the reason for
                    taking the following depositions is, and the fact is, the matter of claims of
                    James W. Beard, vs. the United States of America. And the witness herein named
                    being first duly sworn answereth as follows -</p>
                <p>Quest 1. Witness says - I am forty three years old. I reside in Augusta County
                    Virginia, by occupation a tanner. Prior to the 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>
                    of April 1861, I resided at Mint Spring, Augusta County Virginia.</p>
                <p>2 Witness says - In October 1864, I left the Confederacy, and went into the Union
                    lines, to the State of Ohio</p>
                <p>3 Witness says - I did not pass beyond the Military or Naval lines of the United
                    States, and enter the Rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4 Witness says - I don't think I ever took any oath of allegiance to the
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5 Witness says - I have never taken any amnesty oath that I know of</p>
                <p>6 Witness says - I never was directly or indirectly connected with the civil
                    service of the Confederate States</p>
                <p>7 Witness says - I never held any office of honor or profit, under the
                    Confederate Government</p>
                <p>8 Witness says - I never held any clerkship or employment of any kind under the
                    Confederacy. I never was in the Military or Naval service of the so called
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>10 Witness says - I never was connected in any way with the Confederate
                    Government voluntarily</p>
                <p>11 Witness says - I was ordered to finish some leather, being a tanner, or go
                    into the Army. I did finish some leather sooner than go into the Army that was
                    all I have ever done for the Confederacy</p>
                <p>12 Witness says - I have never done anything except finish some leather as stated
                    above for the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says - I never was engaged in blockade running</p>
                <p>15 Witness says - In 1864 I went into the Union lines. I went to keep out of the
                    Confederate Army. I was absent six months. I was part of the time engaged in
                    tanning, and part engaged in a foundry</p>
                <p>16 Witness says - I never was owner or part owner of any vessel, in my life</p>
                <p>17 Witness says - I never was arrested by the Confederate Government. I never was
                    arrested by the United States Government</p>
                <p>18 Witness says - None of my property was ever taken by the Confederate
                    Authorities</p>
                <p>19 Witness says - I was told after I went into the Union lines that I was
                    threatened on account of my Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>20 Witness says - I never was molested or injured on account of my Union
                    sentiments</p>
                <p>21 Witness says - I don't think I ever contributed any thing to aid the United
                    States Government except that I worked in a tannery that furnished leather to
                    the United States Government</p>
                <p>23 Witness says - I had two brothers in the Confederate army. I did nothing to
                    supply them with Military equipments</p>
                <p>24 Witness says - I have never owned any Confederate bonds, I never did any to
                    support the Confederacy. I have never given aid or comfort to the Rebellion.</p>
                <p>26 Witness says - I never was engaged in making raids into the United States from
                    Canada, or any where else.</p>
                <p>29 Witness says - I never was a parolled prisoner of the United States</p>
                <p>30 Witness says - I never held any office in the Army or Navy of the United
                    States; I never was educated at West Point or the Naval Academy.</p>
                <p>31 Witness says - They gave me a pass to go to Millborough for my sister. I did
                    not use the pass -</p>
                <p>32 Witness says - I was under no disabilities imposed by the fourteenth
                    Amendments to the Constitution of the United States. I do hold the office of
                    Post Master under the United States Government. I took the Iron Clad oath.</p>
                <p>33 Witness says - At the beginning of the Rebellion, I sympathized with the Union
                    cause and not with the Rebellion. I don't know whether I voted for the ordinance
                    of secession or not.</p>
                <p>34 Witness says - I solemly declare from the beginning of hostilities against the
                    United States to the end thereof, My sympathies were constantly with the Cause
                    of the United States and never of my own free will did anything, to injure said
                    cause, but was ready and willing at all times to aid the Union so far as I was
                    able and further the witness saith not August the 21st 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">James W. Beard</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>John Montgomery</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>John Montgomery a witness introduced by the Claimant to prove the taking of the
                    property, being first duly sworn answereth as follows -</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness says - I am fifty nine years old, I reside in Augusta County Va.
                    by trade a blacksmith.</p>
                <p>I was present when thirteen tanned <unclear>kiph</unclear> skins calf were taken
                    mentioned in the claimants petition. I did not see any paddles or corn taken</p>
                <p>4 Witness says - They were taken from the house of the Witness. The claimant got
                    me to take them to my house to keep the Confederates from taking them they were
                    taken by soliders under <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Hunter</p>
                <p>6 Witness says - I think there were some officers present when they were taken. I
                    did I do not know their names - the property that I saw taken was removed on
                    horse back.</p>
                <p>12 Witness says - No receipt was asked for and none was given</p>
                <p>13 Witness says - The property was taken in the day time about the middle of the
                    day.</p>
                <p>14 Witness says - The Army was not encamped in the neighborhood when the property
                    was taken.</p>
                <p>15 Witness says - The property was in good condition. I don't know what it was
                    worth</p>
                <p>19 Witness says - I don't know what they were taken for</p>
                <p>22 Witness says - I don't know what use they were intended for, and I don't know
                    whether the Government ought to pay for them or not, and further the deponent
                    saith not August the 21st 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Montgomery</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Frank Beard</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>Frank Beard a witness introduced to prove the taking of the property being first
                    duly sworn answereth as follows -</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness says - I am fifteen years old. I live in Augusta County, by trade
                    a tanner. I saw two saddles and eight bushels of corn taken by the United States
                    soldiers, it belonged to the Claimant - the property was taken from the
                    claimant's house in the night, no receipt was given and none asked for the
                    property that I saw taken was in good condition. The saddles were almost new,
                    one worth twenty five dollars and the other twenty I do not know what the corn
                    was worth. I think the Government ought to pay for it, after taking it - further
                    the deponent saith not August 21st 1871</p>
                <p>X (his mark)</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>John Engleman</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>John Engleman a witness introduced by the Claimant for proof as to loyalty being
                    first duly sworn answereth as follows -</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness says - I am sixty years old. I reside in Augusta County Va, by
                    occupation a farmer. I have known the Claimant twenty years. I live about five
                    miles from him. I saw him often during the war, so far as I know he was a loyal
                    man to the United States. I don't know what the neighbors said about him, he was
                    too loyal to the United States Government to have been considered loyal to the
                    Confederacy if it had succeeded and further the deponent saith not August the
                    21st 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Engleman</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>William T. Fauber</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>William T. Fauber a witness introduced by the claimant to prove loyalty being
                    first duly sworn answereth as follows -</p>
                <p>Quest 1 Witness says - I am forty six years old. I live in Augusta County
                    Virginia, by occupation a farmer. I have known the claimant twenty five years. I
                    saw him often during the war until I went away - I always considered him loyal
                    to the United States Government. He was so considered by his neighbors. He was
                    too loyal to the United States Government to have been considered loyal to the
                    Confederacy if it had been maintained as a separate Government. He told me if
                    the Confederate States gained their independence he would not have stayed in the
                    Confederacy and further this deponent saith not August the 21st 1871.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">William T. Fauber</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 21st day of August 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>(seal)</p>
                <p>United States Commissioner and special <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for
                    the State of Va.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>Archive Office,</p>
                <p>WAR DEPARTMENT,</p>
                <p>Jan 31, 187</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 268</p>
                <p>Case of James W. Beard, Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>Sold to <abbr expan="Confederate">C.</abbr> States one <abbr expan="dozen"
                    >doz.</abbr> sheepskins one hogskin + 6 lbs Deers Hair amounting in all to
                    $19.00</p>
                <p>Paid at Staunton 1862 by Capt. R. Turk a Q.M. C.S. Army</p>
                <p>His signature is on voucher on file in this office</p>
                <p>
                    <seg type="postscript">Dec. 8/73 Rejected</seg>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>
                    <seg type="postscript">Howell</seg>
                </p>
                <p>Archive Office,</p>
                <p>WAR DEPARTMENT,</p>
                <p>October 31st, 1873</p>
                <p>Book 2, Letters Sent, page 440</p>
                <p>Case of James W. Beard of Virginia.</p>
                <p>(No. 15.991)</p>
                <p>This claimant had a contract with the Rebel Government to furnish leather. Had a
                    tannery in the county of Augusta.</p>
                <p>Writes to the <abbr expan="Secretary">Sec.</abbr> of War from Staunton Va. on
                    22nd Oct. 1862 representing his inability to fulfill his contract for the want
                    of hands and laborers. Asks the details of John J. Beard as a volunteer in 25th
                    Regt. Va. Vols. to assist him in carrying on the business.</p>
                <p>Attached to Mr. Beard's letter there is a certificate signed by a number of
                    inhabitants of Augusta Co. certifying that Jas. W. Beard is proprietor of a
                    tannery in said Co. &amp;c.</p>
                <p>Also certificate of one R. Turk Asst. Q.M. at Staunton Va. that Mr. B. had been
                    furnishing leather to the <abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr> for the last six
                    or eight months and had at the date of his letter a large quantity of leather to
                    finish.</p>
                <p>(W.D. 1511)</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>Archive Office,</p>
                <p>WAR DEPARTMENT,</p>
                <p>April 15, 1874,</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 2</p>
                <p>Case of James W. Beard of Augusta Co.</p>
                <p>(No. 15.991)</p>
                <p>Citizens of the Co. of Augusta. Va. petition for exemption of Thos. Montgomery
                    who is a blacksmith by trade and much needed in said Co.</p>
                <p>"He was prompt in answering the call of his Country and has rendered nine months
                    service, we therefore pray that Thomas A. Montgomery may be exempted to work at
                    his trade for the benefit of the agricultural interests of the country."</p>
                <p>(W.D.S. 1862, W. No. 548, In file)</p>
                <p>
                    <seg type="postscript">Dec 8/73 Reported to Congress rejected</seg>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <!--Enter the testimony of one person here in paragraph tags (between the "div1" tags)-->
                <p>Archive Office,</p>
                <p>WAR DEPARTMENT,</p>
                <p>Feb 28, 1878</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 268</p>
                <p>Case of Jms W. Beard of Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>Bill &amp; voucher for furnishing and blacking 100 sides of leather at $1.00
                    per side also to finishing 48 sides at 50 cts per side amounting to $124.00</p>
                <p>Paid at Staunton May 27th 1862 by Capt. R. Turk a Q.M. C.S.Army</p>
                <p>Also for finishing 12 sides collar leather for $5.00</p>
                <p>
                    <seg type="postscript">Dec 8/73 Rejected</seg>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
