<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0511"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0511">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John Wine, Jr.,
                    1879, Claim No. 18728</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john wine, jr 1879 claim no 18728</title>
        <author>Wine, John, Jr.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 30 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0511</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498398</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John Wine, Jr., 1879,
                            Claim No. 18728</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john wine, jr 1879 claim no 18728</title>
            <author>John Wine, Jr.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington
                            D.C., RG 123 Congressional Jurisdiction #8611</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1879">1879</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Military Authority, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0511T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John Wine, Jr. filed this claim in 1879 for $400, claiming General Torbit's Union
                    troops took 10 cattle in 1864. John was a 50 year old farmer who resided near
                    New Hope. After his exemption for furnishing goods to the Confederate Army was
                    revoked in October of 1864 he crossed through to Union lines and stayed in
                    Illinois until July of 1865. The claim was disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>10 Cattle</cell>
                            <cell>$400.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$400.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>Claimant swears that he did not vote for the adoption of the Ordinance of
                    Secession, but the Record of the Election shows that he did vote for the
                    adoption of the Ordinance of Secession. It also appears from his own testimony
                    that he voluntarily furnished a substitute before the Conscript Law was enacted,
                    and that after that he got a detail as a Farmer in the service of the
                    Confederate <abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> We reject the Claim.</p>
                <p><name type="other">AO Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name>, <name
                        type="other">O. Ferriss</name><abbr expan="Commissioners">Comm.</abbr> of
                    Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>John Wine, Jr.</byline>
                <p>Ques. 2. Ans. My residence then was at the same place where I now reside. I never
                    changed my residence. I was then and still am the owner of the farm upon which I
                    reside. I had at that time about 150 acres of cleared land and 90 acres in
                    timber, situated in Augusta County, about three miles <abbr expan="south east"
                        >S.E.</abbr> of New Hope on South River. I farmed all the time.</p>
                <p>Ques. 3. Ans. I did at no time pass the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr>
                    lines either Military or Naval and enter the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4. Ans. I never took any oath of allegiance to the so called Confederate
                    States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 5. Ans. I took an amnesty oath at New Creek Station in <abbr expan="West"
                        >W.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> in 1864 being forced to leave my
                    house or go into the rebel Army.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6. Ans. I never was in any way connected with the civil service of the
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 7. Ans. I never held any office, or place of trust or honor in the
                    Confederate governments <add hand="h1" place="inline">or</add> in any State or territory.</p>
                <p>Ques. 8. Ans. I held no clerkship, agency or employment of any kind, under or for
                    the Confederate government or army.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9. Ans. I never was in any capacity in the Military or Naval service of the
                    so called Confederate States, State or territory.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10. Ans. Never was an officer or soldier.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11. Ans. I never was in the State <orig reg="Militia">Malitia</orig> while
                    subordinate to the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12. Ans. I never belonged to any home guard or vigilance committee of any
                    kind whatever.</p>
                <p>Ques. 13. Ans. I was not conscripted.</p>
                <p>Ques. 14. Ans. I furnished no substitute.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15 &amp; 16. Ans. I was never employed on any Railroad nor aided in the
                    transportation of soldiers or any thing else for the aid and benefit of the
                    Confederacy. Nor in the Quarter Masters department, or any department at all of
                    the government, Military or Naval of the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 17. Ans. I never had charges at any stores or supplies for the use of the
                    Confederate Army, navy or government. I did not have charge of any trains,
                    teams, Wagons or any thing at all.</p>
                <p>Ques. 18. Ans. I never was in any service employment or business of any kind what
                        <orig reg="so ever">soever</orig> for the Confederate government or in aid
                    of the rebellion or of any of its agencies. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig>
                    any information.</p>
                <p>Ques. 19. Ans. I never was engaged or employed in the manufacture of any article
                    of any kind for the use of soldiers, Army, Navy or government of the
                    Confederacy.</p>
                <p>Ques. 20. Ans. I never was directly or indirectly employed, in collecting,
                    immpressing, purchase or sales of stores or supplies for the benefit of the
                    rebellion. I had no contract or share in any contract for any aid or benefit of
                    the rebellion.</p>
                <p>Ques. 21. Ans. I was not engaged in blockade running or illicit <orig
                        reg="traffic">traffick</orig> or intercourse between the lines or share of
                    goods wares or of any thing brought into or exported from the Confederate States
                    during the war.</p>
                <p>Ques. 22. Ans. I went through the lines the last of <abbr expan="October"
                    >Oct.</abbr> or first of <abbr expan="November">Nov.<hi rend="super"
                        >r</hi></abbr> 1864. I went to the State of Illinois. I went because I was
                    determined never to fight against the Union. I was absent about nine months. I
                    was a laborer on a farm. I returned in July 1865 to my residence in Augusta
                    County.</p>
                <p>Ques. 23. Ans. I never owned in whole or part any boat or vessel.</p>
                <p>Ques. 24. Ans. I never was arrested by either government.</p>
                <p>Ques. 25. Ans. The Confederate authorities took three of my horses, after I left
                    my home and gone through the lines. I never received any pay.</p>
                <p>Ques. 26. Ans. I was threatened with injury to my property this was in 1864 and
                    by persons named Kennerly. There was no damage done however.</p>
                <p>Ques. 27. Ans. I never was molested.</p>
                <p>Ques. 28. Ans. I never contributed to aid the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>Ques. 29. Ans. I had no opportunity to do anything.</p>
                <p>Ques. 30. Ans. I had none nearer than a cousin. I funished him nothing at all.</p>
                <p>Ques. 31. Ans. I never owned a Confederate bonds or had any interest or share in
                    any or any loans. I never did anything unless compelled to support the credit of
                    the Confederate states or the rebellion.</p>
                <p>Ques. 32. Ans. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> aid or comfort to the
                    rebellion.</p>
                <p>Ques. 33. Ans. Never made a raid of any kind or any purpose or engaged in the
                    destruction of any property of the United States.</p>
                <p>Ques. 34. Ans. I never held in custory any persons of any kind or for any
                    purpose.</p>
                <p>Ques. 35. Ans. I belonged to no society or association of any kind or for any
                    purpose.</p>
                <p>Ques. 36. Ans. I never was paroled.</p>
                <p>Ques. 37. Ans. I never held an office nor educated in any Military or Naval
                    School.</p>
                <p>Ques. 38. Ans. I never had a pass.</p>
                <p>Ques. 39. Ans. I was under no disabilities. I have held no office since the war.</p>
                <p>Ques. 40. Ans. I sympathised with the Union Cause. My feelings were always in
                    favor of the Union. My language always emphatic against the rebellion. I did not
                    vote for the ratification of the ordinance of secession. After the ordinance
                    passed I was still for the Union and since have voted with the Union party.</p>
                <p>Ques. 41. Ans. In conclusion, I do solemnly declare <add hand="h1" place="inline">that</add> from the
                    beginning of hostilities against the United States to the end thereof, my
                    sympathies were constantly with the the cause of the United States, and that I
                    never of my own free will and accord, did anything, or offered or sought or
                    attempted to do anything, by word or deed, to injure said cause or retard its
                    success, and was at all times, ready and willing when called upon, or if called
                    upon, to aid and assist the cause of the Union, or its supporters, so far as my
                    means and power and the circumstances of the case permitted.</p>
                <p>Taking of the property by same I was not present when the cattle were taken and
                    will have to rely upon the testimony of those who were present and saw them
                    taken, viz. Jacob Koiner and Sampson Pelter. The Cattle were ten in number on a
                    grazing farm about 8 miles from my residence. There were seven Steers and three
                    spayed heifers, nearly four years old, fat and of large size. They were fit for
                    any market. I think they would have grossed from 1050 <abbr expan="pounds">
                        <hi rend="super">lbs.</hi>
                    </abbr> to 1200 <abbr expan="pounds">
                        <hi rend="super">lbs.</hi>
                    </abbr> each, and worth in gold forty dollars a head. They were taken in
                    October, 1864. I made no effort to obtain a receipt. The Army was in command of
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Torbit and
                    camped at Waynesboro but had probably had left there before I heard of my cattle
                    being taken.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John Wine Jr.</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>Jacob Coiner Jr.</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Jacob Coiner Jr.</p>
                <p>Ans. to 1<hi rend="super">st</hi><abbr expan="general">gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> question.</p>
                <p>My name is Jacob Coiner jr. My residence near Waynesboro a farmer by occupation
                    and my age is 44 years. I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in
                    his claim.</p>
                <p>I was present and saw the cattle taken from the grazing farm of M<hi
                        rend="super">r.</hi> Yount, but at the time did not know whose cattle
                    they were, but supposed they belonged to M<hi rend="super">r.</hi> Yount.
                    I was under arrest at the time. They were driven out of the field and taken in
                    the direction of Waynesboro a distance of about three miles. I do not know that
                    they were taken to Waynesboro but suppose they were as the Army was then in Camp
                    at that place. I suppose there were not less than one hundred soldiers engaged
                    in taking the cattle. I suppose they were taken (at the farm) about one hour.
                    There was a man from Rockingham, a prisoner, but whose name I do not remember
                    present at the time. I do not remember of seeing Sampson Pelter.</p>
                <p>I heard the name of Sargeant Joice called by a superior officer and ordered I
                    think to take charge of the Cattle. I heard nothing said as to what they wanted
                    the cattle for. I did not see the cattle after they left the farm. I would
                    suppose from the condition of the cattle they were killed for beef. There was no
                    one to make complaint. The claimant lived some four or five miles from the
                    grazing farm. I know of no receipt at all. I did not hold any conversation with
                    officers or soldiers nor heard any in relation to taking the cattle.</p>
                <p>They were taken in the day time. I suppose one or two oclock P.M. There was no
                    concealment in taking the cattle. The Army commanded by Gen<hi
                        rend="super">l</hi>. Torbett was then in camp at Waynesboro <del hand="h1">I
                        think</del> They left that night I dont think they remained in camp over a
                    day &amp; night. I never heard the name of any Quartermaster. There had been
                    no battle or skirmish near that I recollect of. The cattle were in good beef
                    order. I do not know the age of the cattle but suppose 3 1/2 yeas old. From my
                    recollection of the cattle I would suppose they were worth forty dollars a head.
                    I suppose they would have grossed ten or eleven hundred pounds each. I have not
                    conversed with the claimant as to the value of the cattle.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Jacob Coiner Jr.</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Sampson Pelter</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Sampson Pelter</p>
                <p>Ans. First general question.</p>
                <p>My name is Sampson Pelter, my age is 38 years. I reside near Waynesboro, <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> my occupation a farmer. I am not related to the
                    claimant and have no interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Ans. I was present and saw the property charged by the claimant taken.
                    There were ten head of cattle. I think the most, if not all were steers. They
                    were taken from the grazing farm of <abbr expan="John">Jno.</abbr> Yount where
                    the claimant had them grazing. The ten head were driven off at the same time.</p>
                <p>Ques. 4. Ans. I do not know where the cattle were taken, nor do I recollect the
                    time they were taken by the Army in command of <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Torbit. It was in the fall of 1864, I
                    think, probably the month of October. I suppose there were 150 or 200 soldiers
                    engaged in driving the cattle off. They were at it, not longer than was
                    necessary to get the cattle together and start them.</p>
                <p>Ques. 5. Ans. I was alone at the time, but there were others, not far distant.
                        M<hi rend="super">r.</hi> Jacob Koiner, and two others who are now
                    dead.</p>
                <p>Ques. 6. Ans. There were officers present, Captains and Lieutenants, I heard no
                    names of Officers or regiments. I heard no orders given. When the Cattle were
                    driven up to where the Officers were standing they then moved off taking the
                    Cattle with them. But little was said. The cattle were driven off by the whole
                    company of Soldiers present.</p>
                <p>Ques. 9. Ans. The Cattle were started in the direction of Staunton, I did not
                    follow and do not know where they were taken.</p>
                <p>Ques. 10. Ans. I do not know what use they made of the Cattle, as I never saw
                    them after their removal from the grazing farm.</p>
                <p>Ques. 11. Ans. There was no complaint made by any one. No voucher or receipt
                    asked for or given.</p>
                <p>Ques. 12. Ans. There was no conversation that I heard. I had none and was alone.</p>
                <p>Ques. 13. Ans. The Cattle were taken in the daytime, I suppose between 10 A.M.
                    &amp; 2 P.M. There was no secrecy shown at all but taken as though they had
                    right to do so. The Army was encamped at Waynesboro about three (3) miles
                    distant from the grazing farm. The Army was in Command of <abbr expan="Generals"
                            >Gen<hi rend="super">ls.</hi></abbr> Torbit &amp; Wilson. I
                    think they remained in their Camp some two days and nights. There had been no
                    battle or skirmish near there. I did not hear the name of any Quartermaster.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15. Ans. The ten Cattle were large and fat. I do not know their age, but
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">they</add> were all big heavy cattle and fat. I reckon from my
                    knowledge of the cattle, that they were worth between forty and forty five
                    dollars a head, and would have readily brought forty dollars. I have never
                    talked with the claimant about the value of the cattle.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Sampson Pelter</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>Jacob W. Zirkle</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Jacob W. Zirkle</p>
                <p>Ans. to first general question.</p>
                <p>My name is Jacob W. Zirkle, my residence near New Hope, Augusta County, my age is
                    62 years and a farmer by occupation. I am not related to the claimant and have
                    no interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant about twenty two years. I resided about 1 3/4 miles
                    from him during the war. I was very intimate with him during that time. I
                    suppose I saw him once a week until he went through the lines, which was in
                    1864. We conversed about the war nearly every time we met and rejoiced over all
                    victories of the Union Army. I always found him bitterly opposed to the
                    rebellion, and always maintained that he never would take up arms against the
                    Union. That he would leave his home and go to the north, if forced to do so. I
                    do not recollect of talking to him in the presence of others. His Union
                    neighbors all had full confidence in his loyalty to the United States and the
                    Union cause. I do not believe he ever contributed or done anything voluntarily
                    in aid of the rebellion. He never owned any Confederate bonds that I know or
                    heard of. My own sympathies were with the Union, and as such I always felt that
                    I had the full sympathy of the claimant. His conduct throughout proved him an
                    honest and sincere adherent of the Union and its cause.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Jacob W. Zirkle</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>Jacob Coffman to prove loyalty</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Jacob Coffman</p>
                <p>Ans. to first <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l.</hi></abbr>
                    question.</p>
                <p>My name is Jacob Coffman, my age is 44 years. I reside near New Hope. I am a
                    farmer by occupation. I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in
                    his claim. I have known the claimant from boyhood. I lived the first two years
                    of the War about four miles from and in 1863 I moved to about 1 1/2 miles from
                    him. We were on very intimate terms of friendship. I saw him frequently and
                    talked with him on several occasions about the war. He always expressed
                    opposition to the rebellion, and said he would not fight against the Union. I
                    was an adherent to the Union, and always felt free to converse with him on the
                    subject of the war. The Union men of the neighborhood never doubted his true
                    loyalty to the Union. I never knew or heard of his doing anything in aid of the
                    rebellion. He went through the lines in 1864 and did not return until after the
                    close of the war.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Jacob Coffman</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>John S. Smith U.S. Special Agent</byline>
                <p>In the matter of the Claim of John Wine, Jr. No. 18728</p>
                <p>In this case, I submit the claimants own deposition only. I find that in the
                    beginning of the war, before there was any conscripting done here, claimant
                    hired a Subsitute &amp; put him in the Confederate Army, the claimant at the
                    time was not liable to be conscripted. That in 1863 when they commenced
                    conscripting men, So that he was liable, he got himself detailed a farmer, that
                    the deatil was made out &amp; signed by a Confederate official at Staunton.
                    That he delivered all &amp; everything he made in 1863 to the Confederate
                    Governemnt, except what he eat &amp; that he delivered a number of Head of
                    cattle to the Confederate Government in 1863. That at the end of 1863 he was
                    again detailed as a farmer, &amp; delivered all he made on his farm in 1864
                    to the Confedeate Government &amp; also delivered a number of head of cattle
                    in 1864. That they never paid him anything, he never aske<hi rend="super"
                        >d</hi> for pay, never attempted to get pay, did not expect pay. That he
                    gave it to them. That in 1862 he furnished a span of horses to Confederate <abbr
                        expan="Government">Gov<hi rend="super">t.</hi></abbr> &amp; got
                    paid for them &amp; that in 1864 they got another Span &amp; did not pay
                    him. That he left in 1864 in Oct. because the Confederate officers refused to
                    renew his detail as a farmer. That if they would have renewed it he would have
                    continued working his farm for the Confederate Government the same as he had
                    done. That he did not want to go into the Army. That it was too <hi
                        rend="underline">dangerous</hi> work for him, (not out of Sympathy for the
                    Federal Government) That he knows, that when he was detailed as a farmer, he was
                    much in the Confederate Service as though he was in the Army. That he testified
                    in his original papers, "that he was not in any way connected with the
                    Confederate Service" That the two Statements are inconsistent that one is
                    untrue, I find that his present Statement is true. That being so I find that the
                    Cattle charged in the account in this claim belonged to the Confederate
                    Government.</p>
                <p>After deliberation, I cannot find that the claimant is entitled to be paid. The
                    claim ought not be paid. Respectfully Submitted to <abbr expan="Honorable"
                    >Hon</abbr> Claim<hi rend="super">s</hi><abbr expan="Commission">Com<hi
                            rend="super">s.</hi></abbr></p>
                <p>Jno. S. Smith<name type="witness"/></p>
                <p>Washington, D.C. Special Agent</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>John Wine Jr.</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Wine Jr. taken at New Hope Augusta County <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a.</hi></abbr> February 27<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> 1878 and before Jno S. Smith Special Commissioner</p>
                <p>John Wine Jr. being duly Sworn Says, I am here to testify for the Government. I
                    am 50 years old. I reside on South River, Middle River Township. I have lived
                    there about twenty years, lived there before and during the war. My claim in
                    this case is for Ten head of Cattle. I lost them I think in 1864. I did not See
                    them taken &amp; do not know what became of them only what I have been told.
                    These cattle were on a Mountain farm that belonged to my Father-in-law, two
                    miles from Waynesboro that is three niles from the residence of Samson Pelter
                    and two miles from Jacob Coiner Jr. Think Jacob Coiner is about my age this farm
                    lays South East from them, there was not &amp; is not any road runs to this
                    Mountain farm, that passes any where near the house of either of these men.
                    Jacob Zirkle lived about two miles from me during the war. he is not related to
                    me. Jacob Zirkle was not a Confederate during the war. There were Some
                    Confederates here during the war. The Jacob Coffman who is a Witness on my
                    papers is young Jacob think he is near fifty-years old he lived about three
                    miles from me. I had a good many neighbors nearer than that at the time when
                    these papers were made to part in this claim, my father was living, his name was
                    John Wine, my name was John Wine Jr. This claim is my own &amp; was mine
                    when it was made. I was a Witness when this claim was made out. I signed my mame
                    John Wine Jr. This claim was made in the name of John Wine because it was his
                    stock that was taken. These cattle did not belong to my father, they belonged to
                    me. My father did not have any interest in these cattle. I cannot tell why this
                    claim purports to be made by him. I lost these cattle in the fall of the year
                    1864. I was at home when these cattle were taken. I went to Illinois in <abbr
                        expan="October">Oct</abbr> 1864, These cattle were last before that. In the
                    beginning of the war I hired a Substitute and put him in the Confederate Army, I
                    done that before there was any Conscripting done here. I was not liable to be
                    conscripted. In 1863, when they commenced conscripting men so that I was liable,
                    I got detailed as a farmer, the detail was made out &amp; signed by a
                    Confederate official at Sta<add hand="h1" place="inline">u</add>nton, What detailed famers made on their
                    farms, belonged to the Confederate government, except what they &amp; their
                        <orig reg="families">famalies</orig><orig reg="ate">eat</orig>. I <orig
                        reg="delivered">delievered</orig> all &amp; everything I made in 1863 to
                    the Confederate Government except what I <orig reg="ate">eat</orig>. I delivered
                    every bit of it to them. I delivered a number of head of cattle to the
                    Confederate Government in 1863. My detail was renewed at the end of 1863 for the
                    year 1864 and I delivered all I made in 1864 on my farm to the Confederate
                    Government, the Same as in 1863. I delivered a number of head of Cattle to them
                    in 1864, cant <orig reg="recollect">recolect</orig> the Confederate Government
                    never paid me for this property. I never <abbr expan="asked">ask<hi
                            rend="super">d</hi></abbr> for pay. I never attempted to get pay
                    any way. I did not expect pay for it. I gave it to them. I had the ten head of
                    Cattle charged for dairy the whole Season of 1864. I had them hid up in this
                    Mountain pasture. I sold a Span of horses in 1862 to the Confederate Government,
                    delivered them to Mike <del hand="h1">Holman</del> Harmon a <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed</abbr><abbr expan="Quartermaster">Q.M.</abbr> at <orig
                        reg="Staunton">Stanton</orig>. I Sold &amp; delivered them voluntarily
                    they paid me for the horses, and in 1864 the Confederates got an other Span of
                    horses from me. They took them I did not Sell them. I left here in <abbr
                        expan="October">Oct.</abbr> 1864 because the Confederate officers refused to
                    renew my deta<add hand="h1" place="inline">i</add>l as a farmer. If they would have renewed my
                    deta<add hand="h1" place="inline">i</add>l as a farmer I would have kept on working my farm for the
                    Confederate government the Same as I had done. I did not want to go in the Army,
                    it was too dangerous work for me. I know Dr. J.S. Myers, he lived at Waynesboro,
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>. I do not recollect of having signed a
                    petition at any time during the war asking that Myers be discharged from the
                    Confederate Army. When I was detailed, I was in the Confederate Service
                    &amp; aiding the Confederate Cause as much as though I was in the
                    Confederate Army. I know that. I do not recollect whether I took the Oath of
                    Allegiance to the Confederate Government the Statement I have made to day in
                    relation to my being in the Confederate Service is true. I do not recollect that
                    I testified when the testimony was first taken in this case, "that I was not in
                    any way connected with the Confederate Service" If it so appears in the papers
                    it is a mistake. I never intend to Swear to any Such thing &amp; did not
                    know I had.</p>
                <p>Subscribed &amp; Sworn to before me <abbr expan="February">Feby</abbr> 27<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> 1878 Jno. S. Smith Speccial Commissioner</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John Wine Jr.</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                <byline>John Wine</byline>
                <p>John Wine. New Hope, Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p>Claimant was 32 in 1861 and farmed his place of 150 situate 3 miles <abbr
                        expan="south east">S.E.</abbr> of New Hope on South River. Was not in any
                    way connected with the Confederate Service. In <abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr>
                    or <abbr expan="November">Nov.</abbr> 1864 he went to Illinois as he was
                    determined never to fight against the Union was absent 9 months, labored on a
                    farm. Was threatened with damage in 1864 by persons named Kennerly. His
                    sympathies and feelings were always in favor of the Union. Did not vote for the
                    ratification of Secession.</p>
                <p>John Wine of Augusta Co. signs petition asking for discharge of Dr. J.S. Myers
                    for the military service to act as their physician. Say that "under the late
                    call for volunteers all the physicians of their immediate neighborhood
                    patriotically responded"</p>
                <p>account</p>
                <p>10 Cattle $400</p>
                <p>Witness: <name type="claimant">John Wine, Jr.</name>, <name type="witness">Jacob
                        Coiner, Jr.</name>, <name type="witness">Samson Pelter</name>, <name
                        type="witness">Jacob W. Zirkle</name>, <name type="witness">Jacob
                    Coffman</name>.</p>
                <p>Testimony taken by <name type="other">Harvey Risk</name><abbr expan="Special"
                        >Spl.</abbr><abbr expan="Commissioner">Comm<hi rend="super"
                    >r.</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>WAR DEPARTMENT, ADJUTANT GENERAL'S OFFICE, April 22<hi rend="super">d</hi>,
                    1892.</p>
                <p>Respectfully returned to the Department of Justice, by authority of the Secretary
                    of War, inviting attention to the following report, viz:</p>
                <p>There are on file in this office, three Vouchers signed John Wine, one sg<hi
                        rend="super">d</hi>. John Wine <hi rend="underline">Jr</hi>. and one
                    in favor of John Wine <hi rend="underline">Sr</hi>. (not signed) in Augusta Co.
                    Va. for forage, and one signed John Wine<hi rend="super">s</hi>, by his
                    mark, at Throughfare Va. for services as laborer.</p>
                <p>One John <hi rend="bold">Wine</hi> of Augusta co. Va. petitioned for the
                    discharge of a physician.</p>
                <p>One John Wine of Blountville, Tenn. petitioned for the discharge of a doctor.
                    Also, signed voucher for payment for forage. No further information found.</p>
                <p><name type="other">
                        <unclear>Wm Holkear</unclear>
                    </name> Asst. Adjt. General</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                
                <byline>United States Treasury Department</byline>
                <p>Treasury Department, Office of the Secretary. Washington, D.C., May 24, 1892.</p>
                <p>The Honorable The Attorney General.</p>
                <p>Sir: In answer to your request of the 9th ultimo, in the case of John Wine Jr.,
                    against the United States, No. 8611 Congressional, I have the honor to state
                    that the name of John Wine Jr. appears in a copy of a list of those who voted
                    for the ordinance of secession in Augusta County, Virginia, the original of
                    which is presumed to be in the custody of the clerk of the court of said county.</p>
                <p>Respectfully yours, <name type="other">Charles Forter</name> Secretary</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
