<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0130"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0130">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of William V.
                    Strough, July 20, 1874, Claim No. 17,938</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of william v strough, july 20 1874 claim no 17 938</title>
        <author>Strough, William V.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 15 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0130</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498355</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of William V. Strough,
                            July 20, 1874, Claim No. 17,938</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of william v strough, july 20 1874 claim no 17 938</title>
            <author>William V. Strough</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche #1832</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1875">1875</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0130T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>The Commissioners disallowed Strough's claim for one horse, despite evidence of
                    his loyalty to the Union, because the Union Army had not taken his horse for
                    military purposes, but rather as part of the destruction of the Valley in
                    October, 1864.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Black Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>The mare for which this claim is made was taken by the army under Gen. Sheridan
                    in Oct. 1864 in what was called the "burning raid"--taken not for army use, but
                    in pursuance of an order to lay waste the Valley of Virginia. Horses mules
                    cattle &amp;c taken by Gen. Sheridan at this time were driven out of the
                    state &amp; sold and the proceeds paid into the Treasury.</p>
                <p>The claim is disallowed.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>, <name type="other">Orange Ferriss</name>,
                        <name type="other">JB Howell</name> Commrs of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>William Strough</byline>
                <p>Ques 1 Ans. My name is William V. Strough, my age is 43 years. My residence near
                    New Hope, Augusta Co. Va. My occupation is a farmer. I am the claimant.</p>
                <p>3 Ans. I was born in Rockingham County, Va.</p>
                <p>4 Ans. I have resided at my present home, for sixteen years, did not change my
                    residence during the rebellion. My business was farming.</p>
                <p>5 Ans. My sympathies were with the cause of the Union, and were as from beginning
                    to the end of the War.</p>
                <p>6 Ans. I never done or said anything against the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>7 Ans. I was always ready to do anything I could in aid of the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>8 Ans. I aided persons to go through the lines, on several occasions. Joseph
                    Rogers, Messrs Clayton &amp; others, in 1863 &amp; 64. None related to
                    me.</p>
                <p>9 Ans. I had some first cousins in the Union army, from West Virginia.</p>
                <p>10 Ans. I was not. Except three months service in the winter
                    <unclear>or</unclear> spring of 1865, our telegraph line, from Parkersburg to
                    Grafton in West Virginia</p>
                <p>11 Ans. I never did -</p>
                <p>12 Ans. I took the Union side, I refused to vote for the Ordinance of Secession.</p>
                <p>13 Ans. I adhered to the Union, and not my state.</p>
                <p>14 Ans. I felt disappointed at the result of Manassas, I rejoiced at the result
                    of Vicksburg &amp; New Orleans and more than glad when the surrender was
                    made.</p>
                <p>Ques 15 Ans. I had no protection or privileges until I went through the lines.</p>
                <p>16 Ans. I have not taken the "Iron Clad Oath."</p>
                <p>17 Ans. H.G. McCausland, H.K. Eakle, J.W. Zirkle &amp; others - the first two
                    are my witnesses.</p>
                <p>18 Ans. I was not threatened or injured. After I left my home, the Confederate
                    Receiver, Thos. J. Michie, now deceased, talked of confiscating my wife's
                    property, but did not.</p>
                <p>19 Ans. I was arrested and carried to Richmond in the fall of 1863. I was
                    released with a furlough for thirty (30) days. I took no oath nor give no bond.
                    And afterward was detailed as a farmer.</p>
                <p>20 Ans. I had a horse taken, for the use of <orig reg="Early's">Earley's</orig>
                    Army. I received nothing for the horse except about twenty dollars.</p>
                <p>21 Ans. I had no property confiscated -</p>
                <p>22 Ans. I was conscripted and furnished a substitute.</p>
                <p>23 Ans. I was compelled by conscription to go into the Army, and I put in the
                    substitute, whom I told to go through the lines, which he did, in 1862, or 63 -
                    My substitute's name was William Murtle. The last I heard of him he was in
                    Wheeling W. Va.</p>
                <p>24 Ans. I was in the Army at Piedmont battle, but did not fight, and that was all
                    the service I was in except as a detailed farmer.</p>
                <p>25 Ans. I was in no service except as stated above.</p>
                <p>26 Ans. I took no oath.</p>
                <p>27 Ans. I have had charge of any thing at all. I sold some grain because I could
                    not help myself. I had no interest in contracts or manufactures.</p>
                <p>28 Ans. I had no interest in blockade running.</p>
                <p>29 Ans. I had no interest in vessels or boats.</p>
                <p>30 Ans. I refused to take bonds, and no interest in any securities -</p>
                <p>31 Ans. I never aided in raising or equiping troops or doing anything else in aid
                    of the rebellion.</p>
                <p>32 Ans. I never <orig reg="gave">give</orig> any information.</p>
                <p>33 Ans. I never belonged to any society or Association for any purpose.</p>
                <p>34 Ans. I never took any oath -</p>
                <p>35 Ans. I had a pass from Richmond, home and from Staunton, home. I took no oath
                    nor <orig reg="gave">give</orig> no bond to get such passes.</p>
                <p>36 Ans. None but Cousins, one I think, and two brothers-in-law. S.M. Miller and
                    J.B. Miller. Samuel was killed, during the War. J.B. Miller, lives near
                    Hermitage P.O. in Augusta Co. I never furnished them anything.</p>
                <p>37 Ans. I was under no disabilities.</p>
                <p>38 Ans. I never asked a pardon.</p>
                <p>39 Ans. I took an Amnesty Oath at New Creek W. Va. in July 1864</p>
                <p>Ques 40 Ans. I was never a prisoner -</p>
                <p>41 Ans. I never was arrested [by U.S.]</p>
                <p>42 Ans. I never was fined or assessed.</p>
                <p>43 Ans. I had no property taken or confiscated under the laws referred to.</p>
                <p>44 Ans. I voted in 1860, for Stephen A. Douglas, for president, and for Union
                    candidates to go to the State Convention. I did no vote for the Ordinance of
                    Secession.</p>
                <p>45 Ans. I did not belong to any Committee, or home guard, or anything to suppress
                    the Union.</p>
                <p>46 Ans. I was called out as a Conscript detail &amp; first as a <orig
                        reg="Militia">Malitia</orig> in July 1861. and as a detail in 1864. I was in
                    the <orig reg="Militia">Malitia</orig> Camp at Staunton, about two weeks, and on
                    duty as a detail about six days during which time the Piedmont battle took
                    place. I was conscripted by a law of the Confederate Congress, and notified by,
                    I think, J.H. M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cue, or Capt Avis, Provost Marshal
                    at Staunton. I put in the substitute because I did not wish to fight against the
                    Union.</p>
                <p>47 Ans. I had no connection with any department of the Army or Navy or Government
                    of the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>48 Ans. I had charge of nothing of the kind named in the question -</p>
                <p>49 Ans. I was not employed in any way specified in the question -</p>
                <p>Ques 50 Ans. I had nothing to do with prisoners of War in any way, or for any
                    cause.</p>
                <p>51 Ans. I was not in the Union Army or navy -</p>
                <p>Taking of the Property -</p>
                <p>72 Ans. I had gone through the lines, and was in Ohio when the Mare, charged was
                    taken, consequently cannot answer any of the questions as to the taking of my
                    Mare.</p>
                <p>79 Ans. The Mare was black, about 3 1/2 years old. When I left her at Jacob
                    Wine's she was in good condition, of medium size, well formed and fine style and
                    well broken to the saddle - I think she was well worth the price I have charged,
                    one hundred and twenty five dollars.</p>
                <p>I have never filed an application for the benefit of the Bankrupt law.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">William V. Strough</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Jacob Wine</byline>
                <p>Taking of the Property</p>
                <p>Deposition of Jacob Wine</p>
                <p>My name is Jacob Wine, my age 72 years. I am a farmer by occupation. My residence
                    near Mossey Creek, Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>I am not related to the Claimant and have no interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>Ques. 72 Ans. I did not see the Mare charged by Claimant taken out of the stable,
                    but saw her in possession of Soldiers a short distance from the Stable.</p>
                <p>73 Ans. The mare was taken about 10 o'clock A.M.</p>
                <p>74 Ans. There was no complaint made by any one to any one.</p>
                <p>75 Ans. No vouchers or receipts asked for or given.</p>
                <p>76 Ans. No payment made that I know of.</p>
                <p>77 Ans. There was no encampment, but what might be called a raiding party, under
                    command of Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi>. Sheridan. There had been a skirmish
                    at Bridgewater, some few miles distant. There were fifteen or twenty soldiers
                    together when the Mare was taken. I did not hear the name of any officer.</p>
                <p>78 Ans. The color of the Mare was black, and young. She was in good order and
                    well built, and fine looking, and of fine life. I think she was cheap at one
                    hundred and twenty five dollars. I do not know anything about her working
                    qualities, but first rate for the Cavalry service, and the army was as far as I
                    saw it was of that service. The Mare had been left with me to keep by the
                    Claimant, and had been in my possession about two weeks or probably longer. Mr.
                    Strough left the Mare with me for fear the Confederates would take it, as he was
                    then on his way through the lines, which was in 1864, and the Mare was taken
                    about the first of October 1864. I live about 16 miles from the Claimant.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Jacob Wine</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Hugh McCausland</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Hugh G. M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Causland</p>
                <p>Question in General as to the loyalty of the claimant W.V. Strough</p>
                <p>Ans. My name is Hugh G. M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Causland. My age is 47
                    years, I reside near New Hope in Augusta County. My occupation is a farmer. I am
                    not related to the claimant. I have known the claimant about 26 years. I resided
                    about 1/2 mile from him during the War, and saw him every few days up to the
                    time he went North. We conversed frequently and freely about the War, and I
                        <del hand="h1">was</del> always found him opposed to it. He said that the war was
                    unjust, that the South had no right to secede, and that before he would
                    participate in the rebellion he would leave his family and go through the lines,
                    which he did (I think) in 1863. He was not at all reserved in his opposition to
                    the War when with his loyal neighbors. His Union neighbors had confidence in his
                    loyalty. He knew my sympathies were with him - if the South had gained its
                    independence he could not have proven any loyalty to it. </p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">H.G. M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Causland</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Henry Eakle</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Henry K. Eakle</p>
                <p>Answer to general question -</p>
                <p>My name is Henry K. Eakle, my age is 55 years, I reside near New Hope in Augusta
                    County. I am a farmer. I have known the Claimant for 15 or 20 years. I resided 3
                    miles from him during the War, I saw him frequently and conversed with him about
                    the War, and always found him very bitter against Secession. He went through the
                    lines - I do not recollect what year. He was always bold and fearless in
                    expressing him self, even at times to those who favored the rebellion. His Union
                    neighbors always had the utmost confidence in his loyalty to the Union. He could
                    not have proven any loyalty to the Confederacy had it succeeded. My own
                    sympathies were with him, which he knew.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Henry K. Eakle</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>Archive Office, WAR DEPARTMENT, January 2, 1877</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 202</p>
                <p>Case of W.V. Strough Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>Bill &amp; voucher for 4 lbs Lard sold to Capt. A.M. Earle for the use of the
                    C.S. Army at $2.00 per lbs $8.00. Paid near New Hope <unclear>Va.</unclear>
                    March 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
