<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0536"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0536">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Mathew Tisdale,
                    1871, Claim No. 7651</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of mathew tisdale, 1871 claim no 7651</title>
        <author>Tisdale, Mathew</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 20 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0536</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498423</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Mathew Tisdale, 1871,
                            Claim No. 7651</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of mathew tisdale, 1871 claim no 7651</title>
            <author>Mathew Tisdale</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, College Park,
                            RG 217, claim #7651</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1871">1871</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Desertion/Leave, Patriotism, Prisons/Prisoners</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0536T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Mathew Tisdale filed this claim in 1871 for $300, claiming Union forces under
                    General Hunters Command took two horses in 1864. Mathew was a 31 year old
                    farmer. He was arrested to join the Confederate Army once in Staunton but he was
                    later released. He helped deserters reach Union lines. The commission allowed
                    $250.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One black Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One brown Mare 8 yrs old</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$125.00</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimants loyalty is established, by his own statements, and the testimony of
                        <abbr expan="William">W<hi rend="super">m</hi></abbr> Andrews, and
                    B.F. <orig reg="Bagby">Bayly</orig>.</p>
                <p>He aided several Union prisoners to escape, furnished money to deserters from the
                    Rebel Army. He was generally regarded as a loyal man, and was hardly safe in the
                    Country during the War, and now that the War is over, he is shunned by the
                    Rebels.</p>
                <p>The horses were taken from his premises by soldiers of <abbr expan="General"
                            >Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>. Hunter's Command, in June
                    1864, while the Army was stationed a few miles off at Staunton.</p>
                <p>We allow the sum of two hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name>, <name type="other">JB Howell</name><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Mathew Tisdale</byline>
                <p>I am 31 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> I am a
                    Farmer. Have lived in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> all my life.</p>
                <p>Ques 2. Witness says: I resided in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr> from April 1st 1861
                    to June 1st 1865 &amp; did not change my residence at any time.</p>
                <p>3. Witness says: I never passed the military or Naval lines of the United States
                    &amp; entered the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>4. Witness says: I never took an oath of allegiance of any kind to the so-called
                    Confederate States.</p>
                <p>5. Witness says: I took the amnesty oath in 1865, in Staunton <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>. It was required of
                    every one. Have never been pardoned by the <abbr expan="President"
                    >Presdt.</abbr> as I have never done any thing to be pardoned for.</p>
                <p>6. Witness says, I never was directly nor indirectly in any manner connected with
                    the civil service of the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> States.</p>
                <p>7. Witness Says: I never held any office or place of honor, profit, or trust
                    under the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr>. States, or any State of the
                    Confederacy.</p>
                <p>8. Witness says: I never held any clerkship or any agency or employment of any
                    kind for or under the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>9. Witness says: I never was in any capacity in the military or Naval Service of
                    the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> States.</p>
                <p>10. Witness Says: I never was an officer soldier sailor or marine in either the
                    military or naval service of the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>. I did not furnish a substitute for either.
                    Never had any connection with any department of the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>. Never had charge of any
                    supplies, stores, or trains in the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr>
                    service.</p>
                <p>11. Witness says, I never was in any service or employment of any kind under the
                        <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt.</abbr> or furnished supplies of any kind to any <abbr expan="Department"
                        >Dept.</abbr> of any sort for their use. I never gave any information to any
                    officer, soldier, sailor or marine of the army or navy of the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>12. Witness says, I never was in any manner engaged in the manufacture of
                    munitions of War, of clothing <unclear>boots</unclear>, or shoes, or articles of
                    any kind for the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>13. Witness says: I never was in any manner engaged in the impressment, taking or
                    furnishing of any supplies of any kind for the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                    >Confed.</abbr> service. Did not have any share or interest in any purchase or
                    contract for the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>14. Witness says, I never was engaged in blockade running, or illicit traffic
                    between the lines. Had no share or interest in any goods brought into the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> States.</p>
                <p>15. Witness says, I did not leave the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr>
                    States between the 1st of April 1861 &amp; 1st of April 1865</p>
                <p>16. Witness says, I was neither the owner nor in any way interested in any vessel
                    engaged in blockade running.</p>
                <p>17. Witness says, I was arrested once by the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> in 1862, in Staunton
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr> by <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Jno. Avis of the Provost Guard. I was released
                    soon after. I took no oath to the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> to effect my release. I was arrested to be
                    part of the army. Never was arrested by the United States <abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>18. Witness say, I had horses, grain, &amp; hay taken by the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> in
                    the spring &amp; fall of 1864. I was paid in <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr> Money, it was of little value.</p>
                <p>19. Witness says: I was threatened to be taken to <abbr expan="Richmond"
                        >Richd.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>
                    because I would not take the oath of Allegiance to the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr> States. I told them I would not take it any way</p>
                <p>20. Witness says: I never was in any way molested or injured on account of my
                    union sentiments.</p>
                <p>21. Witness says, I never contributed any thing to the support of the Union Army,
                    or its cause. Never did anything for the United States.</p>
                <p>23. Witness says: I did <orig reg="not">no</orig> have any near relatives in
                    either the United States or Confederate Armies</p>
                <p>24. Witness says, I never owned any Confederate bonds, nor had any interest in
                    any. Never did anything to support the credit of the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>.</p>
                <p>25. Witness says, I never have given aid or comfort to the rebellion.</p>
                <p>26. Witness says, I never engaged in raiding into the United States from Canada,
                    or in injuring or destroying its commerce.</p>
                <p>27. Witness says, I never was engaged directly nor indirectly in holding persons
                    persons as prisoners, who had been taken by the <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt</abbr>. I once helped some
                    prisoners to escape to their homes, there were seven in the lot</p>
                <p>28. Witness says: I never was in any way connected with any society for the
                    persecution or expulsion of any person on account of union sentiments.</p>
                <p>29. Witness says, I never was a paroled prisoner of the United States.</p>
                <p>30. Witness says, I have never held any office in either the Army or Navy of the
                    United States. Was not educated either at West Point or the Naval Academy</p>
                <p>31. Witness says: I never <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> any pass from the
                        <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr></p>
                <p>32. Witness says, I am not &amp; never have been under any disabilities
                    imposed by the fourteenth amendment of the Constitution of the United States.
                    Have not held any office under the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> since the War.</p>
                <p>33. Witness says: At the beginning of the war, I <orig reg="sympathized"
                        >sympathised</orig> with the union cause. I did not vote either for or
                    against the ordinance of <orig reg="secession">cesission</orig> they threatened
                    to shoot anyone voting against it. After the adoption of the ordinance of <orig
                        reg="secession">cesession</orig> I adhered to the Union Cause, &amp; did
                    not go with my State</p>
                <p>34 Witness says: I do solemnly declare, that from the beginning to the end of the
                    war my sympathies were constantly with the Union Cause, &amp; I was at all
                    times ready &amp; willing to aid its Cause, to the extent of my ability,
                    &amp; so far as my circumstances permitted, &amp; further this deponent
                    sayeth not. Sept 21st 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">M. Tisdale</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 21st day of September 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Randolph Tisdale</byline>
                <p>Deposition of <orig reg="Randolph">Randal</orig> Tisdale to prove taking
                    &amp; furnishing of property</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Witness Says: I am 70 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super"
                        >a</hi></abbr>. I am a Farmer. I was present when the articles mentioned in
                    claimants petition were taken.</p>
                <p>2. Witness says: I saw them taken, one brown mare, &amp; one black mare</p>
                <p>4. Witness Says: The property was taken in June 1864 by officers &amp;
                    Soldiers of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunters Army from the claimants
                    farm. There was an officer present.</p>
                <p>5. Witness says, A man named David Stultz was present &amp; saw them taken.</p>
                <p>6. Witness says: There was an officer present. Do not know his name, rank or
                        <abbr expan="regiment">regt.</abbr> he belonged to the command of <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter of the <abbr expan="United States"
                    >US</abbr> Army.</p>
                <p>7. Witness says: One was taken from the field &amp; one from the plow. I told
                    them we had obeyed <abbr expan="President">Presdt.</abbr> Lincoln's
                    proclamation, &amp; it should protect our (claimants) property. We had never
                    put any thing out of the way. The officer said he was compelled to take them,
                    &amp; that my son should be paid for them.</p>
                <p>8. Witness says, The officer rode the black mare, &amp; the brown mare was
                    ridden off by a soldier</p>
                <p>9. Witness says, The property was taken in the direction of Lexington I went
                    about a mile with them. I did not see it afterwards.</p>
                <p>10. Witness says, The officer said it was taken for the use of the army</p>
                <p>11. Witness says: There was no complaint made on account of the taking</p>
                <p>12. Witness says, There was no receipt asked for &amp; none given.</p>
                <p>13. Witness says, The property was taken before 12 oclock, in the day, it was not
                    taken secretly.</p>
                <p>14. Witness says, When the property was taken, the army was about 4 miles off at
                    Staunton. Hunters &amp; Averills men were encamped at Staunton, <orig
                        reg="stayed">staid</orig> I think two days. Had not been any battle or
                    skirmish near except at Piedmont, 12 miles off, did not know the Quarter Marters
                    or any of them.</p>
                <p>15. Witness Says, The property was in good condition. One black mare was either 4
                    or 5 years old, was worth One hundred &amp; fifty dollars. One brown mare,
                    was worth one hundred &amp; fifty dollars, was about 10 years old.</p>
                <p>19. Witness says, I know the property was taken for the use of the <abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> &amp; not for private use, the officer
                    said so.</p>
                <p>20. Witness say, I think it was taken for the use of the <abbr expan="Government"
                        >Govt.</abbr> &amp; for no other purpose. I have reason to believe the
                    black mare was used by <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter I was told so
                    by several persons who saw her</p>
                <p>21. Witness Says, I believe the necessity of the army compelled them to take the
                    property, the officer told me so</p>
                <p>22. Witness says: I believe it was taken for the necessary use of the <abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> &amp; it should pay for it.</p>
                <p>23. Witness says: I think the officer who took them had orders to take them for
                    the use of the army. The officer said so, &amp; refused to give her up for
                    money or anything else, as he needed them, &amp; further this deponent
                    sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 21st 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Randolph Tisdale</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 21st day of September 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> for State of Virginia</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>William Andrews</byline>
                <p>Deposition of William Andrews to prove loyalty of claimant</p>
                <p>Ques 1. Witness says: I am 49 years old. I reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>. I
                    am a farmer. I have known the claimant 10 years, live near him. Saw him nearly
                    every week during the war. Talked with very frequently about the war. He was a
                    loyal man to the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr><abbr expan="Government"
                        >Govt</abbr>, never heard anything else from him, he was nothing but a loyal
                    man. Every body who knew him regarded him as a loyal man. He has been shunned
                    &amp; avoided by men around him on account of his union sentiments. I have
                    known him to protect &amp; furnish supplies to men, deserters from the <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> Army, until they could get to the Union
                    lines, &amp; he helped them go away. Never knew him to do any thing for the
                        <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt.</abbr> except when he was compelled to furnish them his team by <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> soldiers, with guns in their hands. He
                    was too loyal to the United States <abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> to have
                    been loyal to the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> had it succeeded, he told me, we would all
                    have to leave or be ruined if the Confederates succeeded, &amp; further this
                    deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>Sept. 21st 1871</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">W Andrews</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 21st day of September 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of Virginia</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>B. F. Bagby</byline>
                <p>Deposition of B.F. Bagby to prove loyalty</p>
                <p>Ques 1. Witness says: I am 42 years old. I reside in Staunton <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>. I am by profession a
                    contractor. Have known the claimant 15 years. Lived near him during the war, saw
                    him nearly every day, &amp; talked with him frequently about the war. He was
                    loyal to the <abbr expan="United States">US</abbr><abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt.</abbr> &amp; was so regarded by his neighbors. I do not know that he
                    was injured in person, but his grain was taken by the Confederates, on account
                    of his being a Union Man. I tried several to induce him to take Confederate
                    Money, but he <orig reg="always">allways</orig> refused, saying he had no
                    confidence in it. I do not know that he had any chance to do anything for the
                        <abbr expan="United States">US</abbr><abbr expan="Government">Govt.</abbr>
                    he never left his home when the <abbr expan="United States">US</abbr> troops
                    came in. Never knew him to do anything for the Confederate <abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt</abbr>. I know that he was hardly safe in staying at
                    his home during the war, &amp; had the Confederates succeeded I do not think
                    he could have stayed at all. He never would have made a loyal citizen to the
                    Confederate Government, &amp; further this deponent sayeth not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">B.F. Bagby</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sept. 21st 1871</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this 21st day of September 1871</p>
                <p><name type="other">WG Riley</name> United States Commissioner and Special <abbr
                        expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> for State of <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr></p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
