<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0538"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0538">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Hays Moffett,
                    1872, Claim No. 15469</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of hays moffett, 1872 claim no 15469</title>
        <author>Moffett, Hays</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 23 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0538</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498425</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Hays Moffett, 1872,
                            Claim No. 15,469</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of hays moffett, 1872 claim no 15 469</title>
            <author>Hays Moffett</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche #483</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Patriotism, Slavery, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0538T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Hays Moffett filed this claim in 1872 for $748, claiming the Union army under
                    General Hunter's command took four horses, corn, and flour in 1864. Hays was a
                    farmer and slaveholder who voted for the Ordinance of Secession. The claim was
                    disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bay Horse about 8 years old</cell>
                            <cell>$200.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$200.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bay Mare about 7 years old</cell>
                            <cell>$173.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$173.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bay Mare about 6 years old</cell>
                            <cell>$200.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$200.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Bay Mare about 14 years old</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$150.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>12 bushels of corn at 75 cts per bushel</cell>
                            <cell>$7.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$7.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 barrels of flour at $7 per bl.</cell>
                            <cell>$14.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$14.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>One question <unclear>proponded</unclear> to this claimant he was better
                    qualified to answer than any other person. It is the question which calls on him
                    to state with which side in the Civil War he sympathised. He evades the question
                    &amp; tells us he don't know how he "felt at the battle of Manassas" -
                    "didn't feel for either side" - "Did not vote either for or against the
                    ordinance of secession" The record of the votes in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co.</abbr> saves us all embarrassment if we should other wise have any in
                    disposing of this case.</p>
                <p>The Claimant testifies untruthfully - the record shows that he voted for the
                    adoption of the Ordinance of Secession.</p>
                <p>We reject this claim.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>N.K. Trout and A. Chapman (attorney's) letter to Judge Riley</byline>
                <p>Staunton, Va. Aug. 19. '72</p>
                <p>Judge Riley is respectfully requested, not to submit to the Commissioner this
                    evidence, until we shall have had an opportunity of examining the Claimant
                    before him &amp; some additional evidence, and to give us notice of some
                    convenient time when we may produce before him the evidence received by us.</p>
                <p>
                    <unclear>
                        <name type="other">A.K. Trout</name>
                        <lb/>
                        <name type="other">A. Chapmans</name>
                    </unclear>
                </p>
                <p>of Counsel.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Hayes Moffett</byline>
                <p>In answer to the First General Interrogatory, the Deponent says: My name is Hayes
                    Moffett, my age 64 years, my residence Swoopes Depot, Augusta Co, in the State
                    of Virginia, and my occupation a retired farmer, I am the claimant, and have a
                    beneficial interest in the claim.</p>
                <p>Question 2 Witness Says: I resided on my farm in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> during the whole war. My farm
                    contains 140 acres about 35 acres in woods &amp; 100 acres clear. It was all
                    in cultivation, farmed all the war. Did not have the State of <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> during the war.</p>
                <p>3 No in full</p>
                <p>4 No in full</p>
                <p>5 Witness says. I took the amnesty oath after the war at Middlebrook, Augusta
                        <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I had
                    nothing to be pardoned for.</p>
                <p>6 No in full</p>
                <p>7 No in full</p>
                <p>8 No in full</p>
                <p>9 No in full</p>
                <p>10 No in full</p>
                <p>11 No in full</p>
                <p>12 No in full</p>
                <p>13 No in full</p>
                <p>14 No in full</p>
                <p>15 No in full</p>
                <p>16 No in full</p>
                <p>17 Witness Says. I had my wagon &amp; horses impressed some four or five
                    times by the Rebels for the use of the Confederate Army. I sent a man who lived
                    with me to drive &amp; take care of the horses &amp; wagon</p>
                <p>18 No in full</p>
                <p>19 No in full</p>
                <p>20 No in full</p>
                <p>21 No in full</p>
                <p>22 No in full</p>
                <p>23 No in full</p>
                <p>24 No in full</p>
                <p>25 Witness Says The Confederate Authorities took corn flour &amp;c. from me
                    at different times. I did not secure pay for any of it.</p>
                <p>26 Witness Says The Confederates talked at one time of burning my house down
                    because I was a Union Man. I told them to burn as quick as they pleased. I was
                    never molested any other way.</p>
                <p>28 Witness Says. I gave the Union soldiers all I had to eat, when they passed my
                    place in June 1864. Did not have it in my power to do anything else.</p>
                <p>30 Witness Says. I had no relatives in either the <abbr expan="United">U.</abbr>
                    States of Confederate Armies.</p>
                <p>31 No in full</p>
                <p>32 No in full</p>
                <p>33 No in full</p>
                <p>34 No in full</p>
                <p>35 No in full</p>
                <p>36 No in full</p>
                <p>37 No in full</p>
                <p>38 No in full</p>
                <p>39 No in full</p>
                <p>40 Witness says I don't know how I felt at the battle of Manassas did not feel
                    for either side I thought they had better quit it. Did not vote either for or
                    against the Ordinance of Secession. I was opposed to the war &amp; always
                    said they had too many men on the North side for us.</p>
                <p>44 Witness says. I don't believe I ever said anything about which ought to whip.
                    I did nothing either way. If I had been called on to fight I think would have
                    gone to the bushes. I don't think I would have fought, on either side, I owned
                    two slaves at the time &amp; I knew if the South got whipped I should lose
                    them, and further the deponent saith not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Hays Moffett</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 2nd day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>Deposition of Hayes Moffett recalled, to prove the taking furnishing &amp;
                    value of property.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 Witness says. I was present &amp; saw one horse taken mentioned in my
                    petition. I did not see any other property mentioned in my petition taken the
                    other horses were in the field the corn was in the meat house in a large
                    hogshead shelled, the flour was in the house in the room, in <abbr
                        expan="barrels">bbls</abbr>. The property was all there when I saw the <abbr
                        expan="United States">UStates</abbr> Soldiers go in the direction of my
                    house. When the Soldiers left the property was all gone, there was no one else
                    there to take it but them. I did see them take 2 <abbr expan="barrels"
                    >bbls.</abbr> of Flour &amp; about 12 bushels of corn, I did not see the
                    first three horses taken. Items No 1, 2 &amp; 3. The property was taken in
                    June 1864. I don't know the day of the month, the property was taken by <abbr
                        expan="United States">UStates</abbr> Soldiers under the command of <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter, there were about twenty five men
                    engaged in taken the property. It was all taken in one day, except one horse,
                    which was taken about a week before, eight or ten soldiers were engaged in
                    taking the one horse, Mr. A.G. Wayland &amp; Mr. Mitzer were present
                    &amp; saw some of the property taken. <abbr expan="United States"
                    >UStates</abbr> officers were present when the property was taken. Don't know
                    their names, ranks, or regiments. The horse I saw taken from the field, the
                    flour was removed in pillow slips taken from the bed, the corn was taken in the
                    wagon &amp; hauled off. The Army was on the march when the property was
                    taken, <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter was retreating out of the
                    Valley. The Property was taken along with the moving Army. Did not see any of
                    the property used by the army. Did not make and complaint to any officer. Did
                    not ask for any receipts and none was given. The property was taken in the day
                    time, the property was all in good condition.</p>
                <p>Item No 1. I had one bay mare taken 8 or 9 yers old, worth $200.</p>
                <p>Item No 2. I had another bay mare 7 years old worth $175.</p>
                <p>Item No 3. I had another bay mare 6 years old worth $200.</p>
                <p>Item No 4. I saw taken one bay mare 14 year old worth $125</p>
                <p>Item No 5. I saw taken 12 bushels of corn, it was in a hoghead shelled, was worth
                    .95c per bushel I had measured the corn.</p>
                <p>Item No 6. Saw two <abbr expan="barrels">bbls.</abbr> of Flour taken, it was in
                        <abbr expan="barrels">bbls.</abbr><abbr expan="barrels">bbls.</abbr> full,
                    &amp; worth $7 or per <abbr expan="barrels">bbls</abbr>.</p>
                <p>I have never been paid for this property. Nothing was left in exchange. I am the
                    sole owner of this claim. I have never presented it to any other departments of
                    the Governmentfor payments and further this deponent saith not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Hays Moffett</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 2nd day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>John Mitzer</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John <unclear>Mitzer</unclear> to prove the taking funishing
                    &amp; value of the property</p>
                <p>Ques 1 I am 70 years old, I reside in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> I
                    am a farmer, I was present and saw three horses taken mentioned in the
                    claimant's petition. Items 1 2 &amp; 3. I did not see the other property
                    taken in June 1864 by <abbr expan="United States">UStates</abbr> Soldiers under
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter. There were more than 500 soldiers
                    present when the three horses were taken, the field was full &amp; the road
                    was full, like an old <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> muster. Officers were
                    present. My old woman fed the Officers don't know them, I was the only citizen
                    present, except my family, they saw the horses taken. Some of the horses were
                    ridden off &amp; some led. The Army was marching, I don't know the ages or
                    value of the horses taken they were good horses, in good condition, fat, they
                    belonged to the claimant, were taken from his farm in the field, this is all I
                    know about the case.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Mitzer</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn before me this 2nd day of August 1872.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Albert G. Wayland</byline>
                <p>Deposition of A.G. Wayland to prove the taking, furnishing &amp; value of the
                    property.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 I am 66 years old. I reside in Augusta. I am a farmer and tanner, I was
                    present and saw one horse - Item No.4 - bay horse &amp; 12 bushels corn
                    taken. The property was taken in June 1864, under <abbr expan="General"
                    >Genl.</abbr> Hunter. The horse was taken by about 10 soldiers, &amp; so was
                    the corn. There was an officer present who said his name was <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Smith of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr>
                    Averill's command, he said his horse had given out &amp; he must have the
                    horse. He said he also needed the corn. The Army was on the march when the
                    property was taken, the horse I saw taken was 13 or 14 years old &amp; was
                    worth $125. I saw 12 bushels of corn taken, it was shelled &amp; in the
                        <abbr expan="hogshead">hhd</abbr>, I estimate the quantity by the bulk. Corn
                    was worth at the time .95c per bushel. This is all I saw taken, this all I know
                    about the case, except that the property belonged to the claimant &amp; was
                    all taken from his farm.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Albert Wayland</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 2nd day of August 1872.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
                <p>Deposition of Alb. Wayland recalled - to prove the loyalty of the claimant.</p>
                <p>Ques 1 I have known the claimant 40 years. I lived near him during the war
                    &amp; saw him nearly every day. I talked some little to him about the war.
                    He seemed to be opposed to the war, this killing one &amp; another. I looked
                    upon him rather as a Union man, I think he was looked upon as a Union man by his
                    neighbors. I don't think he voted at all upon the Ordinance of Secession (he did
                    not vote) I don't think he was threatened because he was a union man, he was a
                    very quiet man. I don't think he did anything for either the <abbr
                        expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> or Confederate Governments. He owned no
                    Confederate Bonds, &amp; did nothing to support the credit of the
                    Confederate States. He did not give any information to any Union officer. Never
                    heard him rejoice over any Union or Confederate Victory. I was a Union Man in
                    the beginning &amp; after the State seceded I went with the State. The
                    claimant is a man of character, &amp; good standing, don't think he would
                    bring any unjust claim against the Government. I believe this is a just claim.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Albert Wayland</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 2nd day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>John Mitzer</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John Mitzer (recalled) to prove the Loyalty of the claimant</p>
                <p>Ques 1 I have know the claimants 50 years. I lived very near him during the war.
                    Saw him often during the war. I never heard him say anything about the war
                    during the war. I looked upon him as a Union man, because he did nothing for the
                    Confederate Government. I think he was regarded by his neighbors as a union man.
                    he did nothing for either Government that I know of, he did not own any <abbr
                        expan="Confederate">Confed.</abbr> bonds, &amp; did nothing to support
                    the credit of the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed</abbr>. States so far as I
                    know. I don't think he voted upon the ordinance of Secession. Never heard him
                    rejoice over a union or Confederate victory. He gave no information to any
                    officer of the <abbr expan="United States">US</abbr> Army. I the witness had
                    nothing to do with the war. He never was threatened because he was a Union man,
                    he was a quiet peaceful citizen. I have always found him a man of truth.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Mitzer</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to before me this 2nd day of August</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Albert G. Wayland</byline>
                <p>Deposition of A.G. Wayland recalled to prove loyalty <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of the claimant</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>From my personal knowledge of him regarded him as a Union man at heart.</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>Wasn't there a sentiment prevailing in the community, which prevented good Union
                    men from voting against the ordinance of Secession?</p>
                <p>Answer There was.</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>From the character of the man do you think he would show much feeling either
                    side?</p>
                <p>I do not think he would, he was quiet modest and retiring</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>Does the claimant own the land mentioned in your former deposition?</p>
                <p>Answer. He does not, it has been sold under a Deed of Trust. I believe he is
                    dependent upon his friends, the taking of the horses mentioned in the claim
                    deprived him of the means of cultivating his land, &amp; of supporting
                    himself <del hand="h1">&amp; family</del>. The slaves owned by the claimant an old man
                    and an old woman were really of no value but I believe rather a tax to him. The
                    ownership of these slaves could not possibly have influenced anyone to espouse
                    one side or the other in the war - they were in fact an expense to the party
                    keeping them.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Albert Wayland</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 26th day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>Hayes Moffett</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Hayes Moffett claimant recalled</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>In your former deposition you said you did not vote either way on the Ordinance
                    of Secession. Why didn't you vote?</p>
                <p>Answer. I was sick at the time, &amp; could not go.</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>How would you have voted, had you gone to the polls?</p>
                <p>Answer. I would have voted for the State to stay in the Union, I was opposed to
                    secession.</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>In your former deposition you say you would have gone to the bushes rather than
                    fight. Had you been within the military age, what you have done, which side
                    would you have fought on, had you been left free?</p>
                <p>Answer. I desired to see the Government kept as it was.</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>What were the ages &amp; conditions of the slave owned by you?</p>
                <p>Answer. They were very old &amp; worthless &amp; I think it would have
                    been better for me to have broken up long before I did their posession would
                    have been inducement for me to wish the success of the North.</p>
                <p>Question by Attorney</p>
                <p>What is your relation to the land mentioned in your former deposition?</p>
                <p>Answer. My land has been sold for debt, and after my horses were taken &amp;
                    could not work it, I was left entirely dependent.</p>
                <p>And further this deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Hays Moffett</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 27th day of August 1872</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">WG Riley</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>Archive Office, WAR DEPARTMENT, Jan 3rd, 1878</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 254</p>
                <p>Case of Hays Moffett, Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p>Bill &amp; vouchers for 25 bushels of corn a $4.00 300 lbs of Blade fodder
                    &amp; 250 lbs of Straw sold to the <abbr expan="Confederate States"
                    >C.States</abbr> amount $112.25 Paid at Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va.</abbr><abbr expan="November">Nov.</abbr> 1864 by <abbr expan="Captain"
                        >Capt.</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="Quarter Master">Q.M.</abbr>, <abbr
                        expan="Confederate States of America">C.S.A.</abbr></p>
                <p>Dec. 7/72 - Rejected</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
