<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0319"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0319">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Jacob L.
                    Humbert, July 17, 1871, Claim No. 2524</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of jacob l humbert, july 17 1871 claim no 2524</title>
        <author>Humbert, Jacob</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 19 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0319</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498386</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of Jacob L. Humbert,
                            July 17, 1871, Claim No. 2524</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of jacob l humbert, july 17 1871 claim no 2524</title>
            <author>Jacob L. Humbert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche # 471</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872">1872</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0319T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>Humbert filed this claim for horses, livestock, household goods, and food taken
                    in September, 1864. In 1872, the Commissioners ruled against him because he
                    voted in favor of the Ordinance of Secession and furnished a substitute to keep
                    his son out of the Confederate Army.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>5 Barrels Flour</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$30.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>500 lbs Bacon</cell>
                            <cell>$60.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$60.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>2 Blankets 1 Coverlet</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$15.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>5 Milch Cows</cell>
                            <cell>$120.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$120.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Steer</cell>
                            <cell>$40.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$40.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Heifer</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$25.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Steer</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$20.00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>One Sorrel Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$140.00</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>$140.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>Claimant swears to his loyal sympathy. But he also swears that he furnished a
                    substitute for his son in the Rebel Army, and voted for the Ordinance of
                    Secession, as he says under threats that those who voted against it would be
                    taken to Richmond.</p>
                <p>These acts of disloyalty, are inconsistent with loyal adherence to the Cause of
                    the Union and the Government of the United States. We therefore reject the
                    Claim.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>Jacob L. Humbert</byline>
                <p>In answer to the First General Interrogatory, the Deponent says: My name is Jacob
                    L. Humbert, my age is 48 years, my residence near Staunton, in the State of
                    Virginia, and my occupation a farmer; I am the claimant.</p>
                <p>To question No. 2 he answers - I lived near New Hope Va. during the whole war. I
                    was farming my own land. It consisted of 500 acres - about half of which was
                    timber land.</p>
                <p>To question Nos. 3 &amp; 4 he answers - no in full to each.</p>
                <p>To question No. 5 he answers - I took the amnesty oath at Staunton in the year
                    1865.</p>
                <p>To questions Nos. 6 to 13 inclusive he answers - no in full to each.</p>
                <p>To question No. 14 he answers I furnished a substitute for my son in order to
                    prevent him from being conscripted into the rebel army. My son volunteered and
                    joined the rebel army and I hired this substitute to get my son out to send
                    North. I paid $700 in Confederate money. My son's name was Preston S. Humbert.</p>
                <p>To questions No. 15 to 25 inclusive he answers no in full to each.</p>
                <p>To question no 26 he answers - I was frequently threatened by anonymous
                    communications during the war, with hanging - on account of my Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>To question No. 27 he answers - my property was frequently threatened during the
                    war on account of my Union sentiments.</p>
                <p>To question No. 28 he answers no.</p>
                <p>To question No. 29 he answers no, except to aid Union refugees all I could.</p>
                <p>To question No. 30 he answers - my nephew Samuel Wampler was in the rebel army.
                    He now lives in Augusta Co. Va. I never furnished him with any money or military
                    equipment.</p>
                <p>To questions Nos. 31 to 39 he answers no in full to each question separately put.</p>
                <p>To question No. 40 he answers - at the beginning of the rebellion I sympathized
                    with the Union Cause. I voted the Union ticket. I voted for the Ordinance of
                    Secession. I did so on account of threats made of taking persons to Richmond who
                    did not vote for it. After the Ordinance of Secession was adopted I still
                    adhered to the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>To question No. 41 he answers - I do so solemly declare.</p>
                <p>The claimant here examined by the Commissioner concerning property taken. I was
                    present and saw everything charged in my account taken except the five barrels
                    of flour, and part of the bacon. The bacon and coverlet were taken by Genl.
                    Hunter's army on the 6th of June at the battle of Piedmont. They were taken on
                    the night of the battle. The soldiers broke into my house and carried the meat,
                    blankets and coverlet away. <del hand="h1">They</del> I did not say anything to them as I
                    was not near enough. I don't know whether there were any officers present. The
                    blankets and coverlet were taken off the beds. They took all the bacon I had,
                    and I estimated it at five hundred pound. The same soldiers came to my house the
                    next morning to get my flour. An officer was with them and they said that they
                    had taken my bacon the night previous and that they were compelled to do so as
                    they were cut off from their supplies. I did not ask for any receipts and they
                    did not offer me any. Bacon was then worth from 12 to 15 cents in specie. I
                    don't know what was done with the blankets &amp; coverlet. They were worth
                    $15. My five cows, three steer and sorrel mare were taken by Genl. Sheridan's
                    army about the 27th or 28th of September 1864. The cattle were all driven away
                    by the soldiers. <del hand="h1">I talked to a Colonel - I do not know his name - who was
                        in command.</del> There was no conversation took place between myself and
                    any of them. There were 5 cows, 2 steers and one heifer. The cows were about 7
                    years old and were in very good order. They were worth $30 each. The beef steer
                    was fat &amp; I had been offered $50 in gold for him. The heifer beef was 2
                    1/2 years old and was worth about $25. It was in good condition. The steer was
                    two years old - thin - and worth $15 or $16 - The sorrel mare was in the meadow
                    near the house. She was led away by the soldiers. About forty two or three
                    soldiers with an officer took her. I do not recollect the officer's name or his
                    command. No conversation whatever passed. Nothing was said about receipts. The
                    mare was seven years old in right good order and was worth $145. I never saw her
                    afterwards.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">Jacob L. Humbert</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>Savory B. Aldhiser</byline>
                <p>Savory B. Aldhiser, witness to prove property taken, being affirmed and examined
                    by the Commissioner says:</p>
                <p>I am 30 years old and reside in New Hope, Augusta County Va. I am not related to
                    the claimant and have no interest in his claim. I was present at the claimant's
                    house during the war and saw the Union troops take five barrels of flour, eight
                    head of cattle and one horse from him. The flour was taken on the 6th of June at
                    the time of the battle of Piedmont. I do not remember whose army it was. The
                    flour was in the house and was taken away on a cart by the soldiers. There was a
                    man who talked as if he had authority, who came to <orig reg="impress"
                    >press</orig> the flour. I do not remmeber whether he was an officer. I did not
                    hear anything said at the time. The flour was in barrels. The troops were on
                    their way to Staunton Va. when they stopped and took the flour. I do not know
                    what flour was worth at that time. I saw eight head of cattle and one horse
                    taken by the Union troops at the time of the Burning Raid. I do not know whose
                    army it was - I did know but I have forgotten. It was the army that did the
                    burning. I think there were six milch cows and two other cattle. I do not know
                    what kind they were. I do not know the value of the cattle. They were in good
                    condition. The cattle were all driven away together by the soldiers. There was
                    an officer with the soldiers. I did not hear anything said at the time. The
                    horse was in the field with the cattle and he was led away by the soldiers who
                    took the cattle. It was a sorrel mare - I do not know how old. It was in very
                    good condition - tolerably large - I do not know its age. I do not know the
                    value.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Sabra B. Aldhiser</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>James H. Humbert</byline>
                <p>James H. Humbert, witness to prove property taken, being affirmed and examined by
                    the Commissioner, deposes and says:</p>
                <p>I am 26 years old and live at Rawley Va. I am a farmer. I am a son of the
                    claimant and have no interest in this claim. I was present and saw a sorrel mare
                    taken from my father by the Union troops under Gen. Sheridan at the time of the
                    Burning Raid. It was in the meadow and was led away by the soldiers. There was
                    an officer with them. I did not hear anything said at the time. It was seven or
                    eight years old - in very good condition and was worth about $140. Further
                    deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Jas. H. Humbert</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Noah Beard</byline>
                <p>Noah Beard, witness to prove loyalty of claimant being affirmed and examined by
                    the Commissioner says:</p>
                <p>I am 57 years old and reside at New Hope, Augusta County, Virginia. I am a
                    saddler. I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in this claim. I
                    lived about four miles from him during the war, and saw him occasionally. I did
                    not have much personal acquaintance with him, but knew him well by reputation. I
                    did not talk with him about the war while it was going on. I knew him by
                    reputation as a thoroughly loyal man. I knew his general reputation. It was that
                    of a loyal man. He was regarded a loyal man by his loyal neighbors. I never knew
                    him to be molested or injured on account of his Union sentiment. I never knew
                    him to own any Confederate Bonds, or do anything to sustain the financial credit
                    of the Confederate State. I never knew him to render any aid or assistance to
                    either army. From his general reputation he could not possibly have proved his
                    loyalty to the Confederate government if it had succeeded in maintaining a
                    separate existence, although I know of no act done or language used that could
                    have prevented him.</p>
                <p>Further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Noah Beard</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>Noah Beard</byline>
                <p>New Hope, Va.</p>
                <p>Captain Snow</p>
                <p>Dear Sir,</p>
                <p>I wish to say that I was called on to testify to the loyalty of Samuel Garber,
                    Jacob L. Humbert &amp; Henry K. Eakle &amp; that I was requested to
                    state the truth &amp; the whole truth &amp; nothing but the truth but
                    the questions put prevented me from telling all that I knew in regard to their
                    loyalty &amp; that <unclear>the</unclear> last question put to me in Henry
                    K. Eakle testimony to loyalty I was not permitted to answer the question as I
                    had wished to do from the fact that they said it was evading the question. My
                    answer was this, that from his reputation in the community in which he lived as
                    a loyal citizen to the United States &amp; his conversation heretofore
                    &amp; his acts during the war I consider would of prevented him from proving
                    his loyalty to the Confederacy had it maintained itself as a seperate
                    government. This was my answer in all three of my depositions referred to above.
                    yours Most Respectfully</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Noah Beard</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sept. 7th 1872</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Alfred Rupert</byline>
                <p>Hd. Qrs. 2d Brig. 3rd Div. U. of S. Staunton Va. June 27th, 1865</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="underline">To all whom it may concern:</hi>
                </p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Jacob L. Humbert</hi> a citizen and resident of Augusta
                    County Va. having applied to me for <hi rend="underline">Protection papers</hi>
                    to insure his person family &amp; property against danger - It is hereby <hi
                        rend="underline">directed</hi> and <hi rend="underline">commanded</hi> that
                    the person, family &amp; property of said <hi rend="underline">Jacob L.
                        Humbert</hi> shall not interfered with or violated in any manner.</p>
                <p>All <hi rend="underline">Officers &amp; Soldiers</hi> of U.S. Army &amp;
                    all <hi rend="underline">Citizens</hi> who shall in any manner offend or violate
                    above instructions will be dealt with in the severest manner known to military
                    law.</p>
                <p>Given at Hd. Qrs. U.S. Forces at Staunton Va. this 27th day of June 1865</p>
                <p>by Order of Col. W.W. Stewart Alfred Rupert Lieut. &amp; A.A.A. Genl.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>Archive Office, WAR DEPARTMENT, Jan 31, 1878, Book 3 Letters Sent, page 262</p>
                <p>Case of John L. Humbert, Augusta Co Va</p>
                <p>Bill &amp; receipt for 107 Bushels of Wheat Sold to the C. States, at $4.<hi
                        rend="super">25</hi> amount $454.<hi rend="super">75</hi>. Paid
                    at Staunton Aug 22nd 1863 by Maj H.M. Bell Q.M.C.S.A.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>Archive Office, WAR DEPARTMENT, July 1, 1878</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 325</p>
                <p>Case of Jacob L. Humbert, Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>This claimant sold the Confederate States Commissary agent twenty barrels of
                    flour, for which he was paid twenty five dollars per barrel on the 25th day of
                    May 1863, at Staunton, Va by William J. Nelson, agent of the Com. Dept. of the
                    C.S. Army. See Mr. Humbert's receipts for $500.00, on file in this office.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                
                <byline>Jacob Crumbaker and Samuel Garber</byline>
                <p>We the undersigned Loyal Citizens of Augusta County Virginia do certify on oath
                    that we have known Jacob L. Humbert for many years and know him to have been
                    Loyal to the United States Government, before, at the time &amp; since the
                    taking of the property &amp; supplies in the claimants petition mentioned.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">Jacob Crumbaker</name> New Hope, <name type="witness">Samuel
                        Garber</name> New Hope</p>
                <p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me on this 1st of May 1871 <name
                        type="other">H.G. M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Causland N.P.</name></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d16">
                
                <byline>John Yates, Charles Bates, and Henry K. Eakle</byline>
                <p>We the under signed citizens of Augusta Co. Va. being acquainted with Jacob L.
                    Humbert know him to have been a Union man during the late Rebellion and believe
                    that the matters certified to in the fore going affidavit are in all respects
                    true and would most earnestly and respectfully recommend its payment.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John Yates</name>
                    <name type="witness">Charles Bates</name>
                    <name type="witness">Henry K. Eakle</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d17">
                
                <byline>TS Tukey</byline>
                <p>Staunton Va Feb 22nd 1869</p>
                <p>I was stationed in Staunton two years immediately after the close of the War as
                    an agent of the Freedmens Bureau and from all the information I have I believe
                    your Petitioner was Loyal to the United States Government during the Whole of
                    the Rebellion.</p>
                <p><name type="witness">TS Tukey</name> U.S. Commissioner</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d18">
                
                <byline>C. Douglas Gray</byline>
                <p>I certify that the Petitioner above named was always in my opinion a Loyal
                    Citizen of the United States.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">C. Douglas Grey</name>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <unclear>Register Bankrupt <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></unclear>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
