<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0540"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0540">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John Ruebush,
                    1875, Claim No. 17934</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john ruebush, 1875 claim no 17934</title>
        <author>Ruebush, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 13 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0540</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498427</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John Ruebush, 1875,
                            Claim No. 17934</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john ruebush, 1875 claim no 17934</title>
            <author>John Ruebush</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C., fiche #1828</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1875">1875</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0540T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                
                <p>John Ruebush filed this claim in 1875 for $187.50, claiming the Union army under
                    General Sheridan's command took six head of cattle in 1864 during the "burning
                    raid." Ruebush was a farmer near Mt. Sidney who purportedly urged neighbors to
                    "try Mr. Lincoln." As the property was taken during the Burning Raid, and not
                    specifically for military use, the claim was disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>6 head of Cattle 625 lbs each equal to 3750 lb gross 5cts</cell>
                            <cell>$187.50</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$187.50</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                
                <p>This claimant John Ruebush voted in Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> as the record shows to ratify the ordinance of
                    Secession - And the cattle for which the claim is made were taken in Sheridan's
                    "burning raid" prob. for army use, but driven out of the state, sold &amp;
                    the proceeds paid into the treasury</p>
                <p>The claim is disallowed.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name><lb/><name type="other">Orange
                        Ferriss</name><lb/><name type="other">J.B. Howell</name><lb/><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                
                <byline>John Ruebush</byline>
                <p>In answer to the First General Interrogatory, the Deponent says: My name is John
                    Ruebush, my age 75 years, my residence Augusta County, in the State of Virginia,
                    and my occupation a Farmer; I am the claimant, and have beneficial interest in
                    the claim.</p>
                <p>Interrogatory 2. I lived on my own farm near Mt. Sidney in Augusta County Va.
                    during the whole period of the war.</p>
                <p>3-4 No sir</p>
                <p>5 It seems that I did take some oath after the war. I don't remember distinctly.</p>
                <p>6 to 17 inclusive no sir.</p>
                <p>18 I never furnished the Confederacy with anything I was not compelled to. All
                    farmers were obliged to give a tenth since they took a tenth part of my crops.</p>
                <p>19 to 24 inclusive no sir</p>
                <p>25 yes they took 1/10 of my crops as before stated. They did not pay me for it.
                    They wanted my horses several times but I managed to save them.</p>
                <p>26 to 29 inclusive no sir</p>
                <p>30 none nearer than nephews. One in the county and two in Rockbridge. They were
                    drafted in the militia. I did not aid nor encourage them in any way nor furnish
                    them with anything. They are all now living near their old homes.</p>
                <p>31 to 39 inclusive no sir.</p>
                <p>40 I sympathized with the Union cause. I told more that 50 people it was better
                    for us to stay in the Union, and to try Mr Lincoln first before making a fuss
                    and I always believed it would have been best to have <orig reg="stayed"
                    >staid</orig> in the Union and I never could <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> [several lines of text are
                    illegible]</p>
                <p>41 I was for the Union all the time and am still. I <unclear>didnt have</unclear>
                    any sympathy at all with the rebellion.</p>
                <p>44. I am a native born citizen of the United States and have not passed through
                    Bankruptcy.</p>
                <p>In answer to interrogatories as to the taking of the property deponent says.</p>
                <p>Property I was in the cornfield cutting up corn when my cattle were taken and saw
                    my cattle driven away by some troops of <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr>
                    Sheridan's army in the fall of 1864. While the burning was going on. They were a
                    small squad of cavalry who were taking cattle from all around the neighborhood
                    they drove away 7 cows from me, and I followed them on toward Harrisonburg a day
                    or two after and got some of them back. The six which were taken were worth on
                    average $30 a piece if not more.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John Ruebush</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                
                <byline>David H. Ruebush</byline>
                <p>David H. Ruebeush being duly sworn says</p>
                <p>I am 22 years old. I am a son of the claimant and live with him. I was present
                    when the property was taken and saw it taken.</p>
                <p>They were taken by a squad of union cavalry belonging to the army of Gen.
                    Sheridan at the time of the burning in the fall of the year 1864 Were driven off
                    with other cattle they were collecting. They drove away 7 but we got one of them
                    back. The 6 head taken were 3 milch cows and 3 young cattle; one was 2 and 2 of
                    them were 3 years old.</p>
                <p>The cattle were driven off towards Harrisonburg where my father found and brought
                    home one of the cows.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">D.H. Ruebush</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                
                <byline>Mary J. Ruebush</byline>
                <p>I am 19 years old. I live with the claimant he is my father. I was present at the
                    time our cattle were taken and saw them taken. They were <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> off by a party
                    of cavalry at the time of the burning in the fall of 1864. They <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 4 were
                    cows and three were young cattle. My father went to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> them and
                        <unclear>brought</unclear> one of the cows back in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> days. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> And
                    further the deponent saith not</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Mary J. Ruebush</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                
                <byline>Matthias McKersh</byline>
                <p>Deposition of Matthias McKersh as to the loyalty of John Ruebush</p>
                <p>I am 68 years old, a farmer, live near Mt. Meridian in Augusta County.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant since my youth. I am not related to him and have no
                    interest in his claim.</p>
                <p>I don't remember any particular conversation with him on the subject of
                    Secession. I heard him say that the Union government was good enough for him and
                    that he would have nothing to do with the war. I had frequent conversations with
                    him during the war, and he always spoke in favor of the old government. He never
                    said much about the battles - it was not prudent for one to say much about such
                    things on the Union side. I don't know of his having anything to do about
                    helping refugees through the lines. I only know he used to speak when talking
                    with me in favor of the old government as it was before the war. So far as I
                    could understand him he sympathized with the Union Cause.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Matt. McKersh</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                
                <byline>John W. Landes</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John W. Landes as to the loyalty of John Ruebush.</p>
                <p>I am 41 years old, a farmer, live 2 miles from Mt. Sidney and 1 1/2 miles from
                    Mr. Ruebush.</p>
                <p>I am not related to the claimant and have no interest in his claim.</p>
                <p>I have known the claimant about 35 years. I often heard him speak on the subject
                    of Secession, rebellion and such matters. He was opposed to Secession - and told
                    people that had better wait and try Mr. Lincoln before rushing into a war. Said
                    he believed he would make a good President and that they ought not to break up
                    the union. I was a union man myself, and he knew it, and talked freely with me,
                    but it was dangerous to speak much openly in favor of the union. He was
                    generally known <unclear>however</unclear> by union people as loyal to the
                    United States. I have heard him spoken of as a union man. And I regarded him as
                    a loyal man during the war.</p>
                <p>And further deponent saith not.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John W. Landes</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                
                <byline>Isaac P. Baldwin Special Commissioner</byline>
                <p>REMARKS BY THE SPECIAL COMMISSIONER</p>
                <p>I am of the opinion that this old claimant was a Union man at heart, and had no
                    sympathy with the rebellion.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="other">Isaac P. Baldwin</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>ARCHIVE OFFICE, WAR DEPARTMENT, January 31, 1878</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 262</p>
                <p>Case of John Ruebush of Augusta Co. Virginia</p>
                <p>The name and signature of John G. Ruebush appears on the muster roll of Capt John
                    Avis's Co, of "Provost Guards" raised at Staunton Augusta Co. Virginia</p>
                <p>Dec 20/75 Rejected</p>
                <p>See Muster Roll in Virginia Reserves</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d14">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>ARCHIVE OFFICE, WAR DEPARTMENT, April 29, 1876</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 171</p>
                <p>Case of John Ruebush of Augusta Co. Virginia</p>
                <p>Bill &amp; vouchers for 1000 lbs of Hay amounting to $30.00 Sold to the
                    C.S.A.</p>
                <p>Paid Feb 12th 1864 by Capt. I. Lightfoot</p>
                <p>Disallowed 1875</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d15">
                
                <byline>United States War Department</byline>
                <p>ARCHIVE OFFICE, WAR DEPARTMENT, April 15, 1874</p>
                <p>Book 3, Letters Sent, page 21</p>
                <p>17934</p>
                <p>Case of John Ruebush of Augusta Co. Va.</p>
                <p>Name appears on petition of citizens of that Co. asking discharge of Wm W.
                    Knibble a disabled man.</p>
                <p>"In view of his total disability to perform military duty we feel free to offer
                    this petition and urge our claim."</p>
                <p>See K149.WD18621</p>
                <p>(left in files)</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
