<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="SCC0507"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 id="SCC0507">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John H. Fix,
                    1876, Claim No. 1384</title>
        <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john h fix, 1876 claim no 1384</title>
        <author>Fix, John H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 24 </num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">SCC0507</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible</p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2006">2006</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498394</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Southern Claims Commission: Claim of John H. Fix, 1876,
                            Claim No. 1384</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">southern claims commission claim of john h fix, 1876 claim no 1384</title>
            <author>John H. Fix</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives, Washington,
                            D.C. RG 123, Congressional Jurisdiction #8648</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1876">1876</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Death/Casualties, Economy, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="SCC0507T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John H. Fix filed this claim in 1876 for $200, claiming General Hunter's Union
                    troops took one Mare in 1864. John was a 54 year old farmer who resided near
                    Greenville. He voted for the Ordinance of Secession and had two brothers-in-law
                    in the Confederate Army. The claim was disallowed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="claim_items" id="d5">
                <p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Item Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Claimed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Allowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <hi rend="bold">Amount Disallowed:</hi>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>1 Mare</cell>
                            <cell>$200.00</cell>
                            <cell>$0.00</cell>
                            <cell>$200.00</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="claim_summary" id="d6">
                <p>The Claimant testifies that he voted for secession. Was influenced to vote so by
                    those who said there would be no war. Mr. Fix was not threatened nor molested.
                    He had two brothers-in-law in the <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed<hi
                            rend="super">te.</hi></abbr> Army.</p>
                <p>His surroundings all indicate association and sympathy with the Confederates. He
                    was pleased at the conclusion of the war, but can not tell whether pleased or
                    not when he heard of the battle of Bull Run &amp;c.</p>
                <p>We are not satisfied that he was loyal. Claim rejected.</p>
                <p><name type="other">A.O. Aldis</name><lb/><name type="other">J.B.
                        Howell</name><lb/><name type="other">O. Ferriss</name><lb/><abbr
                        expan="Commissioners">Commrs.</abbr> of Claims</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d7">
                <byline>John H. Fix</byline>
                <p>Deposition of John H. Fix. Claimant</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Ans. My name is John H. Fix, my age is 54 years. My residence near
                    Greenville, Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr> where I have resided all my life. My occupation a farmer.</p>
                <p>2. Ans. I am the claimant.</p>
                <p>3. Ans. I was born on the place where I now reside.</p>
                <p>4. Ans. I resided at the same place and was occupied as a farmer. I made no
                    change of residence or business.</p>
                <p>5. Ans. My sympathies were on the side of the Union, and were so from the
                    beginning to the end.</p>
                <p>6. Ans. I have no recollection of doing or saying anything against the cause of
                    the Union.</p>
                <p>7. Ans. I was ready at all times during the war to aid the Union cause, as far as
                    I could.</p>
                <p>8. Ans. I never had an <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> to do anything
                    except give aid to some unknown soldiers to escape from the rebel lines.</p>
                <p>9. Ans. I had no relatives in the Union army that I know of.</p>
                <p>10. Ans. I was not.</p>
                <p>11. Ans. I never contributed anything.</p>
                <p>12. Ans. I took the Union side and said all I could to operate against secession.</p>
                <p>13. Ans. I adhered to the Union cause and not my state.</p>
                <p>14. Ans. I cannot now say what my feelings were at the results of the battles
                    mentioned but when the surrender of Lee occurred I rejoiced at the conclusion
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">of the war</add> and safety of the Union.</p>
                <p>Ques. 15. Ans. I never had any privileges or protection granted me.</p>
                <p>16. Ans. I never took the ironclad oath, I have held no office.</p>
                <p>17. Ans. David Ziuk, J.H.B. Shultz, James M. Yates, and Adam Hawpe. The two
                    latter are witnesses.</p>
                <p>18. Ans. I was not threatened or molested.</p>
                <p>19. Ans. I never was arrested.</p>
                <p>20. Ans. I had Corn and fodder taken. I did not know the party, he paid me ten
                    dollars in Confederate funds.</p>
                <p>21. Ans. I had no property confiscated.</p>
                <p>22. Ans. I never did anything voluntarily.</p>
                <p>23. Ans. The Confederate laws, and authority exercised by Army officers.</p>
                <p>24. Ans. I never was in any service or employment for the Confederacy or rebel
                    authority.</p>
                <p>25. Ans. I was not in the civil or military or naval service of the Confederacy,
                    in no shape nor form.</p>
                <p>26. Ans. I never took any oath.</p>
                <p>27. Ans. I never had charge of any stores or other property, belonging to the
                    Confederacy, nor sold or furnished any supplies, nor interest in any contract or
                    manufactures in aid of the rebellion.</p>
                <p>28. Ans. I never engaged in blockade running, nor was interested in such
                    enterprises.</p>
                <p>Ques. 29. Ans. I had no interest or share in any vessel or boat for any purpose
                    or on any waters.</p>
                <p>30. Ans. I never did subscribe to any loan to the Confederate states or any state
                    in rebellion.</p>
                <p>31. Ans. I made no contribution of any kind or for any purpose.</p>
                <p>32. Ans. I give no information to any one against the United States.</p>
                <p>33. Ans. I did not belong to any society or association for any purpose.</p>
                <p>34. Ans. I never took an Oath of allegiance to the Confederacy.</p>
                <p>35. Ans. I never received a pass.</p>
                <p>36. Ans. I had two brothers-in-law, Joseph B. Wright and John A. Wright, in the
                    Confederate Army. Joseph volunteered in 1861, and John in about 1862 or '63,
                    Joseph died during the war, and John resides near Arbor Hill, P.O. I did not see
                    them at the time. I <orig reg="gave">give</orig> nothing as an outfit or
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">for</add> their support.</p>
                <p>37. Ans. I was under no disabilities.</p>
                <p>38. Ans. I have never asked for a pardon.</p>
                <p>39. Ans. I took an Amnesty Oath after the close of the War, in 1865, in Staunton,
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> and because I wished to be restored to all
                    my former privileges in the Union.</p>
                <p>40. Ans. I never was a prisoner.</p>
                <p>41. Ans. I was not arrested.</p>
                <p>42. Ans. There never was any fines or assessments levied against me.</p>
                <p>Ques. 43. Ans. I had no property taken or sold by the United States under any
                    law.</p>
                <p>44. Ans. In 1860, I did not vote. I do not recollect of voting during the War. I
                    voted for the ratification of the Ordinance of Secession, but against my own
                    consent, but was influenced to do so by the declarations of leading citizens
                    that if the people would show a <orig reg="unity">unit</orig> there would be no
                    war. I ever after regretted my vote as it was contrary to my convictions and
                    sympathies.</p>
                <p>45. Ans. I never belonged to any committee, home guard or any other association
                    combined against the Union.</p>
                <p>46. Ans. I never belonged to any military organization hostile to the United
                    States. I furnished no substitute.</p>
                <p>47. Ans. I never was employed in any department of the Confederate Government or
                    army, nor on Railroad nor engaged in the transportation of troops or supplies.</p>
                <p>48. Ans. I never had charge of anything for the use and support of the
                    Confederacy.</p>
                <p>49. Ans. I had no employment in <orig reg="Saltpeter">Saltpetre</orig> works,
                    tanning, milling and in nothing to aid or benefit the rebellion.</p>
                <p>50. Ans. I had nothing to do with prisoners, of any class at all.</p>
                <p>51. Ans. I never was.</p>
                <p>Ques. 66. Ans. The property charged in my account belonged to myself.</p>
                <p>67. Ans. The property was taken from my farm, situated in Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr> near Greenville adjoining J.B. Smith &amp;
                    others, about 80 or 90 acres cleared and about 40 woodland.</p>
                <p>68. Ans. I have never filed application in Bankruptcy.</p>
                <p>72. Ans. I was at home, but being very ill with rheumatism, could not be out of
                    my room and did not see the soldiers when they took my mare from the stable.</p>
                <p>73. Ans. The Mare was taken in day light.</p>
                <p>74. Ans. I did not see any officer, and did hear of any being present. I saw no
                    one to complain to.</p>
                <p>75. Ans. I got no voucher.</p>
                <p>76. Ans. I never have received any payment at all. I have never presented this
                    claim to any authority for payment.</p>
                <p>77. Ans. The Mare was taken by soldiers belonging to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Hunter's Army, then marching from
                    Staunton to Lexington.</p>
                <p>78. Ans. I did not see the Mare taken for the reason stated.</p>
                <p>79. Ans. The Mare was 4 or 5 years old, of medium size in good order, full of
                    life and mettle, but very gentle, under the saddle or in harness, perfectly
                    sound and without a blemish.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John H. Fix</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d8">
                <byline>William H. Fix</byline>
                <p>Deposition of William H. Fix</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. Ans. My name is William H. Fix, my age is <unclear>24</unclear> years. I
                    reside near Greenville, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I am a Blacksmith by
                    trade.</p>
                <p>2. Ans. I am the son of the claimant, but have of no special interest in the
                    success of the claim.</p>
                <p>72. Ans. I was at the house, up stairs and saw the Mare taken from the Stable
                    yard.</p>
                <p>73. Ans. She was taken in day light about 12 or 1 Oclock. There was no secrecy
                    shown at all.</p>
                <p>74. Ans. I do not know whether there was an officer present or not, there was no
                    complaint, and my father <del hand="h1">was</del> was confined with pains, &amp; could
                    not go out. There were at least four soldiers engaged in taking the Mare. They
                    were horse back and from their equipments I supposed were Cavalry men
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">&amp;</add> belonged to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi
                            rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Hunter's Army. My father's house is
                    probably half mile from the Turnpike road, on <add hand="h1" place="inline">which</add> the Army was then
                    marching.</p>
                <p>75. Ans. No voucher was given or asked for.</p>
                <p>77. Ans. The Mare was taken by Soldiers belonging to <abbr expan="General"
                    >Genl.</abbr> Hunter's Army. Then marching from Staunton to Lexington, in the
                    month of June, 1864, the soldiers led the Mare away, and went on the road in the
                    direction of Lexington and <orig reg="parallel">paralel</orig> with the Turnpike
                    where the main army was then marching.</p>
                <p>78. Ans. I saw the Mare taken away by soldiers.</p>
                <p>Ques. 79. Ans. The Mare was a bay, and about 6 years old. She was medium size,
                    and in good working order, and fine looking, of good life and well broken to
                    ride and to work. I am satsified that at the close of the war, if in the same
                    condition as when taken she would have brought two hundred dollars. My father
                    sold a 4 year old at the close of the War of common appearance and inferior
                    qualities for One hundred &amp; twenty five dollars. I believe that the four
                    men engaged in taking the Mare, were soldiers belonging to General Hunter's
                    Army, all their equipments were soldiers-like, and being so close to the Main
                    body could not have <add hand="h1" place="inline">been</add> private citizens.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness"><abbr expan="William">W<hi rend="super"
                        >m.</hi></abbr> H. Fix</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d9">
                <byline>Adam M. Hawpe</byline>
                <p>Loyalty Proven</p>
                <p>Ques. 1. My name is Adam M. Hawpe, my is 70 years. I reside near Greenville,
                    Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> My
                    occupation is a farmer. I am not related to the claimant, and no benefit in his
                    claim.</p>
                <p>53. Ans. I have known the claimant all his life, and all the time intimately.</p>
                <p>54. Ans. We reside about 2 1/2 miles apart and same distance during the War.</p>
                <p>55. Ans. I met him frequently during the war, how often I cannot say. We attended
                    the same churches, stores and Post Office.</p>
                <p>Ques. 56. Ans. I conversed with him very frequnetly about the War. I have no
                    recollection at any time of those present, and cannot recollect any particular
                    words and expressions used by the claimant, but I know that his sentiments and
                    sympathies were in accord with my own, and I was opposed to secession as
                    violently as any man in the United States.</p>
                <p>57. Ans. I do not know that he did anything to aid the Union cause, he had no
                    opportunity to do anything and if he had it would have been extremely hazardous.</p>
                <p>58. Ans. I never heard him <add hand="h1" place="inline">speak</add> a disloyal word or do a disloyal act.</p>
                <p>59. Ans. I never had any one speak of him as a Secessionist.</p>
                <p>60. Ans. His reputation amongst his loyal neighbors was that of a strong Union
                    man, he was a very cautious and timid man. Adam Ziuk and John H.B. Shultz were
                    well known Union men, and Gibsons and others and they knew him well enough to
                    testify for him.</p>
                <p>62. Ans. I was myself an adherent to the Union and well known to the claimant.</p>
                <p>63. Ans. There were threats made against those who might refuse to vote for the
                    Ordinance of Secession.</p>
                <p>64. Ans. I know of nothing, by which he could have established loyalty to the
                    Confederacy.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness"><abbr expan="Adam">A<hi rend="super">m.</hi></abbr>
                        M. Hawpe</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d10">
                <byline>James M. Yates</byline>
                <p>My name is James M. Yates. I reside near Staunton. <add hand="h1" place="inline">I am not related to
                    the</add> claimant. My age is 35 years. I am a <abbr expan="United States"
                    >U.S.</abbr> Rev. Storekeeper.</p>
                <p>Answer to 53. Ans. I have known him since the winter of 1860 &amp; '61. I
                    knew him intimately from that time <orig reg="until">till</orig> the fall of
                    1864.</p>
                <p>Ans. to 54. Ans. I suppose it was three miles from my residence to his.</p>
                <p>55. Ans. I met him about once a week.</p>
                <p>56. Ans. At the commencement of the war we conversed together about the cause and
                    results of the war, and he entertained and expressed the same views which I
                    entertained myself, that the war was unjust upon the part of the South. That the
                    Union should and he believed would be maintained. I do not recollect of ever
                    holding a conversation with him in the presence of others.</p>
                <p>57. Ans. I do not know of anything that he did except his declarations to me. I
                    heard from either a man by the name of Parrack or Harvey that the claimant aided
                    and give information to parties, who were trying to escape from the Confederate
                    service.</p>
                <p>58. Ans. I never heard him express a word, or do anything against the Union.</p>
                <p>59. Ans. I never heard anything that the claimant should have said or done
                    against the Union.</p>
                <p>60. Ans. I think that his reputation was that of a Union man. I heard on one
                    occasion John Brownlee, of near Greenville, say that "he doubted his (Fix)
                    loyalty to the South." Brownlee was a strong rebel.</p>
                <p>Ques. 61. Ans. David Parrack, Andrew Ziuk, <add hand="h1" place="inline">&amp;</add> Adam Hawpe, of
                    the same neighborhood all of whom I presume could testify to his loyalty.</p>
                <p>62. Ans. I was an adherent to the Union cause during the war, and am still. The
                    claimant knew my position by my words and acts.</p>
                <p>63. Ans. I do not know of any.</p>
                <p>64. Ans. I do not know of anything except his language to myself, he was a very
                    quiet and timid man.</p>
                <p>65. Ans. I know nothing except what I have stated.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">James M. Yates</name>
                </p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d11">
                <byline>John H. Fix</byline>
                <p>Petition</p>
                <p>To the Hon. the Commissioners of Claims Under the Act of Congress of March 3,
                    1871</p>
                <p>Your petitioner, John H. Fix, does <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> &amp; present that he is a citizen
                    of near Greenville Augusta County Virginia and was at the time his claim
                    occured. That he is the original owner of the herein after mentioned claim. That
                    there was taken from the petitioner for the use of the Army of the United States
                    for which no payment has been made or compensation received in any manner or
                    from any source for any part there of the following described supplies.</p>
                <p>One Horse $200.00</p>
                <p>That the price charged is the fair market value for the supplies at the time and
                    place last mentioned as your petitioner was informed and believes, that said
                    supplies were taken by the <abbr expan="United States">US</abbr> forces under
                    General Hunter on or about the 10 of June 1864 and no voucher or receipts were
                    given for the same.</p>
                <p>That this claim has never been presented to any Executive Department for
                    settlement.</p>
                <p>The petitioner further says that he hereby <unclear>invests and</unclear>
                    appoints <unclear>P. F. Venable</unclear> his true and lawful Attorney to appear
                    before the Claims Commission appointed under the Acts of Congress on March 3,
                    1871 or any Court Department or Bureau of the Government of the United States
                    and prosecute this Claim to final issue with full power of Substitution hereby
                    ratifying and confirming of said Attorney, shall lawfully do in virtue hereby
                    and hereof annulling and invoking all other power of Attorney in the premises.
                    Your petitioner further avows that he is a citizen who remained loyal adherent
                    to the Cause &amp; <del hand="h1">of</del> the Government of the United States during
                    the war and was as loyal before and at the time of the taking or furnishing
                    property for which claim is made.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John H. Fix</name>
                </p>
                <p>John H. Fix being duly sworn, deposes and says that he is the petitioner named in
                    the foregoing petition and who signed the same that the matters there in stated
                    are true of his own knowledge. And deponent further says that he did not
                    volunteer or serve in the Confederate army or navy, either as an officer,
                    soldier, or in any other capacity at any time during the late rebellion that he
                    never volunatarily furnished any stores supplies or other material aid to said
                    Confederate Army or Navy or to the Confederate Government or to any officer
                    department or adherent of the same, in support there of and that he never
                    voluntarily accepted or exerices the function of any office under or yielded
                    support to the said Confederate Government.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="claimant">John H. Fix</name>
                </p>
                <p>Subscribed and Sworn to before me this 24<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of
                    April 1871 at Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>
                <p><name type="other">James M. Baldwin</name> N.P.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d12">
                <byline>John A. Brownlee</byline>
                <p>State of Virginia<lb/>County of Augusta</p>
                <p>John A. Brownlee a citizen of the County and State aforesaid being duly sworn do
                    depose and say that I am well acquainted with John H. Fix of said County and
                    State, and that <del hand="h1">he is</del> am well aware of the fact that said Fix, had
                    one Horse taken from him of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> forces
                    under <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l.</hi></abbr> Hunter on
                    or about the 10<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of June 1864, and that said
                    horse was taken for use in the U.S. service, and was of the full marketable
                    value of Two hundred dollars.</p>
                <p>I do further swear that I know that said John H. Fix was a citizen loyal to the
                    Government of the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> throughout the
                    rebellion that he never by act or deed sided or assisted the Confederate
                    Government, its officers or adherents, nor served said Confederate Government in
                    any capacity.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">John A. Brownlee</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> day of May
                    1871 at Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a.</hi></abbr></p>
                <p><name type="other">James M. Baldwin</name> N.P.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="testimony" id="d13">
                <byline>Adam M. Hawpe</byline>
                <p>State of Virginia<lb/>County of Augusta</p>
                <p>I Adam M. Hawpe of the County and State aforesaid being duly Sworn, deposes and
                    says that he is well acquainted with John H. Fix of said County and State, that
                    he knows that said Fix, was during the war of the rebellion a loyal citizen of
                    the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> that he never rendered any voluntary
                    aid or support to the Confederate Government, its officers or adherents, nor did
                    he serve said Confederate Government in any capacity. I do further swear that to
                    the best of my knowledge and believe that the claims presented by said Fix for
                    payment of One Horse taken by the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> forces
                    in 1864, is correct and just, and that the price charged for the same is
                    reasonable, and just.</p>
                <p>
                    <name type="witness">Adam M. Hawpe</name>
                </p>
                <p>Sworn to and Subscribed before me this 24<hi rend="super">th</hi> day of
                    April 1871 at Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super"
                    >a.</hi></abbr></p>
                <p><name type="other">James M. Baldwin</name> N.P.</p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
