<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.02.09">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/18/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-02-09">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">9</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.02.09.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.02.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Fifteenth Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Georgia has ratified the Fifteenth Amendment, and it is claimed by the
                        Radicals that this makes up the requisite number of States to establish it
                        as the law of the land. It is doubtful, however, whether the Secretary of
                        State will declare the amendment ratified by twenty-eight States in view of
                        the fact that New York has withdrawn her consent, given by a former
                        Legislature, and the further fact, that the ratification of Indiana was the
                        act of less than a quorum of the members of its Legislature.</p>
                    <p>The proposition is in itself sufficiently startling, and the manner of its
                        adoption so outrageously regardless of the true sentiment of the people,
                        that he may well hesitate before he declares it ratified according to the
                        forms of law. For instance, there is no sensible man, who has mingled
                        largely with the people of this Commonwealth, who doubts, that, if the
                        amendment had been submitted at any time in the past, or if it were
                            <sic>summitted</sic> now, to them at the polls, it would have been, and
                        would be now, overwhelmingly defeated. Negro suffrage has always been
                        unpopular with our people and is no less so now. It is an act of fearful
                        injustice to the people, therefore, for a Legislature elected without
                        reference to this question at all to undertake to force this obnoxious
                        doctrine upon a State whose people were up in arms against it and anxious to
                        have an expression of opinion upon it, each one for himself. And so it was
                        in many other States. Designing men have so arranged it that the people, who
                        believe in a White man's government, could express their opinions at the
                        ballot box, but were forced to submit to the action of men of their own
                        party, who claimed to represent them by voting for this amendment, when, in
                        reality, they knew that they would be representing their sentiments truly by
                        voting against it. The amendment, even if ratified by twenty-eight
                        Legislatures is not the work of the people. It is simply a successful piece
                        of political chicanery, having its origin in the minds of wicked aspirants
                        for power, who thought they saw in this measure an opportunity to push their
                        fanaticism, and, at the same time insure the ascendancy of their party for
                        many years to come.</p>
                    <p>Our State constitution contains the word <emph rend="italic">white</emph> as
                        one of the qualifications of a voter within this Commonwealth. That same
                        constitution provided the process of its amendment. It is difficult for a
                        Pennsylvanian to see how the Fifteenth Amendment can operate so as to
                        enfranchise the negro, in this State until our State constitution is altered
                        according to its own provisions. The Radicals do not hesitate to violate the
                        forms of law, however, and the amendment will be declared binding upon all
                        the States whenever the Secretary of State issues his proclamation asserting
                        that the ratification of twenty-eight States has been procured.</p>
                    <p>Then, too, there is the other objection, that the assent of the Southern
                        States has been procured by force and fraud. It is an outrage that the
                        American people should not tolerate, that the fundamental law of their
                        republic should be thus changed so vitally by compulsory measures applied to
                        certain States of the Union. Perhaps, some day, these questions may be
                        raised before a competent and fearless tribunal and this scandalous
                        proceeding receive the condemnation that it so richly merits. Meanwhile, we
                        presume, the negro will vote, and be elected to office.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Scathingly reports on the inevitable confirmation of the 15th amendment.
                    Attacks it for violating the will of the people and states rights. Only hopes
                    now that some day it will be condemned by like-minded men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Negro in the United States Senate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Washington correspondent of the New York <emph rend="italic"
                        >Herald</emph>, writing under date of the 2nd instant, gives the following
                        account of the reception extended to the negro Senator from Mississippi when
                        he presented himself in the Senate on that day. We commend it to those who
                        rejoice in the elevation of the black man to such a position of honor and
                        trust:--"Revels, the Mississippi Senator, the first representative of his
                        race and color chosen to fill a seat in the upper branch of the national
                        legislature, made his appearance again to-day on the floor of the Senate.
                        Revels was dressed in a black suit of fine cloth, coat very long and
                        clerical like, and pants and vest of corresponding proportion. He wore dark
                        gloves, also, and carried a mulatto colored stick. The distinguished darkey
                        made quite a sensation. The moment he came into the Senate Chamber and took
                        his seat on one of the luxurious lounges, several Senators hurried over to
                        him, shook him warmly by the hand and welcomed him to his new field of
                        labor. Charles Sumner was among the first to offer, in very hearty style,
                        smiling all over and saying a quantity of very pretty things, which the
                        colored Senator heard with genuine pleasure. It was a spectacle worth
                        looking at to see Sumner and Revels, thus practically illustrating the idea
                        of political and social equality. Thayer, Chandler, Howard, Cameron, Warner,
                        Spencer, Drake, Lewis, Howe and other Senators paid their respects. Cameron
                        had quite a talk with Revels. Spencer, of Alabama, sat down with Revels,
                        and, while making his congratulations, took a full survey of the ladies in
                        the gallery, who were looking down upon the scene, some with pleasure and
                        others with astonishment and horror. Spencer, you must know, is a great
                        favorite with the ladies. An effort was made to get fiery little Garret
                        Davis to allow himself to be led into the presence of Revels for
                        introduction, but the live Kentuckian could not see it; neither could
                        McCreery, colleague of Davis, who clings to the old time prejudices with
                        true <emph rend="italic">ante bellum</emph> tenacity."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes from a Republican paper on the acceptance of Hiram Revels in the
                    Senate. He received warm introduction from most Republican senators but some
                    bystanders and upper South Senators only looked on with horror. Generally a
                    positive tone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tax! Tax! Tax!</head>
                <origin>Pomeroy's Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Republicans evidently calculate on an eternity of taxation. Mr. Grant's
                        administration is determined to push the scheme of converting the
                        Commissioner of Internal Revenue into a cabinet officer, with a
                        proportionate increase of salary and dignity. This means that there are to
                        be more taxes, and more officials. At the very time when people look for,
                        and have a right to expect a reduction of taxation, and the discharge of at
                        least a portion of the officials who are fattening at their expense, they
                        are met by a plan that involves a perpetuation of taxes and an increase of
                        tax-gatherers.</p>
                    <p>The Radicals have the majority in Congress just now. They have the power, and
                        they will probably exercise it, to push this measure through. But we predict
                        that the new Secretary of Internal Revenue will be the shortest-lived
                        Cabinet official that has ever been known. His official existence may
                        continue until the inauguration of the next President, although it may
                        terminate with the first session of the new Congress that is to be elected
                        next fall. The signs are unmistakable that the people are heartily sick of
                        Grant and all his consequences--brothers-in-law included.</p>
                    <p>When the Democracy comes into power it will make a clean sweep of the whole
                        brood of tax collectors, and effect a thorough reform of our tax system.
                        Even the skeleton of the new Cabinet Minister will not be left to mark the
                        vanity of Republican hopes of everlasting taxes.</p>
                    <p>In the meantime Grant and the Republicans may go on crowding tax-gatherers
                        into the Cabinet, Custom-house, and every other place where a cent can be
                        wrung out of the people.</p>
                    <p>But it will be pleasant work for Democrats to bowl them all over some of
                        these days.</p>
                    <p>In the meantime, however, we must all grin and bear it.---<emph rend="italic"
                            >Pomeroy's Democrat</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints an article which shows how Republicans are apt to continue high
                    taxes because Grant is thinking about making Internal Revenue a cabinet
                    position. Recognizes Republicans have the power to do this but predicts it won't
                    last long. Promises that Democrats will sweep out all trace of internal revenue
                    taxes once elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Chinese Immigrants</head>
                <origin>Annapolis Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article calls attention to the increasing number of Chinese immigrants
                    coming to the United States. The "influx" of "heathen idolaters" is a problem
                    that must be addressed. While European immigrants are always welcome, America
                    should not "open wide the floodgates by tapping this endless horde of Chinese
                    Pagans."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.02.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicolls</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. S. J. Nicolls, former pastor of Chambersburg's Presbyterian
                    Church, will give a lecture in Repository Hall on February 14th to raise money
                    to benefit the poor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. J. G. Schaff will deliver an address at the Court House on Friday.
                    "It will be mainly devoted to the question of the destiny of the wicked,
                    particularly to an examination of those Texts of Scripture which are supposed to
                    contradict his position in relation thereto."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Director of the Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzelman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frederick Long was sworn in as Director of the Poor in place of the
                    retiring Mr. Heintzelman. The following officers will be installed: Samuel
                    Brandt, steward; Dr. William H. Boyle, physician; John R. Orr, attorney and
                    clerk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Knights of Pythias</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A group of Fayetteville citizens have secured a charter to establish a
                    lodge of the Knights of Pythias. "This Order is making rapid strides in
                    advancement, and if a rigid examination is made as to the character and standing
                    of all applicants for membership, it is destined to become the first benevolent
                    institution in the United States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lloyd</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. John Lloyd of Orrstown delivered an amusing lecture on the "Irish
                    Character" in the Greenvillage Lyceum on Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Religious Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. G. Schaff announces a full schedule of speaking engagements throughout
                    Augusta County. He plans to "preach Jesus and the Resurrection."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>United American Mechanics</head>
                <origin>Opinion</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A council of the United American Mechanics will be formed in Chambersburg.
                    About 28 members have already joined. They state that their object is "to assist
                    each other in obtaining employment; to encourage each other in business in
                    preference to others; to establish a sick and funeral fund; to assist in
                    establishing a general fund for the relief of widows and orphans of deceased
                    members, and to aid members who, through Providence, may become incapacitated
                    from following their usual avocations, in obtaining situations suitable to their
                    afflictions." Interested persons can call on George Wood.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin Co. Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>President</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Franklin County Horticultural Society was held on February
                    1st. Eighteen members were present, including three ladies. A number of fruits
                    and vegetables were exhibited.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Special Term of Court which began on the 31st ult. continued all last
                        week until Saturday evening, His Honor, Judge Rowe, presiding.</p>
                    <p>Jacob B. Cook vs. Jesse Kean, Sr. Appeal by Deft. from the judgment of
                        Charles W. Lego, Esq., for $28.78. Verdict for Plff. for $44.52.</p>
                    <p>Levi Sanders vs. David Miller and David Miller, Jr. Summons in Debt on a
                        Promissory Note. Verdict for $27.</p>
                    <p>John Miley vs. John Wade. Ejectment for a tract of land in Quincy township
                        containing three acres, with a two-story dwelling house and other buildings
                        thereon erected. Jury discharged, having failed to agree.</p>
                    <p>Jacob Kyler vs. Jacob Heisy and wife. Sci. Fa. <emph rend="italic">sur</emph>
                        Mechanics' Lien. Settled by a confession of judgment by Defts. for $62 and
                        one-half the costs.</p>
                    <p>David Guyer vs. William Forbes. Summons in Assumpsit for lumber furnished to
                        Deft. as builder of a School House in Letterkenny township. Jury
                            <sic>dischared</sic>, having failed to agree.</p>
                    <p>Alexander E. McDowell vs. Peter Brough, Samuel F. Greenawalt and John A.
                        Brough. Summons in Assumpsit founded on a promissory note. Verdict for Plff.
                        for $5442.38.</p>
                    <p>M. G. Huff vs. F. C. Weidlich. Appeal by Deft. from the judgment of S. M.
                        Armstrong, Esq. for $55.81. Verdict for Plff. for $50.81</p>
                    <p>Jacob Laniz and wife vs. Jacob Lemaster. Summons case <emph rend="italic"
                        >sur</emph> Slander. Verdict for Plff. for $200.</p>
                    <p>Wm. Gelwicks, Assignee of W. C. McNulty in Bankruptcy vs. Samuel
                        Lesher.--Summons in Assumpsit on a promissory note. Verdict for
                    defendant.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kean</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lego</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanders</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heisy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weidlich</ln>
                        <fn>F. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lemaster</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gives brief summaries of cases before a special session of county court and
                    the verdicts reached. Mostly small claims cases.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flora</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lethers</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burhman</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George E. Flora and Sophia C. Lethers, both of Maryland, were married in
                    Waynesboro at Bowden House on January 27th by the Rev. A. Burhman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moats</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burger</ln>
                        <fn>Teannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hibshman</ln>
                        <fn>H. H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Moats and Miss Teannah Burger, both of Tomstown, Franklin County,
                    were married on January 27th by the Rev. H. H. B. Hibshman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kane</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisaner</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Kane and Miss Jennie C. Reisaner, both from near Fayetteville, were
                    married by the Rev. J. Fohl on February 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham R. Kohler and Miss Lydia A. Kohler, both of Maryland, were married
                    at Hay's Hotel in Greencastle by the Rev. J. M. Bishop on February 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushnell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNair</ln>
                        <fn>M. Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Proctor</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Bushnell of Illinois and Miss M. Alice McNair, formerly of
                    Chambersburg, were married in Illinois on December 23rd by the Rev. Robert
                    Proctor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valentine</ln>
                        <fn>Leah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Leah A. Valentine died near Greencastle on January 30th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mary E. Fisher died in Chambersburg on February 1st. She was 35 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindline</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Kate Kindline died in Chambersburg on February 4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frank Miller died in Chambersburg on February 4th. He was 22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.02.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
