<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.06.01">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/25/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-06-01">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">1</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.06.01.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Edwin M. Stanton. Letter From Jeremiah S. Black to United States Senator Henry
                    Wilson</head>
                <origin>The Galaxy</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Jeremiah S. Black defends the Buchanan administration from charges of gross
                    mismanagement of the secession crisis, and takes issue with depictions of Edwin
                    Stanton as a strong Republican and supporter of abolition. Buchanan, he argues,
                    acted out of reverence for the constitution in holding that he had no power to
                    make war upon the South. He never flinched from asserting the government's
                    rights to uphold the law, however. Stanton remained a good Democrat even if he
                    was a loyal supporter of the president who appointed him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.06.01.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>More Legislation Against White Men</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The present Congress seems capable of perpetrating any sort of infamy upon
                        white men. It has now under consideration, with every likelihood that it
                        will pass, a bill which might properly be termed "a bill to discourage
                        naturalization." It proposes to take the power of naturalization from the
                        State Courts altogether, and lodge it exclusively in the United States
                        Courts. If this bill becomes a law, a foreigner cannot be naturalized in
                        Franklin county. He will be obliged to go to Philadelphia to procure his
                        naturalization papers. What a great expense, and to what inconvenience will
                        this put those who have lived in this country long enough to become
                        citizens! Then, too, the bill provides that the person naturalized shall not
                        vote until six months after he has received his naturalization papers. This
                        is done to discourage foreigners from being naturalized.</p>
                    <p>These obstacles are thrown in the way of white men. If the skin of the
                        German, or Irishman, were black, no such stringent act would be passed. But
                        these Radicals hate foreigners, because the masses vote the Democratic
                        ticket.</p>
                    <p>We appeal to our fellow-citizens of foreign birth. Are you willing to support
                        a party which legislates against you in this manner? Your friends may desire
                        to come to America. If they do come, and reside in the rural districts, they
                        will not be allowed to do as you have done. They can not go to their nearest
                        county Court, and file their intentions to become citizens. They must travel
                        two or three hundred miles to do it. And when their time comes to procure
                        their papers, they must travel the same weary distances, take their
                        witnesses with them, and bear this great expense. All this is done so that
                        persons of foreign birth will become discouraged and prefer not to procure
                        papers at all. The consequence will be that black men will have so much more
                        power and their votes are counted sure for the Radical party.</p>
                    <p>White men, foreign-born and native Americans, think of this scheme to make
                        the votes of black men more effective, and crush the party that devised, and
                        is seeking to carry it out.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks Congress for considering a bill the editor believes is meant to
                    discourage immigrants from becoming citizens. Calls it an attack on white men
                    for the purpose of elevating the power of black men. Asks immigrants if they
                    will stand for this and urges them to vote Democratic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>More of Cessna's Dirty Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Cessna, from the Committee of Elections, made a report in the South
                        Carolina contested election case of Wallace against Simpson declaring that
                        A.S. Wallace was duly elected and was entitled to the seat.--He moved the
                        previous question, which was seconded, and then the resolution was
                            adopted.--<emph rend="italic">Congressional Proceedings, May
                        27th.</emph></p>
                    <p>Of course. That is just the kind of dirty work for which Cessna is
                        preeminently fitted. Nothing seems to delight him more than to be dabbling
                        in a contested election case: and he prefers to be concerned for the fellow
                        who has been beaten at the polls. He imagines that his constituents will
                        consider him a sharp and shrewd lawyer, if he succeeds in securing the
                        office for the minority candidates. But his constituents here
                        <unclear>have</unclear> since discovered the resources which the honorable
                        member has at his command. He had gained an unenviable <del/> by his
                        manipulation of contested election cases before he went to Congress.--He
                        helped to swindle Senator Duncan out of his seat in 1865. He assisted in
                        ousting Senator Shugart and tried hard to unseat Senator McIntyre. It was
                        his prolific <del/> that suggested to Mr Scull the idea of prompting to
                        cheat Senator Findlay out of his seat, which project happily miscarried.
                        When he went to Congress, he found that his <unclear>skill</unclear> as a
                        political juggler had preceded him. The suggestion was at once made, "put
                        Cessna on the Committee on Contested Election Cases. He won't let a <emph
                            rend="italic">Democrat</emph> in under any circumstances." And he has
                        fulfilled the prediction to the letter. A majority of 10,000 has proved
                        insufficient to keep a Democrat in, when Cessna's Christian conscience said
                        "turn him out." He gravely gives his opinion, too, that, under such
                        circumstances, there should not be a new election, <emph rend="italic">but
                            that the defeated candidate ought to be declared elected and advanced to
                            a seat</emph>. Accordingly, as Judge Woodward said the other day at
                        Reading, in every contested election case, the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Democrat</emph> has been turned, or kept out, and the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Radical</emph> put, or kept in, and this without regard to the majority
                        the Democrat may have had.</p>
                    <p>In this very case, Simpson was elected by an overwhelming majority. We forget
                        the exact figures but it was in the neighborhood of <emph rend="italic">four
                            thousand</emph>. It seemed that, owing to some disability, he was unable
                        to take the oath. Then comes this dirty little political trickster with a
                        report, declaring <emph rend="italic">Wallace, the defeated candidate, duly
                            elected and entitled to the seat, and moved the previous
                        question</emph>. Thus he put the gag into the mouths of Democrats and honest
                        Radicals, who would have denounced the outrage, so that this iniquitous
                        proceeding should not be ventilated. This is the man, conservative white men
                        of the 16th Congressional District, who will obtain a renomination at the
                        hands of the Radical Congressional Conference, and who will ask you for your
                        suffrages. The man whose conscience is so sacred as to allow him to
                        perpetrate such an informal outrage, is not worthy of the confidence and
                        support of an honest constituency. Get ready to flagellate him most
                        unmercifully.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces Cessna's work in Congress on the Committee of Elections. Claims
                    he fraudulently declares defeated candidates as winners in contested elections
                    in order to secure Republican victories. Gives several examples and urges the
                    16th Congressional District of Pennsylvania to oust him in the next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>They Ought to be Represented</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The names of <emph rend="italic">two hundred and twenty-eight negroes</emph>
                        have been furnished to John Cessna as making up the number of colored voters
                        in the Borough of Chambersburg. The total number of votes cast in this
                        Borough for Governor last October, was 1103. Add to this number the 223
                        negro votes, and we have an aggregate for this Fall's election of 1331
                        votes. The negro vote is therefore a little over the <emph rend="italic"
                            >one-sixth</emph> of the whole vote.</p>
                    <p>But again: The vote for Geary in the Borough was 579. The 228 negro votes
                        will all be cast for the Radical candidates. Assuming that the 579 white
                        voters will "stick" (which is not at all probable, and will make our
                        argument stronger for the black man) the Radical vote would then be 807. The
                        negro vote would therefore be more than <emph rend="italic"
                        >one-fourth</emph> of the Radical vote of the Borough.</p>
                    <p>The Radical County Committee has been called to meet on the 4th instant, to
                        fix the time for holding a County Convention. In that Convention, the
                        Borough will be entitled to <emph rend="italic">thirteen</emph> delegates.
                        The negro vote, being the <emph rend="italic">one-fourth</emph> of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Radical</emph> vote, ought to be entitled to at least
                            <emph rend="italic">three</emph> colored delegates from the Borough in
                        the Convention.</p>
                    <p>Casting, as the negroes will, <emph rend="italic">one-sixth</emph> of the
                            <emph rend="italic">whole</emph> vote of the Borough, they are clearly
                        entitled on that basis, to <emph rend="italic">two</emph> delegates of their
                        color in the Convention.</p>
                    <p>In Antrim and Montgomery townships, the negroes will cast a pretty large
                        vote. They ought to consider in their meetings whether they will demand
                        representation according to their proportion of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Radical</emph> vote, or according to their proportion of the whole
                        vote. There is no reason why they ought not to demand it according to their
                        proportion of the <emph rend="italic">Radical</emph> vote, inasmuch as the
                        white representation in the convention is based on the strength of the
                        Radical vote in the several election districts.</p>
                    <p>Such men as Henry Monks, Ashford Collins, Elijah Hammett, Joseph R. Winters,
                        Alexander Lewis and Moses Anderson, and others we might name, ought to see
                        to it that they are allowed their full representation in the next Radical
                        Convention. Their brethren all through the South have had this privilege
                        accorded to them as one of the least of their privileges, and the party that
                        is to get the solid negro vote, ought not to dare to refuse it here.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monks</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Ashford</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammett</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Calculates the number of votes blacks will bring to the Republican party
                    and challenges them to insist on representation at the Republican conventions
                    because of that voting strength. Probably hopes to show the hypocrisy of the
                    Republican party if they fail to let in black representatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>You are Right</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ANTRIM TOWNSHIP, May 28th, 1870.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph>--The stand you have so ably taken
                        in behalf of "the white man's party" is the platform of all Democrats in our
                        section of the county, as it no doubt is everywhere else. And strange as it
                        may seem it is only since the announcement by the authorities that the
                        requisite number of States had ratified the thing called the "fifteenth
                        amendment" and the subsequent negro jubilee in token of their joy of the
                        event, that a large portion of Republicans have waked up to the real sense
                        of this new order of affairs. Many of these, we have the most positive proof
                        for asserting, are throwing off the yoke they too long bore and joining
                        hands with us. Your motto, that white men alone ought to rule America, is
                        the true one even if we should not at once succeed. If our party were to
                        court for any negro votes, many Democrats would not vote at all, while the
                        position we have assumed is sure to unite us as one man, and command the
                        support of such Republicans as are absolutely opposed to negro suffrage;
                        especially will this be so when it comes to the point, that our schools and
                        churches and graveyards and juries and other places will be indiscriminately
                        filled with whites and negroes. Let us, therefore, not be discouraged; the
                        weight of this negroism will itself destroy the means by which it calculates
                        to accomplish its most cherished objects. The bold extremes to which it is
                        driving its measures so hastily, is the undoubted precursor of the ultimate
                        overthrow of all its infernal schemes to equalize and amalgamate the whites
                        and blacks of this country.</p>
                    <p>The distinction which God and nature have irrevocably fixed between us and
                        them will not soon give way to the accursed doctrine of training us and our
                        offspring up for the companionship of the sooty African. We want him below
                        us or above us, not with us. Giving him the ballot is a heavy tread on a
                        tender spot in the body politic, but the intrusion will not stop here of its
                        own accord. We must do what we can to stay it. We must resort to the laws of
                        self preservation. We must lend no assistance to radicalism under any guise,
                        by contributing to the education of the "freedmen," so called. We must make
                        no clubs to break our own heads with. A "learned nigger" will be a "learned"
                        enemy in the hands of radicalism. The two are allied to each other in the
                        bonds of politics, therefore it behooves us to be aware of mistaken
                        sympathies. Our cause will admit of no avoidable mistake.</p>
                    <p>Yours,<lb/> WHITE MAN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints another article from an anonymous writer calling himself WHITE MAN.
                    This writer praises the paper for standing up for white supremacy, urges all
                    Democrats not to back away from it even if they are defeated in elections.
                    Insists whites and blacks must be separate and nothing should be done to change
                    that.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.06.01.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Radical County Committee will meet in Chambersburg to fix a date for
                    their convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Odd Fellows Picnic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Columbus Lodge, No. 75, will hold a picnic at Brown's Mill on June 16th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Internal Revenue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balaley</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George J. Balaley, Deputy Collector of the Internal Revenue for Franklin,
                    will receive taxes on income and special taxes on business between June 14th and
                    18th. He will hold office in Hoke's Building, Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Change in the Repository Office</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. Wilson Hays has sold his interest in the Franklin Repository to Mr. H.
                    S. Stoner who recently assumed management of the business department of the
                    paper. The editors of the Spirit regret to see Hays "drop out of the editorial
                    fraternity" but anticipate good relations with Stoner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Let Them Learn</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our correspondent from Antrim is right in his views in the main, but we do
                        not agree with him in his position as to not educating the negro. We are in
                        favor of educating him--not, however, in the same schools as the whites. Let
                        the negroes be taught in separate schools, and taught to the utmost of their
                        ability to learn. If they are to have a voice in the selection of officers
                        to administer the government, it is by all means advisable that they should
                        be able to read the constitution, and, especially, their tickets, so that
                        their Radical guardians may not cheat them too badly.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comes out in favor of educating blacks, just wants them in separate schools
                    from whites. Since they can vote and hold office now, they should at least know
                    how to read, the paper argues.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mercersburg Classis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callender</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Thirtieth Annual Meeting of the Mercersburg Classis of the Reformed
                    Church of the United States was held in Schellsburg on May 19th. A number of
                    local clergy delivered addresses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Decoration Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Monday was the day set apart for the purpose of doing honor to our soldier
                        dead. The ceremony of strewing flowers upon the graves of those who fell in
                        battle, or died in the service of their country, is a beautiful one, and our
                        citizens generally relinquished business in the afternoon to participate in
                        its observance. Arrangements had been made to begin at 3 o'clock P. M., but
                        on Monday morning, the Silver Cornet Band notified the Committee of
                        Arrangements that they would not furnish the music for the occasion. The
                        Committee then secured the services of the Fayetteville Band but it was
                        found impossible for it to attend before 5 o'clock, and the procession did
                        not form, therefore, until that time. The "Housum Zouaves," Knights of
                        Pythias and Odd Fellows, together with a large body of citizen soldiers,
                        made up the procession. They visited the several graveyards and the
                        Cemetery. At the latter place an excellent address, very appropriate to the
                        occasion, was delivered by Rev. I.N. Hays.</p>
                    <p>During the forenoon, the children kept pouring into Repository Hall, bearing
                        in their hands the choicest flowers in abundance, and these were strewed
                        upon soldiers' graves in the graveyards and cemetery.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the Decoration Day festivities. Gives the names of the groups
                    involved in the procession and speeches made at the graveyards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Appointment of Assessor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Valley Spirit:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>GENTLEMEN:--As an article in your issue of the 25th instant does great
                        injustice to the Democratic members of the Board of County Commissioners, I
                        desire the use of your columns to say a word by way of explanation. When the
                        new Board of Commissioners was organized, on the first Monday of February,
                        1870, they elected Henry C. Koontz clerk. He was a strong Democrat. George
                        Foreman, who went out of the office, was a Republican, and had filled the
                        office with satisfaction to all parties. I had been elected as a Republican,
                        Assessor for the Borough of Chambersburg, and feeling anxious to do
                        something for George Foreman, I called upon the Commissioners and proposed
                        to resign, provided they would appoint George Foreman Assessor for the
                        Borough in my place. Upon this condition I resigned, and would have resigned
                        upon no other. As this arrangement was perfectly fair all around, and made
                        no change in the political complexion of the Assessor, the Commissioners
                        assented, and the appointment of Geo. Foreman was made. In this it is
                        difficult to see anything of which the Democratic party should complain of
                        William Shinefield and J. H. Brumbaugh, old and tried Democrats.<lb/> JOHN
                        DOEBLER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>Henry C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints a letter from the former Assessor of Chambersburg defending the
                    County Commissioner Board's decision to appoint a Republican as the new
                    Assessor. Took offense at the article printed in the Spirit the week before and
                    comes to the defense of the Democrats on the Board for their decision, explains
                    exactly what happened.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowen</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoup</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Theodore Mowen of St. Thomas and Miss Annie Shoup of Cashtown were married
                    on May 26th by the Rev. John Fohl at his residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stull</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca Stull died in Quincy on May 12th. She was 36 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin Rock died in Mt. Alto on May 21st. He was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret McClure died in Chambersburg on May 5th. She was 78 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Kunkle died in St. Thomas on May 20th. He was 80 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.06.01.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
