<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.05.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/20/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-05-11">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.05.11.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.05.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>White Men Must Rule America</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Negromania is only the madness of the hour. It will give place eventually to
                        sounder principles. The fanaticism which has fraudulently invested the negro
                        with the right of suffrage, and which is now seeking to place him upon a
                        plane of perfect equality with the white man, will yield ere long to the
                        more quiet, but stronger, conviction which is forcing itself upon the
                        thinking men of the country, that the only safety for free institutions is
                        in keeping the absolute control of them in the hands of the superior race.
                        He would have been denounced as a madman even three years ago, who would
                        then have declared that, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred
                        and seventy, we would have negroes at the polls, negroes in the jury box,
                        negroes in State Legislatures, negroes appointed to prominent positions of
                        public trust, and a negro in the United States Senate. The march of this
                        fanaticism has been very rapid indeed. And now, the people stand appalled at
                        the terrible mischief which their unfaithful representatives have wrought.
                        They see these same political schemers who have imposed the Fifteenth
                        Amendment upon the country by chicanery and fraud, appealing to these new
                        suffragists to sustain their tottering party. The Radical leaders recognize
                        the fact--too patent to be ignored--that the best men everywhere are
                        disgusted with the doctrine that the negro is the equal of the white man.
                        Hence their frantic appeals to the negroes to "vote solid," to "remember
                        their friends" and to be "true to the great principles of the Republican
                        party."</p>
                    <p>There is no necessity for this extraordinary zeal. The Democratic party is
                        not bidding for the votes of the negroes. It proposes to adhere to its
                        old-fashioned doctrine <emph rend="italic">that this country is to be
                            governed by white men</emph>. It can see no strength to the republic in
                        making a race just released from bondage an element of the governing power.
                        All the foresight, and calm, and deliberate thought of the best minds of the
                        country are needed to keep the machinery of a republic in good running
                        order. With a territory so vast as ours--with so many diverse notions as to
                        measures of public policy--with so many conflicting interests--with
                        thirty-seven wheels running within one great wheel--the wisest statemanship
                        is required to preserve the essence of our republican institutions. And now,
                        if into the class of our rulers, men are to be introduced who are
                        confessedly in a condition of tutelage, and they are to have a controlling
                        voice in the making and administration of the laws, what hope can be
                        entertained for the permanent happiness and prosperity of the nation?
                        Politicians may hoot at this idea, as they certainly will, and go on
                        struggling for the votes of the colored people simply to extend their
                            <unclear>reign</unclear> of power, but thoughtful men will see in it an
                        element of weakness which, in after years, may either permanently discover
                        States that are now only jarring and discordant, or that may cause a nation,
                        desponding of the success of republican institutions, to fly to a different
                        form of government. To prevent such disastrous results, the Democratic party
                        insists upon adherence to the doctrine that white men must rule America.</p>
                    <p>It makes its appeal to the white men of the country. It is high time that
                        Conservative men, heretofore identified with the Republican party, who were
                        always hostile to negro suffrage and who, if an opportunity had been
                        presented them as was pledged to them by their party leaders, would have
                        voted the amendment down by overwhelming majorities--it is high time for
                            <emph rend="italic">such</emph> men to sever the leading-strings of
                        party, and cast their votes with the men who are in favor of white men
                        ruling America.</p>
                    <p>Let the issue be distinctly defined and fairly and squarely fought. Let
                        Democrats disdain to truckle to this policy of procuring negro votes. Let
                        them stand firmly upon the platform which has been their boast and pride for
                        many years, that this government was made by white men for the benefit of
                        white men. Let protection--the utmost protection--be always afforded to the
                        negro in the enjoyment of the rights which properly belong to him under the
                        laws of the land, but let him not be put into positions where he is to
                        govern white men. Democrats, and all who love republican institutions, write
                        high up upon your banners the words, WHITE MEN MUST RULE AMERICA.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Forcefully supports the continuance of the Democratic Party principle that
                    white men must control the government. Says Radicalism is waning and will soon
                    disappear along with their doctrines. Claims all intelligent men know that
                    whites must run the country and urges Conservatives in the Republican party to
                    break ranks and restore white rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For the Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From all quarters come wholesale denunciations of the last Legislature. The
                        Philadelphia and Pittsburg papers are filled with damaging comments upon the
                        action of the majority of that body. It is boldly charged that two-thirds,
                        and perhaps four-fifths of its members were open to bribes. It is asserted
                        that there was no chance for the passage of any bill until it was definitely
                        ascertained how much its friends would agree to pay. When it was "pinched"
                        and "squeezed" to the last dollar, some arrangement, satisfactory to both
                        parties, was agreed upon, and the bill passed.</p>
                    <p>We have no reliable information as to the truth or falsity of these several
                        charges. Our own opinion is that there is a great deal of truth in them. We
                        have heard it charged that there was one member of the Legislature who was
                        willing to sell his vote at any time for two dollars and a half. That the
                        most monstrous outrages have been perpetrated upon the people of this
                        Commonwealth by their representatives, none will deny. Huge schemes to
                        enrich private parties at the expense of the Commonwealth have been pushed
                        through both branches of the Legislature. Special legislation has been their
                        constant occupation. The General Laws are very few indeed. They could all
                        have been passed in three weeks, allowing the greatest freedom for
                        discussion. But the time of the Legislature was taken up almost entirely
                        with private bills. The majority of these were jobs set up by certain
                        members and passed out of courtesy to them, when, if the truth were known,
                        they would never have consented to become their champions, if there had not
                        been a large consideration offered for each one of them. It seems to be
                        money, therefore, and not principle that controls the Pennsylvania
                        Legislature.</p>
                    <p>Of course, there are honorable exceptions to this general rule. It gives us
                        pleasure to bear out testimony, in this particular, to the unselfish
                        services of our own representative, Captain George W. Skinner. He bore,
                        throughout the entire session, a reputation for sterling honesty. His hands
                        are not soiled with bribes. His principles were known of all men. He was
                        always candid in the expression of his opinions, and no selfish
                        considerations ever induced him to swerve from the path which his sense of
                        duty marked out for him. He entertained an earnest and honest desire to
                        serve his constituency by procuring the passage of the Border Claims Bill
                        and to that he devoted all his talents and energy. That the bill failed is
                        not his fault. Perhaps, in his anxiety to serve his constituents in this
                        way, he may have voted for measures which, under other circumstances, he
                        would not have supported, but surely he is not to be blamed for this. There
                        is no member of the last Legislature who was more popular than he, and no
                        one whose character for honesty stood higher.</p>
                    <p>We have written these words for the reason that we feel it to be the duty of
                        the Democratic County Convention to renominate Captain Skinner. He has been
                        faithful and true, and the Democracy should show their appreciation of his
                        services by tendering him a unanimous renomination. That they will do so, we
                        do not doubt for a moment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Charges the Republican legislators with gross corruption and bribery,
                    claims they only care about private bills rather than bills which will help the
                    state. Also praises Chambersburg's representative and urges the Democratic party
                    to push for his renomination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Income Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that income taxes have been reduced from 5% to 3% and the
                    $1000 exemption retained. The editors applaud this, but argue that the tax
                    should be eliminated altogether. "President Grant in his annual message to
                    Congress recommended that the taxes be kept up to their present high figure, and
                    that this odious income tax be continued. But he does not feel what the people
                    feel. With business depressed, trade languishing, and commerce dead, men of
                    business feel very little like paying the enormous taxes that they used to pay
                    when business of every kind was inflated."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.05.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A large number of "excellent books for children" have been added to the
                    Sunday School Library of the Central Presbyterian Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Mr. Everett, Pastor of the Lutheran Congregation at Gettysburg,
                    has accepted a position with the Lutheran Church of Greencastle. The $1000
                    salary played a large role in his decision.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Grady's Old Fashioned American Circus will perform in Chambersburg on
                    Friday. They will also perform in Greencastle and Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Enterprise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gelwicks and Burkhart on the Chambersburg Diamond is the largest mercantile
                    house in the Cumberland Valley. They already sold out one immense shipment of
                    goods and are now in New York on a second buying trip.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Prisoners Removed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Columbus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Streets</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sheriff Fletcher moved Andrew C. Unger, Henry Gray, Columbus Green, and
                    William Streets to the Eastern Penitentiary. They had all been convicted of
                    larceny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. F. Dyson oversees the Franklin County Bible Society Depository on
                    South Second Street near the United Brethren Church. He keeps a regular supply
                    of Bibles and Testaments. The poor receive copies for free. Sabbath Schools may
                    buy them at cost--40 cents for Bibles and 10 cents for testaments. German copies
                    are also available. The society is funded through voluntary contributions, and
                    county churches will take up a collection soon. Donations can be made to
                    Treasurer Jacob Hoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Horse Thief Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Miller, who had been in Franklin posing as a government agent, was
                    arrested in Maryland for horse theft. He is now suspected of stealing the horses
                    of Jacob Strickler and Samuel Lehman of Franklin County. He will be brought to
                    the county to face trial unless Maryland authorities insist on keeping him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>I. O. O. F.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Edmond</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stokes</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heiss</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bertram</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trinnick</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholson</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stokes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trinnick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The officers of the Grand Encampment of Odd Fellows of Pennsylvania are
                    visiting subordinate encampments in a number of counties including Franklin. The
                    county's posts have been holding elaborate receptions replete with addresses and
                    processions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Re-Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In compliance with notice given by a Committee of Invitation and
                        Arrangements, many of the officers of the 126th Regiment, Penna. Infantry
                        Volunteers assembled in the parlor of the National Hotel, in this borough,
                        on Tuesday last, May 3d, 1870, at 10 o'clock A. M. A temporary organization
                        was effected by electing Col. James G. Elder, President; Lieut. Geo. W.
                        Welsh, Secretary. A full discussion of the propriety of forming a permanent
                        organization, and for the best plans for the carrying out of the purpose,
                        was had, entire unanimity of feeling and belief being shown as to both its
                        desirability and practicability. The following committees were appointed: a
                        committee of three to draft a Constitution and set of By-laws for the
                        Society--the committee to report at the next meeting. Lieut. Col. D. W. Rowe
                        and Lieutenants John Stewart and Jere Cook compose the committee. And a
                        committee of five to make arrangements for the proper celebration, by a
                        re-union of the entire regiment, on the anniversary of the great battle of
                        Fredericksburg, December 13th, in which the regiment took an active and
                        distinguished part. The Chairman appointed Sergeants Mahon and Seiders and
                        Lieutenants Cook, Fletcher and Platt to attend to these duties. The business
                        of the meeting having been dispatched, an adjournment was carried until 2 P.
                        M., when the members of the regiment, together with a number of invited
                        guests, sat down to a sumptuous dinner prepared at the National. Ample
                        justice was done the feast by the doughty warriors of the 126th and their
                        friends who had, like them, been trained on many well-stricken fields. The
                        dinner over, a succession of toasts, pledged in most cases in sparkling
                        water, followed but we have not been furnished with the text of the toasts,
                        nor with the addresses of the toaster and responses of the toastees. We
                        presume they were fairly up to the average of after-dinner speeches, as made
                        by Americans and Englishmen when "on their legs." The meeting, throughout,
                        is said by those present to have been a great success and to indicate the
                        possibility of forming a Society which will, year by year, bring great
                        pleasure and much profit to its members. Upon motion the company adjourned
                        to meet again on the 13th of December, 1870, at Chambersburg.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the gathering of veterans of the 126th Penn. Infantry and their
                    plans for a reunion in December to remember the battle of Fredericksburg. Lists
                    the names of men selected for different committees and the responsibilities of
                    each.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckenrode</ln>
                        <fn>David E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David E. Eckenrode and Miss Rebecca Jane Stake, both of Amberson's Valley,
                    Franklin County, were married at the residence of Mrs. Sarah E. McLaughlin on
                    March 19th by the Rev. A. E. Fulton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Showman</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mills</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Showman and Miss Mary E. Mills, both of Horse Valley, Franklin
                    County, were married at the residence of the bride's mother on March 10th by the
                    Rev. A. E. Fulton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn>Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callender</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. George W. Burke of Newcastle, Indiana, and Miss Belle Shook, daughter
                    of Jacob Shook of Greencastle, were married on April 28th by the Rev. S. N.
                    Callender.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Woods, Jr., died in Chambersburg on May 8th. He was 5 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hornibe</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Hornibe died at an advanced age in Montgomery on April 24th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary E. Lightner died in Mercersburg on April 30th. She was 34 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dill</ln>
                        <fn>John Franklin Ashway</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dill</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dill</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Franklin Ashway Dill, son of Isaac and Fanny Dill, died near St.
                    Thomas on March 23rd. He was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vandersmith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Vandersmith died at Church Hill on May 2nd. He was 90 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strike</ln>
                        <fn>Matilda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strike</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Matilda Strike, wife of Solomon Strike, died near Mowersville, Franklin
                    County, on April 21st. She was 29 years old. She was interred in Newburg. She
                    leaves a husband and three children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.05.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
