<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.12.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-12-07">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.12.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.12.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Not Cheap Voting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>During the campaign, the Radical leaders of Franklin County were willing to
                        foot all the bills the payment of which was necessary to qualify the negroes
                        to vote. All they asked of them was that they should vote for Cessna and the
                        whole ticket. Accordingly, in the Borough of Chambersburg, out of the
                        $100,000 corruption fund, they paid the taxes of over two hundred colored
                        suffragists. All but a few who were property holders, were assessed
                        twenty-eight cents and this was the amount that had to be forthcoming in
                        every case.</p>
                    <p>Now, all this was cheerfully paid under the expectation and in the hope of a
                        glorious triumph. But when defeat was their lot instead of victory, they
                        began to regret the useless expenditure of this money, and, after casting
                        about for some time to reimburse themselves, they hit upon the idea of
                        assessing each colored voter <emph rend="italic">seventy-five cents</emph>.
                        They knew that a large portion of them could not, and would not pay
                        anything, and they thought that by assessing three quarters of a dollar,
                        they might raise from those who were able to pay as much as they had
                        expended for all. Colored agents were selected to go among the negroes and
                        collect this assessment. One of these agents got from the poor darkies for
                        this purpose about <emph rend="italic">twenty dollars</emph> which he
                        "salted down" in his own pockets, saying "if I hab to do de dirty work, I'se
                        gwine to be paid for it."</p>
                    <p>The darkies say it isn't <emph rend="italic">cheap</emph> work voting the
                        Radical ticket.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses local Republicans of buying black votes and when the former failed
                    to win the election, assessed black voters a fee to compensate for the loss.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Census</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints Pennsylvania's census returns. Franklin's population
                    stands at 45,383, an increase from 42,126 in 1860.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.12.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dramatic Troupe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Coleman Dramatic Troupe performed last week in Repository Hall to small
                    crowds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Reunion of the 126th Regiment PA. Vols.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Railroad is issuing excursion tickets to veterans who
                    wish to attend the reunion of the 126th Pennsylvania Volunteers. It will be held
                    in Chambersburg on December 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Palace Show of America</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dickson and Zucher's Novelty Silver Show and Carnival of Fun will exhibit
                    in Repository Hall on December 6th and 7th. Their performance is reputed to be
                    very entertaining. They will be giving away flour, coal, and silverware to
                    guests.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>College Grounds to be Laid Out</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Donald</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curwen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Donald Mitchell and Dr. John Curwen visited Chambersburg to see Wilson
                    College. Mitchell has a plan for the layout of the grounds, and Dr. Curwen,
                    Superintendent of the State Insane Hospital, has been an important supporter of
                    the college.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>It Don't Cost Much</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the statement of the Borough Treasurer, $12,834.50 have been
                    spent on street repairs. The work of cutting down the Waynesboro road continues.
                    "It is a luxury to have these alterations made in the streets at such figures.
                    The groaning tax-payers seem to favor it and we must 'grin and bear it.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Case of Supposed Lockjaw</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockersmith</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Job Hockersmith, an employee of S. and J. Robinson in Chambersburg, cut his
                    finger slightly last week and has since come down with the symptoms of lockjaw.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Dr. Willits' Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willits</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two hundred people heard Dr. Willits lecture on "Sunshine or the Philosophy
                    of a Happy Life." He entertained the crowd with his gift for humor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Dental Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrest</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neldich</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>G. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Dental Society met in the rooms of Dr. H. Forrest on
                    December 1st. The society elected officers, including G. W. Neldich, president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Thief Caught</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Book</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Book, a black man wanted for stealing money from the store on
                    Wingert, Phillips, and Co., was apprehended in Harrisburg for a separate crime.
                    Officer Houser brought him to Chambersburg to face trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Population of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We <sic>ary</sic> under obligations to Gen. E.M. Gregory, U.S. Marshal for
                        the Eastern District of this State, for the statistics which we give below
                        in relation to the population of Franklin County. Instead of giving us,
                        however, the population of each census subdivision, it would have been far
                        more gratifying and satisfactory to have had the population of each township
                        and Borough separately.</p>
                    <p>In 1860, the population of the county was 42,126 and in 1870 it is 45,383.
                        Showing an increase of 3,257 in the last ten years.</p>
                    <p>The population of Lurgan, Fannett and Southampton townships is 5,435.</p>
                    <p>Of Green, Letterkenny and Metal townships, 6,954.</p>
                    <p>Of North Ward of Chambersburg and Hamilton township, 4,611.</p>
                    <p>Of St. Thomas and Peters townships, 4,516.</p>
                    <p>Of Warren and Montgomery townships, and Mercersburg Borough, 5,188.</p>
                    <p>Of South Ward of Chambersburg, 3,333.</p>
                    <p>Of Guilford and Quincy townships, 6,214.</p>
                    <p>Of Antrim township and Greencastle Borough, 5,413.</p>
                    <p>Of Waynesboro' and Washington township, 3,719.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists population census data for Franklin county, emphasizing the fact that
                    the county experienced an increase in population over the last ten years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Curiosity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Greencastle <emph rend="italic">Echo</emph> has the following:--"A
                        colored man, who claims to be a native of Prussia, has been exhibiting
                        himself around the town the past week. He has a double organization, and can
                        change his heart in four different positions, whilst his bowels revolve
                        around like a ball with great rapidity--backward and forward--and when their
                        motion ceases, an extra set of ribs slide down and cover the entire abdomen.
                        He says he does not suffer in the least from their curious freak of
                        nature.--Several of our physicians say that he is a curious phenomenon, and
                        that there is nothing in the medical works pointing to a similar case."</p>
                    <p>This man was in this Borough last week. He is one of the most astonishing
                        pieces of humanity that we have ever seen. The above account from the <emph
                            rend="italic">Echo</emph> is not at all overdrawn.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the exploits of a visiting black man who can do unusual
                    maneuvers with his body.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Baby Abandoned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some time ago, a woman about thirty years of age, came from Cumberland county
                        to the Alms House, having with her a child three or four years old. About
                        nine weeks ago she was confined and gave birth to a male infant.--Both the
                        children remained at the Alms House and the mother went to the Montgomery
                        Hotel to work. On last Wednesday morning, she went out to the Alms House and
                        took the children away.</p>
                    <p>About ten o'clock of the same morning a child was found in a woodpile on the
                        ground attached to Mr. T. B. Wood's Foundry in this Borough. Its clothing
                        was there with it. This fact was soon noised about town. Dr. Boyle, who is
                        the Physician at the Alms House and who was present at the birth of the
                        infant to which we referred, went to the house to which this child had been
                        taken and immediately recognized the child of the woodpile as the one that
                        belonged to the Alms House. He went to the Montgomery Hotel and confronted
                        the woman telling her that she had abandoned her child, that the fact was
                        known, and that she must at once take it in charge.--She answered him
                        nothing, but afterwards went to the house and claimed the child.--It was
                        discovered that she had made her arrangements to leave town in the one
                        o'clock train of Wednesday and commit the child to whatever fate might
                        befall it.</p>
                    <p>A colored woman expressed an earnest desire to take the child and raise it,
                        and to this proposition the heartless woman cheerfully acceded, parting with
                        it without any apparent reluctance whatever. She took the older child and
                        left on Thursday. She gives the name of Elizabeth Grimes. She is a white
                        woman, but the father of the child is certainly a black man.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimes</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tells of an incident where a woman attempted to abandon a baby at the alms
                    house. She was caught but then let a black woman adopt the child. Editor
                    speculates the woman abandoned her baby because the father was black.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Death of Mr. Isaac Snively</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Snively, son of Benjamin Snively of Antrim, died at his father's
                    residence of consumption. He was interred in Cedar Hill Cemetery, Greencastle.
                    Snively was "a gentleman of the finest feelings, a sincere and true friend,
                    honest, upright and courteous." He served in the 126th PA regiment. He lived in
                    Pittsburgh for quite a while and worked for the Adams Express Company. He
                    recently visited Europe where his health improved for a short time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weber</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Elvina C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob M. Weber of Green and Miss Elvina C. Rice of Fayetteville were
                    married on December 4th by the Rev. Dr. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel Geddes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>Enos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Geddes Noonan and Miss Ann E. Rodgers, both of Carrick, were married
                    on November 17th at the residence of Enos Rodgers by the Rev. J. Smith Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConnell</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Jane McConnell died on November 7th at the residence of J. D. Walker.
                    She was 76 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>James W. Ginley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Ginley Witherow, son of William and Laura Witherow, died on
                    November 19th. He was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.12.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
