<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.11.16">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/09/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-11-16">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Result of the Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday of last week, elections were held in two, and on Tuesday, in
                        eighteen States. It was a general battle and resulted most disastrously to
                        the Radical party. The President, sitting in the White House, may well take
                        time to glance at the political field and study the lesson which these
                        elections teach. The October elections were sufficient to indicate the drift
                        of the tide to him and he was quick enough to discern it. He and his
                        counselors concluded that some more vigorous measures must be taken, and
                        they were accordingly instituted, to prop the fortunes of his tottering
                        administration. Swarms of Deputy Marshals were appointed to watch the polls
                        in the interest of the Radicals, and troops were stationed near by, so that
                        military force might be used, if necessary, to sustain these Marshals. These
                        novel proceedings aroused the indignation of American citizens and, without
                        distinction of party, they resolved to rebuke the man who dared to make
                        these military demonstrations at the polls. The civil power has proved
                        victorious. The ballot has shown itself more potent than the ballet. The
                        common sense and prudence of the American people, have, at least, postponed
                        the conflict which the presence of the bayonet was calculated to provoke and
                        prevented the bloodshed which the inauguration of this despotic proceeding
                        was likely to produce.</p>
                    <p>From North, South, East and West come the glad tidings of victory for the
                        Democracy and Conservative forces. And where victory was an impossibility,
                        the spectacle is presented of the Radical forces staggering under the fierce
                        onslaughts of their foes, and exclaiming "Another such victory and we are
                        undone."</p>
                    <p>In New York, Governor Hoffman has been reelected by about thirty thousand
                        majority. The whole Democratic State ticket has been elected. In New York
                        City, A. Oakey Hall, Esq., has been reelected and Tammany makes a clean
                        sweep of all the City offices. In that State <emph rend="italic">we make a
                            gain of four Democratic Congressmen</emph>. In the present Congress, the
                        New York delegation stands 19 Radicals, 12 Democrats. In the next, the
                        Democrats will have 16 and the Radicals 15. The Democrats also carry the
                        Legislature.</p>
                    <p>In Tennessee, the Democrats elect six members of Congress. This is a clear
                        gain of six, the whole delegation in the present Congress being Radical.</p>
                    <p>In Missouri, a most signal triumph has been achieved over the Administration.
                        McClurg was the Administration candidate for Governor. B. Gratz Brown was
                        the candidate of the opposition. The two United State Senators from that
                        State were divided. Senator Drake supported McClurg whilst Senator Schurz
                        espoused the cause of Brown. During the campaign, the President wrote to the
                        Federal officers in Missouri that loyalty to his Administration would be
                        shown by voting and working for McClurg. It was distinctly announced to the
                        office-holders that their "heads would be in the barrel before moonlight" if
                        they dared to vote for Brown. Notwithstanding these threats, the masses, not
                        having the fear of Grant before their eyes, turned out and defeated the
                        President's favorite by 40,000 majority. This is a glorious commentary upon
                        such unwarranted interference with the rights of the people as that which
                        the President has been guilty of.</p>
                    <p>With reference to the status of the Missouri Legislature the St. Louis <emph
                            rend="italic">Democrat</emph> has the following:</p>
                    <p>Returns and estimates from ninety-five counties appear to indicate the
                        election to the House of sixty-five Democrats; fifteen members supported by
                        both Democrats and Liberals, sixteen Liberal nominees and nineteen
                        Republicans. There are 126 members of the House and sixty-nine makes a
                        majority. The nineteen counties to hear from divided between the Liberals
                        and the Republicans, and it may be that in consequence of the split some
                        Democrats are elected, either straight-out or on the Fusion tickets. The
                        majority of the Fusion nominees are pledged to Democratic measures. The
                        Democrats, either by themselves or in conjunction with the Liberals, elect
                        at least eighty members of the House, giving a convenient working majority
                        and several to spare.</p>
                    <p>There are eight Democrats in the Senate holding over, and seven elected on
                        Tuesday as Democrats, making fifteen straight-out Democrats. Seven Fusion
                        candidates, elected by Democratic votes, may properly be added to the
                        foregoing, making twenty-two Senators out of the thirty-four. Some of the
                        Senators holding over are liberals.</p>
                    <p>Some changes may be made, and probably will be, by the official returns; but
                        not enough to alter the substantial fact that the next Legislature will be
                        Democratic.</p>
                    <p>In Delaware, the Democracy have done nobly despite the negro vote. Of the
                        result, the <emph rend="italic">Delawarean</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>We take pleasure in laying before our readers this week the result of the
                        election in this State last Tuesday. The victory for our candidates and our
                        principles was won over the Radicals, aided by the whole negro vote and the
                        third party combination called "Independent Democrats" in this county. The
                        contest was a fair and square one. The Democrats raised their standard at
                        the outset, and never lowered it an inch. They held that white men should
                        govern the State of Delaware untrammeled by obligations to an inferior race
                        for patronage or support, and nobly have they conquered.--To the usual
                        congratulations over the victory in Kent and Sussex, we have this year to
                        add the complete triumph of the whole Democratic ticket in New Castle. This
                        result was scarcely expected outside of that county, as the Radicals carried
                        part of their ticket two years ago, and this year voted on their side at
                        least 8,000 negroes. But it seems that for every vote the Radicals gained by
                        the Fifteenth Amendment they lost a white vote and something more.</p>
                    <p>The legislature is Democratic throughout. The majority for Mr. Ponder, for
                        Governor, is 2,479, and for Mr. Biggs, for Congress, 2,434. Not a single
                        Radical is elected from one end of the State to the other. It is unnecessary
                        to say anything about the tricks resorted to by our adversaries to save
                        themselves from defeat. Let the remembrance of them tinge the cheeks of
                        their authors with shame. We have the satisfaction of knowing that they
                        proved unavailing.</p>
                    <p>"Maryland, my Maryland," has retained her full delegation of Democrats. By
                        the enfranchisement of the negroes, the Radicals expected to carry the
                        Fourth and Fifth Districts at least. To give our readers an idea of the
                        marvelous change that has been wrought in that State we refer briefly to the
                        figures in the Fourth District. It is composed of the counties of Allegheny,
                        Washington, Frederick and Carroll. Two years ago, the Democratic candidate
                        for Congress had a majority of 565. Since then 3,300 negroes have been
                        enfranchised, and were registered prior to the election, in that District.
                        They all voted for Mr. Smith, the Radical candidate, and yet, Mr. Ritchie,
                        the Democratic candidate, has a majority of 1,837. The aggregate Democratic
                        majority in Maryland is 13,502.</p>
                    <p>One by one, the States which have been cursed with the rule of carpet-baggers
                        in the South are throwing off the yoke which Radical Congresses have imposed
                        and joining hands with the Democracy to rid the country of the baneful
                        influence of Radicalism.</p>
                    <p>Florida has wheeled into line, the Conservatives electing a Congressman,
                        Lieutenant-Governor, and both Houses of the Legislature.</p>
                    <p>In Alabama the Democrats elect three members of Congress and a majority of
                        the State Legislature. In the present Congress the delegation stands 4
                        Radicals to 2 Democrats, so that there is a Democratic gain of one.</p>
                    <p>Little Delaware has covered herself with glory, electing a Democratic
                        Governor by about 2,500 majority, a Democratic Congressman and a Legislature
                        unanimously Democratic. With the aid of the negro vote, the Radicals
                        confidently expected to whirl Delaware into the Radical ranks.</p>
                    <p>Large Democratic gains are reported in Illinois. The smoke has not cleared
                        away sufficiently to show the actual gain of Congressmen for the Democracy
                        but it is said to be three, and perhaps four.</p>
                    <p>The indications are that a perfect tornado swept over Arkansas and that the
                        Democrats have elected the entire Congressional delegation.</p>
                    <p>Nevada, for the first time since its admission as a State, has been carried
                        by the Democracy.</p>
                    <p>New Jersey has done badly. The Radicals there have carried the Legislature
                        and gained one Congressman. At this writing we can not say to what this
                        result is attributable unless it was owing to local feuds in the Democratic
                        ranks. It is certainly not due to the enfranchisement of the negroes, for
                        everywhere else the negro vote has been a tower of strength to the
                        Democracy.</p>
                    <p>Democrats and Conservatives everywhere should draw inspiration from the
                        general result of these elections to urge them on to further conquests. The
                        Presidency is within their grasp in 1872. The discontent of the people with
                        the Grant administration is growing greater day by day. The masses are
                        becoming thoroughly disgusted with the corruption that prevails in high
                        places, exhibiting itself in reckless extravagance and dabbling in immense
                        jobs, as well as with the tendency towards centralization which finds vent
                        in the employment of the military forces to control elections. Let our
                        organizations be kept up and, if possible, be made more thorough, so that
                        Pennsylvania may give a large majority for the Democratic Presidential
                        candidate in 1872.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Catalogues the triumphs Democrats experienced all over the country in the
                    recent elections. Believes this is proof that black suffrage was the downfall
                    and not savior of the Republican party. Calls on Conservatives to take heart
                    from the results and work to bring a Democratic president to office in 1872.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Who Shall the Democrats Nominate for Speaker of the Next House of
                    Representatives?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article calling on Democrats to choose Capt. G. W. Skinner their
                    representative to the Republican caucus for speaker of the State House of
                    Representatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Improvements in St. Thomas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John F. Walter had a house built in St. Thomas and Col. W. D. Dixon
                    recently painted his.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holsinger</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sheriff Fletcher moved John and William Thomas, both black men convicted of
                    stealing the horse of John S. Holsinger and the buggy of William C. Sharp, to
                    the penitentiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sackman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>W. Rush</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following were elected to the St. Thomas Lyceum: Jacob Sackman,
                    president; W. Rush Gillan, vice president; John C. Detrich, secretary; Cyrus C.
                    Gelwicks, treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Off in the Country</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hershberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major Hershberger, Franklin County's renowned artist, is staying in Fulton
                    County and is working hard on several nature paintings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two religious revivals are underway in Letterkenny, one in Strasburg and
                    one in Karper's Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Gone to Europe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. John L. Blair of Mercersburg is on a trip to Europe to visit the
                    Medical University at Edinburg, Scotland. "The Dr. is a self-made man. His
                    medical education was obtained through his own exertions." He attended the
                    University of Maryland and graduated with high honors. "The Dr. certainly
                    deserves credit for his persistent energy in endeavoring to become master of
                    such a science as that of medicine, and we wish for him that his efforts may be
                    abundantly crowned with success." He is known to the community for his
                    prosecution of William Davis for the rape of a young girl named Mary Snyder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Teacher's Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kidd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raub</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheely</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Teacher's Institute will meet in Chambersburg on
                    November 21st. A number of well-known teachers will address the convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grier</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fetter</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas S. Grier and Miss Minnie R. Fetter, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on November 3rd by the Rev. I. N. Hays, assisted by the Rev. James F.
                    Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>T. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Gracy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. T. C. Robinson of Westmoreland County and Miss Mollie J. Skinner of
                    Chambersburg were married on November 10th by the Rev. James F. Kennedy,
                    assisted by the Rev. Gracy Ferguson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Royer</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin D. Royer and Miss Jennie Taylor, both of Franklin Furnace, were
                    married on November 10th by the Rev. James F. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donovan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Osterman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenzel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Father</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Donovan and Miss Mary Osterman, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    on November 15th in the Catholic Church by Father Stenzel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stahl</ln>
                        <fn>Emma J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stahl</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stahl</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emma J. Stahl, daughter of George and Catharine Stahl, died near Scotland
                    on October 19th of consumption.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.11.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
