<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1870/pa.fr.vs.1870.04.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/18/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1870-04-06">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">6</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.04.06.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.04.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Border Claims</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The people of the border counties have been refused payment of the debt which
                        the State owes them. This rich Commonwealth, through her Legislature, has
                        refused to be just to her citizens, for the movement to secure payment of
                        the losses sustained at the hands of Union and Rebel forces was not an
                        appeal to the generosity, or magnanimity of the Legislature. It was an
                        earnest and respectful demand for justice. That movement has failed for the
                        present, and the men who are staggering under the terrible losses which fell
                        upon them during the war, have been told by the representatives of the
                        people that they must bear their heavy burdens alone, or, if unable to bear
                        them, must sink under their weight. There is apparently no disposition to
                        shift these burdens from the shoulders of the few to the shoulders of the
                        many, and to make the tens of thousands who lived in peace and comfort
                        during the war, share, in some degree, the losses which befell, in a common
                        cause, those who were always open to the ravages of the enemy. We say <emph
                            rend="italic">in some degree</emph>, for even if every dollar that was
                        lost on the border, in horses, cattle, grain, household goods and
                        comfortable homes, had been paid, in accordance with our demand, the
                        compensation would be inadequate. Talk of the losses which Harrisburg, or
                        Philadelphia, or Pittsburgh sustained. A Philadelphia paper gravely
                        commented on the loss that Philadelphians sustained, <emph rend="italic"
                            >owing to the interruption of business</emph>. That article was
                        exceedingly ludicrous to our people. Had Philadelphians witnessed the total
                            <emph rend="italic">suspension</emph> of business here, not for days, or
                        weeks even, but for whole months--had they seen the hurried packing and
                        shipment of goods, time and again--had they seen the droves of cattle and
                        horses that were captured--had they seen large store rooms broken open and
                        plundered--had they witnessed the ransacking of private houses from garret
                        to cellar--had they stood where property and life were endangered by the
                        terrible conflict that raged all around them--had they been forced to fly
                        from their homes, fired by the torch of the invading foe, and when night
                        came, found themselves without any roof above them except God's own arched
                        sky, they might talk and write of the loss which Philadelphians sustained.
                        But until such has been their experience, let them cease to compare their
                        trivial annoyance to the gigantic misfortunes and calamities which have
                        deranged the business, blighted the hopes, and crushed the hearts of the
                        people of the border counties.</p>
                    <p>For our part, <emph rend="italic">we are in favor of letting Philadelphia
                            prosper without the trade of the border counties</emph>. We have no idea
                        that grass will grow in her streets on that account. We are not inclined to
                        magnify the advantages which accrue to the City of Brotherly Love from this
                        quarter. But we are not disposed to help, in any degree, those who not only
                        refuse to help us, but who accompany their refusal with insults that have
                        made the blood boil in our veins--insults unmerited, unjust and, besides,
                        most infamous in their nature.</p>
                    <p>We know that the excuse is made that the business men of Philadelphia knew
                        nothing of these attacks before they were made, and that they ought not to
                        be held responsible for them. But we cannot see the force of this assertion.
                        Granting that they did not instigate these attacks, which they were very
                        likely to do in order to avoid increased taxation, why did they not protest
                        against them? Why did they not memorialize the Legislature, praying that
                        body to pass a bill which would indemnify us for our losses? Silence, under
                        such assaults, known to be utterly groundless, was criminal. If Philadelphia
                        desires to have the money of the people of the border counties in the way of
                        trade, let her business men understand that these claims of the border
                        counties against the State must receive the support of the people of
                        Philadelphia. <emph rend="italic">To business men and all citizens
                            therefore, we say buy your goods and transact all your business in
                            Baltimore and New York, until the business men of Philadelphia awake to
                            the necessity of doing something for us</emph>. Touch the pockets of men
                        and you touch their hearts. The trade of the border counties is not to be
                        despised. They can wield a power which will be no weak weapon in their
                        hands, if they do but form the determination to wield it.</p>
                    <p>Again. There are some politicians who think that they can gain popularity by
                        opposition to these claims. They imagine that, as the greater portion of the
                        State lost nothing by the war, the majority of the people of the State are
                        opposed to the payment of these claims. But they forget that the people
                        outside of the border counties will not be governed in casting their
                        suffrages by the question, Is he in favor of, or is he opposed to the
                        payment of the border claims? They will vote upon different grounds
                        altogether.</p>
                    <p>But let the people of the border counties rally as a unit, <emph
                            rend="italic">determined to know no question before the payment of the
                            border claims</emph>.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Let them instruct their Senators and Representatives in
                            the Legislature not to vote for any man for any office who refuses to
                            pledge himself publicly in favor of the payment of the Border
                        claims</emph>.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Let them vote for no man for Congress who has failed in
                            his duty in this effort to secure the payment of these border
                        claims</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Let them thus show that they are in earnest in this matter, and that they
                        mean to continue in earnest until the claims are recognized and paid. By
                        adopting such a course, men throughout the State will see that these claims
                        are not in the hands of speculators, but that <emph rend="italic">the people
                            who bore the losses</emph> are demanding payment. And the patrons of
                        daily papers will give the proprietors to understand that they can not libel
                        with impunity a people who have made such enormous sacrifices for the Union
                        as the people of the border counties have made.</p>
                    <p>Prominent among these politicians is the Governor of this Commonwealth. He
                        was opposed to the payment of these claims this winter. He so <emph
                            rend="italic">informed</emph> his friends privately in the House of
                        Representatives. Men of prominence there asserted that if the bill did pass
                        it would meet with the Executive veto. The <emph rend="italic">Topic</emph>,
                        a new daily paper published at Harrisburg, which claims to be the "organ" of
                        His Excellency, asserted in an article, which we publish in another column,
                        that had the bill passed, "it would have put the Governor to the painful
                        necessity of vetoing it." And as though the injury done to our people by the
                        defeat of the bill was not sufficient, it adds to it a gross insult by the
                        comment, "there is nothing like putting down a rebel raid on its first
                        appearance." If the State Government had thought of that in 1862, and kept
                        our gallant Reserve Corps on the border, instead of sending it to the bloody
                        battle-fields of Virginia, Stuart's rebel raid would have been put down on
                        its first appearance, and the claim for damages sustained by reason of this
                        neglect would not now be made.</p>
                    <p>The Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Topic</emph> does not seem to have a
                        good memory, however. This "rebel raid," as he chooses to call it, did not
                        make its first appearance this winter. It is almost eight years since
                        Stuart's raid. It is seven years since Lee's invasion. It is six years since
                        McCausland's deed of vandalism. Ever since then, the people of the border
                        have pressed upon the State Legislatures the justice of their claims. And
                        during all this time, whilst the loyal people of this Commonwealth have
                        exulted over the victory which crowned our arms at Gettysburg, the
                        representatives of this same people have persistently refused to make their
                        patriotic constituents bear their share of the losses which fell upon the
                        people of the border by reason of that battle.</p>
                    <p>We desire to inform the Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Topic</emph> and
                        his master, the Governor, that as this was <emph rend="italic">not</emph>
                        "the first appearance" of this "rebel raid," <emph rend="italic">so it will
                            not be the last</emph>. It will return again to plague the inventors of
                        malignant falsehoods against the border sufferers. It will not "down" at the
                        bidding of any man. The claim is as just as any that was ever made, and it
                        will be pressed until it shall have been liquidated. If this generation
                        fails to secure it, the next will. The intention is to fight it out on this
                        line if it takes a century.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Topic</emph> says the Governor would have been under
                        the "<emph rend="italic">painful necessity</emph>" of vetoing the bill. What
                        would have been the <emph rend="italic">necessity?</emph> Why would it have
                        been <emph rend="italic">painful?</emph> If the Governor uttered his true
                        thoughts and feelings at Mercersburg when he expressed his sympathies for
                        the men who bore these losses, and his opinion that the State ought to
                        assume the burden, then clearly his approval of our bill would not have done
                        violence to his feelings or his judgment. There would have been no reason
                        for him to encounter the pain which a veto would have occasioned.</p>
                    <p>If the Governor's sympathies were with the people of the border--if he
                        believes, as he can not help believing, that their claim against the State
                        is just, how could he be under the necessity of vetoing this bill?--Was
                        there any other reason operating upon his mind? Is there a power behind the
                        throne greater than the throne itself? Is the Governor a mere catspaw to
                        pull roasted chestnuts out of the fire for a small oligarchy? Did somebody
                        suggest to him that the people of the border ought not to be paid because
                        that might interfere with certain operations in which they were both
                        interested? Or, if he acted on his own responsibility, does he wish to
                        believe the report that has been heretofore widely circulated with reference
                        to him, that the surest evidence that he does <emph rend="italic">not</emph>
                        mean to do a thing, is a declaration from him that he <emph rend="italic"
                            >does</emph> mean to do it? These are questions which we can not answer
                        because we can not peep behind the scenes. We can not know the inside
                        workings of the Gubernatorial Ring.</p>
                    <p>But no matter what were the motives that influenced the Governor, certain it
                        is that he is responsible for the defeat of the bill. He said distinctly
                        that he would take the responsibility, and upon him let it rest.</p>
                    <p>He need not lay the flattering unction to his soul, however, that this bill
                        is buried beyond the hope of resurrection. It only sleeps. The time will
                        come when the representatives of the people of this Commonwealth will make
                        haste to discharge these obligations.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laments the failure of the border claims bill to pass the legislature.
                    Blames special interest groups in the big cities, Republicans, and especially
                    Governor Geary. Again stresses the sacrifices border men made to the cause and
                    how they deserve their just compensation. Says the bill may still pass in the
                    future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Fifteenth Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Secretary of State has issued a proclamation declaring the Fifteenth
                        Amendment adopted by three-fourths of the States. He claims thirty States
                        for the Amendment. In this number New York, Indiana and Georgia are
                        included. New York <emph rend="italic">rescinded</emph> her ratification
                        before the requisite number was obtained. In Indiana, only a <emph
                            rend="italic">majority</emph> of the Legislature ratified the Amendment,
                        whereas the Constitution of the State requires <emph rend="italic"
                            >two-thirds</emph> for the passage of any act or joint resolution.
                        Georgia gave her consent in obedience to the mandate of General Terry, who
                        is her military dictator. In addition to this, all the States that seceded
                        were dragged into the support of the Amendment by the bills which passed
                        Congress for their re-admission. Thus was the ratification of this Amendment
                        obtained. Not by the free will of the people, but by the basest chicanery
                        and fraud. The party in power did not hesitate to override State
                        Constitutions and the National Constitution, in order to carry out their
                        cherished scheme of enfranchising the negroes.</p>
                    <p>And yet this Amendment, thus incorporated into the Constitution by
                        unconstitutional and tyrannical means, will, we doubt not, be enforced. The
                        blacks will be allowed to vote in Pennsylvania this fall, and the opinions
                        of the majority of the people of this Commonwealth will be utterly
                        disregarded.</p>
                    <p>President Grant thought the issuing of this proclamation a proper occasion to
                        send a message to Congress. He adverts to the Constitution as "that revered
                        instrument." Yes, "revered" with a vengeance! If he had said that <emph
                            rend="italic">despised</emph> Constitution, he would have come nearer
                        the mark. He urges the newly-enfranchised race "to <emph rend="italic">make
                            themselves worthy</emph> of their new privilege." Were they not worthy
                        before? Are they not worthy now? Why invest them with this right until they
                        have made themselves worthy?</p>
                    <p>He seems to have a high regard for Washington in this address. He quotes him
                        freely. Washington was a man to whom Grant ought never to refer. His whole
                        public life is one complete condemnation of the motives that have actuated
                        Grant and the line of policy which he has seen fit to pursue. This very
                        message which the President sent to Congress was sent for no other purpose
                        than to influence the negro vote by causing the negroes to think that he
                        feels a great interest in having them educated and elevated, when, in
                        reality, he cares more for his cigars and terrier pups, and billiard tables,
                        than he does for them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces with bitterness the passage of the 15th amendment. Gives the
                    examples of New York and Indiana and Georgia to show how it was passed
                    fraudulently and against the will of the people. Also ridicules Grant, saying he
                    does not care about the blacks at all but only wants their votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.04.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Literary Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Literary Exhibition will be held in New Guilford School House on April
                    9th. The event will include dialogues and speeches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Go to Hear Miss Dickinson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Anna E. Dickinson will speak next Tuesday in Repository Hall. "She is not
                    surpassed in eloquence by any woman in the Union." Tickets are 75 cents and will
                    go to benefit the Monumental Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>B. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebok</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. B. G. Huber of Ickesburg Circuit, Pennsylvania Conference of the
                    U. B. Church, and Miss Nannie J. Cormany of Franklin were married at the
                    residence of the bride's parents near Pleasant Hall on March 30th by the Rev. H.
                    W. Rebok.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagner</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Maurer and Miss Amanda G. Wagner, both from near Greencastle, were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father on March 24th by the Rev. D. F.
                    Good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armor</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles E. Armor of Gettysburg and Miss Susan Dixon of Franklin were
                    married on January 31st by the Rev. W. H. H. Deatrich.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porter</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. J. Porter died in Stoufferstown on March 31st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sheets, wife of John Sheets, died in Chambersburg on April 2nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wigfall</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Wigfall, formerly Miss Mary Chambers, died in Chambersburg on
                    April 2nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Helen M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Helen M. Sibert died in Chambersburg on April 1st. She was 23 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Edward E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward E. Etter, son of John M. Etter, died in Hamilton on March 24th. He
                    was 5 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resh</ln>
                        <fn>Susan R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resh</ln>
                        <fn>M. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susan R. Resh, wife of Mr. M. B. Resh, died near Waynesboro on March
                    15th of consumption. She was 40 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Mohler died in Shippensburg on April 1st. He was 30 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. C. Lesher died in Chambersburg on March 20th. He was 26 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowermaster</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Bowermaster died in Southampton on March 28th. He was 66 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1870.04.06.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
