<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.05.17">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/24</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-05-17">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>17</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.05.17.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Blessing Which May Be a Curse</head>
                <origin>Chicago Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is the common habit of people in this country to look upon hte right to
                        vote a very great blessing. The number of those who entertain this opinion
                        is very large, compared to the number of those who also believe that the
                        right to vote may be, and not unfrequently is, a very great curse.</p>
                    <p>Suppose a political party, wielding the patronage a government, and filling
                        every office with bad men -- thieves, cut-throats, hypocrites and
                        scoundrels. With such men to make and execute the laws, can a people be
                        blessed with good government? Finding that power is about to pass from them,
                        the thieves, cut-throats, hypocrites and scoundrels proceed to confer the
                        elective franchise upon a class of persons who have never been made
                        acquianted with its use; who understand not even the first rudiments of
                        political economy; who have lived and propagated in the lowest ignorance for
                        age. Having done this, the bad men. To say that the right to vote, would be
                        blessing, and not a curse, to the class which should thus be made to
                        exercise that right to their own injury, would be to speak very obvious
                        nonsense.</p>
                    <p>Now this is what the Jacobin party has done, and is striving to do, with
                        reference to the southern freedmen. The leaders in that party voted to
                        enfranchise the freedmen in the expectation that they could be used, as a
                        class, to continue those leaders in power.--They are now engaged in a
                        desperate effort to realize that exportation by counseling the freedmen to
                        organize a black man's party in the South, and vote as a class to put
                        certain northern white men in office. If the freedmen listen to these
                        pernicious counsels, the right to vote, instead of a blessing to their race,
                        will be a curse not only to themselves, but to the nation.</p>
                    <p>The right to vote is a blessing only when the possessor of it is left
                        perfectly free to act upon his own individual judgement. Whenever that
                        judgement is subordinated to the purposes or interests of another, instead
                        of a blessing, the right to vote is a curse to its possessor.--<emph
                            rend="italic">Chicago Times</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article questions the legitimacy of American democracy if the political
                    system can be manipulated by "thieves, cut-throats, hypocrites, and scoundrels"
                    who confer suffrage rights upon blacks solely in order to entrench the Radicals'
                    hold on power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Girls In College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that two women have applied to attend the University of Michigan,
                    and, judging by the sentiments expressed by the state legislature, they are
                    expected to get in.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Excursion of Capitalists</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a group of fifteen capitalists from Philadelphia will soon tour
                    southwestern Virginia in search of investment opportunities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Immigration</head>
                <origin>Democratic Mirror</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>From Ireland, it is reported that "a heavy tide" of emigrants recently
                    departed for the U. S. The tide of emigrants is expected to grow over the course
                    of the year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.05.17.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Thursday of last week, while the "Washingto Fire Company" of Wilmington,
                        Delaware, on a visit to Richmond, and the Richmond Fire Companies were
                        testing the relative capacities of their steam engines, in that city, a
                        difficulty occurred between one of the Wilmington Fireman and a negro man.
                        This subsided, but in measuring the distance to which the engines had
                        respectively thrown streams of water, the negroes crowded upon the firemen,
                        and one of them being pushed back by a fireman, another negro struck the
                        fireman and was knocked down in return by another fireman. The police came
                        up and arrested both the negro and the fireman and were taking them off when
                        the negroes made an attempt to rescue their comrade. The police received
                        accessions to their numbers and prevented the rescue for some time, and
                        although armed, and attacked by sticks, brickets, and missiles of all
                        descriptions, and some of their number badly damaged by the blows received,
                        yet they refrained from using their weapons. When the police had nearly
                        reached the second station House the negroes made a final and successful
                        effort to rescue the negro prisoner and carried him away in triumph. Gen.
                        Scholfield was apprised of the riotous conduct of the negroes and appeared
                        upon the scene, with Mayor Mayo and several companies of soldiers. He
                        requested the sulky, sullen mob to disperse. But they did not heed his
                        request, adn he ordered the soldiers to clear the streets, which they did in
                        "doublt quick," but not until they had bruised the heads of several freedmen
                        with the butts of their muskets. During that night mounted soldiers patroled
                        the streets and all was quiet.</p>
                    <p>On Saturday night the Police arrested a negro for disorderly conduct on the
                        streets, when another attempt was made by the blacks to rescue him. This
                        time several of the police were badly bruised, but they used their firearms,
                        and prevented the rescue of the rescue of the prisoner and well night
                        dispersed the negroes, two of whom were shot, before the soldiers arrived on
                        the scene. By the assistance of the soldiers the ringleaders were arrested,
                        among them was one white man. After this arrest everything again relapsed
                        into quiet.</p>
                    <p>We are sorry to chronicle this, but as long as the negroes listen to the low,
                        mean whites, hired with a price to come among them and stir up strife
                        between them and the Southern whites, for pecuniary gain to their pretended
                        friends, the Radicals, we can but expect a repetition of just such scenes,
                        which must redound to their great disadvantage, if it does not lead to their
                        speedy extinction.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports on a melee that occurred in Richmond last Thursday,
                    after an fight broke out between a local black man and a visiting white fireman.
                    In the ensuing violence, both men were arrested, but the black man was freed
                    after the crowd forced policemen to give him up. The next night a similar
                    incident occurred, but ended on a far more tragic note after the police killed
                    two men and injured several others before the army arrived to help arrest the
                    ringleaders, which included one white man.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Horace Greeley delivered a speech in Richmond last Tuesday
                    before a large audience composed of blacks and whites. Greeley told the crowd
                    that confiscation was a "delusion" and urged blacks to seek other means of
                    procuring land.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Maryland Radical Convention assembled in Baltimore last
                    Tuesday; blacks represent half of the delegates attending the convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus McCormick, a former resident of Augusta, made $167,760 last year from
                    the Reaper he invented, relates the piece. McCormick now lives in Chicago.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Baltimore Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses outrage at Judge Underwood for his latest charge to the Grand
                    Jury in Richmond, labeling his words an "abusive production."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Jefferson Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article chronicles Jefferson Davis's appearance in a Richmond court and
                    his release from custody.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Arrest of Massachusetts Lawyer on the Charge of Inciting the Negroes to Riot
                    and Bloodshed</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary>"Last night Jedekiah K. Haywood, of Mass., was arrested for using
                    language at the negro meeting on Friday night calculated to create a riot. His
                    language was as follows:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Last night Jedekiah K. Hayward, of Mass., was arrested for using language at
                        the negro meeting on Friday night calculated to create a riot. His language
                        was as follows:</p>
                    <p>When I go back to Massachusetts, shall I tell the people there that you are
                        determined to ride in the same street cars in which white man and woman
                        ride? ("Yes!") Shall I tell thtem that you intend to occupy any boxes or
                        seats in the theatre for which you pay your money? ("Yes, yes!")--Shall I
                        tell them that you will go to any public school where people are taught?
                        ("Yes!") Shall I tell them that you intend, in whatever manner you may see
                        fit, to have every right that any white citizens of the State of
                        Massachusetts enjoys? ("Yes!") If you want these things and cannot get them
                        of yourselves the young men of the Old Bay State will help you to get them.
                        They came once adn laid for months for you in the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Chickahominy</emph> swamps, and they will come again.--(Cheers.) We
                        have paid taxes to make you free, and we will pay more to get you what you
                        want. (Cheers.)</p>
                    <p>He then went on, as he said, to caution this vast audience. During his visit
                        to Richmond he had discovered bravery among them that was astonishing. But
                        those who might be disposed to be reckless, he would warn that they owed a
                        duty to the brave men who had risked, he would warn that they owed a duty to
                        the brave men who had risked so much for them.--(Cheers.) You would not
                        endanger the life of the illustrious Underwood, would you? ("No! No! That we
                        wouldn't!") Well, then as soon as he leaves you may have a high carnival for
                        what you please. It is useless for me to advise you as to what to do; for
                        great masses generally do what they have a mind to [Long and continued
                        cheering.]</p>
                    <p>here John A. Fitchett arose and said: "Mr. Speake, you may tell the people of
                        Massachusetts that the colored people of Richmond are determined to enter
                        any barroom, hotel, theatre or street car they may wish." ["Yes, they will!"
                        Cheers.]</p>
                    <p>The speaker said that a law would have to be passed for Virginia as had been
                        passed for Massachusetts, compelling hotel proprietors, etc., to allow the
                        colored men equal privileges with the whites. [Loud cheers, and cries of
                        "That's what we want here," and "We are going to have it here, too!"]</p>
                    <p>He was arrested on a warrant from the mayor, and was bailed in $3,000 to
                        appear to-morrow.</p>
                    <p>Hayward was arrested by order of the Mayor, it is understood, at the instance
                        of General Scholfield, but on our putting the question to the Mayor, with a
                        view of learning the facts, he declined to answer. We therefore think it
                        safe to conclude that the arrest was made at the instance of General
                            Scholfield.--<emph rend="italic">Rich. Times</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The trial was in progress Monday, Tuesday and Wednesday, but up to the time
                        of going to press, we have been unable to learn the decision of the
                    Mayor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of the speech delivered by a white northerner who was
                    arrested for inciting blacks to riot in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.05.17.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferral</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Recounts the proceedings at the celebration of the fourth anniversary of
                    Stonewall Jackson's death. The events included a parade and a host of speeches
                    by prominent local men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the Staunton Musical Association's first concert was a smashing
                    success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel B. Brown, formerly of Staunton, is visiting town this week. Brown
                    says the wheat and cotton harvests in the area around his new home in southwest
                    Georgia are expected to be bountiful.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Council of the Clergy and Laity of the Episcopal Church of
                    the Diocese of Virginia convened in Staunton last Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Richard Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>Jordan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Richard Taylor Smith, "colored," was arrested and brought before Mayor
                    Trout for breaking into the residence of Jordan Powell, "colored," and stealing
                    a trunk and its contents. Smith acknowledged his guilt and was sent to face the
                    Grand Jury charged with Grand Larceny and Burglary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahoney</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that Henry Mahoney, the "efficient" Superintendent of the
                    Staunton and Parkersburg Turnpike Company, has "gotten his road into excellent
                    condition."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Valley Railroad Company stockholders will hold a meeting in
                    Staunton on May 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benson</ln>
                        <fn>Olivia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 15 P. H. Trout and Olivia Benson, fourth daughter of Judge N. E.
                    Benson, dec'd, of Montgomery, Alabama, were married by Rev. M. Mahan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cuff</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cuff</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 13 Henry Cuff and Mary Jane Cuff were married by Rev. John L.
                    Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 14 Lt. Joseph N. Ryan and Mattie E. Francisco were married by Rev.
                    W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 14 Robert Cochran, formerly of Augusta, and Sallie C. Francisco were
                    married by Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.05.17.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and news briefs.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
