<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.07.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/15</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-07-12">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For The Girls--How To Get A Husband</head>
                <origin>Columbia (Miss.) Index</origin>
                <commentary>"From an excellent communication published in the Columbus (Miss.) <emph
                        rend="italic">Index</emph>, of the 8th of June, we copy the following
                    expressly for the girls:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From an excellent communication published in the Columbus (Miss.) Index, of
                        the 8th of June, we copy the following, "expressly for the girls:"</p>
                    <p>Being old, and therefore allowed license for teasing the girls on matrimonial
                        subjects I consult them about their future prospects often, and find that
                        the opinion obtains with them, that the young men were never so slow in
                        proposing as in these days; which, we must admit, gives them a good, not to
                        say all-powerful reasons, for not taking a husband. Now, young ladies, the
                        whole secret with nine-tenths of you, of not being able to get off your
                        parents' hands, is simply this; You don't know how to work. you can't keep
                        house. You can't make a pair of breeches. you can't tell, for the life of
                        you, the difference between bran and shorts or which cow gives the
                        buttermilk. The young men generally came out of the war "with the skin of
                        their teeth," with no fortune, I might say, but their wardrobes of gray and
                        their canteens, and to marry with them now, rest assured, relates more to
                        making a living with the assistance of a love, industrious helpmate, than
                        indulging in opera music, moonshine, and poetry. Do you know what they say
                        of one of your butterfly young ladies who has held them in the parlor
                        engaged by the hour listening to "elegant nothings?" Nineteen times out of
                        twenty is this--"Well she is all right for an evening's entertainment, but
                        she will not make a good wife."</p>
                    <p>There is no possible objection to the accomplishments of music, painting, and
                        the like, as such, but the idea is to be able to set these parlor amusements
                        aside for the period, when the stern duties of married life, all for your
                        practical knowledge. Show the young men that you can do your part of double
                        business; that you can cook a meal's victuals on a pinch; that you can sweep
                        up, and dust, and darn old stockings, and save a penny toward an accumulate
                        pound; that you will not be a dead expense to him through life. Believe me,
                        my young friends, as many true heroic, womanly hearts beat over household
                        duties, as flutter beneath the soft light of a parlor chandelier. your kiss
                        is just as sweet, your smiles just as bright, your heart as happy and
                        tender, after a day's exertion in a sphere worthy of true womanhood, as in
                        places of dissipation, frippery, and silly amusement. Have an ambition to do
                        your part in life; cultivate industrial habits, and let the parlor
                        accomplishments go with the higher accomplishments I have roughly
                        enumerated. it is astonishing how soon a domestic young lady is found out
                        and appreciated. It is because she is such a rare exception to the general
                        rule.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article advises young women to concentrate on their homemaking skills
                    as the best way to land a husband, rather than cultivating an appreciation of
                    the arts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.12.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A meeting of "respectable" citizens of Albemarle was held in Charlottesville
                        on the 1st inst., in which a series of resolutions were passed, declaratory
                        of their purpose to co-operate with the Republican party, on the ground that
                        it was the only party that could secure to the people of Southern States
                        protection to life and property, and affirming that they considered
                        themselves "in honor bound to the unconditional maintenance of the Union of
                        the States." as to their desire to co-operate with the Republican party,
                        from conviction of the truth of their principles, or from policy, expediency
                        or fear, we have nothing to say, but when they declare, <emph rend="italic"
                            >as it were</emph>, that the people of the Southern States "are in honor
                        bound to the <emph rend="italic">unconditional</emph> maintenance of the
                        Union of the States," we are indisposed to let such action pass without a
                        notice, however respectable or intelligent the promulgators of such a
                        doctrine. No such idea obtained in the days of the formation of the
                        Republic, or to-day would have witnessed no such Government as we have, for
                        the States would have delegated no powers to a general agent, but have
                        reserved all, and there would have been to-day as many small Republics, at
                        least, as there were colonies. It has remained for these gentlemen, in sight
                        of the last resting place of the "Sage of Monticello," to promulgate this
                        doctrine terrible to the prospects of our country and totally destructive of
                        Republican Government on this Continent. We maintain that no man, be he from
                        the North or South, be he White or Black, is in "honor bound" to the <emph
                            rend="italic">unconditional</emph> maintenance of the Union of the
                        States. Our ancestors framed and gave their adherence to no <emph
                            rend="italic">unconditional</emph> Union, but to a constitutional Union.
                        In yielding our cause as lost, we sore to support no <emph rend="italic"
                            >unconditional</emph> Union, but the Constitution and the laws made in
                        pursuance thereof, excepting therefrom the Emancipation Act. No man has been
                        disfranchised for participation in the late war, on account of thus
                        endeavoring to destroy an <emph rend="italic">unconditional</emph> Union,
                        and no one is required now to swear allegiance to an <emph rend="italic"
                            >unconditional</emph> Union. The idea which the majority in the North
                        maintain is that the Union is indissoluble, but, however their acts may
                        belie their profesions, they claim it still as a Constitutional Union. We
                        submit therefore that we, one and all, are bound in honor to support no
                            <emph rend="italic">unconditional</emph> Union, but a Union under a
                        written Constitution. A few malcontents, months ago, proclaimed themselves
                        unconditional Union men, but so little of intellect and influence heralded
                        this cry that it was of no moment to combat the heresy, but when men, who
                        lay a just claim to respectability and intelligence, proclaim such a
                        doctrine, it is time that all parties should arise to dispel this political
                        dogma, which contains within it, that which will sap the foundations of
                        Republican Government in this country.</p>
                    <p>We claim to have ever revered the Union under the Constitution, but never do
                        we expect to counsel, advise or give aid to a Union of these States, <emph
                            rend="italic">without conditions</emph>, and we opine that the day will
                        come, if it has not already, when the respectabilities of Albemarle will
                        hide their heads for shame over the doctrine promulgated in their 1st of
                        July Resolutions.</p>
                    <p>The people of the South yielded to the stern arbitrament of the sword, and
                        without a murmur have done, and are doing, all that was required of them to
                        restore peace and prosperity to the country, and guarantee equal rights to
                        all classes, but they have not been required to do that which would render
                        nugatory their oaths to support the Constitution, and they will not
                        voluntarily do so by declaring themselves supporters of an <emph
                            rend="italic">unconditional</emph> Union. The Albemarle gentlemen are
                        too eager to affiliate with the Republicans, and we suggest to the latter
                        that before they are admitted they should again be required to take an oath
                        to <emph rend="italic">support</emph> the Constitution of the United
                    States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At a meeting in Charlottesville on July 1, relate the editors, the
                    "'respectable' citizens" of Albemarle County adopted several resolutions
                    offering their support for the Republican party on the grounds that this act
                    demonstrated their commitment "to the unconditional maintenance of the Union of
                    the States." The editors have little to say about their counterparts' decision
                    to join the Republicans, choosing instead to direct the full brunt of their
                    criticism on the notion that being a true American requires devotion to any such
                    ideological principle, which they contend is unconstitutional.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Hunnicutt, of the Richmond <emph rend="italic">New Nation</emph> the Radical
                        leader in Virginia, calls the Resolutions of the Albemarle Gentlemen
                        "perfect clap trap" and fears it is another "Trojan Horse" "filled with
                        armed soldiers" "<emph rend="italic">newly reconstructed
                        secessionists</emph>," but asserts that "<emph rend="italic">it will never
                            capture</emph> (the Republican) <emph rend="italic">Troy</emph>." He
                        says "these newly converted respectabilities are not going to <emph
                            rend="italic">ride over</emph> and <emph rend="italic">over ride</emph>
                        the loyal men who have borne the heat and burden of the day" and pronounces
                        their effort "a deep, dark and damnable plot to divide the Republican party
                        of Virginia," but declares the Republicans in Virginia too thoroughly
                        drilled to be captured by these new converts. Therefore there will be no
                        seats in Hunnicutt's Convention for the Albemarle delegation, and besides
                        Hunnicutt says "his disciples will henceforth govern Virginia." Really the
                        Albemarle co-operationists are in a nice condition, spurned by the
                        Republicans, with but few sympathizers elsewhere.</p>
                    <p>"'Better the fire upon the roll,<lb/>Better the shot, the blade, the
                        bowl,<lb/>Than crucifixion of the soul,'<lb/>Albemarle, oh, Albemarle!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that the Radical leader in Virginia, Hunnicutt, doubts
                    the sincerity of the "'newly reconstructed secessionists'" in Albemarle, who
                    lately adopted resolutions in support of the Republicans, labeling their efforts
                    "'perfect claptrap.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that the residents of Louisa county have followed the
                    lead of their counterparts in Albemarle. The "co-operationist" from the two
                    counties, it scoffs, hope to send delegates to "be admitted to seats in the
                    gallery of Hunnicutt's Convention" so that they "might be allowed to fall in the
                    rear of the Republican party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that House's Judiciary Committee failed to issue its
                    impeachment report before the October deadline and will continue its work on the
                    document when Congress returns from adjournment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Gen. Scholfield has reiterated that "persons disfranchised under
                    the Reconstruction and Supplemental acts" are not eligible to vote, despite
                    rumors to the contrary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the House approved Thad Stevens's supplemental Reconstruction
                    bill by a vote of 119 to 31; all Republicans voted in favor of the measure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Samuel Sterling, Collector of U. S. Internal Revenue, reports that he has
                    collected $157,515.68 in taxes from district residents for the past fiscal year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Surrat Trial--Expected Developments by the Defense</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article lays out what is expected to be Surratt's defense against the
                    charge that he played a role in Lincoln's assassination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Stevens' Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of Thad Stevens's bill to amend the Supplementary
                    Reconstruction act. Among the proposed provisions are measures that grant
                    military commanders the right to remove officials when they deemed it necessary
                    and order registrars to be vigilant when tallying lists of voters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Registration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the total registration in Alexandria, Va., is 2,603, with a
                    black majority of 505.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Amusing Burlesque</head>
                <origin>Charlottesville Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article ridicules the citizens of Charlottesville who endorsed the
                    resolutions in support of the Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dall</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goodloe</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. Howe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article recounts the events at the Augusta Fire Company's Fourth of
                    July picnic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallagher</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hugh L. Gallagher, a resident of Augusta, has spent a considerable sum to
                    remodel his mill, reports the article. When completed, the improvements,
                    designed by the noted Richmond architect Joseph Hall, will make Gallagher's mill
                    equal to any other in the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>William H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>E. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferral</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sojourner</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Captain</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>T. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gooch</ln>
                        <fn>G. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>H. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that officers were selected at the last meeting of the Union Royal
                    Arch Chapter, No. 2, Staunton, Va.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors lament that local blacks have organized a Union League chapter
                    in Staunton because it will force whites to form "defensive Leagues" to counter
                    the threat posed by the new organization.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a black girl was killed in Greenville after she was run over
                    by a stage coach.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article offers a warm appraisal of the "Closing Soiree" at the Masonic
                    Female Seminary of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmondson</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>H. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that officers were selected at the meeting of Staunton Lodge No.
                    43 on June 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Jr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Laments the passing of Alex H. H. Stuart, Jr., son of Hon. Alex H. H.
                    Stuart, of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article states that 177 of the 238 members of the African Methodist
                    Episcopal Church in Staunton voted to join "the Northern Branch of Church." The
                    remaining 61 failed or refused to vote on the matter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hemp</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hemp</ln>
                        <fn>Susan E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the infant daughter of John D. and Susan E. Hemp drowned in a
                    spring on the farm of John D. Baylor, near Baylor's Mill in Augusta. She was 15
                    months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that Gen. Scholfield appointed Brevet 1st Lieut. J. T. H. Hall, 2nd
                    Lt. Vet. Reserve Corps, as Commissioner for the counties of Rockingham,
                    Shenandoah, Highland, and Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that this year's bumper crop may be the best wheat harvest on
                    record.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blain</ln>
                        <fn>A. McR.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Informs readers that A. McR. Blain has obtained a patent for a machine that
                    pares, chores, and slices apples. His invention is said to be "superior" to all
                    similar machines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Tom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that a black man charged with raping two young girls was arrested
                    and committed to jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that, at their last meeting, the Directors of the Augusta County Fair
                    named Col J. B. Baldwin President and Prof. Jed. Hotchkiss Secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 13 John B. Heizer and Lizzie Shultz, of Rockbridge, were married by
                    Rev. William Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex H. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alex H. H. Stuart, Jr., died in Staunton last Saturday from typhoid. He was
                    21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.12.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
