<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.06.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-06-14">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.14.01">
            <pageNote>The page contains a number of anecdotes and short news articles.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.14.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We again called attention last week to the necessity of all, who are not
                        disfranchised registering their names as voters, when called upon to do so
                        by the Boards of Registration. In this issue we publish the notice, of the
                        President of the Board, that registration will be commenced, in District No.
                        1 and 2, Staunton, and District No. 3, Middlebrook, on June 22nd, to-morrow
                        one week, and continue until and including June 29th, Sunday excepted. The
                        time for registering, revising the lists and reporting to the commandant of
                        the State is short and we desire to impress upon all the necessity of
                        promptly presenting themselves for registration.</p>
                    <p>There are also several points to which we desire particularly to call the
                        attention of our people. There will be but one place of registration in each
                        magisterial District, and consequently but one place of voting, and no one
                        can vote except at the place he registers. Each one is, therefore, expected
                        to register in his magisterial District, where he must vote.</p>
                    <p>there will be two lists, one for those who are registered as voters, and
                        another for those who are rejected or are considered doubtful, with the
                        reasons therefor. The latter we may call the doubtful list, and upon which
                        we advise all, who are uncertain whether they are disfranchised, or are
                        rejected, to have their names placed and let the matter be decided by the
                        commandant of the State. In this way many will be allowed ultimately to
                        register as voters, who are inclined to believe they are disfranchised.</p>
                    <p>We desire also to remove the impression that any one who aided the rebellion
                        is, therefore, disfranchised. We publish the <emph rend="italic"
                        >order</emph> of Gen. Schofield in our last issue, from which this
                        conclusion was erroneously drawn, in the 3rd paragraph of which he
                        distinctly says that no one is disfranchised for participation in the
                        rebellion, unless he <emph rend="italic">previously</emph> was either a
                        member of Congress or officer of the United States, civil or military, and
                        as such took an oath to support the Constitution of the United States, or
                        was a member of any State Legislature, or executive or judicial officer of
                        any State and afterwards engaged in insurrection or rebellion against or
                        gave aid and comfort to the enemies of the United States, or has been
                        convicted of felony against the laws of any State or of the United States.
                        He then proceeds to define the executive and judicial officers of a State to
                        be "Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Secretary of State, Auditor of Public
                        Accounts, 2nd Auditor, Register of the Land Office, State Treasurer,
                        Attorney General, Judges of the Supreme Court of Appeals, Judges of the
                        Circuit Courts, Judge of the Court of Hustings, Justices of the County
                        Courts, Mayor, Recorder and Alderman of any city or incorporated town, who
                        are <emph rend="italic">ex-officio</emph> Justices, Coroners of towns and
                        counties, Escheators, Inspectors of tobacco, flour and other commodities."</p>
                    <p>No all who held any one of these offices before the war and afterwards gave
                        aid and comfort to the enemies of the United States and all who have been
                        convicted of felony are disfranchised, but no one is disfranchised for
                        aiding in any way in the late war, unless he previously held one of the
                        offices which General Schofield enumerates, as given above by us, and all
                        such can take the oath required, which we publish again for the information
                        of our people, and is as follows:</p>
                    <p>"I ---, do solemnly swear, or affirm, in the presence of Almighty God, that I
                        am a citizen of the State of ---; that I have resided in said State for ---
                        months next preceding this day, and now reside in the county of ---, or the
                        parish of ---, in said State, as the case may be; that I am 21 years old;
                        that I have not been disfranchised for participation in any rebellion or
                        civil war against the United States, nor for felony committed against the
                        laws of any State or of the United States; that I have never been a member
                        of any State Legislature, nor held any executive or judicial office in any
                        State, and afterwards engaged in insurrection or rebellion against the
                        United States or given aid or comfort to the enemies thereof; that I have
                        never taken an oath as a member of any State Legislature, or as an executive
                        or judicial officer of any State, to support the Constitution of the United
                        States, and afterwards engaged in insurrection or rebellion against the
                        United States, or given aid or comfort to the enemies thereof; that I will
                        faithfully support the Constitution and obey the laws of the United States,
                        and will, to the best of my ability, encourage others so to do. So help me
                        God."</p>
                    <p>Some may think that they can not take this oath on account of swearing that
                        they have never been disfranchised for participation in the Rebellion, when
                        the Alexandria Constitution disfranchised all who aided or abetted the
                        Confederacy. We would ask all such to reflect a little and remember that
                        Congress, by its Reconstruction act, ignores that Constitution, and
                        consequently no disfranchisement under tat act could possibly be claimed.
                        The President of the Board, and Registrars in this county so hold, as Gen.
                        Schofield plainly does, for which we again refer to paragraph 3rd of his
                        order No. 34, the substance of which we quote above, that no one is
                        disfranchised, for participation in the Rebellion, (by the Alexandria
                        Constitution or any act of Congress,) unless he <emph rend="italic"
                            >previously</emph> held one of the offices we have enumerated. All
                        conscientious scruples on this score must therefore, be thrown to the wind.</p>
                    <p>We have endeavored, in as concise a way as possible, to show that aiding in
                        the Rebellion, according to Gen. Schofield's order does not disfranchise any
                        one unless he previously held certain designated officers which required an
                        oath to be taken to support the Constitution of the United States, and we
                        again appeal to all as a duty they owe to themselves and posterity to come
                        forward and register, and be thereby placed in a condition thereafter to
                        exercise the right of suffrage.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors remind readers of the importance of registering to vote, and
                    examine some of the provisions contained in Gen. Scholfield's proclamation on
                    voter eligibility. Evidently there is considerable confusion over who is
                    actually disfranchised.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Piedmont Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that the Piedmont Land Agency "received two
                    installments of immigrants within the past few days" and has supplied area
                    planters with white laborers. "All that is necessary," the piece contends, "is a
                    little energy in this direction, and we can induce a large immigration of
                    reliable white laborers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that a delegation of northern Republicans are in Richmond to help
                    bridge the divide between the Hunicutt and Botts factions of the Republican
                    party in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Gen. Howard appointed J. M. Langston, a black lawyer
                    from Ohio, as Inspector of Freedmen's schools in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Southern Negro During the War</head>
                <origin>New York Citizen</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is simply a bald, bold, black falsehood to speack of the Southern
                    negroes as having been faithful to the Union, or faithful to anything but the
                    rebellion, during the recent civil war."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contends that, contrary to northern beliefs, most southern
                    blacks did not support the Union during the late war. Rather, it explains,
                    "ninety five per cent. of them were as faithful to the Confederacy as any
                    average equal number of Southern whites."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.14.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lotts</ln>
                        <fn>Martin H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>J. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"The June Term of the Circuit Court for Augusta County, commenced its
                    session here on June 1st, Judge H. W. Sheffey Presiding. The Grand Jury found
                    indictments against Martin H. Lotts for Burglary and also for attempting to burn
                    the jail against William Wilson, colored, for Barn burning, against J. Henry
                    Bird, colored, for burning an unoccupied house, against Richard Taylor Smith,
                    colored, for burglary, and various others for minor offences. Martin H. Lotts
                    was tried on 1st indictment found guilty and sentenced to three years in the
                    penitentiary. J. Henry Bird, colored, tried and found 'not guilty.' Richard
                    Taylor Smith, colored, tried and found guilty of petit larceny--punishment not
                    yet pronounced by the court. William Wilson, colored, arraigned and nolle
                    prosequi entered--prisoner retained in custody and a Grand Jury directed to be
                    summoned. Martin H. Lotts was tried on second indictment for attempting to burn
                    the jail, and jury returned a verdict of 'not guilty.' Various matters of no
                    general interest were disposed of."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that caterpillars have been "ravaging the forests on the Northwestern
                    side of the town for some days past."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article proudly notes that Lorenzo Sibert has obtained a patent for an
                    invention that converts "iron ore into cast-steel, at any ordinary Furnace, at
                    the cost of Pig-iron." It is "probably the greatest invention of the age," says
                    the piece.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Staunton Business College has opened its doors. Classes
                    are held in the room used by the Odd Fellows' Lodge, above the First National
                    Bank.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several farmers in the county have noticed a blight on their wheat, reports
                    the article. Consequently, it calls on all farmers to check their fields.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that the Circuit Court adopted a law last week "allowing a practicing
                    attorney to act as Judge pro tem in any case in which the Judge is interested."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the "Ladies of the Baptist Church" made $105 at their
                    Strawberry Festival last weekend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burges</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 30 William T. Wright and Sarah F. Burges were married by Rev. A. A.
                    P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 30 John F. Houff and Mary V. Neff were married by Rev. J. W.
                    Kiracofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Maria E. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 30 Joseph M. Jordan and Marie E. E. Craun were married by Rev. C.
                    Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.14.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
