<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.04.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/19</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-04-26">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.04.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Nomadic Character of the Black Population</head>
                <origin>Richmond Esquire; New York Evening Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italic">Evening Post</emph> calls the attention of
                        the political calculators to the fact that a great change has been made in
                        the last few years, in the distribution of the negroes as compared with the
                        census of 1800. Apart from those who went Northward, and from the increased
                        mortality, the more northern of the Southern States have suffered a large
                        loss from the tide of emigration that sets southward.</p>
                    <p>"With the removal of all restraints the negroes have wandered at will,
                        sometimes towards the cities, but generally southwards. Late statistics show
                        that in some counties in Virginia the number of laborers has been reduced
                        full one-half, and throughout the State the negroes have noticeably thinned
                        out. No figures are given in Kentucky to show the extent of the exodus from
                        that State, but there is general complaint of the loss of labor, and the
                        local journals say that all the best field hands are going to the Southern
                        cotton grounds.</p>
                    <p>"From States South of Kentucky and Virginia the negro movement is still
                        southward. Within a year the two Carolinas are estimated to have lost from
                        one-forth to one-third of their negro population, though the Charleston
                            <emph rend="italic">News</emph> thinks that only 25,000 field hands have
                        gone from South Carolina, and these went, it says, to Mississippi,
                        Louisiana, Alabama, Texas and Florida. Still further South, the Macon <emph
                            rend="italic">Telegraph</emph> is still confident that Georgia has lost
                        one-third of her negroes, and that the loss of North Carolina and South
                        Carolina is still greater. The Augusta <emph rend="italic"
                        >Constitutionalist</emph> says, "if a correct census should be taken of the
                        negro population of Georgia, a startling exhibit of decrease would be
                        manifest;" and that "one of the chief causes of this decrease is migration
                        to the South and Southwest." Even in Alabama, which would seem, at least in
                        summer, about as far South as the most aspiring or perspiring colored
                        laborer would desire to go, there is a marked scarcity of labor which the
                        Selma <emph rend="italic">Times</emph> explains by stating the depletion is
                        due to the agents who are everywhere "offering extraordinary inducements to
                        the negroes to go to Mississippi, Louisiana and Texas."</p>
                    <p>This disposition to migrate will interfere very much with the calculation of
                        the radical politicians, even could they control the negro vote as they
                        hope. As twelve months' residence is requisite to voting, most of these
                        rovers will be disfranchised everywhere; so that while the States which they
                        have left will have the white preponderance greatly increased, those to
                        which they have gone will be but little effected. This emigration will put
                        the States of Virginia, North Carolina, Georgia, Florida, Alabama, and
                        Arkansas, wholly above any serious interference thro' colored suffrage;
                        while the whites of South Carolina, Mississippi and Louisiana will be able
                        to maintain themselves without difficulty.</p>
                    <p>Nor will Texas, which has drawn off so many of the blacks, be in any jeopardy
                        of coming under their control, as its white population exceeds the black
                        nearly three to one.</p>
                    <p>It will be seen, therefore, that those who would organize the black
                        population against the whites, would engage them in an utterly hopeless
                        contest in every State in the South. They would be outvoted every where, and
                        would besides forfeit that good will which is infinitely more important to
                        them than votes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that, according to the latest population figures, the
                    number of blacks in the South has decreased considerably since 1860. In addition
                    to the North and West, it relates, large numbers of blacks have departed the
                    Upper South for Mississippi, Louisiana, Alabama, Texas, and Florida.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Distribution of Seeds in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. M. Scholfield Brevet Major General U. S. A.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a letter from Gen. Scholfield in which he appeals for the
                    appointment of a representative to serve as the Agriculture Bureau's agent in
                    Virginia. The agent's task would include disbursing seeds to farmers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.04.26.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last issue we publish the proceedings of the meeting of the colored
                        people, held here, without comment, in the first place for want of space,
                        they being received just before going to press and secondly, that we
                        preferred to see the result of the convention which assembled in Richmond,
                        on the 17th, to which the meeting here sent delegates.--The Richmond
                        convention has had its say and has committed the unfortunate and ignorant
                        colored people of this State to a policy, calculated to result is great
                        injury to them. Judging from the resolutions which we published, the meeting
                        of the colored people here was anything but conservative, yet the Richmond
                        convention went a bow shot beyond. We feel that our colored people have been
                        greatly misled by designing whites in the meeting here as well as at
                        Richmond. They had no hand in getting up the resolution in either case, and
                        infatuated with the idea of participating in a political meeting they could
                        be and were easily manipulated to vote for any and everything. Great
                        allowances should be made for them. They are ignorant and credulous. They
                        surely have no ill will to those who have shown them only kindness
                        throughout their lives, and have not the slightest idea of the purport of
                        the resolutions they have voted for, and we again repeat that we should make
                        many allowances for them.</p>
                    <p>There is, however, a duty incumbent upon each and every one of us. By our
                        inertness we have allowed the ignorance of the colored people to be abused
                        by evil-designers. Although we cautioned our people weeks since that they
                        must explain candidly and truthfully to the colored people their new
                        condition, yet we forebear to upbraid, but suggest that they lose no more
                        time in dalliance between inclination and duty, but follow the course
                        indicated by the latter. It is incumbent upon each and every one of us to
                        explain to those around us their exact condition. That it was no love for
                        them that induced those, who were brought them from the wilds of Africa and
                        first enslaved them, and, finding them unprofitable chattels, not only sold
                        them for a price, but guaranteed their possession and servitude forever to
                        their Southern purchasers, but the <emph rend="italic">exigencies</emph> of
                        a war, thought to be fruitless by any other course, which caused the
                        proclamation of their freedom. That is was no desire to see them awarded
                        justice that they were suddenly lifted to the position of suffragans, but
                        simply that the power and spoils might remain in the hands of the Radical
                        leaders, the first crumb of which will be awarded none of those who wear
                        dusky skins. If the contrary obtained, why are the few in the Northern
                        States denied the political privileges thrust upon their sable brethren at
                        the South? It must be truthfully explained to them wherein their interests
                        and the interests of the whites of the South are identical and that a mutual
                        dependence exists between them, the one for labor and the other for the
                        means of honorable sustenance, and that this will only be interrupted by
                        their failure to realize the fact, and act with confidence in and not
                        distrust of those whites among whom they were born and raised. Then action
                        based upon distrust of their former masters, and most reliable and
                        sympathizing, friends, must exhibit itself sooner or later, and must result
                        in their being supplanted by white labor which <emph rend="italic"
                        >will</emph> understand that confidence between employer and employee is
                        essential to the success of both. They must have it explained to them that
                        the white people in every part of the world have been duped by fair
                        promises, which were never intended to be kept, but simply to win their
                        confidence to secure some benefit to the wily and unprincipled, and be
                        warned that they are now being beset by adventurers, who seek only their own
                        self emolument, which they deem easily attainable through the ignorance of
                        the suddenly enfranchised blacks. We must cause them to consider who has
                        aided in sustaining them since they were freed and see if they do not find
                        it to be their old and tried friends in the South and not their pretended
                        friends in the North. The negro, being called upon, is learning to reason,
                        and with a little effort on our part, will reach the proper conclusion and
                        act upon it. But if we allow him, by our inertness, to become the prey of
                        those who will excite his passions and prejudices for their own advantage,
                        it will not be his fault, but ours. We repeat therefore, that it is
                        incumbent on us to impress upon the minds of the colored people these, and
                        many other things which will suggest themselves to all, and which the narrow
                        limits of a newspaper article forbids us to mention. Justice to ourselves
                        and duty to those who were once our faithful slaves, and, from their general
                        conduct, still entitled largely to our sympathy and friendship, alike demand
                        it. We learn with pleasure that General Echols will address them, by
                        invitation, on Saturday night, but we are not content with this.--Other
                        prominent gentlemen must follow with timely advice, and each and every one
                        must use our efforts to get the colored people to reason and reflect upon
                        their condition and exercise judgement and discretion in their acts, and
                        give them timely advice and counsel lest they be led astray by those who
                        ever the lay in wait for the innocent.</p>
                    <p>Thank God we are not responsible for the present unfortunate conditions of
                        the blacks, but unless we are alive to our duty we will be in a great degree
                        responsible for the terrible future which awaits the colored people of this
                        country. We have seen the Indian waste away because no sympathizing friend
                        was by when avarice sought his broad domain, and "make room for the white
                        man" was the cry which thrust him, reluctant, a pitiful pension from the
                        Government, to the further side of the Continent whence the track of the
                        last [unclear] vanished leaving [unclear] of time. It [unclear] from the
                        black man we must instruct him and make him understand that his interests
                        are ours, that his existence is no more incompatible with ours then when he
                        was a slave, but that his labor is needed and desired, and that his place
                        will only be supplied when he fails to do his duty and act for the best
                        interest of his employer.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors offer a critical appraisal of the political convention held by
                    black Virginians last week. The delegates, several of whom were selected at a
                    meeting in Staunton two weeks ago, agreed upon a program that "committed the
                    unfortunate and ignorant black people of the State to a policy calculated to
                    result in great injury to them." The editors place blame for the radical
                    sentiments expressed in the convention's resolutions on "designing whites" who
                    misled the freedmen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the U. S. Internal Revenue will lose almost $10 million
                    due to crop damage caused by the late floods in Louisiana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that several thousand Indians have evaded Gen. Custer's forces in
                    Colorado.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Disgusted Delegate</head>
                <origin>"We have been called on by Mr. E. L. Houff, a delegate from Augusta to the
                    African Church pow-wow at whose request we publish the subjoined preamble and
                    resolutions which were offered by him in that body and were unanimously and
                    contemptuously voted 'under the table.' Mr. H., who seems to be a sensible and
                    well-meaning person, is satisfied that he was entirely out of place in any such
                    body, and that the convention was got up and controlled by corrupt and designing
                    (white men) for their own selfish ends. He will take care, in the future, not to
                    be caught in any such company. The following is the paper which was submitted by
                    Mr. H., and which expresses his own sentiments and, as he assures us those of
                    the 'Union men' of Augusta:"</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Houff's preamble and resolutions express conservative, non-politically
                    threatening views; the resolutions condemn cession, call for reconciliation, and
                    oppose confiscation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Starvation in South Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that several women's deaths in the Kershaw and Sumter districts in
                    South Carolina have been attributed to starvation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Another General Order</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of Gen. Scholfield's order requiring all temporary county
                    and city appointments to be "made upon the concurrent recommendations of the
                    county court or city council and the president of the board of registration."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Terrible State of Things in Georgia</head>
                <origin>Savannah Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that there have been violent confrontations between blacks
                    and whites in two Georgia counties--Camden and Bryan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.04.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Proceedings of the County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>W H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>R. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>Gen.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Orlando</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balley</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strouse</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCausland</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simes</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carrot</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cavanaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanfossen</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"The following cases were presented before the County Court during the
                    April term. W. H. Marshall, charged with rape, was examined and acquitted. R. L.
                    Robinson, charged with bastardy, was discharged from his recognizance and
                    complaint dismissed. The use of the Court House was granted to Gen. Echols, to
                    address the black population of the Town and County. The Sheriff and deputies
                    returned the delinquent Tax list for the year 1866, which was allowed and
                    ordered to be certified. Col. George Baylor renewed his bond as Notary Public.
                    Orlando Smith was granted the privilege of extending the Law office of D. S.
                    Young, on the north-west corner of the Jail lot 4 feet, 8 inches. E . W. Bailey
                    was appointed Surveyor of the public road, vice W. A. Bell resigned. The usual
                    certificate was granted E. B. Strouse, to obtain a license to practice law in
                    the Courts of the Commonwealth. An order was entered certifying that W. D.
                    McCausland, William Simes, James H. Berry, Samuel Carrot, John C. Ott, Moses
                    Cavanaugh, Jacob S. Sheets, and William E. Vanfossen are residents of the State
                    for the purpose of procuring artificial limbs."</summary>
                <note>The article discusses several other cases heard during the April term, but
                    they are illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>Leonidas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>During the last meeting of the Staunton Lyceum, officers were selected for
                    the ensuing year. After the selection process, Dr. J. H. Hewitt gave a satirical
                    lecture to the ladies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Almost a year after a similar incident, reports that article, another body
                    was found under Rev. William Baird's lot near Burke's Foundry. Though the body
                    was in "a very decayed condition," the article asserts the remains appear to be
                    from a white child. The editors call for an investigation into what appears to
                    be a "favorite place for burying children" who "have come to their death by foul
                    means."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Partent</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Chief of Police</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>From the Staunton's Chief of Police, it is learned that only $10,000 of the
                    $13,000 in taxes assessed for Stanton has been collected. The article asserts
                    that the outstanding sum is mostly owed by black residents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Consor</ln>
                        <fn>S. L. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Rev. S. L. M. Consor, assigned to Staunton by the Baltimore
                    Conference of the M. E. Church, has arrived and taken over his duties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Echols is among the guests scheduled to speak tomorrow night before
                    Staunton's black community, relates the article. The various speeches will be
                    delivered at the Court House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownlee</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 4 Joseph Wilson and Margaret E. Wilson were married by Rev.
                    Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownlee</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 4 William C. Miller and Mary S. Brownlee were married by Rev.
                    Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butts</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vance</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>Helen M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vance</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 11 William Vance, Jr., and Helen M. Jenkins, formerly of
                    Rockbridge, were married by Rev. S. F. Butts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanrahan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanrahan</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 21 Mary Hanrahan, widow of Patrick Hanrahan, of Ireland, died at
                    the residence of W. H. Tams in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slanker</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 11 Maria Slanker died at her residence in Staunton. She was 70
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.04.26.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and news briefs.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
