<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.06.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/02</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-06-28">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>How The Negroes Are Deluded</head>
                <origin>Brandon (Miss.) Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that Radicals in Mississippi have intimidated blacks
                    into voting the Republican ticket by threatening them with physical violence.
                    These same Radicals have duped blacks into believing that the federal
                    authorities intend to confiscate property and distribute it among them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Boston Slave Trade</head>
                <origin>Lincolnton (N. C.) Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Based upon information gleaned from a "reliable source," the article
                    reports that, after embarking on ships bound ostensibly for Liberia, numbers of
                    American blacks have been shipped surreptitiously to Cuba and placed back into
                    slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our Circuit Court last week the question came up as to which branch of the
                        Methodist Church were the real owners of the church property located in this
                        place.</p>
                    <p>The Congregation now worshipping in the church property have held undisputed
                        possession of it for upwards of fifty years. The last Legislature, with a
                        view no doubt to make a peaceful solution of the question as to the right of
                        property, passed an act granting the privilege to the members of the various
                        churches throughout the State to take a vote as to which branch of the
                        church they would adhere to.</p>
                    <p>The Methodist Congregation in this place, in accordance with that act, took
                        the vote and out of 118 persons entitled to vote, 101 voted to adhere to the
                        Methodist Church South, while the remainder either failed or refused to
                        vote.</p>
                    <p>The result of the congregation was reported to the Circuit Court to be
                        entered upon the record as the law requires.</p>
                    <p>Col. Baldwin as Counsel for the Congregation South, presented the papers in
                        Court, when Mr. Woodson of Harrisonburg and Maj. Bell of Staunton, counsel
                        for the Northern branch of the church, offered a petition of remonstrance
                        signed by Rev. Mr. Consor, the preacher in charge of the Northern Methodist
                        Church at Staunton, Rev. Lawson, colored preacher in charge of the large
                        colored Congregation, now worshipping in their own church in Staunton, by
                        one member of Mr. Consor's Congregation, and three colored persons, members
                        of the colored Congregation.</p>
                    <p>These petitions objected.</p>
                    <p>1. That the Methodist Church in Staunton is built upon a lot which was
                        conveyed for the use of the Methodist Episcopal Church and that it belongs
                        of right to the members of that Church.</p>
                    <p>2. That the congregation now in possession of the Church do not belong to the
                        Methodist Episcopal Church South, and consequently have lost their right to
                        the property.</p>
                    <p>3. that the petitioners and others, belonging to the two congregations
                        represented by them, are the true members of the Methodist Episcopal Church,
                        and as such are entitled to the Church property, and</p>
                    <p>4. That the act of the Legislature under which the proceedings have been had
                        is unconstitutional and void, and the whole movement without validity, and
                        that the papers relating to it ought not to be admitted to record.</p>
                    <p>For the congregation it was replied:</p>
                    <p>1. That the title to the Church property could not be tried in this
                        proceeding, except so far as this congregation has a right to it, and that
                        if others claim an adverse right they must sue for it in regular form.</p>
                    <p>2. That the object of the law of the last legislature was to protect <emph
                            rend="italic">local religious congregations</emph> who when their Church
                        divided were compelled to make choice between the different branches of it,
                        and to allow them in such cases to take their property with them, and that
                        it was the purpose of this congregation to claim the benefit of that
                        protection.</p>
                    <p>3. That the petitioners, which they claim to be Methodists, do not pretend to
                        belong to this congregation, and of course have no right to interfere with a
                        proceeding which concerns this congregation alone and cannot effect the
                        rights of any other parties, and that the law of Virginia recognizes only
                            "<emph rend="italic">religious congregations</emph>," each of which is,
                        under the law, distinct from all others, even of the same Church.</p>
                    <p>4. That in this proceeding the court will confine its inquiries to the
                        regularity and fairness of the steps taken to ascertain the determination of
                        the congregation, and will hear no objection which is not founded upon some
                        suggestion that by reason of fraud, accident or mistake the vote has not
                        been correctly taken or reported.</p>
                    <p>5. That the Court will not undertake to pass upon the constitutionality of
                        the law until the question is distinctly presented in an issue fairly made
                        between, proper parties, so that a decision will end the controversy.</p>
                    <p>The question was extensively argued, but the Court refused to entertain the
                        objections of the Petitioners of the ground that they were not members of
                        the Congregation, whose action they opposed, and that the only legitimate
                        inquiry in these proceedings was as to the regularity or fairness of the
                        vote of the Congregation, under the Act of the General Assembly, The action
                        of the Congregation being found regular was ordered to be entered upon
                        record.</p>
                    <p>Whether this controversy will be prosecuted further, is not known. If it
                        should be the final result will be of considerable interest to our people,
                        involving, as it does, a large amount of church property.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Methodist congregation in Staunton voted to remain part of
                    the Methodist Episcopal Church South by an overwhelming majority. The decision
                    was contested by members of the northern branch of the church in Staunton and
                    black congregants, who filed a lawsuit to nullify the vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Gen. T. W. Patton, of Pennsylvania, was invited to deliver an
                    address before an audience of blacks in Richmond last Monday, but when the
                    organizers of the event found out the "tenor" of his "proposed remarks" they
                    refused to allow him to speak.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls on registrars to remain vigilant so as to insure that black men under
                    21 years of age who, "through ignorance," may try to register to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Negro Experiment Worked Out In Jamaica</head>
                <origin>New York Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Following the abolition of slavery in the British West Indies, recalls the
                    article, Parliament granted limited suffrage to blacks. Later, the
                    qualifications were relaxed, allowing a far greater number of blacks to vote.
                    According to the article, the failure of the electoral experiment pushed
                    Parliament to rescind voting rights in Jamaica and place control of the island
                    in the hands of a committee appointed by the Crown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A correspondent of the <emph rend="italic">Anti-Slavery Standard</emph>,
                        writing from Virginia with an evident understanding of the party machinery
                        among the negroes, gives the Republican party fair warning of what is in
                        reserve for them. The negro vote, he says, will decide the Presidential
                        election. The negroes understand this perfectly and are laying their plans
                        in accordance with it. "There are several negores," says the writer, "fitted
                        for the position of Vice-President, and <emph rend="italic">that race claim
                            that the second office in the nation shall be filled by a negro</emph>."
                        The correspondence fully indorses their claim, and wishes it distinctly
                        understood that it must be conceded or the negro vote will be cast against
                        the Republican party. The party, he says, dare not refuse it as its defeat,
                        without the negro vote and the vote of Northern men who will back their
                        claim, is certain. What will Senator Wade do in this contingency? He has
                        pledge himself to "keep ahead" of the people on all questions of radicalism,
                        and here is one which demands its immediate attention. Threre are negroes
                        who, we are satisfied, would preside over the Senate with quite as much
                        dignity, intelligence and grace as Senator Wade himself does:--but will he
                        think so? Perhaps he can get the negroes to postpone this question until
                        that of the "redistribution of property" is settled.--<emph rend="italic"
                            >New York Times</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Freedmen in Virginia believe that a black man should, and will, be on the
                    next Republican Presidential ticket, relates the article. In contrast to most
                    portraits of the ex-slaves as political neophytes, the article presents blacks
                    as cognizant of their importance in the upcoming Presidential election and
                    intent on benefitting from their position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Good Idea</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article proposes that northern and western farmers should form an
                    association and invite their southern counterparts to "visit them and examine
                    the workings of the system which they have adopted for the cultivation of the
                    soil."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>H. W. Sheffey, Chairman; Bolivar Christian and Jed Hotchkiss, Secretaries</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>English</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hansberger</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article provides a synopsis of the proceedings from the June 24 meeting
                    on the extension of the Central Railroad Line to the Ohio River. Those in
                    attendance agreed upon four resolutions in support of the railroad project.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="p">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Register! Register!</head>
                <origin>Examiner</origin>
                <commentary>"After reading the following appeal made to the manhood of her
                    countrymen by a Southern lady, what man, young or old, who has one spark of
                    gallantry in his bosom will fail to enroll his name and become a volunteer in
                    the new war for the ascendancy of his race, and the honor of his State and her
                    fair daughters. 'Breathes there one with soul so dead to every manly impulse'
                    that he will not leap to the front in joyful response and register."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Ella B--</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The poem calls on white men to do their "manly" duty and register.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that blacks attending a "mixed political meeting" in
                    Charlotte County, Va., "took ground against the reconstruction policy." It is
                    surmised that their position reflects a growing concern among blacks that the
                    white majority in Virginia is too strong to overcome at the ballot box,
                    therefore, blacks must reach a common ground with whites to make sure they will
                    not "be unfairly dealt with" once whites return to power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that an instrumental concert performed by the blind students at the
                    Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institute on June 25 was warmly received.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antrim</ln>
                        <fn>G. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>P. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>States that "very little of general interest transpired" during the June
                    term of the County Court, which was held last Monday. As called for by the
                    legislature, ten men were selected as Directors of the Augusta Agricultural
                    Fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laporte</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>Rachel Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 16 Alexander Laporte and Rachel Ann Roberts were married by Rev.
                    George A. Shuey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peaco</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peaco</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 20 Alexander S. Peaco and Elizabeth M. Peaco were married by Rev.
                    W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moneymaker</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 6 John W. Patterson and Sarah E. Moneymaker were married by Rev. R.
                    C. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashby</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roudabush</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roudabush</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 20 John A. Ashby and Nannie V. Roudabush were married by Rev. R. C.
                    Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoneburner</ln>
                        <fn>Charles D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trenary</ln>
                        <fn>Blanche L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trenary</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 25 Charles D. Stoneburner, Foreman at the Staunton "Vindicator,"
                    and Blanche L., daughter of John Trenary, were married by Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.06.28.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and news briefs.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
