<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.04.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/15</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-04-05">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>05</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.04.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Virginia Emigrants To Chili</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Day Book</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a group of young Virginians, many of whom were in the
                    Confederate service, enlisted in the Chilean Navy because they "could not find
                    employment this free (?) and happy (?) country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Nail Factory To Be Established In Lynchburg</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A man from West Virginia intends to build a nail factory in Lynchburg, says
                    the article. The factory is expected to create numerous jobs, but requires an
                    outlay of $175,000 in capital.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Great Plough</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a model of the great Fowler steam plough, which has been use
                    in England for the past ten years, is on display in New Orleans. The machine
                    cost 2,500 pounds to construct and was imported to be tested on the "immense
                    plantations on the banks of the Mississippi."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.04.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Glorious News From Connecticut</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Celebrates the Democratic victories in the recent Connecticut election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warren</ln>
                        <fn>Uriah N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ennis</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nuckols</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tebbets</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the names of those appointed by the Post Master to serve as mail
                    carriers for the next four years, beginning July 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The confiscation scheme of Mr. Stevens, advocated by him in a lengthy and
                        carefully proposed speech, before the adjournment of Congress, seems to have
                        met with but little sympathy in the House and less in the country at large.
                        The Radical papers, with but few exceptions, oppose confiscation and we
                        doubt not that Mr. Stevens' last effort on that subject has been made. Our
                        readers, we think, need not worry themselves on this subject, for it is very
                        improbable that it will ever be mooted in Congress again, so little favor
                        did it meet with under Mr. Stevens' manipulation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contending that the proposal introduced by Thad Stevens on the eve on the
                    last session of Congress has "met with but little sympathy in the House and less
                    in the country at large," the editors express doubt that any bill to confiscate
                    rebel property will ever become law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Character Of The Negro By An African Explorer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"M. DuChaillee, in his recent published work, 'Journey to Asbango Land
                    and Further Penetration into Equatorial Africa,' makes the following
                    observations respecting the character of the negro:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The extract asserts that, without the "civilizing" influences of whites,
                    blacks "will soon fall back into barbarism."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Chillicothe (Ohio) Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The sum total of the doings Congress may be summed up in the following
                        statement. While it is constantly increasingly the taxes of the people to
                        pay. It is constantly oppropriating money to take care of the negroes, and
                        as constantly injuring the business by which the white people have to take
                        care of themselves. It legislates for Africa, not for America. It was
                        elected by a white constituency, but devoted all its time and energy to the
                        blacks. Black is the standard color for "loyalty" -- all negroes are
                        "loyal," but if a man has a white skin, upon his "loyalty," unless he thinks
                        negroes a great deal better than white folks. To hear the Radical leaders
                        talk to judge from their legislation, a stranger would think that their
                        constituents were all negroes and that the Southern States were located in
                        Africa. <emph rend="italic">Chillicothe Ohio Advertiser</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The diatribe criticizes Congress for overtaxing whites and appropriating
                    the money "to take care" of blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Va. Stay Law Constitutional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a Circuit Court Judge in Salem has ruled the Stay Law,
                    enacted by the General Assembly in March 1866, constitutional.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Acquisition of Russian America By The United States</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The story discusses some of the diplomatic consequences of the Americans'
                    pending deal to purchase Alaska, and supplies a variety of related facts about
                    the region.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Confiscation</head>
                <origin>Providence Journal</origin>
                <commentary>"The Providence Journal (Rep.), which has gone to great lengths in
                    defending Radical men and measures, is compelled to say of Stevens' confiscation
                    scheme:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Until now, relates the article, the "Providence Journal" has endorsed the
                    Reconstruction schemes promulgated by the Radicals, yet even this Republican
                    newspaper describes the proposal to confiscate rebel property as "vindictive"
                    and "remorseless."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals are making desperate preparations to unite the colored vote of
                        the South in favor of the Radical party. The most wicked appeals to their
                        passions and prejudices are being circulated among them, and every effort
                        made to array them in deadly hostility to the white people in the coming
                        elections. To counteract these mean and devilish influence, the people of
                        the South must keep constantly before the colored people the fact that the
                        Radical party at the North only want to use them for their party purposes,
                        as is fully evidenced by the fact that both in New York and Ohio they have
                        refused to grant them suffrage, and have only given it to them in the South
                        in hatred and revenge on the white man. The Northern people, too, vote the
                        original slave stealers, and brought the African to this country and sold
                        him to our people. We have kept him and civilized and christianized him, and
                        made him what is -- far superior to his own race had [unclear]. The white
                        people of the South are now and ever have been, his only friends, for a
                        black man stands no more chance in the North than spoons do in the reach of
                        Butler. <emph rend="italic">Lynchburg Republican</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Decrying Radical efforts to pit southern blacks against southern whites,
                    the article calls on readers to "counteract these mean and devilish influences"
                    by making it known to blacks that Radicals "only want to use them for their
                    party purposes." By contrast, Southern whites "are now and ever have been" the
                    black man's "only friends."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter From General Beauregard</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>G. T. Beauregard</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Among the advice given in his correspondence, Beauregard states that,
                    rather than fighting against the imposition of black suffrage, white southerners
                    should accept it and seek to use it "to defeat our adversaries with their own
                    weapon."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.04.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Staunton Musical Association will give its first
                    performance during Easter week at the Hall of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind
                    Institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolivar</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Col. Bolivar delivered an address entitled "The Scotch Irish
                    of the Valley" at the Staunton Lyceum last Monday. Next Monday, Dr. A. M.
                    Fauntleroy will deliver a speech entitled "Was the Revolution of 1776 a
                    Mistake?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that $600 was "cleared" at the meeting of the Staunton Building
                    Association last Saturday. Thus far, about one hundred shares at ten percent
                    have been sold.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John Clark, who was assigned to Staunton at the last meeting of the
                    Baltimore Conference of the Episcopal Church South, began his tenure last
                    Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the Memorial Fair raised $170 last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that someone broke into W. P. Johnson's Tobacco Store last Friday
                    night and stole about $15 worth of tobacco.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute Of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. H. Wilson, C. W. Stafford, Pat. O'Tool</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Tool</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schever</ln>
                        <fn>George Paul</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contains a memorial and a series of resolutions passed by the Augusta Fire
                    Company in honor of their fallen colleague, George Paul Schever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayers</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLoughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Helen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLoughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 27 William L. Ayers, of Goshen Bridge, and Helen, daughter of
                    Andrew S. McLoughlin, dec'd, of Rockbridge County, were married by Rev. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Runnels</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel D. Myers and Maggie J. Runnels were married by Rev. William A.
                    Harris last Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Leander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 25 Leander Wright and Mary Francis Laughlin were married by Rev.
                    Thomas Preston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Livick</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 28 Alexander Dull and Sarah Francis Livick were married by Rev.
                    Thomas Preston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Showalter</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Showalter, a former resident of Augusta County, died in Rockingham
                    County on March 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas Robert Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 26 Thomas Robert Lee, son of William T. and A. M. Herring, died.
                    He was 3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.04.05.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
