<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.07.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/17</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-07-26">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Word To Single Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article advises women to marry patient and polite men if they hope to
                    be happy. "In the severest of winter," it suggests, as the truest test of
                    commitment, their husbands "would not mind going to bed first."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Fred Douglass' Speech</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is given, in the Norfolk Journal, as the conclusion of Fred
                        Douglass' speech in Norfolk, on the 4th of July: "Had the Southern
                        Confederacy not been blinded by prejudice, she would have used the means
                        which were in her power to employ, of achieving a lasting independence. That
                        is, the Confederate government would have unshackled every slave, and as
                        freemen, armed for the fight, marched them, shoulder to shoulder with the
                        whites, to the field of battle. Had this been done, said he, to-day you
                        would have been a free and independent people. Mr. Lincoln struck the
                        key-note of success just in time, when he issued his emancipation
                        proclamation."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a speech delivered in Norfolk on July 4, Fred Douglass reportedly told
                    his audience that the biggest mistake the Confederacy made in the late rebellion
                    was its failure free the slaves and allow them to fight as freemen for the
                    South. Had the Confederate authorities done so, white southerners would be a
                    "free and independent people" today.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>An Exacting Bride and a Sensible Bridegroom</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the story of a bride who informed her fiance on the eve of her
                    wedding that, once married, she would require a cook and a chambermaid otherwise
                    she would not consent to the nuptials. Stupefied by her demands and unable to
                    afford her wishes, the groom "acted wisely," opting to extend his life as a
                    bachelor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Freedmen</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A friend who has been residing in the peninsula for some months past, informs
                        us that there are about 28,000 negroes between Williamsburg and Hampton--a
                        distance of thirty-six miles. These people are sustained with rations
                        furnished by the Government, at a cost of $60,000, monthly, while five
                        companies of cavalry are required to patrole the country to prevent
                        depredations. Every effort has been made to induce a portion of them to
                        remove to Florida, the officers of the Government offering them free
                        transportation. There is a standing offer of this nature made by Gen.
                        Armstrong, of the Freedmen's Bureau, to convey the men, with their families,
                        to any point they may select, with the view of engaging in useful labor. But
                        they have persistently refused every offer of the kind and rejected every
                        overture made to get them employment. Under the provisions of the Civil
                        Rights bill it is impossible to do anything contrary to their wishes, and so
                        they remain huddled within this limited area and are a heavy tax under the
                        Government. Some of them have taken to highway robbery, and, but for the
                        presence of a large cavalry force, a residence in that country would be
                        intolerable. How long, we wonder, will the people submit to this enormous
                        tax to support such idle and worthless pots of the Black Republican party?
                        Verily! Radicalism is a dear experiment, taxing the patience and pockets of
                        the people to a degree unprecedented in the history of any country.--<emph
                            rend="italic">Lynchburg Virginian</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article complains that a large group of ex-slaves has encamped on a
                    peninsula on the Eastern Shore where they are reportedly living on rations
                    provided by the Freedmen's Bureau. Contending that the blacks have refused all
                    entreaties to relocate to places where they might find employment, the piece
                    blasts the Civil Rights bill, which prohibits employing force to move them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.26.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Friday last the President returned to Congress the Supplementary
                        Reconstruction bill with his reasons for not approving the same.</p>
                    <p>It is clear and concise, and with conclusive reasoning shows its entire
                        unconstitutionality.</p>
                    <p>He asserts that the section declaring the intent and meaning of the prior
                        acts fixes upon them a meaning at variance with their language, which made
                        the government of the Southern States subject to military authority, in some
                        especial particulars, or as they expressly stated, "<emph rend="italic">as
                            hereinafter presented</emph>," while this declaratory act makes them
                        subject to unlimited military authority, and declares that it is impossible
                        to conceive any state of society more intolerable than that to which the
                        twelve millions of people in the Southern States are reduced by the United
                        States Congress. He says the power given a military officer to remove any
                        civil officer of a State is greater than all the Departments of the Federal
                        Government, separately or collectively, have ever dared to exercise and
                        shows, by the appointment of U. S. military officers to perform civil duties
                        in the Southern States, that the United States assumes the civil government
                        of these States, and makes patent the folly of the United States attempting
                        to carry on governments which are declared <emph rend="italic"
                        >illegal</emph> by military officers, who must perform the duties imposed by
                            <emph rend="italic">illegal</emph> State authority. He calls especial
                        attention to that section which provides that military commanders and their
                        appointees shall not be bound "by the opinion of any civil officer of the
                        United States" and exhibits the folly of requiring officials appointed, who
                        may be totally ignorant of their duties, to ask information solely from
                        military officers who may be equally ignorant.</p>
                    <p>He points to the assumption of Congress that the ten communities are not
                        States and have no legal governments, while in the acts of Congress from
                        1861 to 1867, by the action of the Supreme Court, and by the assessment and
                        collection of the Revenue they are recognized as States of the Union, and
                        successfully does away with the argument that these States are conquered
                        territories.</p>
                    <p>Finally he alludes to the vesting of the power of removing from and
                        appointing to office in the Southern States in a military officer, subject
                        only to the approval of the General of the U. S. Army, thereby depriving the
                        President of a Constitutional and essential power, he being responsible for
                        the faithful execution of the law and yet deprived of the power to do so,
                        and expresses his inability to give his assent to the surrender of this
                        trust to any one, high or low, and says in conclusion:</p>
                    <p>"If this executive trust, vested by the constitution in the President, is to
                        be taken from him and vested in a subordinate officer the responsibility
                        will be with Congress in clothing the subordinate with unconstitutional
                        power, and with the officer who assumes its exercise. This interference with
                        the constitutional authority of the executive department is an evil that
                        will inevitably sap the foundations of our federal system; but it is not the
                        worst evil of this legislation. It is a great public wrong to take from the
                        president powers conferred upon him alone by the constitution, but he wrong
                        is more flagrant and more dangerous when the powers so taken from the
                        President are conferred upon subordinate executive officers, and especially
                        upon military officers. Over nearly one-third of the States of the Union
                        military power, regulated by no fixed law, rules supreme.</p>
                    <p>Each one of these five district commanders though not chosen by the people or
                        responsible to them, exercises at this hour more executive power, military
                        and civil, than the people have ever been willing to confer upon the head of
                        the executive department, though chose by and responsible to themselves. The
                        remedy must come from the people themselves. They know what it is, and how
                        it is to be applied. At the present time they cannot, according to the
                        constitution, repeal these laws; they cannot remove or control this military
                        despotism. The remedy, nevertheless, is in their hands; it is to be found in
                        the ballot, and is a sure one, if not controlled by fraud, overawed by
                        arbitrary power, or from apathy on their part too long delayed. With abiding
                        confidence in their patriotism, wisdom and integrity, I am still hopeful of
                        the future, and that in the end the rod of despotism will be broken, the
                        armed rule of power be lifted from the necks of the people, and the
                        principles of a violated constitution preserved."</p>
                    <p>The bill however was passed over the veto by a large majority in both
                    Houses.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors praise President Johnson's rejection of the Supplementary
                    Reconstruction bill and concur with his assessment of the measure as
                    unconstitutional. They describe his speech as "clear and concise" and based upon
                    "conclusive reasoning."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How the Message was Received--A Sharp Discussion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece reports that the battle over whether to impeach President Johnson
                    has divided Republicans in Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Iron-Clad Oath</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article asserts that delegates attending Virginia's state convention
                    will not have to take the iron-clad oath because members of the Convention are
                    not included among the various classes of citizens required to do so.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that several prominent local men delivered addresses last Saturday
                    night concerning the present political situation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindig</ln>
                        <fn>Henry C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyden</ln>
                        <fn>D. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that Henry C. Kindig and A. J. Polmer purchased Peek's Mill,
                    located on Christian's Creek, and have begun to make improvements on the
                    structure and machinery. The mill will operate under the supervision of D. J.
                    Hyden.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With registration in the county complete, the final tally for Augusta is
                    3,484 whites registered to vote and 1,206 blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin>Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarlan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Felix T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Dr. McFarlan, of Dayton, and Felix T. Sheets, of Mossy Creek
                    Paper Mills, were both injured after they were thrown from the wagon they were
                    riding in. Apparently the accident occurred when the horses took fright and ran
                    off.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the passing of William Carroll, son of Jacob Carroll, who died in San
                    Francisco on June 12. William was a native of Staunton, but moved to California
                    15 or 18 years ago. He was 40 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Delia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that "Delia Lewis and Nancy Robinson (colored)" were arrested on
                    Sunday morning for using "abusive language and fighting on the street." The
                    women were brought before the mayor and bound over for $50 each. Unable to
                    provide the security, they were sent to jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Registration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Includes the final registration for several other counties in the area
                    around Staunton: Frederick (1,931 whites, 501 blacks); Rockingham (2,851 whites,
                    424 blacks); Botetourt (1,376 whites, 632 blacks); Craig ( 411 whites, 45
                    blacks); and Clarke (765 whites, 371 blacks).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghue</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. B. B. Donaghue purchased the home residence and lots belonging to the
                    estate of William Kinney, dec'd, for $12,300.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that, during the its last term, the County Court of Rockingham
                    decided it was "'inexpedient and improper to allow any claims for provisions
                    furnished during the war.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Achord</ln>
                        <fn>Zeddie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 17 John R. Taylor, of Winchester, and Zeddie A. Achord were married
                    by Rev. J. L. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.07.26.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements and brief news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
