<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1867/va.au.rv.1867.03.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/13</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-03-15">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1867.03.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Bankrupt Law</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains an abstract of the Bankruptcy Law that lays out the
                    legislation's primary features.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Internal Revenue Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article relates some of the "more interesting features" of the recently
                    adopted law regulating taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1867.03.15.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The subject of calling a Convention under the Military Re-construction bill
                        seems to have exorcised the people of our State to a greater degree than was
                        consistent with their usual calm and patient fortitude under trying
                        circumstances. We believed all the while it was the occasion of greater
                        excitement than there was any necessity for. Although our every feeling and
                        sentiment revolted at the idea of Virginians being made a party to their won
                        degradation, as it seemed to us would be the case if their representatives
                        in the Legislature called the Convention, yet we did not think proper to add
                        to the feeling, which seemed to be increasing, between those who opposed and
                        those who favored a speedy call of a Convention by the General Assembly, by
                        inveighing against the precipitancy which the latter proposed as the proper
                        course to be pursued. We felt that it was useless to argue against the
                        calling of a Convention by the Legislature, as we were satisfied then, as we
                        are now, that Congress is not done with us. There is too much capital in
                        Southern Re-construction for the Radicals to let go the hold which they have
                        upon us yet.--He that thinks otherwise is but flattering the wishes which
                        beget his thoughts. No! when Conventions are called and Constitutions framed
                        in accordance with every requirement of this bill, Congress will refuse to
                        approve them and admit our representatives, until every particle of Radical
                        capital is exhausted from the anomalous political condition in which the
                        people and States of the South are now placed.</p>
                    <p>The Stevens-Sherman-Shellabarger bill provided in a general way for Southern
                        re-construction, by the calling of Conventions, &amp;c., but failed to
                        specify who should call these Conventions. This want of specificness induced
                        the contrariety of opinion on the subject in this State, and has attracted
                        the attention of members of Congress, as will be seen from the bills offered
                        in the Senate by Messrs. Sumner and Wilson, which we publish in another
                        column. It is stated by a late telegram that the Judiciary Committee of both
                        Houses of Congress will report a bill similar to the bill offered by Mr.
                        Wilson, which will settle this question by making it the duty of the
                        Brigadier Generals to call the Convention, or if they prefer delegate the
                        authority to the acting Governors. We doubt not this will be equally
                        acceptable to those who opposed voluntarily accepting a degrading scheme and
                        those who would soften the inevitable blow by a precipitate acceptance. We
                        do not cease to report the S. S. S. bill as unconstitutional and outrageous,
                        and to condemn its authors, aiders and abettors, who could force it upon a
                        brave though powerless people, but we do feel a satisfaction in knowing,
                        since come it must, that we are not to be made parties to our own
                        degradation by voluntarily accepting it, but that it is to be forced upon
                        us, and that the only subject of division among our people since the defeat
                        of the Confederate armies is thus removed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rather than fight what appears to be a futile battle, the editors
                    acknowledge that there seems little reason to resist the call for a
                    constitutional convention. They do not support the move, but recognize that
                    there is little they can do to stop it since the Radicals are in command of the
                    political situation in Congress and seem intent on moving forward with the
                    scheme.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the passage of the Stevens-Sherman-Shellabarger bill, an association of
                        negroes styled "The Loyal Political Society" has been organized under the
                        leadership of Hunicutt, and others of that ilk. The object is to send
                        lecturers throughout the State to inform the negroes in regard to their
                        newly acquired privileges and for whom they should vote, these lectures to
                        be supported by an initiation fee of twenty-five cents and a contribution of
                        ten cents per month. Here we have the seeds of future disturbances preparing
                        to be sowed broadest throughout the State. These lectures will endeavor to
                        poison the minds of the negroes against their only friends, the whites of
                        the South, and will succeed with the ignorant material with which they will
                        deal, unless an antidote is administered. This antidote we have at hand. It
                        seems to us incumbent on those persons, in every community, who have the
                        greatest influence with the colored class, to call them together and explain
                        carefully and truthfully the situation in which they are placed, by the act
                        declaring them suffragans, and point out to them the course they should
                        pursue, which leads to no conflict with, but will retain the friendship of
                        their white friends of the South, with whom their lot is inevitably cast,
                        and upon whom they are certainly dependent. A failure to do this is a
                        failure to perform a duty to our former faithful slaves, who will thus be
                        left at the mercy of those men who will be sent among them to sow distrust
                        broad-cast, and whose teachings can only be productive of evil to Whites and
                        Blacks.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors report that an association of blacks named the "Loyal Political
                    Society" was formed by "Hunicutt and his ilk" in the wake of the passage of the
                    Stevens-Sherman-Shellabarger bill. The goal of the organization is to raise the
                    political consciousness of Virginia's freedmen by sending lecturers across the
                    state to speak. According to the editors, these lecturers "will endeavor to
                    poison the minds of the negroes against their only friends, the whites of the
                    South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From the report of Gen. Howard, Commissioner of the Freedmen's Bureau,
                        relative to the destitution in portions of the South, we learn that the
                        number of destitute persons in Virginia are, White 2,500, Black 2,500; North
                        Carolina, White 3,000, Black 2,000; South Carolina, White 5,000, Black
                        5,000; Florida, White 500, Black 1,000; Georgia, White 7,500, Black 5,000;
                        Alabama, White 10,000, Black 5,000; Tennessee, White 1,000, Black 1,000;
                        Mississippi, White 1,862, Black 2,038; Arkansas, White 1,000, Black 500;
                        Louisiana, White 300, Black 200, making a total of nearly 60,000 persons, in
                        the States named, utterly destitute, and for whom Government aid is asked.
                        This is indeed a sad picture, and especially in a section where want has
                        been hitherto unknown.</p>
                    <p>If the Northern people were in a condition to reason, they could see that it
                        is the reckless legislation of Congress, for the past two years, which has
                        not only produced this destitution, but has kept the South in a state of
                        productive inaction, which must tell ultimately on the national credit. They
                        cannot understand this until it is brought home to their own doors, which
                        the sages of the North see coming in the shape of bankruptcy and
                        repudiation.</p>
                    <p>Be it said to the credit of Congress, however, which has so little on the
                        score of magnanimity and generosity to be credited with that one House has
                        passed an appropriation to relieve this deplorable destitution.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Noting that if the circumstances were similar in the North immediate action
                    would be taken to remedy the situation, the article discusses the contents of
                    the report issued by Gen. O. O. Howard, Commissioner of the Freedmen's Burearu,
                    which provides a breakdown of the number of destitute in the South. The agency
                    supplied aid to nearly 60,000 people, more than half of whom were white.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that George Tucker, the man selected Mayor of Alexandria by the
                    town's Radicals and blacks, confronted the mayor-elect (based upon the returns
                    of whites only) and "demanded possession of the seal of the Corporation and the
                    keys to the public buildings." The request was "politely declined."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Baltimore Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that President Johnson has determined his selections for the
                    commanders of the southern military districts: Gen. Scholfield will command the
                    first, Gen. Sickles the second, Gen. Thomas the third, Gen. Ord the fourth, and
                    Gen. Sheridan the fifth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Smugly notes that a measure in the Massachusetts legislature to request
                    Congress to prohibit disfranchisement on "account of color" was overwhelmingly
                    defeated. "It seems what is sauce for the goose is not sauce for the gander."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>General McCausland</head>
                <origin>Mason County Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Gen. McCausland returned to the South from his self-exile in
                    Mexico last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sumner's Supplementary Plans of Reconstruction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article includes additional criteria to be fulfilled by the South
                    before its representatives will can be re-admitted to Congress. Among the
                    stipulations is a resolution requiring the establishment of public schools for
                    blacks and whites to help reduce the region's abysmal illiteracy rate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Circleville (Ohio) Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After comparing President Johnson to Abraham Lincoln, the article contends
                    that the two men's goals are the same--to keep the South in the Union--yet
                    Lincoln never had to face the prospect of impeachmen as Johnson currently does.
                    "Such," it declares, "is the consistency of Radicalism."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1867.03.15.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells the story of Col. C. C. Clay, a former commander of the local post,
                    who ran into some difficulties while traveling with his entourage in the
                    vicinity of Jackson's River and Cow Pasture. Four of the nine men who
                    accompanied Clay drowned when the boat they were traveling in capsized.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors refute the rumor that Radicals intend to publish a newspaper in
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that a black man named John Randolph was committed to jail last
                    Thursday for stealing a pair of shoes from P. B. Hoge's store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>A. G. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that A. G. L. Van Lear, of Augusta, was among the "graduates in
                    Medicine at the Maryland University."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Langley</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 1, Charles E. Langley died on the Stage between New Market and
                    Woodstock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that A. T. Gilkeson bought P. B. Hoge's home in Gospel Hill for
                    $5,250.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>New Orleans Elections Stopped By General Sheridan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Gen. Sheridan postponed elections scheduled for next week
                    until "the district commander under the new law is appointed, or special
                    instructions received covering the case."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chase</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baer</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 7 John W. Chase and Eliza A. Baer, of Churchville, were married by
                    Rev. George A. Shuey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teabo</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clough</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 5 James W. Teabo and Sallie J. Clough, of Louisa County, were
                    married by Rev. E. Bagby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 12 W. P. Johnson and Elizabeth White were married by Rev. George
                    B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 18 Willie, son of James R. and Sarah E. Norris, died near Midway.
                    He was 7 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 7 S. A. Richardson died at his residence in Staunton. He was 43
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. William P. Tate, 46, died at his residence near Stauton on March 9,
                    1867.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coursey</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 9 Thomas F. Coursey died near Smith's Mill after suffering a few
                    days illness. Coursey was 60.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1867.03.15.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
