<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.03.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/31/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-03-19">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.03.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Democratic State Organization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"...the Black Republican party at the North, whose sectional views are known
                        to be hostile to the South and threaten the dissolution or consolidation of
                        the Union."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rutheford</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discusses the meeting of the Democratic State Central Committee and the
                    need for organization against the Opposition. Article also lists electors to the
                    Convention.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.03.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Letcher and Goggin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goggin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emphasizes that Goggin's speech was a complete failure.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We certainly did misunderstand the "spirit of the remarks" of the Spectator
                        of the 8th, and answered under that misunderstanding, but since he disclaims
                        any offensive construction, we freely retract anything in our article in
                        reply, which may be construed so as to hurt the feelings of the gentlemen of
                        the Spectator. We are heartily glad that our neighbor has at last consented
                        to answer our question in reference to his political position. He "takes
                        pleasure in saying that he has never repudiated, but still adheres to the
                        sentiments which he advocated in 1855." Now, we know that the Spectator was
                        a know nothing journal, and advocated know nothing principles in 1855, and
                        we know that the know nothing principles of '55 were religious intolerance,
                        bitter opposition to foreigners, and secrecy. And the Spectator "still
                        adheres" to those principles. How, then, does that paper support Mr. Goggin,
                        who declares he is not and never was a know nothing? How does that paper get
                        its own consent to support a man who is blarnying the Irish and angling
                        for Irish votes in Richmond, while it entertains the bitterest feelings of
                        opposition to all foreigners in Staunton, and holds the opinion that
                        foreigners of all kinds ought to be deprived altogether of the elective
                        franchise?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules the Spectator's past as a Know Nothing paper.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.19a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. Goggin Repudiates the Convention Which Nominated Him</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goggin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Botts</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Claims that Goggin repudiated a statement made by John Botts and endorsed
                    by the party convention that his party would accept the support of free
                negroes.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. Spurgeon...</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spurgeon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Spurgeon announced his intention to battle slaveowners.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article recounts how an Opposition man boldly went to a writing desk at the
                    Vindicator and wrote, "HURRAH FOR GOGGIN!"</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>District Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The democracy of the fifth magisterial district convened in the 
                        Academy at Waynesboro on Saturday the 12th inst. for the purpose of 
                        selecting delegates to the Harrisonburg Convention.</p>
                    <p> The meeting was organized by appointing Capt. C.G. Miller President 
                        and Col. T.M. Durborarr Secretary.  The President upon taking the Chair, 
                        in a few brief and appropriate remarks stated the object of the 
                        meeting.</p> 
                    <p>On motion--that the Chairman appoint the delegates.  Agreed. That by 
                        the request of the meeting, the Chairman be included in the number of 
                        delegates, when the following persons were selected and also their 
                        alternates.</p>
                    <p> Delegates--Caldwell, Wm.; Durborarr, T.M.Col.; Gallaher, H.L.; 
                        Hansbarger, G.; Kindig, H.W.; Koiner, Eliga; Koiner, Martin;  Koiner, 
                        Absalom; Koiner, C.D.; Koiner, David W.; Koiner, Absalom; Koiner, 
                        Martin; McCune, Samuel Col.; Miller, C.G.; Miller, C.G.Capt.; Stofer, 
                        Jacob;  Terrell, Robt.</p>
                    <p> Alternates--Darnall, H.M.; Koiner, Cyrus; Kindig, Abram; Reeder, 
                        John W.; Koiner, John K.; Koiner, Simeon; Leonard, John; Keeser, John 
                        K.; Kindig, Henry; Reeves, David; Koiner, Gideon; Taylor, John.</p>
                    <p> Absalom Koiner submited [sic] the following resolution: Resolved, 
                        That the Democracy of the Waynesboro district have confidence in the 
                        discretion and wisdom of the district convention to assemble at 
                        Harrisonburg on the 30th inst. and that they will heartily support the 
                        nominee of the Convention, no matter what county he is taken from, 
                        regarding the parties of the district as a common brotherhood.</p>
                    <p> On motion of A. Koiner. that a democratic assocation be formed.  
                        Agreed. On motion, the following persons were chosen as officers: Capt. 
                        C.G. Miller, President, Col. T.M. Durborarr, Sec'ry, H.L. Gallaher, 
                        Treasurer.</p>
                    <p> Resolved, That the association meet on the second Saturday in April, 
                        at Waynesboro, and that Mr. W.S.H. Baylor, the Senatorial Elector, be 
                        invited to address the association. Agreed.</p>
                    <p> Resolved, That the proceedings be published.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>C.G. Miller, Pres't. T.M. Durborarr, Sec'y.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caldwell</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Darnall</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Durborarr</ln>
                        <fn>T.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>H.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hansbarger</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keeser</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindig</ln>
                        <fn>Abram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindig</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindig</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Simeon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Eliga</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Gideon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>C.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leonard</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>C.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>C.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeder</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stofer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn>Robt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Democrats of the fifth magisterial district convened in
                    the Academy at Waynesboro on March 12 to select delegates and alternates to the
                    Harrisonburg Convention. The men listed above were chosen.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.19b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mt. Solon District Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the Democratic citizens of Mount Solon Precinct, 
                        convened on the 12th inst., for the purpose of appointing delegates to 
                        the district Congressional Convention to be held at Harrisonburg on the 
                        30th inst.  The meeting was organized by calling J.J.Cupp, Esq. to the 
                        Chair, and the appointment of James T. Clarke, Secretary.</p>
                    <p> On motion, the sense of the meeting was taken as to the propriety of 
                        holding a Convention to nominate a candidate to represent the ninth 
                        Congressional district in the Congress of the United States.  Whereupon 
                        -</p>
                    <p> It was resolved that it is highly expedient and conducive to the 
                        best interest of the party and promotive of harmony in its ranks to hold 
                        the proposed Convention.</p>
                    <p> It was further resolved that the Chairman appoint --delegates who 
                        with the Chairman and Secretary, shall represent this Precinct in the 
                        proposed Convention.</p>
                    <p> The Chair appointed the following gentlemen delegates, vis:<lb/> H. 
                        Clarkes, Esq., Jacob Shreckhise, Dr. W.R. Blair, T.B. Clarke, S. Paul, 
                        J.C. Rivercomb, J.A. Hamrick, David Miller, S. Samuels, Dr. B.F. 
                        Hopkins, W. Howell, J.M. Campbell, George Messersmith, Henry Philips, 
                        W.D. Clarke, J.F. Hottel, Geo W. Crawford, George Kerricote, G. W. 
                        Bears, J.H. Kirling, George Airey, Mathew Hogshead, Woller Odor, J.T. 
                        Maupin, A. Beaver.</p>
                    <p> On motion, a copy of the above proceedings was ordered to be 
                        forwarded to the office of the Vindicator with a request that they be 
                        published. The meeting then adjourned.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>J. J. CUPP, Ch'n. James T. Clarke, Sec'y T.M. Durborarr, Sec'y.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Airey</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>W.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>James T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>T.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamrick</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Mathew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hottel</ln>
                        <fn>J.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howell</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerricofe</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirling</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>J.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCampbell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Odor</ln>
                        <fn>Woller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rivercomb</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Samuels</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of the Mt. Solon district met on March 12 and chose the men
                    above to be delegates to the Harrisonburg Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.19c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mt. Sidney District Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    
                    <p>Pursuant to public notice, a meeting of the Democratic party was held 
                        at Mount Sidney, March 12th, 1859, for district No. 7, to appoint 
                        delegates to attend a District Convention to be held in the town of 
                        Harrisonburg, Rockingham Co., on the 30th inst., for the purpose of 
                        nominating a candidate for Congress, to fill the place of the Hon. John 
                        Letcher, whereupon Thos. Weisan was called to the Chair, and Dr. Humston 
                        appointed Secretary.  The object of the meeting being explained, the 
                        following resolutions were adopted:</p>
                    <p> Resolved, that the 6 delegates appointed from this district to the 
                        Petersburg Convention, be appointed to the Harrisonburg Convention, and 
                        the Chairman with the assistance of three members of the meeting, 
                        appointed the following delegates:<lb/> Col. Wm. Anderson, Capt. Thos 
                        Burke, Capt. Wm. T. Heiser, Thos P. Wilson, Jas. A. Clinedinst, Wm. 
                        Anderson, Dr. Humston, Sam'l K. Harper, David Vanpelt, Dr. Kubler, John 
                        Rimel, Thos. W. McCue, Wm. T. Sheets.</p>
                    <p> On motion, resolved, that the Vindicator publish the proceedings of 
                        this meeting, and that the democratic papers of the District be 
                        requested to copy. On motion, the meeting adjourned.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>THOS P. 
                    WILSON,Chairman, N. Humston, Secretary</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clinedinst</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Sam'l K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heiser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kubler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rimel</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanpelt</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of the Mt. Sidney district met on March 12 and chose the men
                    above to be delegates to the Harrisonburg Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.19d</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>District Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the democratic party held in Greenville on Saturday, 
                        March 12th, 1859, Ballard Smith was called to the Chair and James W. 
                        Newton appointed Secretary.</p>
                    <p> The following resolutions were unanimously adopted:</p>
                    <p> Resolved. That there be one from each precinct in the district, to 
                        be associated with the Chairman, to recommend ten delegates to the 
                        meeting to represent us in the convention which is to be held in 
                        Harrisonburg on the 30th inst.</p>
                    <p> Resolved. That Wm. Rush, John T. Antrim and Joseph Long, be a 
                        committee to act with the Chairman.</p>
                    <p> The committee then reported the following delegates viz:<lb/> John 
                        Rush, Geo. M. Apple, Wm. A. Abney, J. W. Newton, Joseph Long, Wm. Hess, 
                        C. Davis, A. Gardner, J. B. Scott, J. N. Mitchell.</p>
                    <p> Said report was unanimously adopted by the meeting.</p>
                    <p> Resolved, That the proceedings of the meeting be published in the 
                        Stanton Vindicator.</p>
                    <p> On motion, the meeting then adjourned.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>BALLARD SMITH, Ch'n J. W. Newton,
                    Sec'y</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gardner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rush</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of the Greenville district met on March 12 and chose the men
                    above to be delegates to the Harrisonburg Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.19e</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>District Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Pursuant to previous notice, a meeting of the Democrats of Precinct 
                        No. 2 convened on Saturday the 12th inst., for the purpose of appointing 
                        delegates to meet in Harrisonburg on the 30th of March, 1859, B. F. 
                        Points was appointed Chairman and E. T. Albertson, Secretary.</p>
                    <p> The following named Gentlemen were appointed Delegates to said 
                        convention.<lb/> H. L. Ople, J. W. Bucher, R. W. Stevenson, J. B. 
                        Sherer, R. D. Hill, Jas W. Crawford, M. G. Harman, G. F. Elick, R. H. 
                        Fisher, Alexander Anderson and E. Dooley.</p>
                    <p> On motion, the Chairman and Secretary were added to the list of 
                        delegates.</p>
                    <p> On motion, the following resolution was unanimously adopted:</p> 
                    <p>Resolved, That it is inexpedient in our opinion, to run democratic 
                        candidates for the Legislature in May next, and we pledge our 
                        Magisterial District No. 2 to vote against any such movement.</p>
                    <p> On motion, the thanks of the meeting were tendered to the Chairman 
                        and Secretary.</p>
                    <p> On motion the meeting adjourned.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>B. F. POINTS, Ch'n E. T. 
                    Albertson, Sec'y</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Albertson</ln>
                        <fn>E.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bucher</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dooley</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elick</ln>
                        <fn>G.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>R.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>R.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherer</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>R.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of Precinct No. 2 met on March 12 and chose the men above to
                    be delegates to the Harrisonburg Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.19f</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>District No. 1</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday, March the 12th, the Democracy of Magisterial District 
                        No. 1 met for the purpose of appointing delegates to a convention.</p>
                    <p> On motion of Col. Peyton, Maj. J. B. Watts was called to the Chair, 
                        and Geo. M. Cochran appointed Secretary.</p>
                    <p> On motion of S.B. Brown, a committee of three was appointed to 
                        nominate suitable delegates; carried.</p>
                    <p> Persons named by the Chair, - S. B. Brown, J. C. Marquis, and W. J. 
                        D. Bell.  Before the committee retired, on motion of J. A. Harman, The 
                        Chairman, Secretary and Committee, were appointed delegates, and the 
                        committee ordered to nominate 12 others.  Committee retired, and after a 
                        short absence returned and reported the following names, to wit:<lb/> 
                        Geo. Baylor, F. B. Fuqua, J. O'Hare, J. L. Peyton, S. H. Hilb, J. 
                        Politz, D. S. Bear, A. W. Harman, J. A. Harman, D. T. Doom, W. S. 
                        Baylor, John Daily.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>D.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W.J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>S.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Daily</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>D.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuqua</ln>
                        <fn>F.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilb</ln>
                        <fn>S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hare</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>J.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pollitz</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of Magisterial District No. 1 met on March 12 and chose the
                    men above to be delegates to the Harrisonburg Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.19g</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.03.19.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lohr</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 2, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>X.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Polly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 14, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauver</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 10, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seeley</ln>
                        <fn>Horace</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on March 13.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reubush</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Reubush, only son of John Reubush, Jr., died on March 9 at age
                8.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wartmann</ln>
                        <fn>Ella Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wartmann</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wartmann</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ella Wartmann died on March 17 at age 2.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and markets</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.03.19.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
