<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'>-->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.07.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/1/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-07-08">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.08.01">
            <pageNote>International news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Fourth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    
                    <p>Last Monday was a stirring day in Staunton.  What with the beating of 
                        drums, the waving of plumes, the flashing of bayonets, and the flying of 
                        colors, the good old town became so bewildered and unsettled that we 
                        verily believe it will take at least a month for it to regain its 
                        original natural and dignified appearance.  The companies present were 
                        the Monticello Guard, a fine looking, well-uniformed and well-drilled 
                        company, commanded by Capt. Mallory, of Charlottesville;  the 
                        Continental Morgan Guard, of Winchester, who, uniformed as the heroes of 
                        '76, and commanded by Major Washington--a near relative of the immortal 
                        Father of his country-- irresistibly carried the mind back to those days 
                        so dear to every American heart-- those times which tried men's souls;  
                        the Mountain Guard, commanded by Col. Bushong, from Spring Hill, in this 
                        county, as fine looking a body of men as we ever saw, but lately 
                        organized and consequently but imperfectly drilled;  the uniformed 
                        officers of the militia of the county, and last, but not least, the West 
                        Augusta Guard, who well sustained the military reputation of Staunton.  
                        There were also several fine bands present on the occasion, whose 
                        excellent music added greatly to the attractions of the day.</p>
                    <p> The military and citizens, after parading the principal streets of 
                        the town, adjourned over to the Institution grounds, adjoining the 
                        premises of Mr. H. J. Gray, who had kindly offered the use of his yard 
                        for the purposes of the pic-nic.  A speech was here delivered by Mr. 
                        Sheffey, the orator of the day, which we did not hear, but which is 
                        spoken of in terms of eulogy.  The Declaration of Independence was then 
                        read for the benefit of all patriots with an insane desire to be bored, 
                        and the crowd passed to Mr. Gray's yard, where an immense amount of 
                        eating and drinking was done, and speeches delivered by Maj. Washington, 
                        Col. Terrill, Gen. Harman, Mayor Trout, Capt. Harper, John D. Imboden, 
                        Esq., James Cochran, Esq., Capt. Mallory, Lieut. Wertembaker, and 
                        others, in response to sentiments.</p>
                    <p>We were present at but small part of the celebration, and could not, if 
                    we had space, give a detailed account of the proceedings.  From all we 
                    could see and hear, what with the eating, drinking, fighting, shouting, 
                    speechifying, and playing the devil generally, the day passed off to the 
                    excessive delight and satisfaction of all concerned, except some few 
                    poor devils with bunged eyes and skinned faces, who, we must confess, 
                    seemed prepared to "pitch into" the first fellow, who, in the excessive 
                    kindness of his heart, might wish him "many returns of the same happy 
                    day."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mallory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dushong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>H.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertembaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article praises the patriotic fourth of July services in Staunton.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.8a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Commencement of the Wesleyan Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Institute Staunton Va. The annual commencement exercises of this 
                        flourishing institution came off the last week, in the presence of a 
                        large number, of its friends.  It was gratifying to the excellent 
                        Principal and his co-laborers to see such a large number of strangers 
                        present, especially such a large delegation of Ministers, representing 
                        part of Maryland and a large extent of our Virginia Territory.--This 
                        unusual attendance and accompanying enthusiasm was properly construed as 
                        a harbinger of good to the institution, and will give a new impulse to 
                        ministerial effort in its behalf, and a fresh incentive to the 
                        indomitable Principal whose untiring energy has made the last year, the 
                        most successful, financial period in its history, its number of pupils 
                        72, the largest number that has ever attended, except one year, and its 
                        standard of scholarships second to that of no other Female School in the 
                        State.  The incipient exercise pertaining to this commencement was a 
                        baccalaureate  sermon by Rev.. J. A. McCauley, of Fredericksburg 
                        preached on Sunday June, 26 before a very large and highly appreciated 
                        assembly.  It was based upon John, Chap iv. verse 27th, "And upon this 
                        came his disciples and marvelled that he talked with the woman."  The 
                        space allotted to this communication forbids a critical review by this 
                        chaste and beautiful sermon, yet to express the general sentiment of an 
                        intelligent audience I must say that his theme, "Christianity and Woman" 
                        was treated in a masterly style and abounded in numerous and sparking 
                        gems of thought, and glowing strains of genuine and impassioned 
                        eloquence.  He closed with a fervid appeal in behalf of female 
                        education, and the Wesleyan Female Institute, alluded in feeling terms 
                        to his former connection with the Institute, and spoke with moving 
                        pathos as he referred to some of the bright flowers cultivated in this 
                        nursery of piety and learning, who now transplanted in a celestial world 
                        will ever bloom and blossom in immortal brightness.</p> 
                    <p>On Monday the examination commenced under the supervision of the 
                        examining committee consisting of Rev. O.P. Wirgman, J. N. Davis and J. 
                        W. Wolf. It was conducted with great fairness, no special parts having 
                        been selected with a view to display;  indeed the common sentiment of 
                        the committee and spectators was that it was entirely too rigid, yet, it 
                        but reflected the more credit upon the young ladies who get along with 
                        surprising facility, evincing a thorough mode of instruction, which 
                        drilled them in studying principles rather than skimming over and 
                        "cramming" a few lending points.  The young ladies excelled in the very 
                        department where we ordinarily expect more or less failures;  the 
                        department of Mathematics.  Having attended the examinations and 
                        commencements of several literary institutions, I must do the young 
                        ladies, and the [text missing] principal, the justice to say that I 
                        never saw so rigid an examination in Geometry and Conic sections, and 
                        never saw any class of pupils acquit themselves with more facility and 
                        credit.  In the varied departments all the classes did well and to 
                        particularize, might seem to indicate undue partiality, yet I must speak 
                        in terms of the highest commendation of the graduating class, and the 
                        two talented sisters who figured very conspicuously and with great honor 
                        to themselves in their respective classes.  The examination closed on 
                        Wednesday, and that evening at 8 o'clock the young ladies and their 
                        friends repaired to the Baptist Church, where they were entertained by a 
                        Literary Address delivered by Rev. B. F. Brooke, D. D., of 
                        Baltimore.</p>
                    <p>The regular commencement exercises closed on Thursday 
                            evening before an overflowing and intelligent auditory.  The department 
                            of music had a good representation, who did themselves and their 
                            indefatigable instructor, Prof. Turner, great credit, and who enlivened 
                            the occasion by interspersing the exercises with delightful and 
                            thrilling strains of vocal and instrumental music.  The programme for 
                            Thursday evening was made up of English and Latin Salutatory, reading of 
                            essays, dialogues, conferring degrees, and valedictory.  The English 
                            Salutatory was read by Miss Amanda E. Deleplane, of Kingsley, Va., the 
                            "Salutatio in lingua latina" by Miss Mattie E. Arbogast, of Lexington, 
                            Mo., and Valedictory by Miss Lizzie Ruse, of Loudoun co., Va.  These 
                            young ladies received the degrees, the 1st honor being awarded to Miss 
                            Mattie E. Arbogast for excellence in Latin and French, and the other 
                            graduates sharing equally in honor.  This graduating trio leaves the 
                            institution wreathed in rosy chaplets wrought by diligence and laudable 
                            emulation, and if their future career be estimated by their collegiate 
                            standing, they will ever reflect a bright halo to linger around and 
                            bless the portals of their Alma Mater.  The various pieces of original 
                            composition evinced a high degree of belles lettres cultivation, and the 
                            dialogues were well conceived and readily expressed.  the only criticism 
                            to be made upon this part of the exercises was the want of vocal power 
                            in most of the young ladies.  Very often it was difficult to hear in 
                            remote parts of the room, yet this applies to all schools, and arises, 
                            doubtless, from fright conjoined with natural difference.  In this 
                            respect, Miss Sallie Veitch is a good model, and we trust her manner 
                            will be imitated the next commencement.</p>
                    <p> In conclusion--this institution occupies at present a more permanent 
                        basis than ever, is more successful than ever, promises more than 
                        before, and consequently inspires its friends with renewed hope, and 
                        will excite all to renewed effort.  It especially commends itself to the 
                        Ministers, whose institution it is, and to whose fostering care it looks 
                        for continued support with the same solicitude and filial confidence 
                        that marks the child-like trust daily exemplified around the altars and 
                        hearthstones of their own household.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>FREUND.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingman</ln>
                        <fn>O.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The commencement of the Wesleyan Female Institute was grand.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.8b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Federal Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brockenbrough</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Special term of the Federal Court for the Western District commenced last
                    Wednesday.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are gratified to learn that the ladies of the M. E. Church realized the handsome sum of $466, 
                        at their late Fair.  Much credit is due them for their efforts in aiding in the erection of 
                        their new house of worship.  We have been requested by the ladies to return their thanks to the 
                        Charlottesville Band, for the delightful music they discoursed on the occasion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the M.E. Church raised $466 at their Fair.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.8c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Wise's Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gov.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article calls attention to and praises a letter written by Gov. Wise on the
                    question of the rights of naturalized citizens.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Pennsylvania Democracy</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary>"The Democracy should accept and work with the generous offers of
                    support from its friends up north."</commentary>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gov.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiekman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article comments that the Pennsylvania Democracy will support legislation
                    that protects the rights of slaveholders.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Congressional Protection versus Squatter Sovereignty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses disbelief that there is even a question about whether or not
                    slavery in the territories should be protected by Congress.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Election Returns</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is now official that Letcher has won the election.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Hon. Edward Everett's wife died last Saturday.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cass</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>Max L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Henry Wise to Mayer says that naturalization is a pact between
                    the United States and the foreigner: allegiance for protection.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>List of letters remaining at the Staunton post office.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.08.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oder</ln>
                        <fn>Kate S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on June 23, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutcheson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutcheson</ln>
                        <fn>Mildred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutcheson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Hutcheson died at the age of 20 on May 20, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckinridge</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Johnson died on June 24 at age 83.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 7, 1859, the infant William Cowan died.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.08.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
