<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'>-->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.09.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/1/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-09-02">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.02.01">
            <pageNote>Most of front page filled with story entitled "The Judge's
            Daughter."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>New Alum Springs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harouff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harouff sent a bottle of Alum spring water from Bull Pasture road that is
                    very tasty.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Paper</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator says that from now on it will publish stories that will be
                    more pleasing to the general reader than boring political articles.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Laying of Corner Stone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Masonic Fraternity will lay the cornerstone of the new M.E. Church on
                    September 16.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We admit the following communication, signed "Parnassus," from a highly
                        respectable and intelligent source, not with a view of entering the ring,
                        but, on the contrary, with a solemn pretext, that while we will take pride
                        in making our paper the vehicle of all moral and religious instruction, we
                        can never permit it to approach the field of sectarian controversy. Our
                        labor will rather be to pour oil on the waves of excitement, or to make some
                        suggestions to both parties which may tend to conciliation and peace. We
                        regret that our usually prudent and right- thinking friends of the
                        "Spectator" should, from what we must with great deference consider a
                        mistaken, though we doubt not an honest view, of editorial responsibility,
                        have admitted into their columns the fire-brand which has stirred this
                        strife. If the very objectionable words contained in the communication to
                        that paper, signed "Conservator," had been spoken of an individual and
                        printed, there can be no doubt that the editors would have incurred all the
                        legal responsibility of a prosecution and suit for libel; and the question
                        is, whether, in the eye of natural justice, the responsibility is not
                        infinitely greater, when they are addressed to the whole community. The
                        charge that a sect of professing Christians, in obedience to an ancient and
                        loved mode of assembling themselves together, "ignore the Sabbath," "violate
                        the peace and good order of society," by permitting or giving occasion for
                        "drunkenness, profanity, huckstering, fighting, lewdness, and almost every
                        crime," is a very grave one, and the assailed party, though without legal
                        remedy, and unwilling to violate the laws of peace by a call for personal
                        satisfaction, surely has a right to place the responsibility somewhere--upon
                        some visible agent in the commission of the wrong. It may be asked, then,
                        should the wickedness of communities go unwhipped? By no means. The
                        interests of society may often require their chastisement at the hands of an
                        independent press. Nor should a press properly conducted shrink from the
                        performance of such a duty when the sacred cause of virtue and religion
                        requires. But we cannot concede that the performance of so high a duty
                        should be covered under the shield of anonymous irresponsibility. The editor
                        is bound, before he admits wholesale accusation into his columns, to be
                        satisfied, personally, of its truth, and of the high public necessity for
                        its correction or reform. Being so satisfied, it is his duty to assume the
                        responsibility, but until so satisfied, he should reject such
                        communications, come from whatever quarter they may. Now, from all our
                        brothers of the "Spectator" have said, we are confident that they have no
                        such opinion of the Methodist Episcopalians, as would induce them to adopt
                        as their own the severe strictures of "Conservator," and that the article
                        has been admitted into their columns under what we consider a mistaken view
                        of editorial duty, which we hope they will reconsider, as it is a very
                        important question for the press. To our friends of the Methodist Church, we
                        would suggest that they can well afford to overlook and forgive the error.
                        Their acknowledged and exemplary piety-- their extended usefulness as the
                        glorious pioneers of the Christian Church--will blunt the shaft of
                        accusation, and make it fall harmlessly at their feet, while the God- like
                        virtues of chastity and love make it a sweet duty to forgive trespasses. Let
                        bygones then be bygones. Messrs. Editors of Vindicator:--We have been no
                        little surprised at the supercilious pride and arrogance with which the
                        editor of the Staunton Spectator attempts to conceal the faux pas of which
                        he plainly has been guilty. See with what complacency the editor of so
                        widely circulated a sheet as the Spectator wraps himself and lies down to
                        sleep in the pleasant delusion that all wrong things published or said, all
                        immoral things, whatever be their tendencies, may be safely laid aside on
                        the shoulders of correspondents. See with what effrontery he contends that
                        the medium through which such deleterious writings come, shall be pure and
                        stainless as the new-fallen snow. See with what calmness and dignity he
                        steps aside to let the rebuke of the justly offended fall to the
                        ground.--And does he really know no better than to pretend that a sheet is
                        not morally responsible for, and identified with, all the ideas, whether for
                        good or evil, it circulates to the world? He needn't be alarmed about the
                        word responsible. We use it in no fighting sense, but we repeat that any
                        editor is morally responsible for the general tone and tenor of the
                        publication of which he has control; if not, his chair is only a dunce's
                        stool, and our worthy friend should be adorned with a cap and bells. He is a
                        puppet in the hands of some wire puller behind the scenes. Oh! blush even to
                        intimate that the press, the great lever by which the world is moved, has
                        sunk so low as to have lost all self-respect, all judgement of right and
                        wrong, and has become the mere cat's paw of some artful demagogue. But we
                        are glad to be able to give the editor of the Spectator credit for more
                        intellect than his present predicament would indicate.--How long has it been
                        since this same loud-mouthed defender of the privileges of the press refused
                        to copy an article from another paper, although assured of the possession of
                        the name of the author by that editor? And although that editor offered to
                        hold himself responsible until the real name should be produced. Then,
                        "mirabile dictu," we heard the startling fact that his sheet would be
                        identifying itself with the article--would be held responsible by the public
                        for its sentiments; but these changes are readily made by a man who in one
                        year can denounce catholicism, and in the next preach up the doctrine of the
                        right of freedom of worship. By the publication of such anonymous
                        communications, are you not aware that you subject a great many innocent men
                        to the suspicion of their authorship? Why, how is the community to know that
                        you yourself are not the writer, or at least the instigator, of such
                        slanderous trash? You offer the writer's name to any one who wishes personal
                        redress! This is nonsense.--No one feels justified in making a personal
                        affair of a communication which is insulting to a whole sect. We dread not
                        the influence of its sentiments in the least, but we are unwilling to assist
                        any sheet which is filled with such contemptible slurs against a form of
                        worship which is identified with one particular denomination. This is what
                        we mean by holding the editor responsible. You affect great superiority of
                        editorial etiquette, &amp;c., over him who has been forced thus publicly to
                        defend his rights. Do you not think such expressions as "good fellow," "hold
                        on to your belt," "puerile," and the general style of your reply, unworthy
                        of an editor to a preacher of the gospel. Are they not silly attempts on
                        your part to appear humorous, supercilious, in fact contemptuous. Beware, my
                        dear sir, how you trifle with Methodist Camp-meetings and Methodist
                        preachers. Your publishing the communication of "Conservator" was
                        objectionable--your reply to the Rev. Mr. Tebbs was almost insulting. [You
                        admit that this denomination has some power; they may learn where to bestow
                        their patronage.] I understand that you remarked upon the first reading of
                        the Reverend gentleman's letter, that you felt indignant, but upon a second,
                        your wrath passed away, and you determined to make it a subject of
                        merriment. If you had perceived that it was studendum non legendum, and
                        exerted yourself to a third perusal, you might have discovered its "logical
                        cogency," which would have rendered this exposition unnecessary.
                    .</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>PARNASSUS</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator criticizes the Spectator for publishing an anonymous letter
                    (written by "Conservator") that accused the Methodist Church of behavior
                    unfitting for Christians. It also reprints a letter written by "Parnassus" that
                    criticizes "Conservator."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvsept59.html#9.2a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Messrs. Editors of Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Oh! blush even to intimate that the press, the great lever by which the
                        world is moved, has sunk so low as to have lost all self-respect, all
                        judgment of right and wrong, and has become the mere cat's paw of some
                        artful demagogue."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter criticizes the Spectator's editors for failing to be morally
                    responsible for what is written in their paper.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The County Court closed its sitting last Thursday.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Good Sale</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argonbright</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Argonbright auctioned off her property to Sellers at $45 per
                acre.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Corns and Deformities of the Feet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Dr. Schultz, who has done such good service to the citizens of Staunton
                        during the past week, has decided to remain here a few days longer. Any one
                        who yet doubts his ability to perform all he promises, would do well to
                        advise with the following gentlemen: C. R. Mason, G. C. Yeakle, To. Lebach,
                        J. B. Watts, B. W. Bagby, and Dr. B. B. Donaghe.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mases</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeakle</ln>
                        <fn>G.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lebach</ln>
                        <fn>To.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>B.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Schultz has served Staunton citizens with feet problems so well that he
                    will stay a few days longer.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvsept59.html#9.2b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Alleghany High School</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleghany High School is just as good as its east coast sister
                school.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Special Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bramham</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The tract of land advertised by Bramham is where all the editors of the
                    Vindicator were born and bred.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Important Decision</head>
                <origin>The Spectator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We understand that the Court of Appeals have unanimously affirmed the
                        judgement of the Circuit Court of this county in the case of "Saner vs. the
                        Central Railroad Company."--At the November term, 1856, of the Circuit Court
                        of Augusta, Jacob Sanger recovered a verdict of $6,000 damages for injuries
                        received by the plaintiff whilst a passenger on the cars of the defendant.--
                        The cars were thrown off the track by a large stone left lying near the
                        rails by the carelessness of some hands in the employment of the
                        contractors, who were "balasting" the road, and the plaintiff had his leg
                        broken. At the trial the Company contended that they were not responsible
                        for the acts of the hands in the employment of their Contractors. The Judge
                        (Thompson) held that they were, and on this point the case went up. This is
                        the first case in Virginia settling the extent of the liability of Railroad
                        Companies as passenger carriers, and it holds them up to the most rigorous
                        responsibility. The judgement amounts to over $7,000 at this time, exclusive
                        of counsel fees paid by the Company. Counsel for Sanger, John B. Baldwin and
                        J. D. Imboden, and for the Company, T. J. Michie, A. H. H. Stuart and James
                        Lyons, Esqs.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Spectator</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>T.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lyons</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Court of Appeals has affirmed the decision of the Circuit Court of this
                    county in the case of Sanger v. Central Railroad Co. Sanger wins damages for
                    having his leg broken when the train went off the tracks.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvsept59.html#9.2c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mr. Botts and the Presidency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Botts</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rives</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goggin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crittenden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bates</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Because of the dedication of his allies, Botts's bid for the presidency
                    should be taken seriously. Staunton better get moving soon and declare its
                    support of Stuart.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>International and national news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.02.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>X.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>East</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 25, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Statton</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caracofe</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 21, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brook</ln>
                        <fn>G.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Cynthia Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on August 18, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburn</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Fishburn died in Waynesboro on August 15 at age of two.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>A.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An infant child of the Greiners died in Deerfield on August 10.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhize</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhize</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Shreckhize died on August 27 on the Long Glade. She was a member of
                    the Presbyterian Church.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.02.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
