<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'>-->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.03.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/31/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-03-05">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.03.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Lynch Law Administered by Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At Lynnville Oregon county, Ill., a few days ago, a shoemaker 
                        named Ozias G. Elliot was arrested on the charge of having murdered his wife, whose body was 
                        found buried under mysterious circumstances, and whom he had always greatly ill-treated.--While 
                        the coroner's jury were holding an inquest on the body, the prisoner was attacked in the hotel, 
                        where he was in custody, by a number of infuriated women, who tore out his hair and handled him 
                        so roughly that his life was in danger.  He was then locked up in an upper room by the officers, 
                        to keep him from the fury of the women, and while there he jumped out of the window and escaped.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In Oregon a man who was arrested for murdering his wife was attacked by
                    women hoping to avenge his wife's death.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.5a</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Much of right-hand column illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.03.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Convention Meeting on Monday Last--The Free Fight Renewed by the Democracy of
                    Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats of the County met on the first day of March court and decided
                    to hold a convention in Harrisonburg to elect a man to Congress. Article
                    generally praises the Democracy and criticizes the Opposition; much is
                    illegible.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Different Gentlemen Who Are Supposed To Be In Nomination for Governor by the
                    Opposition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goggin</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article makes fun of Opposition candidate's name and different ways of
                    spelling it.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Organize! Organize!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We entreat our friends in the country to commence actively and immediately the work of 
                        organization throughout the county.  If the friends of democracy and the Union go about the work 
                        with their whole soul (as we verily believe they will,) we have a lively hope and a distinct 
                        presentiment that old federal Augusta will yet be redeemed from Know-Nothing rule, and take its 
                        place among the counties of the old Dominion as a friend of liberty and State rights.  We have 
                        very little doubt if we of the democracy do our whole duty, with a statesman so dear to his own 
                        party, and so respected and honored by his opponents, we will be able to carry a vote vastly 
                        superior to any ever polled in this old county.  We will here state that Saturday, the 12th 
                        inst. was suggested by the central committee for holding meetings throughout the county, to 
                        appoint delegates to the District Convention, because it was thought very advisable by them, to 
                        have all these meetings on the same day so that a fair and impartial delegation may be 
                        appointed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article entreats Democrats to organize. The party will hold meetings
                    throughout the county on March 12 for the purpose of appointing delegates to the
                    District Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.5c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our thanks are due...</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our thanks are due the Rev. Geo. B. Taylor of this place, for a copy of his prize essay on 
                        Sunday Schools, for which the premium of $50 was awarded by a committee.  We have, not as yet, 
                        read the work, but the reputation and ability of the author are sufficient ground for us to 
                        recommend it to the public as a first rate practical work.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thanks Taylor for his prize essay on Sunday Schools. Even though the
                    committee has not read his piece, the man's reputation is such that it will
                    reward him a minimum of $50.00 for what it is sure is a fine work.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.5b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fires</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kemper</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Kemper's barn burned down with eight horses and mules, two cows, and three
                    buggies; damage was estimated at $2000.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fires</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>T.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michie's stable, on Simpson's lot, was burned down last Saturday.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fires</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Monday, a coal fire was discovered at Grove's carpentry shop but was put
                    out before damage could be done.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>What Does it Mean?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator has declined to inform the Vindicator about what it means by
                    "American." Article criticizes the Spectator for its dodging of the
                issue.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Court Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Last Monday was Court Day; many Democrats were present.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting in Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Pursuant to a notice published some time previous in the Vindicator, 
                        the Democrats of Augusta assembled inthe Court House on Monday for the 
                        purpose of deciding whether there was a majority of the Democrats in the 
                        county in favor of holding a Convention for the purpose of nominating a 
                        candidate to represent this District in Congress.</p>
                    <p> On motion, Benj. Crawford, Esq. was called to the chair, and H.B. 
                        Michie, and J.M, Crank, appointed Secretaries.</p>
                    <p> Jacob Baylor, Esq., moved that the Chair appoint seventy-five 
                        delegates to attend a Convention, to be held the 30th of March, in the 
                        town of Harrisonburg, and requested the Chairman at the same time to 
                        appoint gentlemen whose personal predilections were not known to 
                        him.</p>
                    <p> John Harman Esq., opposed this motion on the ground that it was 
                        unfair to exclude democrats merely because there opinions had been 
                        formed, and moved as a substitute that if a Convention be held, that all 
                        the democrats of Augusta be appointed delegates.</p>
                    <p> Mr. Koiner presented the following resolution, to wit:</p>
                    <p> Resolved--That the Democrats of Augusta are in favor of holding a 
                        Convention for the purpose of nominating a candidate for Congress.</p>
                    <p> Mr. Geo. M. Cochran, Jr., presented the following amendment, to 
                        wit:</p>
                    <p> Resolved--That the Democratic party of Augusta will cordially agree 
                        to a district convention to nominate a candidate for Congress, provided 
                        that all the counties of the district unite with us in convention.</p>
                    <p> Capt. Reuben D. Hill spoke in opposition to a Convention, and was 
                        followed by Absalom Koiner, Wm. S.H. Baylor, Jacob Baylor, in favor of 
                        it.</p>
                    <p> The vote being taken on Mr. Cochran's amendment, it was lost by a 
                        large majority.</p>
                    <p> Mr. Koiner's resolution, "whether or no there shall be a convention: 
                        was then put to the house and was decided in favor of a convention by a 
                        triumphant majority.</p>
                    <p> Mr. Koiner then offered the following resolution, which was 
                        unanimously adopted:<lb/> Resolved--That 100 Delegates be appointed from 
                        the County of Augusta to the District Convention, proposed to be held at 
                        Harrisonburg on the 30th of March next;--that said, delegation be 
                        appointed by the Democracy of several magisterial districts, in meetings 
                        to be held in each district;--that the number of delegates from each 
                        district, shall be in proportion to the democratic vote cast by each 
                        district in the last Presidential election;--and that the Chariman and 
                        the Secretaries of this meeting are appointed a committee to make the 
                        apportionment, and publish the result of the information of the district 
                        meetings.</p>
                    <p> On motion of Absalom Koiner, Esq., resolved that the Chairman of the 
                        meeting be empowered to apoint thirteen active and energetic democrats 
                        as a Central Committee for the purpose of organizing the party for 
                        active service during the present canvass.  The Chair appointed the 
                        following gentlemen:</p>
                    <p> Col. George Baylor, R.G. Bickell, H.B. Michie, J.M. Crank, Wm. S.H. 
                        Baylor, John A. Harman, David Bucker, R.H. Fisher, George M. Cochran, 
                        Jr., H.L. Opie, Sam'l B. Brown, Wm. A. Burke, Wm. A. Abney.</p>
                    <p> On motion, the meeting adjourned sine die.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Benj. Crawford, Chairman. J.M. Crank, H.B. Michie, Secretaries</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickell</ln>
                        <fn>R.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bucker</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crank</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>P.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>H.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Democratic meeting in Augusta decided to send 100 delegates from Augusta
                    County to the District convention in Harrisonburg on the 30th. The article is
                    followed by a list of how many delegates came from each city (Staunton heads the
                    list with 11).</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar59.html#3.5d</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>District Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An announcement from several Democrats calls for a meeting of the First
                    Magisterial District in Staunton on March 12 at the Court House to nominate
                    delegates to the proposed District Congressional Convention.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>District Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announcement for meeting of Democrats of Second District to meet in
                    Staunton March 12 to appoint delegates to District Convention.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>List of letters left at Staunton post office; congressional news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.03.05.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bright</ln>
                        <fn>Michael A.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Bright, of Lewisburg, married Martha Guy on February 21,
                1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 20, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sampson</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graves</ln>
                        <fn>Portersfield</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crone</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Crone, of Richmond, married Mr. Grayer, of Staunton, on February 17,
                    1859 in Washington, D.C.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brower</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wine</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wenger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wenger</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 22, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>E. Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendron</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cochran died on February 15, 1859, in Staunton.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.03.05.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, court news, and announcements for Congress</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
