<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.07.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/1/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-07-15">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.15.01">
            <pageNote>An article on Napoleon Bonaparte</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Charleston Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Speculates how the Democratic convention will decide the issue of slave
                    expansion into the territories; it appears northern Democrats under Douglas want
                    non-intervention of Congress on this issue.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Market House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our neighbor of the Spectator suggest the idea of converting the Market House, which he contends 
                        has turned out a humbug and nuisance, into a large and commodious Town Hall.  It will be 
                        remembered by our readers that we suggested at the time of the building of the Market House the 
                        feasibility of erecting above it such a hall, but, our worthy city Fathers thought differently, 
                        and so the enterprise fell through, or rather never commenced.  We fully concur with the 
                        Spectator that such a hall is an absolute necessity, but that it would be expedient to convert 
                        the Market House into a Hall, we doubt.  That the Market at present is an unutterable humbug and 
                        nuisance, and that something is wrong somewhere, and some body is responsible we don't deny, but 
                        there is as little doubt that a good market is infinitely to be desired, and can be established 
                        in our town, with proper management.  This could be done if the proper authorities would stir 
                        themselves to have the laws carried into force, and also to enact various other ordinances, 
                        which could be enumerated, and which would be to advantage.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator disagrees with the Spectator that the Market House should be
                    turned into a Town Hall, although the Vindicator agrees that a Town Hall needs
                    to be built.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.15a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Vote in the Congressional District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goggin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Letcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>There was an error in the tally of votes in Rockbridge: 20 votes were
                    discovered against Skinner. Article criticizes Harris for refusing to
                    participate in a convention. Then it tallies particular configurations of votes
                    in each county: for Augusta, Letcher and Skinner received together 1289 votes;
                    Letcher and Harris 89; Goggin and Harris 1126; and Goggin and Skinner
                564.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Crops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The wheat crop seems fine.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Springs Travel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Travel to the Springs already appears heavy.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.15b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Views of Mr. Stephens of Georgia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The great principle to be carried out is expansion--the right of the people
                        of the South to go to the Territories with their slave property--protected
                        by this Constitution, on a platform of equal rights."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the rights of southerners to bring slave property to the
                    territories.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pirce</ln>
                        <fn>G.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company would like to thank Aetna Insurance for a $20
                    donation.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Volunteer Toasts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mallory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article prints the toasts of the visiting military companies.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Henry Wise regrets that he can't attend the festivities on the
                    4th at the Military Festival in Staunton.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Staunton Spectator</origin>
                <commentary>"The following suggestion we clip from the Spectator, which we take
                    pleasure in giving all the publicity which our circulation affords. We hope the
                    farmers of Augusta will act on the suggestion."</commentary>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following suggestions we clip from the Spectator, which we take pleasure in giving all the 
                        publicity which our circulation affords.  We hope the farmers of Augusta will act on the 
                        suggestion: "Let our citizens when they send their flour, hay, whiskey, cattle, &amp;c., to market, 
                        require their Commission Merchants to send them checks on the Richmond Banks in payment.  Then 
                        let our citizens hand these checks to the Staunton Banks.  This will make the Staunton Banks 
                        creditors of the Richmond Banks, and when the brokers come up with Staunton notes for 
                        redemption, our banks, instead of paying out gold and silver can redeem their notes with checks 
                        on Richmond Banks.  The balance of trade is several hundred thousand dollars in favor of Augusta 
                        against Richmond every year, and yet Richmond is always drawing specie from the Augusta Banks.  
                        If our farmers and graziers, &amp;c., will only adopt our suggestion the process will be reversed.  
                        We cannot only meet all demands on us by checks on Richmond, but, if necessary, we can draw 
                        large balances in species from Richmond.  It is obvious that this would greatly strengthen our 
                        banks and give activity to business by enabling our banks to extend greater facilities to 
                        enterprising men.  Try the experiment and we will soon witness the beneficial results.  The 
                        visits of the brokers will be stopped--the war on the interior banks will cease--and the 
                        metropolitan bank will be taught a lesson of courtesy to the country banks.  We shall hear no 
                        more of inability to accommodate the public with reasonable loans."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator tells farmers to require their Commission Merchants to send them
                    checks on Richmond banks for their payments. Then let Staunton citizens hand
                    these to Staunton banks. This would greatly strengthen the Staunton banks and
                    make more credit available to local merchants.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.15c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Celebration of the 4th at Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        After the picnic was over the Company was called to order by Gen. Harman.  N. K. Trout was 
                        appointed to preside, assisted by Major Washington, Capt's Harper, Mallory, Bushong, and Baylor. 
                        The following regular toasts were drunk: 1st.  4th of July--A day which history has inscribed 
                        in her annals with a pencil of light.  May its annual return show that the spirit of liberty 
                        born in 1776 will never die. 2nd.  George Washington--Virginia the home of his birth--America 
                        the theatre of his civil and military exploits, the world the habitation of his fame. After this 
                        toast was drunk, in silence, the people desiring to see and hear the near kinsman of George 
                        Washington, Major Washington was loudly called for and responded in appropriate terms. 3rd.  Our 
                        ancestors of the revolution.--Immortal for their heroic deeds in the time which tried men's 
                        souls--may their descendants ever gratefully cherish in their hearts their memory, and live 
                        worthy of such progenitors. 4th.  The few survivors of the war of the Revolution--like the 
                        Sibylline leaves they become dearer to our souls as 
                        their numbers grow less.-- The President remarked that there was no old soldier present, but 
                        this morning a near kinsman of Col. Charles Porterfield, who fell fighting at Camden, had handed 
                        him the journal kept by that gallant officer in that trying time.  "I hold it in my hand it is a 
                        venerable looking record--among other matters frequently noted in it is his intimacy with, and 
                        good opinion of Gen. Morgan, in honor of whom the handsome company, now our guests, have named 
                        themselves "the Morgan Continental Guards." Major Washington, Commander of the Morgan 
                        Continental Guards, proposed Col. Charles Porterfield.  He entered the war a private in Capt. 
                        Daniel Morgan's company of volunteers from Frederick County, in 1775--he fell at Camden in 
                        August 1780, all honor to his memory and justice from his country. 5th.  The Constitution of the 
                        United States, the aegis of our liberty--may it never be perverted into an engine for its destruction. 
                        6th.  The President of the United States. 
                        7th.  The Senate of the U. S.--When danger menaces the Nation, we look to the wisdom and 
                        conservatism of the Senate for its salvation. 8th.  The People--May they ever observe the 
                        distinction between liberty restrained by law, and liberty destructive of law. 9th.  The 
                        Union.--May the bonds which make our nation of States one of the greatest of Governments never 
                        be weakened by an internal feud.  Opposition from without will but strengthen them. 10th.  The 
                        Volunteer Citizen Soldiery.--In the hour of peril looking to the post of danger as the post of 
                        honor, on the field of battle show themselves invincible. Responded to by Capt. Mallory of 
                        Monticello Guards. 11th.  The Army and Navy of the United States.--The former when directed by 
                        Military skill, knows no such word as defeat the latter the right-arm of our defence and the 
                        hand maid of our Commerce. 12th.  The State of Virginia.  Let those who do not love her cavil as 
                        they please, we are not ashamed of such a mother. 13th.  The Ladies.--God bless them!--The last 
                        of our regular toasts but the first in our hearts--then "let the toast be dear woman." Responded 
                        to by Col. Terrell. The President read the following letter from his excellency, Gov. Wise: 
                        RICHMOND Va.  June 30th, 1859. Gentlemen:--Being a Visitor of William and Mary College I am 
                        compelled to attend to its affairs on the 4th prox. at a meeting of its Board.  This will 
                        prevent me from attending your Military festival, at Staunton.  I give you:--The American Union: 
                        Liberty to all--Equality to all--Protection to all persons and all property everywhere, at home 
                        and abroad! Yours truly, HENRY A. WISE. VOLUNTEER TOASTS The visiting military 
                        companies.--Welcome citizen soldiers--our hearts and our hands are open to receive you--you have 
                        shown yourselves to be honorable and worthy guests, we are sure you will make the best soldiers. 
                        Responded to by Maj. Washington and Capt. Mallory in spirited soldier speeches. Kenton 
                        Harper--Captain of the Augusta Volunteers and Governor of Parras while in Mexico--a good 
                        citizen--a brave officer. Responded to by the Captain in a very happy style. The President 
                        announced that the Hon. Wm. C. Preston is now in the County visiting the graves of his 
                        ancestors, and would join us in celebrating the day, but he desires me to say that his impaired 
                        health forbids it. Hon. Wm. C. Preston.--A son of Virginia--the late distinguished senator from 
                        the Palmetto State--may he long live to witness the national prosperity and liberty, to the 
                        protection and securing whereof he has faithfully devoted his talents and unsurpassed eloquence. 
                        The Ladies of Staunton--unsurpassed for their personal attraction and amiability of 
                        character--Long may they live to make happy such occasions as this by the sunshine of their 
                        presence. By Gen. Harman.--The Staunton Militia.  Appropriately responded to by Capt. J. D. 
                        Imboden.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mallory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article prints toasts from the 4th of July celebration.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly59.html#7.15d</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Some international news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.15.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>X.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Almarode</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on July 4, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Robert Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Samuel Garber died on July 6 at age three.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.07.15.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
