<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'> -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1859/va.au.rv.1859.09.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/2/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1859-09-16">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.16.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Charleston Convention: Will the Southern Democracy Prove Loyal to the
                    South?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns Southern Democrats that it is likely that the squatter sovereign
                    Senator Douglas will be nominated as candidate for the presidency at the
                    upcoming Democratic convention. Article asks that the South send only the most
                    loyal Southerners to the convention.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Hon. Alex. H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Vindicator is pleased to see that Stuart is being considered as a
                    potential candidate for the Opposition in the upcoming presidential
                election.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>New Enterprise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Messrs. Sicher, as may be seen by their advertisement, have ventured on the experiment, new 
                        to Staunton, of opening a store almost exclusively for the ladies, who may now, without being 
                        exposed to prying eyes, purchase numberless little unmentionable "fixins," which they are shy of 
                        calling for at a counter beset with the horrid men.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Messrs. Sicher have opened a new store exclusively for ladies in Staunton.
                    This will allow women, "who may now, without being exposed to prying masculine
                    eyes, purchase numberless little unmentionable 'fixins,' which they are shy of
                    calling for at a counter beset with the horrid men."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvsept59.html#9.16a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Henry Winter Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Opposition congressman Davis made a speech in favor of the Northern
                    wing of the Opposition, even though his Baltimore constitutency usually shares
                    the interests of the South. The Vindicator believes that he has "thrown off his
                    mask and appeared in his true character of a rampant Black
                Republican."</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from S.A. Douglas to Lucy Stone turning down her invitation to speak
                    at a women's rights convention, despite his regrets.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Programme of Procession</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cockman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Veitch</ln>
                        <fn>E.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The cornerstone of the new M.E. Church will be laid; gives the order of
                    procession and route of the march to the church.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Proceedings of Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the Council of the town of Staunton, on Saturday 
                        night last, the following proceedings took place, among others:</p>
                    <p> The Committee heretofore appointed to examine the Reservoir, 
                        returned a report concluding with a resolution instructing said 
                        committee to have the bottom of the Reservoir plastered with Hydraulic 
                        Cement and to do whatever else may be necessary to render said Reservoir 
                        water tight, which was adopted.</p>
                    <p> A resolution was adopted directing the Street Commissioners to have 
                        the name of the principal Streets of the Town painted on suitable boards 
                        and placed at each prominent Street crossing, indicating the name of 
                        said Streets.</p>
                    <p> A preamble and resolution in relation to the salary of the Attorney 
                        for the Commonwealth was presented, and, on motion, laid over until the 
                        laying of the next levy.</p> <p>A resolution was adopted authorizing the 
                            Mayor to give the proper notice through the newspapers of 
                            an intended application to the General Assembly of Virginia at its next 
                            session for an extension of the Town limits.  And Messrs. Imboden, 
                            Baylor and Bell were appointed a committee to report on such limits.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Staunton town council took place last Saturday, at which
                    time they decided to plaster the reservoir with cement and paint street names on
                    boards. The council also debated the salary of the Attorney for the Commonwealth
                    and discussed how to extend the town limits at the next General Assembly.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvsept59.html#9.16b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>J. Baker Thompson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>J. Baker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thompson, of Staunton, has accepted the presidency of a college at Little
                    Rock.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Henry A. Wise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"It is a war of the People and Henry A. Wise against the Politicians."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Recommends that Wise be nominated for the presidency at the Charleston
                    Convention, for it is he that has the people's best interests at
                heart.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>What Mr. Clay Thought of a Whig Administration and of Mr. Seward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Unless the South be outnumbered in the 'irrepressible conflict,' and driven,
                        consequently, to absolve itself from the North, the onward destinies of the
                        Union must ever be superinduced by Democratic administration."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, if Clay were still alive, he would despise Seward's
                    unconstitutional abolitionist politics.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Virginia in the Councils of the National Democracy</head>
                <origin>Virginia Index</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A friend not long since remarked to us that he had attended several 
                        National Conventions of the Democratic party, and that in every instance 
                        he had witnessed with pleasure and pride the deference shown to the 
                        Virginia delegation.  It appeared to him that this State, with an 
                        electoral vote never exceeding seventeen, within the period to which he 
                        referred, had during that time carried more influence in Convention than 
                        New York or Pennsylvania, and on some important occasions more influence 
                        than all the States combined.  He felt proud of a State that could 
                        accomplish such important results through its moral power alone.</p>
                    <p> Our friend fully understood and appreciated the cause of the great 
                        influence of Virginia in the councils of the party.  He knows that it 
                        was attributable entirely to the prevalence of the impression that the 
                        Democracy of Virginia are honestly devoted to principles--broad, 
                        defined, legible principles--that they go in Convention not for the 
                        purpose of securing merely selfish ends through bargains and intrigues 
                        with political sharpers, but for the patriotic purpose of co-operating 
                        in the selection of candidates for the highest offices of the Republic, 
                        who are faithful and true to its best interests.--Heretofore Virginia 
                        has indeed occupied an enviable position in our National Conventions.  
                        Since 1836, she has said to her brethren in Convention, "Virginia asks 
                        nothing for herself.  She only asks that the first offices of the 
                        government shall be filled by men who rightly understand and who will 
                        faithfully carry out its true principles."  And it must be admitted that 
                        these professions of Virginia have been well illustrated in her 
                        acts.</p>
                    <p> It should surely be an object near the heart of every true Democrat 
                        of Virginia, to support and maintain the proud character which his party 
                        in the State has acquired by its liberal, patriotic and disinterested 
                        course in Convention.  We sincerely hope that the Virginia Democracy 
                        will not suffer in numerical or moral force, by the disputes that have 
                        unfortunately arisen amon
                        g them in consequence of the appearance of rival Presidential candidates 
                        in their ranks.  We hope their hitherto proud flag will not be lowered 
                        before the Charleston Convention. Such must and will be the case, 
                        however, if we have a protracted war between the rivals here, and then 
                        take it for final decision to the Convention at Charleston.  In that 
                        event, "the rest of mankind" will come to the conclusion that we are, 
                        after all, just as selfish and just as bad in every respect as they are. 
                        Even the hards and softs of New York will rise up in judgement against 
                        us!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Virginia Index.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Beseeches Virginia Democrats to try to resolve factional differences within
                    the Virginia Democratic party before the Charleston Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvsept59.html#9.16c</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.16.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byan</ln>
                        <fn>Stella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 8, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doderick</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyner</ln>
                        <fn>Rossanah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 8, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snellers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 10.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thayer</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on Sepember 9.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latman</ln>
                        <fn>A.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sturgis</ln>
                        <fn>P.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sturgis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 4, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jno. Mohler died in Luray, Virginia on August 30 at age 24.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>James McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jas. Gilbert died on September 3 at age 19.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sosey</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sosey</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie Sosey died on September 8 at age 7.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>International news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1859.09.16.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
