
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.03.30">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/29/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-03-30">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>30</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.30.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.30.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Mercersburg Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Mercersburg railroad project has at length assumed such a shape as to
                        justify the conclusion that the road will be built. Preparations for its
                        construction are rapidly going forward. The contract for the work has been
                        let, and the arrival of carts, horses and Milesians, and the erection of
                        shanties along the line of the survey, give assurance of the sincerity of
                        those concerned in the enterprise, and much encouragement to the citizens of
                        Mercersburg, and the community around.</p>

                    <p>On the 23d inst. a large and enthusiastic meeting of the subscribers to the
                        capital stock of the road was held in Mercersburg, a general discussion
                        followed, and it is said the best feeling prevailed. Rev. Dr. Creigh
                        presided, and the meeting was addressed by Frederick Foreman, Wm. Adams, Wm.
                        M'Kinstry of Mercersburg, and Mr. Jones, of Reading. The greatest anxiety
                        prevailed for the speedy prosecution of the work. Mercersburg and vicinity
                        have so long been kept back by the want of rapid and easy communications
                        with the rest of the world, that the people are unanimous in urging forward
                        the road as vigorously as possible. Considerable disappointment has been
                        felt and expressed that the line of the road was not located further south
                        than it is, but the clear and satisfactory statements of <orig reg="Mr."
                        >Mr</orig> Jones seemed to reconcile all to the route determined upon. It
                        was demonstrated by the surveys that the line adopted is much the better for
                        the road, has easier gradients and lighter curves. Our informant assured us
                        that the people returned from the meeting delighted with the consciousness
                        that they were really to have a railroad, that their quietude was surely to
                        broken by the shrieks and whistle of the iron horse, and that they were on
                        the eve of speedy communication with the "rest of mankind." We heartily
                        congratulated Mercersburg upon her prospects, and hope she may speedily
                        rival or even surpass all the other towns in the county.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor makes favorable comments about the inevitable construction of
                    the Mercersburg Railroad. He notes that public opinion was unanimous in setting
                    up the railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.30.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donahue</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ash</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lloyd</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Garrah</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Feight</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeMoyer</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodcock</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Izel</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rudisill</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The second annual session of the Central Pennsylvania Conference of the M.
                    E. Church met in Lewistown. Rev. W. W. Paxton of Chambersburg was elected to
                    local orders. Appointments were made in the Carlisle District including: E. W.
                    Kirby, First Church, Chambersbburg; J. Donahue, Second Church, Chambersburg; H.
                    M. Ash, Shippesnburg; J. H. M'Garrah, Mechanicsburg; J. W. Feight, Mont Alto; J.
                    A. DeMoyer, Waynesboro; J. A. Woodcock, Greencastle; G. W. Izel, Mercersburg; H.
                    Linn and L. A. Rudisill, M'Connellsburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Meeting of Colored Republicans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The literary and political organization of our colored citizens held a
                        meeting in the A.M.E. church, on Thursday evening last, at which essays were
                        read and speeches delivered by a number of members. We were not present, but
                        have learned from those who were, that the proceedings were highly
                        creditable, and manifested an earnestness of purpose of improvement, mental,
                        moral, and political, very gratifying, and testifying to the wisdom that
                        bestowed upon them the rights of suffrage. The orators and essayist took
                        high ground in favor of the Republican party, and scouted the assertion of
                        the Democracy, that they could "buy the niggers with whisky." Some of the
                        speakers had been slaves, and gave touching descriptions of the horrors of
                        slavery, as felt in their own experience. They know to whom they owe their
                        liberty, and to whom they should ascribe all the efforts made to keep them
                        in bondage; and we think the Democrats with their "infernal machine," that
                        serves them instead of truth and righteousness elsewhere, will hardly buy
                        the "nigger vote," here or otherwhere. We hope our white citizens will do
                        all they can to encourage the colored men in their efforts towards
                        improvement; for, as was well said by Joseph Winters in his address on last
                        Thursday, their elevation is more dependant upon the improvement of the
                        white man's heart than the colored man's mind."</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article notes a meeting of black voters in the A. M. E. Church. It
                    reports that the general tone of the meeting was in favor of the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleagle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. W. Crooks, one-time propreitor of the Greencastle Echo, died recently in
                    Fayetteville. He had also written articles for the Repository. William Fleagle
                    issues resolutions of sympathy and respect on behalf of Gilmore Lodge, I.O.O.F.,
                    of Fayetteville upon the news of Crooks' passing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. Barnes, pastor of the First M. E. Church of Chambersburg, has been
                    appointed presiding elder of the Danville District. Barnes served in
                    Chambersburg two years and the congregation was sad to see him go. Rev. E. W.
                    Kirby will take Barnes' place. He comes with recomendation as "a perfect
                    christian gentleman, and possessing abilities of a high order as a preacher."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin>Mercersburg Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Subscribers to the proposed railroad met in the lecture room of the
                    Presbyterian Church in mercersburg on Wednesday. Mr. Jones, representative of
                    the company, explained the ongoing plans, sending everyone home satisfied of the
                    promise of the project.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Academy was closed on Friday for spring vacation. The
                    school has been flourishing under Dr. Shumaker, and attendance is filled to
                    capacity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Go to Hear Her</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miss Anna E. Dickerson will speak in Repository Hall on April 12th.
                    Admission is 75 cents and will benefit the Monumental Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>Amos M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegerreis</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kearns</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Amos M. Elder and Mrs. Mary A. Kegerreis, both of Path Valley, were married
                    on March 15th at the Parsonage of the Upper Tuscarora Presbyterian Church by the
                    Rev. J. E. Kearns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pym</ln>
                        <fn>Eloise</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Eloise Pym died in McConnellsburg on March 24th at the residence of
                    her son, Dr. William F. Trout, after suffering a long and painful illness. "Her
                    earthly record was filled with deeds of love and mercy to the poor and needy.
                    She lived for others and set self aside so that her Master might be served in
                    all things."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallagher</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Nancy Gallagher died near Carrick on March 18th. She was 93 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Jones died at Carrick on March 22nd. He was 78 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.30.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
