
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.06.01">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-06-01">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>01</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.01.01" exists="no">



            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.01.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Honest Elections Not Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>It is too well established by unbroken experience to the contrary to hope
                        that anything a Republican Congress may or can do will receive the approval
                        of the Democracy. Still the various measures proposed and the laws made in
                        Congress receive different degrees of disapproval. Democracy as a National
                        party may be practically dead; its hopes of ever electing a Chief
                        Magistrate, or of having a controlling voice in either house of Congress may
                        be <orig reg="infinitesimally">infinitessimally</orig> small; still it has
                        its green spots, its oases, its wells of pure, we cannot say undefiled,
                        Democratic waters, which even the Fifteenth Amendment cannot obliterate or
                        make waste. New York city has never yet run after strange gods, and it is
                        even possible in a few States to elect Democratic Governors and
                        Legislatures. These last and slender remains of what was once the dominant
                        party from Maine to Texas must be cherished and guarded with jealous care.
                        If they too be swallowed up by the insatiable monster of radicalism,
                        Democracy will exist only in the memory of its crimes and misdeeds.</p>

                    <p>Imagine then the consternation created in the Democratic camp by the passage
                        through the Senate of Sherman's bill providing a general election law, a
                        bill to enforce the Fifteenth Amendment, a bill to protect honest voters,
                        and to punish perjurers, repeaters, ballot stuffers and forgers in
                        elections. It is authoritatively said that the bill, or one closely
                        approximating to its provisions, will pass the House and become a law, and
                        what, Oh! what will the Democracy do then? The Fifteenth Amendment was
                        almost more than they could bear and live. It destroyed all hope of their
                        becoming a party whose dominion would extend over the country, a party of
                        latitude and longitude. Still it left them rich spots not to be despised. It
                        did not take from them New York city. Nay, as the last election
                        demonstrated, it made them stronger in that famous stronghold than before.
                        It supplemented their already enormous majority by the negro vote. True the
                        wishes of the negroes were not consulted as to their choice of candidates,
                        only when they came to deposit their ballots they were informed that they
                        had been relieved from the irksome duty of exercising citizenship, and that
                        kind friends had already used their names and cast their ballots for the
                        incorruptible Democracy.</p>

                    <p>But just when they had arranged everything to their entire satisfaction, when
                        they had manipulated State laws and city ordinance exactly to suit their
                        taste, when they could have swelled their majority by adding the negro votes
                        to their other enormous frauds large enough to have carried the State
                        itself, the Senate threatens them with a law actually intended to protect
                        honest voters and to prevent and punish fraudulent ones, and it is well
                        framed to accomplish those ends. Was ever anything more despotic,
                        high-handed and unconstitutional than this? We are sure nothing in our
                        recollection has excited Democratic indignation as it has. And this feeling
                        is not confined to New York city. In other cities, and even outside of the
                        cities, with one voice they cry out against it. We have no doubt that its
                        passage will determine Wallace to refuse the chairmanship of the next
                        Democratic committee in this State. It would settle the fate of prematurely
                        aged naturalization papers, as well as the fate of a good many Democratic
                        aspirants for Congress and the Legislature. Among other things it would put
                        an end to the large number of contested election cases by increasing the
                        peril of fraudulent votes. If it accomplished this alone, it would be no
                        trifling good.</p>

                    <p>But best of all, if it becomes a law it discriminates in favor of no
                        political party. It protects the honest voter of either party and punishes
                        the fraudulent of both. The Democracy object to it, because being most
                        dishonest they are most hurt by it. Of course they do not give that as a
                        reason. They say that it is subversive of State sovereignty and State
                        rights, but that is mere stuff. A national law which provides the means for
                        enforcing an honest election is not likely to seriously damage State rights.
                        We hope that Congress will speedily make Sherman's bill a law, and by its
                        rigid enforcement make fraudulent voting, or unlawful interference with
                        qualified voters such a dangerous experiment as that few will have the
                        temerity to undertake it.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> assails the Democrats for
                    opposing a senate bill that targets election tampering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>No Principles--No Issue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Democracy of this, the 16th Congressional District have by the general
                        concurrence of their journals fully admitted that they have no issue upon
                        which to go before the people in the approaching Congressional campaign. In
                        some districts in the State they have taken issue with the Republican party
                        on the tariff question, but here, though the Bedford <emph rend="italics"
                            >Gazette</emph> and the Somerset <emph rend="italics">Democrat</emph>
                        make a feeble show of free trade, the party is afraid to array itself
                        against a protective policy. They have agreed to be unanimous, however, in
                        assailing the colored vote, which explains what we mean by the assertion
                        that they have no issue. The negro question is finally and eternally
                        settled. The Fifteenth Amendment could not be revoked except in the same way
                        as it was adopted, by the concurrence of three-fourths of the States to an
                        act of Congress submitting the question to them. This of course can never be
                        done. Then what means or what is the use of the cry of the "White men's
                        party?" Nothing more than that they dare not take issue on the tariff, that
                        all other issues are dead, and that they hope to win a few Republicans to
                        their party by thus exciting their prejudice against the negro. Suppose that
                        there were enough of Republicans opposed to the Fifteenth Amendment to
                        enable the Democracy by voting with them to elect their ticket, what would
                        such a result accomplish? It would not deprive the colored people of the
                        right to vote. It would not annul the Fifteenth Amendment. It would in fact
                        do nothing except elect some corrupt demagogues to office, and in no respect
                        benefit the disaffected Republicans.</p>

                    <p>Then nothing is clearer than this, that the leaders of a bankrupt and
                        desperate party want to ride into office on the wave of a miserable
                        prejudice. That is the whole sum and substance of the "white man's party."
                        That is the whole text from which they preach. It has no principle and no
                        character. If they did not think they saw personal advantage in it they
                        would have nothing to do with it; and if they succeeded in their aims if
                        they could entice enough ally Republicans to their party to elect them they
                        would laugh at their folly and enjoy the offices.</p>

                    <p>We have yet to learn of any Republicans who are willing to sacrifice the
                        principles of their party for the sake of such a prejudice though the <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph> boasts loudly of such, but if there be any
                        we shall not allow them to throw away their votes without fully informing
                        them that they will be merely making themselves the dupes and tools of
                        designing Democratic leaders.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial argues that the local Democrats are constantly bringing up
                    the issue of blacks' rights and inciting racial prejudice because they have no
                    other issues to campaign on.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper celebrates passage of the 15th Amendment. "It puts the power to
                    protect the ballot box against fraud and corruption in the hands of United
                    States officers, and punishes offenders in the United States Courts, and gives
                    the President the necessary authority to enforce the law."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Distribution of Documents</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italics">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>I don't think it would be amiss to reply to the statement made by the <emph
                            rend="italics">Valley Spirit</emph>, in its last week's issue, in regard
                        to the distribution of documents, &amp;c., to the colored people by Mr.
                        Cessna. The writer should know that his colored brethren have sufficient
                        gratitude to support, and enough of discrimination to know their friends,
                        without the aid documents. His own manhood, if he possessed any, should
                        teach him that the vituperation and abuse of the colored people by the
                        journal which he represents cannot but make them a unit in support of Mr.
                        Cessna.</p>

                    <p>That the <emph rend="italics">colored</emph> editor of the <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph> has long been in sympathy with the party
                        that teaches that a black man has no right which a white man is bound to
                        respect is well known. But that he should play the spy in the camp of his
                        own people, who have been oppressed and kept in bondage for over two
                        centuries, passes all belief, and makes the epithet "nigger," which his
                        party friends so much delight in bandying about, apply with peculiar force
                        to him. A COLORED VOTER.</p>

                    <p>[It is currently reported that the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> has
                        secured the services of an apostate colored man as associate editor. - ED.
                        REPOS.]</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This author of this letter states that black voters know that the
                    Republicans are their true friends and attacks the editor of the <emph
                        rend="italics">Valley Spirit</emph>.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.01.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. W. Hays has dissolved his relations with the Repository and Henry S.
                    Stoner has taken his place. He will handle business concerns. Jere Cook remains
                    editor. Hays is retiring to resume practice of his profession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowen</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimison</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Theodore M'Gowen announces that the Republican County Committee will meet
                    in the office of Thomas J. Grimison on June 4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Not Cunning, But Right</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper applauds the decision of the Democratic-controlled Board of
                    County Commissioners to replace departing Republican Capt. Doebler with
                    Republican George Foreman. The members of the board believed they had a duty to
                    respect the wishes of the voters at the last election, much to the chagrin of
                    the Valley Spirit who accused the commissioners of violating Democratic
                    principles. The paper scoffs sarcastically that "a splendid chance to swindle
                    the colored voters out of their votes was lost by this appointment, but we hope
                    it will find some consolation for its grief in our assurance that a perfectly
                    fair and just assessment will now be made and no man's rights will be violated
                    or trifled with."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Decoration Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The ceremonies attending the decoration of the soldiers' graves in this
                        vicinity were a grand success. The only thing which created dissatisfaction
                        was the refusal of the Chambersburg Silver Cornet Band on Monday morning to
                        play. The Fayetteville Band was secured in their stead. About 430 P.M.
                        returned soldiers and citizens assembled in front of the Court House. The
                        procession was divided into two divisions, one division, under charge of the
                        Chief Marshal, Col. McGowan, composed of the returned soldiers and citizens,
                        preceded by the Fayetteville band, visiting the graveyards of the Falling
                        Spring and Catholic Churches, the other division, under charge of Capt.
                        Skinner composed of Housum Zouaves, the Knights of Pythias and the members
                        of the Columbus and Chambersburg Lodges, I. O. O. F., preceded by the Drum
                        corps, visiting the various graveyards south of Market street. After the
                        ceremonies in these localities were concluded, the two divisions united and
                        proceeded to the cemetery where a short eloquent and exceedingly appropriate
                        address was delivered by Rev. I. N. Hays. The services were concluded with a
                        benediction by Rev. Gotwalt. Our citizens all seemed interested in the
                        ceremonies of the day. The ladies, with their accustomed generosity, made
                        large donations of wreaths, flowers, and <orig reg="bouquets"
                        >boquets</orig>. The music furnished by the Fayetteville Band elicited the
                        praise of all who heard it.</p>

                    <p>The respect shown the memories of our heroic dead is an evidence that their
                        services and patriotism will not soon be forgotten by those who survive
                        them.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwalt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This report about the recent Decoration Day celebrations declares the
                    festivities "a grand success."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Keehan</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkens</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowden</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society met on the 24th. Miss Mattie
                    M'Keehan and Calvin Gilbert were elected members to the society. Committees were
                    appointed for the upcoming exhibition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Orrstown Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dehart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper defends Mr. Knisely and Mr. Dehart, two Republicans reportedly
                    elected to posts in Orrstown, from attacks made by the Valley Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Mercersburg Classes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callender</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Thirtieth Annual Meeting of the Mercersburg Classes of the Reformed
                    Church of the United States met in St. John's Church in Schellsburg on May 19th.
                    Rev. P. S. Davis of Chambersburg preached the opening sermon. Rev. S. N.
                    Callender of Greencastle was elected president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Internal Revenue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George L. Balsley, Deputy Collector of Internal Revenue for Franklin, will
                    receive taxes on annual incomes and special businesses and professions in Hoke's
                    Building in Chambersburg between June 14th and 18th. Licenses must also be paid
                    at that time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Colored Band</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The African Americans of Chambersburg are holding a festival in Repository
                    Hall to raise money to purchase instruments for a brass band. A lecture will
                    also be delivered. Admission is 25 cents. "Those who have witnessed the
                    entertainments given by the colored people, in the Hall, need not be reminded
                    that this will be worth attending."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keggereis</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Keggereis, a disabled soldier from Fanettsburg, has been appointed
                    watchman and messenger at a government department in Washington. John Cessna
                    secured the post for the veteran, who had not been able to find any work he
                    could do.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. J. White of the Olive Branch Encampment No. 13, I.O.O.F., has been
                    elected District Deputy Grand Patriarch of Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. W. Hays is resuming the practice of law in partnership with Jere Cook.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Edmund Culbertson of Columbus Lodge No. 75, I.O.O.F., has been elected
                    District Grand Master of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An ice cream festival will be held in Repository Hall under the auspices of
                    the Ladies' Improvement Society of the First M. E. Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The citizens of Shippensburg have organized a new brass band.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowen</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stroup</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Theodore Mowen of St. Thomas and Miss Annie Stroup of Cashtown, Franklin
                    County, were married in Chambersburg on May 26th by the Rev. John Fohl at his
                    residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret M'Clure died in Chambersburg on May 5th. She was 78 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>



            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.01.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
