
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.07.13">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/05/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-07-13">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.07.13.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.07.13.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Income Tax Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We stated a short time ago that the Senate had struck the Income tax section
                        of the Tax Bill now before Congress, and every person believed that it would
                        stay struck out. Last week, however, the vote striking it out was
                        reconsidered, and the result was to reinstate the tax in modified form. It
                        now goes back to the House with the chances in favor of its being concurred
                        in there. This will establish a tax, of two and a half per cent on incomes
                        over $2000, until the end of the year 1872. Hitherto there was a tax of five
                        per cent on incomes over $1000. After the last change made by the Senate an
                        attempt was made to defeat it by a resolution to prevent its collection
                        until ordered by Congress. This was defeated by a tie vote, Senator Cameron
                        failing to vote.</p>
                    <p>So far as this Congressional district is concerned the modification made by
                        the Senate is a practical abolition of the tax. A very limited number of
                        persons will be liable to a tax laid on the excess of two thousand dollars
                        on incomes, and the same thing is true everywhere, except in the principal
                        cities. In its present shape the tax is not burdensome or onerous. Only such
                        as are prosperous and wealthy will be liable, and yet it is the most odious
                        tax imposed by Congress. All classes of people condemn it, even those who
                        never have and never will pay it. A member of Congress, to satisfy his
                        constituency, must oppose the tax, though only an insignificant portion of
                        them are liable. What is the cause of this sentiment? People say because it
                        offends by invading our private and personal affairs, and by encouraging
                        perjury. We doubt whether that is the real or the whole reason. It is a tax
                        upon the rich and influential. It discriminates against them, and their
                        wealth and position enable them to educate public opinion in their cause. By
                        retaining the Income tax, other taxes which oppress the laboring classes may
                        be removed at once; by striking it off they are sure to be retained. Which
                        ought to be done? Yet the people say the Income tax must cease, and Congress
                        ought to hearken to the will of the people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a modified version of the income tax has passed the
                    Senate. Even though it affects only the very wealthy, the editors marvel at the
                    widespread public opposition to the tax, and speculate on the reasons for it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.07.13.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Laying the Corner Stone of the Protestant Episcopal Church and Other
                    Ceremonies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The South Central Convocation of the Protestant Episcopal Church of the
                    Diocese of Pennsylvania met in Chambersburg on Tuesday, Wednesday, and Thursday.
                    Ministers from throughout the region attended. The corner stone of Trinity
                    Episcopal Church, Chambersburg, was laid during the ceremonies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sentman</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Claudy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A bridge collapsed upon James C. Atkinson, Solomon Sentman, and William
                    Claudy while they were fishing in a creek near Roxbury. Claudy died in the
                    accident. He was 25 years old and leaves a wife and infant child.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Carlisle District Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A religious camp meeting will be held at Red Barn Station on the Cumberland
                    Valley Railroad between August 3rd and 12th. Large numbers of Chambersburg
                    citizens are expected to attend. Interested parties can rent tents from John D.
                    Speer, Chambersburg. Canvas and board tents with floors and roofing can be
                    rented for $10. Those without their own provisions can purchase accomodation on
                    site for $6 for the term, $1 per day, 50 cents for breakfast and tea, and 75
                    cents for dinner. Excursion tickets will be issued to all who attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Supreme Court Cases</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Supreme Court of Pennsylvania heard the following cases: Bitner vs
                    Bitner, Judge King, judgement affirmed; Fleming's Appeal, Judge King, judgement
                    affirmed; Fahrney vs Holsinger, Judge King, judgement affirmed; Barncord vs
                    Parker, Judge King, judgement affirmed; Thompson vs Kyner, Judge Rowe, judgement
                    affirmed; Greenawalt vs M'Dowell, Judge Rowe, judgement affirmed; Eyster vs
                    Sprecher, et. al., Judge Rowe, judgement affirmed; Sally Mahon vs George
                    Johnson, Judge Rowe, judgement affirmed; Oliver vs Bonebrake, Judge Rowe,
                    judgement affirmed; Gillan vs Dixon, Judge Rowe, judgement affirmed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edwards</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Board of Wilson College is erecting a school building on the college
                    grounds. Dr. Edwards is president of the institution. Rev. J. W. Whitman, J. F.
                    Kennedy, and J. A. Crawford have been chosen professors. Rev. Dr. Creigh was
                    appointed lecturer on Evidences of Christianity and Rev. I. N. Hays on Christian
                    Culture. A lady of "eminent qualifications" has also been secured for one of the
                    departments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritchey</ln>
                        <fn>Atchison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Atchison Ritchey, "one of the oldest and most respected citizens of
                    Mercersburg," died suddenly on Monday after suffering an illness of a few hours
                    brough on by an attack of asthma. Ritchey was 70 years old and had been an
                    "active, energetic man." "He was a man of strong convictions, and frank and open
                    in the avowal of his opinions. He was a life long enemy of slavery, and when
                    advocates of its abolition were few and feeble, he never concealed his
                    detestation of the hated institution, nor hesitated to assist and befriend its
                    victims when striving to escape. He lived long enough to see his principle
                    triumph, to see slavery abolished in the land, and to see, also, those who had
                    no words to say for abolitionism when it was odious, become its nosiest
                    champions when it was popular to be so."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Appointment of Viewers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teeter</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Judge Rowe and Judge Armstrong heard the claimants for damages against the
                    Southern Pennsylvania Railroad. Kennedy, Stewart, and William M'Lellan apeared
                    for the railroad, and Sharpe, M'Gowan, Clarke, and Stenger spoke for the
                    petitioners. The court appointed the following committee to assess the damages:
                    Benjamin Snively and A. B. Wingert of Antrim; William Bossert of Hamilton; W. S.
                    Amberson of Waynesboro; J. C. Austin of Chambersburg; W. W. Britton and Joseph
                    Gilmore of Letterkenny. The will begin by inspecting the property of David
                    Teeter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>New Presbytery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wing</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Synod of Harrisburg of the Presbyterian General Assembly met to set the
                    bounds of the new presbyteries. Franklin County will be included in the
                    Presbytery of Carlisle. The following officers were selected for it: Rev. Dr.
                    Wing, moderator; A. J. Mitchell, stated clerk; Rev. J. A. Crawford, temporary
                    clerk; J. Smith Gordon, treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummins</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Hassan struck Peter Cummins in the head with a brick during a fight
                    begun while the two men were drinking with a man named Kane in the yard of the
                    Indian Queen Hotel. Hassan was arrested and Cummins is not expected to recover.
                    The paper blames the incident on "the madness occasioned by whiskey" since the
                    two men were very good friends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Medical Society of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>J. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Medical Society met in Chambersburg. Dr. J. K. Davidson
                    of Greencastle persided. As at every meeting, the participants read essays on
                    cases, theories, and therapys. A large number of members attended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. C. M'Dowell, son of John M'Dowell of Chambersburg, was admitted to the
                    Naval Academy. "Master Craig M'Dowell is a bright and promising boy of excellent
                    habits and we feel sure will strive to deserve the honor which he has received."
                    His brother, Capt. Sam M'Dowell, "a gallant artillery officer" was killed during
                    one of Sherman's campaigns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Large Sale of Bank Stock</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pym</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The executors of the estate of the late Mrs. Pym of McConnellsburg sold 150
                    shares of the First National Bank of Chambersburg for $10,952.50 ($73.01 2/3 per
                    share). The par value of the stock is $50.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Appointed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>David A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gen. Gregory, Marshal of the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, appointed
                    David A. Wertz of Chambersburg deputy marshal to assist in taking the social
                    statistics of Adams, Franklin, York, Cumberland, Dauphin, Perry, and Lebanon
                    counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. G. Schaff announces that he will preach on Sunday at Marion station and
                    on the Court House steps in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>Robert M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Robert M. Bard and her two daughters are moving to California to join
                    members of the family already there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>T. X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. T. X. Orr preached in the Central Presbyterian Church on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minnie Hutton, daughter of William and Mary Hutton, died on July 11th. She
                    was 4 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.07.13.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
