
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.04.27">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/30/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-04-27">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.04.27.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.04.27.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Commercial's Sympathy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Chambersburg REPOSITORY might stand a chance of getting something done
                        for the relief of those who suffered from rebel invasion if it would
                        manifest a little common sense. Those sufferers have the sincere sympathy of
                        every part of the State. Precisely what should be done for their relief, and
                        if anything, however, are questions about which men must be permitted to
                        differ. The surroundings of the bill of the late session were so bad as to
                        repel the support of many of the sincerest friends of the cause. The editor
                        of the REPOSITORY is either ignorant or careless if he is not prepared to
                        admit this much. If support of that bill or any similar bill with similar
                        surroundings is to be made the test of friendship for the sufferers on the
                        border, then we fear they will continue to fare badly. They can well afford
                        to have the REPOSITORY abate some of its peculiar zeal in their behalf. Its
                        style of advocacy is unfortunate--<emph rend="italic">Pittsburgh Commercial,
                            22d</emph>.</p>

                    <p>Those who recollect the columns of unqualified abuse of the border people
                        which the <emph rend="italic">Commercial</emph> published a month or two
                        ago, and the ill-concealed pleasure it took in cruelly insulting the feeling
                        and wounding the honor of many thousands of brave and patriotic people, will
                        be no little surprised and pleased to learn that it has so far mended its
                        ways as to say that there is little in the way of those who suffered from
                        the rebel invasions getting relief except the lack of common sense in the
                        REPOSITORY. To think that "these sufferers have the sincere sympathy of
                        every part of the State," and they wholly ignorant of it and likely to be
                        ever so long, had it not been for this chance paragraph of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Commercial</emph>. Well, the oddest things are forever
                        happening, and people and newspapers have the strangest way of showing
                        sympathy! Of course we have no right to complain if their way of showing is
                        not exactly the approved way, nor the old-fashioned way inculcated by an
                            <orig reg="eminent">eminet</orig> teacher whom we were taught to accept
                        as authority on the subject.</p>

                    <p>Though this offer of sympathy and good will on the part of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Commercial</emph> be somewhat late, it will be gratifying
                        to our readers to know that they have it at all. They surely are willing
                        that it should shift the indefensible and foolish assaults it made upon them
                        over to the bill that was offered for their relief, when it finds that it is
                        politic so to do. To judge from its greatly improved tone and temper since
                        our notice of last week, we cannot admit, however amiable we feel, the
                        charge it makes as to our lack of sense. The manifest improvement we have
                        wrought in it must vindicate us from any such allegation.</p>

                    <p>There is a word or two we must say, however, to correct a false impression
                        the <emph rend="italic">Commercial</emph> seeks to make throughout the whole
                        paragraph. Its effort is to show that its opposition was to the kind of bill
                        and the influence it had, not to the border people. This we emphatically
                        deny. We are familiar with all it wrote on the subject, and know that it
                        took the position that the border people were entitled to nothing, and tried
                        to maintain it throughout with such marvelous misstatements, as nothing but
                        the grossest ignorance could excuse. If it has learned better since, we are
                        glad, and hope it will make such amends as honest minds seek to make when
                        convinced of error. It can rest assured that we did not misrepresent the
                        sentiment of the border people on the subject of their losses in our last
                        issue, and their determination to use their power to secure the relief to
                        which they are entitled.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> expresses offense at a
                    Harrisburg editor's previous articles in opposition to border damage claims,
                    noting how that same writer is now apologizing to the border people only when it
                    is politically advantageous to do so. The editorial insists that the <emph
                        rend="italics">Repository</emph> has always had the interests of the border
                    counties at heart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Who Will Carry the County Next Fall?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns the Republicans of Montgomery, Peters, and Antrim that the
                    Democrats are boasting they will carry the county in the next election "even if
                    every colored voter casts his ballot with the Republican party." They claim to
                    have support from the parties building the railroad from Mercersburg and will
                    "import" voters if they must.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.04.21.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>After the Negro Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The extreme scarcity of local news will perhaps justify Local Editors in
                        using double extra magnifying glasses when hunting for items; at all events
                        it is not worth while quarreling with them if they do. It is no
                        justification however for manufacturing, out of the whole cloth, a half
                        column of stuff which has not the slightest foundation in the truth, and
                        attempting to impose it on their readers. Our neighbors, across the way, did
                        this last week, and manufactured the most astonishing story about the
                        colored voters, and how the Republican party was trying to manipulate their
                        votes. They told how we had attended the meetings of the colored people, and
                        we were actually shocked when we learned from them what we had there done,
                        and how meanly we thought of our newly made citizens. Well, we were at one
                        of the meetings. We were very respectfully invited to come, and we very
                        respectfully agreed to go. The meeting was held for the purpose of making
                        arrangements to celebrate the proclamation of the adoption of the Fifteenth
                        Amendment on the 26th inst., and we went as a spectator purely. We might say
                        here that we were regarded as such, and that those who held the meeting did
                        not see fit to consult us in any <orig reg="particular">partiaular</orig>.
                        The Local Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, however, thought
                        us of more importance than the negroes did, and informed us, much to our
                        surprise, that we were there "for the purpose of <orig reg="molding"
                            >moulding</orig> the opinions and shaping the actions of the negroes
                        according to our own wishes." We did not know that such a deep laid plot was
                        hidden in our heart, and feel badly since we have learned it, to think how
                        completely the colored folks circumvented it. But this sharp Local
                            Editor<orig reg="-">,</orig> what a sly dog he is?<orig reg="-"/> told
                        us still more about ourselves, that we don't know. Robie Burns was right. We
                        didn't see <orig reg="ourselves">oursels</orig> as <orig reg="others"
                        >ithers</orig> see us. What wicked thoughts we were thinking of our colored
                        citizens without being aware of it until "the Local" told us in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph>? Why, we "regard the negroes as 'dumb driven
                        cattle' and think and say that all we need to do is to direct them to do so
                        and so, and forthwith it will be done. We believe them to be like a flock of
                        sheep which will follow wherever the <orig reg="bellwether"
                        >bell-wether</orig> leads the way."</p>

                    <p>Ah! no Mr. Local, that last was too big a whopper. We were willing to believe
                        the first, but now we disbelieve the whole story. We can't go the <orig
                            reg="bellwether">bell-wether</orig> part. We know too much of the
                        colored folks for that. Why, if the biggest <orig reg="bellwether"
                            >bell-wether</orig> in the Democratic herd was to marshal the negroes
                        and tell them with all the well known eloquence of the "Local" himself, that
                        just across in the Democratic lot there was the finest grazing in the world,
                        and if they just went over with him they could get all they wanted for
                        nothing, do you think that a single one would be fool enough to believe him?
                        No, not one, unless he is far more stupid than any we know.</p>

                    <p>The "Local" further told his readers that "we indulge in vehement
                        denunciations of the negroes who dare assert their independence," that "we
                        instruct our pupils"--who are they pray?--"to murder the man who shows the
                        slightest symptoms of flinching from the support of the Radical party," that
                        "we cried lustily in the meeting, when one of the negroes asked to have his
                        name erased from the roll, 'put him out', 'kill him,'" &amp;c. Who ever
                        heard of a Local cutting a story so fat as that? Why if we denounced the
                        negroes who assert their independence we would denounce them <emph
                            rend="italic">en masse</emph>, for in a body they repudiate the
                        Democracy and all their wiles. On the contrary we applaud and admire their
                        independence. As to inviting them to murder any who may not agree with them
                        in politics, the murdering of the poor negro has so long been the exclusive
                        work of the Democratic party that they have for many years regarded it as an
                        indefeasible right, and the obstacles which the Fifteenth Amendment puts in
                        the way of their exercising this truly Democratic amusement is the ground of
                        their main objection to its incorporation in the Constitution. But after the
                            <orig reg="bellwether">bell-wether</orig> story we do not deem it
                        necessary to enter any specific denial to anything the "Local" has said.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial answers accusations by the <emph rend="italics"
                    >Spirit</emph>. The author denies that Republicans are exploiting black voters,
                    stating that blacks hated the Democratic party and were too independent minded
                    to be manipulated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>His Honor Judge King presided until Wednesday, when His Honor Judge Rowe took
                        his seat and presided during the remainder of the week. The following cases
                        were disposed of:</p>

                    <p>Jere Cook, Trustee of Eliza Cook, vs. Daniel Palmer.--Feigned issue to try
                        the validity of Judgment No. 120 of January term, 1869, for $3000. Jury not
                        being able to agree was discharged.</p>

                    <p>Frederick Guyer vs. William Kaiser.--Summons Case in Trover and Conversion.
                        Defendant plead not guilty. Jury found for defendant.</p>

                    <p>Emanuel Sites vs. Emanuel Kuhn, Executor of Jacob Sites, dec'd.--Summons Case
                        in Assumpsit. Jury found for plaintiff, $150.</p>

                    <p>John W. Sollenberger, Trustee of Jacob L. Wingert, vs. Ephram Shank.--Appeal
                        from judgment of S.M. Armstrong, Esq., for $87.50. Jury found for plaintiff
                        $94.50.</p>

                    <p>Samuel Reisher vs. George H. Storm and Jacob Hatmaker.--Appeal by defendants
                        from judgment of S.M. Armstrong, Esq., for $51.80. Jury found for
                        defendants.</p>

                    <p>W.W. Jones vs. Andrew Baker, J.R. Smith and J.M. Brown.--Summons Case in
                        Assumpsit, founded on promissory note dated Oct. 1st, 1868, payable in 60
                        days after date, for $375. Jury found for plaintiff, $125.42.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaiser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sites</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sites</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Ephram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Storm</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hatmaker</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This report lists the cases - mostly civil - and verdicts of the county
                    court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Horticultural Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society will hold an exhibit in
                    Repository Hall in June. Supporters in Philadelphia and in Franklin donated
                    money for premiums. The Chambersburg Nursery Association will give $25 worth of
                    trees, shrubs, and flowers to the resident who keeps the neatest yard during the
                    summer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Assault and Battery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiley</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiley</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An African American woman named Margaret Wiley was beaten by her husband
                    James Wiley while aboard the train. "Mrs. Wiley, it appears, did not enjoy the
                    felicities of married life, and had determined to leave her lord and master. She
                    purchased a ticket for Carlisle and after the train had started her husband
                    entered the car she was in, and without ceremony commenced beating her." Justice
                    Armstrong issued a warrant for his arrest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chesnutwood</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper warns that Dr. A. C. Wood, consulting physician of Dr. Allen, is
                    a "humbug and swindler." Wood was in town selling his "Lightning Cure" when he
                    was recognized by Capt. Kyner as Dr. Augustus Chesnutwood who, a few years ago,
                    absconded from Orrstown, leaving his landlord in the lurch.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Another Veteran Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sgt. Benjamin Wallace died on April 14th after suffering a short illness.
                    "He was among the best of Franklin county's soldiers in the late war, having
                    served four years and six months in the 11th Pennsylvania cavalry. When duty
                    called he was at his post. Those who knew him as a soldier, praise him as such
                    in the highest terms. As a citizen he was beloved by all who had formed his
                    acquaintance, for his kindness of heart and genial disposition."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seidenstricker</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sgt. A. Seidenstricker, a veteran of Hancock's Corps, has purchased the
                    Franklin Club Room, in Repository Hall, from John Gelwicks. Seidenstricker has
                    years of experience in the restaurant business and promises to cater wll to the
                    public.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The governor has approved a measure allowing the supervisor of Franklin
                    County to levy and collect an additional road tax.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Trouble on the Railroad</head>
                <origin>Mercersburg Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A laborer's strike for higher wages interrupted work on the railroad from
                    Mercersburg. All were paid off and went back to work with the exception of a
                    dozen or so men who went looking for work elsewhere.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Bollinger and Thomas H. Wallace, both of Greenvillage, leave for the
                    far west on May 2nd. They plan to tour Salt Lake City and report on their
                    journey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appenzeller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Appenzeller, a "highly respected citizen" of Greencastle, died on
                    April 18th. He was 54 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Robinson of McConnellsburg was admitted to practice in the courts
                    of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lessig</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorden</ln>
                        <fn>A. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin Taylor of Dry Run and Miss Martha Lessig from near Carrick were
                    married on April 14th by the Rev. A. Smith Gorden.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Maria Reynolds died in Mercersburg on April 18th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shetter</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Shetter died in the Indian Queen Hotel in Chambersburg on April
                    23rd. He had reached "an advanced age."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.04.27.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
