
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.08.31">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/06/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-08-31">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.08.31.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.08.31.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Campaign Repository</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>In our local columns, see the prospectus of the Campaign REPOSITORY. We
                        intend with the aid of the friends of the Republican cause to send into the
                        county a thousand copies of the REPOSITORY every week in addition to our
                        regular list. We wish to do this solely for the advantages of the party and
                        not for our own profit, and have therefore put the price down to the lowest
                        figure. The great effort of the Democracy in the present campaign will be
                        directed to the election of their candidates for Congress. They have
                        declared their intention to concentrate all their power throughout the
                        States to this end, and their plan is to allow strong Republican districts
                        to go without a contest, and to bend all their energies to carry Republican
                        districts which gave small majorities at the last election. The Sixteenth
                        District is one of those in which they hope to elect a Democrat.
                        Unfortunately for their purposes they have nominated a man who was a traitor
                        during the war, and is a notorious Free Trader now, but unless his
                        objectionable record and his odious principles are fully exposed they will
                        try to deceive the people into the belief that he is neither of these.</p>

                    <p>We want the help and assistance of all true and earnest friends of the
                        Republican cause to aid us in giving the wildest publicity to the real
                        political character and conduct of Benjamin F. <orig reg="Meyers"
                        >Myers</orig>, and believe that in so doing they will give material aid to
                        the cause of their party. We want clubs organized in every township for the
                        Campaign REPOSITORY, and we want particularly that those who do not now
                        receive a county paper be supplied with it. If there are any who can not
                        afford to pay for it let the money be raised in the township, so that no one
                        shall be found without a newspaper who is willing to receive and read one.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> announces its intention to
                    distribute an extra 1,000 copies of its paper in order to expose the Democratic
                    nominee for Congress as a traitor and a "notorious Free Trader."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Strange Anomoly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper wonders why the Democrats nominated B. F. Myers for Congress
                    since he is a free trader who opposses the tariff. Pennsylvania Democrats have
                    in the past insisted they favor protection.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Political Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Now is the time to take note of the political situation in Franklin county.
                        The whole ticket to be voted for this fall by each party has been chosen,
                        County Legislative and Congressional.</p>

                    <p>In the last named the Republican Conference has not yet met, but the choice
                        of a candidate has been as clearly settled as if it had. A majority of the
                        five counties have already declared for Hon. John Cessna. The Democratic
                        Conference which met at McConnellsburg, last week, closed its work by
                        putting in nomination Mr. B. F. <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig>, of Bedford.
                        It is settled therefore that the Congressional fight will be made by two men
                        both from Bedford county, and it may be truly stated, that this is the only
                        particular in which the two candidates are alike. In every political feature
                        of the present campaign they are as diametrically opposed as it is possible
                        to be.</p>

                    <p>We are glad that this is so. Mr. Cessna is a fair representative of the
                        radical Republican school, and Mr. <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig> is the
                        truest type of the Democracy named for Congress in the District. In no
                        particular do their views or principles so nearly run parallel as to allow
                        the members of the Republican party to vote for the other candidate without
                        doing violence to their party faith.</p>

                    <p>No other man in the District named in connection with this nomination could
                        so truly represent the National Democratic party as Mr. <orig reg="Meyers"
                            >Myers</orig>. In the rebellion he was a friend of the <orig
                            reg="Confederate">confederate</orig> cause, and never hesitated to
                        manifest as much sympathy with it as was consistent with personal safety.
                        His most bitter disappointments during the war were those which came of the
                        success of the loyal armies, and he did not conceal his satisfaction at
                        their reverses and defeats. He has opposed every measure for the restoration
                        of the South States inaugurated and carried out by a Republican
                        administration and Congress. He denounced the Emancipation Proclamation of
                        President Lincoln, the enfranchisement of the negroes of the rebel States,
                        and the adoption of the Fifteenth Amendment. He is the champion of the White
                        Man's Party today, which denies the validity of that Amendment, and declares
                        its determination to return the colored population back to a condition of
                        practical servitude if ever it should be restored to power. In all this,
                        which neither Mr. <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig>, nor his friends will
                        deny, he does not much differ from the majority of the other Democratic
                        leaders. But in one important particular he does differ vitally from a large
                        body of the democratic voters of the Sixteenth Congressional district. He is
                        the avowed and earnest advocate of the pernicious Free Trade doctrines,
                        which British gold and British influence are attempting to fasten upon the
                        labor and industry of this country. He is the enemy of every laborer in the
                        land, and would reduce the price of workmen's wages down to the low standard
                        of wages in Europe. He is the proprietor and Editor of the Bedford <emph
                            rend="italics">Gazette</emph>, and is also one of the owners and Editors
                        of the Harrisburg <emph rend="italics">Patriot</emph>, both of which papers
                        persistently oppose the policy of protecting and fostering manufacturing and
                        laboring interests of this country, and urge the removal of all duties from
                        foreign importations which have been imposed to help build up domestic
                        industry and enable manufacturers to give a fair day's wages for a fair
                        day's work. In this matter he is opposed to the interests of Democrats and
                        Republicans of this District alike, for their prosperity is largely bound up
                        in their labor. If that does not receive a fair compensation the industry of
                        the country must languish and die.</p>

                    <p>In every particular we have mentioned Mr. Cessna holds views opposed to those
                        of Mr. <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig>. At the beginning of the war he gave
                        all his <orig reg="energies">erergies</orig> to the Union cause, though he
                        did not cease to act with the Democratic party until that party declared
                        itself in sympathy with the rebellion. Then he openly and boldly disowned
                        it, and from that day to this he has not ceased to condemn its acts, and to
                        give his best efforts to defeat its ends.</p>

                    <p>We believe that we have not misrepresented Mr. <orig reg="Meyers"
                        >Myers</orig> in what we have written. We intend to present his political
                        record and views to the voters of this district during the campaign and we
                        are glad that both are so positively made and defined by himself that there
                        can be no mistaking them. At present we intended no more than a general
                        statement of his position. Hereafter we will speak more specifically.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> declares that Benjamin F. <orig
                        reg="Meyers">Myers</orig>, the Democratic nominee for Congress, sympathized
                    with the Confederacy, is opposed to the enfranchisement of freedmen, and is "the
                    enemy of every laborer in the land" because of his stance on free trade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>That Remonstrance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>If a forty pound shell were to fall upon the Court House pavement, without
                        warning, some evening when the steps are lined with Democratic politicians
                        earnestly discussing the approaching campaign, it would create no greater
                        consternation than did the <orig reg="dispatch">despatch</orig> from
                        M'Connellsburg on Thursday evening last, announcing the nomination of B. F.
                            <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig> by the Democratic Conference for
                        Congress. If the situation hadn't been so excessively ludicrous to
                        Republicans they could not have helped <orig reg="sympathizing"
                        >sympathyzing</orig> with the Democracy in their hope stricken dismay.
                        Before the Conference met, the cry had gone forth "give us any person but
                            <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig>. His war record will damn him, and his
                        Free Trade heresies will cause hopeless defeat," and so extreme was the
                        feeling that a remonstrance was actually got up embodying these objections,
                        and signed by thirty of the leading Democrats of Chambersburg, and by them
                        forwarded to the Conference to influence the Conferees against <orig
                            reg="Meyers">Myers</orig>. Indeed the very men who last winter pledged
                        themselves to the support of <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig>, joined in this
                        paper for his defeat, and though we condemn their insincerity we do not
                        wonder at their extraordinary conduct at this time. They did not think then
                        that <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig> stood any chance of nomination, and
                        gave the promise freely. But when it became probably, nay almost certain,
                        they saw it must bring inevitable defeat to the party in the District, and
                        in their despair they protested against it. With a few exceptions all the
                        leading Democrats in town signed the protest of remonstrance.</p>

                    <p>Now that <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig> is nominated their situation is
                        really pitiable. They are on record against him, yet they must support him.
                        Some of them had pledged themselves for him, then betrayed him, and now have
                        no alternative but to work and vote for him.</p>

                    <p>Perhaps the most miserable of the lot is Skinner, the Democratic candidate
                        for Assembly. <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig> had been particularly friendly
                        to Skinner, and had taken occasion in the <emph rend="italics"
                        >Patriot</emph> last winter and since to say all sorts of nice things about
                        him, but the latter, who is not famed for gratitude any more than he is for
                        political shrewdness, saw <orig reg="Meyers'">Myers'</orig> unpopularity,
                        and fearing it would drag him down too, was prominently instrumental in
                        getting signatures to the protest. Now that his plans have all "gang" wrong,
                        and his ingratitude and want of political shrewdness all exposed, and <orig
                            reg="Meyers">Myers</orig> the successful candidate, we will not
                        undertake to say what his feelings are. Political sins, like hens, will come
                        home to roost, and we fear that the fruits of Skinner's youthful folly and
                        mature ingratitude are rapidly wending their way homeward. He could not have
                        hoped to help himself if he had by such unfair means defeated <orig
                            reg="Meyers">Myers</orig>. For the latter would have become his enemy.
                        His present position is only worse than this in that he has made him his
                        enemy and yet has failed to keep him from the top of the ticket. Who will
                        say Democratic politics are not lovely in Franklin county?</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial suggests dissatisfaction and disunion among Democratic party
                    members at the nomination of Benjamin F. Meyers as the candidate for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that thirty leading Democrats of Franklin County
                    protested the nomination of Myers for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Nomination of Myers a Success</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper jokes that the nomination of Myers "delighted" Republicans and
                    pleased only some Democrats. Republicans are delighted because they feel they
                    can defeat the Democratic nominee for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Workingmen and Free Trade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that working men oppose free trade and are "beginning to
                    discriminate between their own interest and the success of the Democratic office
                    hunters."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Fifth Avenue and Shade Trees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"A Citizen" calls for the planting of shade trees along a street in
                    Chambersburg. He asserts that if Charles H. Taylor of the Franklin County Bank
                    offered subscriptions, then many private citizens woul;d contribute money toward
                    the project.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.08.31.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Republican County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimason</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Theodore M'Gowan announces that a meeting of the Republican County
                    Committee will be held in the office of Thomas J. Grimason on September 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>A meeting was held in the Council House, in the borough of Shippensburg, on
                        Thursday evening last, with a view to awaken an interest among the people of
                        that town in Mirimar railroad, of which notice has been made in these
                        columns. The meeting was called to order by placing Mr. S. S. Shryrock in
                        the chair. Mr. John Mifflin, of Columbia, Pa, the Engineer of the road,
                        spoke strongly in favor of the enterprise and set forth the advantages which
                        railroads had been in developing the resources of our country. Our townsman,
                        John Stewart, Esq., who happened at the meeting spoke encouragingly of the
                        project and presented as an illustration of the advantage which railroads
                        afford communities, the condition of our own valley prior to and since the
                        completion of the Cumberland Valley railroad. That thoroughfare had
                        contributed an immense degree to the activities of the valley, in enhancing
                        the value of property and promoting the comfort of the inhabitants along the
                        line of the road. Rich in deposits of iron ore as is the region of country
                        through which it is proposed to build the Mirimar railroad that line of
                        travel would tend to the development of those mines of wealth and in various
                        ways add to the enterprise and prosperity of the entire valley. At the
                        conclusion of Mr. Stewart's remarks, Mr. Moor again rose and gave in detail
                        the results of the efforts thus far put forth in procuring subscriptions to
                        the stock. In the brief time that had been given to that work subscriptions
                        to the amount of one hundred and eighty-seven thousand dollars had been
                        secured, and that the entire stock would be taken in a short time he had not
                        a shadow of a doubt. The road could not fail to pay and pay well. It was a
                        well established fact that the region of country lying on the south side of
                        Cumberland Valley was the richest and most productive land in the valley;
                        and he spoke within bounds when he said that in addition to ordinary
                        articles of transportation, at least five hundred tons of ore would daily
                        pass over the road to Harrisburg and other cities, thereby affording not
                        only an immediate source of revenue to the road, but at the same time add
                        very materially to the wealth of the owners of the numerous iron ore mines
                        contiguous to the road. Mr. Moor urged upon the people of Shippensburg the
                        importance to them of having the Mirimar railroad continued to that place
                        and solicited their aid and hearty <orig reg="cooperation">co
                        operation</orig> in the work.</p>

                    <p>The irrepressible President of the Mirimar railroad, Col. D. V. Ahl, was
                        present at the meeting, laboring with his usual zeal in behalf of the
                        enterprise. Owing to the inclemency of the weather the attendance at the
                        meeting was small but, we are informed that the people of that ancient town
                        manifest considerable interest in the object of the meeting. Should a
                        reasonable amount of the stock of the Mirimar railroad be taken by the
                        people of Shippensburg, the road will doubtless be extended to that town.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryrock</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moor</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mifflin</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ahl</ln>
                        <fn>D. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article notes a recent meeting in which railroad enthusiasts presented
                    the benefits of establishing a new line in the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Melancholy Event</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. M'Clure, wife of A. K. M'Clure, was taken "in a deplorable condition
                    of insanity" to Kirkbride's Insane Asylum in Philadelphia on August 22nd. "For
                    some months past she manifested alarming indications of disordered
                    intelligence." "This sad event will bring sorrow to our community, where Mrs.
                    M'C. is highly esteemed for her many social and personal virtues. She was
                    endowed with high natural powers of intellect, which she cultivated carefully;
                    was always foremost in promoting movements for the general good, was hospitable
                    to a proverb, and benevolent and beneficant to a degree that makes her name
                    cherished by the indigent wherever she has resided."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Fair Company has issued a list of prizes for this years
                    fair. The paper encourages Franklin County citizens to support the event.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Reformed Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A festival will be held in the yard in front of the Reformed Church of St.
                    Thomas on Friday and Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Mercersburg Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>THE <emph rend="italics">Mercersburg Journal</emph> says that the quiet of
                        the village was disturbed on last Saturday night by a free fight,
                        participated in by the railroad laborers on one hand and the colored people
                        on the other, which resulted in some cracked heads and bloody noses. It adds
                        that a feud has existed between the workmen and colored people for some
                        time, but assigns no reason for the bad blood, and makes no charges against
                        either party as causing or instigating the difficulty. We fear that our
                        Milesian friends are a little unreasonable in their conduct towards the
                        "bloody negers," and can't resist going in and giving the "divels of
                        spalpeens a sound bating."</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This news item from the <emph rend="italics">Mercersburg Journal</emph>
                    reports that a fight broke out between railroad workers and blacks and further
                    notes that "a feud has existed between the workmen and colored people for some
                    time."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Higgins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that the man killed when thrown by his horse was not
                    named Duffield as previously reported. His name was Higgins and he resided with
                    James Duffield. He was carrying some plow irons to the blacksmith shop when one
                    struck the side of his horse, causing it to become unmanageable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Protracted Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A protracted meeting will be held in the Bethel Church of God beginning on
                    September 2nd. A number of distinguished ministers are expected to be present,
                    including Rev. P. D. Collins, known popularly as the "Indian Preacher." Members
                    of all denominations are invited to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Washabaugh's Brewery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin Ludwig has purchased the Washabaugh Brewery from the Chambersburg
                    Woolen Manufacturing Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Correction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The reunion of the 77th Pa. Vols. will be held on Chambersburg on October
                    6th, not the 13th. The 6th coincides with the fair, making it a convenient time
                    to hold the event.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lutheran Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. L. A. Gotwald will preach in services at the Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carolus</ln>
                        <fn>Curtis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Curtis M. Carolus and Miss Susan Brown, both of Franklin, were married on
                    August 25th at the residence of Mr. Hoke by the Rev. Z. A. Colestock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mead</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Josiah Mead died in Chambersburg on August 26th. He was 67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Helen Seibert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Helen Seibert Spangler, daughter of Jacob and Ann E. Spangler, died in
                    Chambersburg on August 30th. She was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodenhaver</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodenhaver</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodenhaver</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Annie Rodenhaver, daughter of Henry and Anna M. Rodenhaver, died on August
                    13th. She was 7 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.08.31.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
