
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.04.13">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/29/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-04-13">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.04.13.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.04.13.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Lesson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>During the past week, quietly, unobtrusively and without excitement has been
                        witnessed in several of the States the spectacle which establishes the fact
                        that our government is in practice, as well as in theory, one of equal
                        rights. Close upon the proclamation of the Secretary of State announcing the
                        adoption of the Fifteenth Amendment, came municipal elections in Ohio,
                        Missouri, Illinois and other States, and the recently enfranchised citizens
                        mingled with their white brethren at the polls and deposited their ballots,
                        the badges of their manhood. The elections passed off so quietly and orderly
                        that in spite of the novelty of negroes voting except in the places where
                        the elections were held, there was scarcely a feeling of curiosity, much
                        less of excitement manifested.</p>

                    <p>And yet scarcely any other event in the history of our country ought to give
                        greater satisfaction than this, and no other thing can be pointed to which
                        so clearly proves the practice of our government to conform to the high
                        standard of equal rights which we claim for it before other nations. It is
                        hard to believe, now that the rights of the humblest no matter what his
                        color or condition are freely conceded and protected too, that this end was
                        reached through rivers of blood and years of fierce conflict; that a matter
                        so eminently just and right should have been disputed at all, and that while
                        freely admitting the principle in our declaration of rights we should have
                        so obstinately and persistently resisted it in practice. But truth and right
                        have triumphed in the adoption of the Fifteenth Amendment and not only in
                        our country but throughout the civilized world will this victory be felt.
                        Human bondage may still exist, but its days are numbered. The end is no
                        longer doubtful nor the result uncertain. Let us rejoice that four millions
                        of slaves, enslaved because their skins were not so fair as ours, though of
                        the whiteness of their hearts we could not judge, have been made freemen in
                        one day, and not only made freemen, but armed also with the power to protect
                        themselves in their freedom. A great monster of crime has been met and
                        vanquished in our land, and the good results of its overthrow do not end
                        with it. The spirit of evil is hundred-handed and in destroying slavery one
                        of the hands has been cut off. It has lost so much power and is thereby so
                        much less able to withstand the force of truth and right in every future
                        conflict. With slavery destroyed, brutal ignorance and poverty must
                        disappear. Abject want and besotted ignorance are incompatible with the
                        condition of freemen. As these evils grow less, so do others depending upon
                        them. Injustice, oppression and tyranny will still abound, but their shadows
                        must grow smaller and smaller as the light of intelligence spreads, and the
                        protection of the State is thrown around the citizen.</p>

                    <p>The colored race is armed with the ballot. Every colored male citizen has a
                        voice and a vote in the framing of laws and the choice of rulers, with no
                        restrictions except such as are imposed on the whites also, and may
                        rightfully aspire to any position in the land. Though it required no
                        prophetic vision to foretell the coming of this event, since the close of
                        the war, one of the great political parties persistently refused to see it,
                        and strove as if mad to build insuperable, obstacles between itself and the
                        colored voters. Not satisfied that the war to perpetuate slavery was waged
                        wholly by the Democratic party, and though it resulted in striking the
                        chains off of every slave in the land, the Democracy of the North resisted
                        step by step the ratification of the Fifteenth Amendment, and did not cease
                        when it was morally certain of accomplishment. It is safe to assert that as
                        a party the Democracy have never made a single record in favor of impartial
                        justice and equal rights. On the contrary every department of the government
                        under Democratic rule was subverted to the end of perpetuating and building
                        up negro slavery. The Supreme Court inspired by the slave Democracy so far
                        forgot the end of its being as to make the declaration that the negro had no
                        rights which the white man was bound to respect, and thus commit a
                        government based on equal justice and equal rights to a policy of the
                        blackest injustice and the foulest oppression. Nor did Congress or the
                        Executive, under the same baleful influence, hesitate to make laws and
                        execute them in pursuance of the same end.</p>

                    <p>But in spite of its long catalogue of wrongs and injustice to the colored
                        race, universal suffrage is accomplished, and the Democratic party must face
                        a million of newly made freemen with a freemans' weapons in their hands, and
                        the fact seared into their memories that when they were powerless to help
                        themselves and could only beg for justice it never ceased in its efforts to
                        bind the chains of slavery tighter upon their limbs. To the Democracy the
                        colored race owes nothing but hatred, life long unceasing hatred.--Words are
                        powerless to describe the bitterness, the contempt, the scorn with which
                        they spoke and wrote of the "despised race," and heaped insult upon
                        servitude. Even their claim to humanity was denied. They were called
                        beastlike, besotted, stupid, ignorant, only fit for a state of slavery. But
                        why repeat these things? The greater the truth of these assertions, the
                        greater their own crime, for, it was they who made them what they were, and
                        it is too recent for them to be forgotten or denied. No wonder the Democracy
                        stand paralyzed in presence of the Fifteenth Amendment. It is a two-edged
                        sword which they have spent years in sharpening for their own destruction,
                        and they fully perceive and appreciate the danger of their situation. One
                        thing they have clearly resolved upon, and that is that the newly
                        enfranchised citizens are a power, and, as such must be respected, but it is
                        yet a little too soon, in the face of a century of party oppression, to take
                        them to their embrace and tell them in glowing terms how they have always
                        been the real friends of the black man. This will come, however, and we warn
                        the colored voters now, that before the October election they will witness
                        and be prepared to verify our prediction.--Why, mark the difference in their
                        conduct, already, all over the country. The negroes vote without
                        interference or impediment even in strong Democratic precincts. In New York,
                        where but a few years ago the highly civilized Irish citizens murdered them
                        in the streets by the hundred, their processions parade unmolested and
                        respected, and none seem more anxious to protect their rights than the
                        Democratic city authorities. Even the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>,
                        which so loved to gather and publish every tit-bit of slander and shame
                        against the negro, and did not hesitate to fabricate such when needed, is
                        strangely silent now. Once there was scarcely a single issue of the paper
                        which failed to detail, with disgusting minuteness, some brutal and horrible
                        crime, either real or fictitious, perpetrated by a colored man, and always
                        accompanied with the appeal to their readers that this was the kind of beast
                        that the Radicals wished to make their political and social equal. But there
                        is none of that now. The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> is as inoffensive
                        as the most thorough Radical journal in the land. Other Democratic papers in
                        this Congressional district pursue the same course. The Bedford <emph
                            rend="italic">Gazette</emph>, a willing, but weak imitation of Brick
                        Pomeroy, has grown as gentle as a sucking dove.</p>

                    <p>In a short time these journals will begin to talk. They have not changed, but
                        the circumstances have. They hate and despise the negro still, but the negro
                        is not the helpless creature he once was. He is a man and stands forth armed
                        with the badge of manhood. They despise the negro, but they respect his
                        power. Hence they would conciliate it and if possible use it. The colored
                        race cannot be deceived in this matter. The record the Democratic party has
                        made through the long years of oppression and shame cannot be effaced in so
                        short a time, and the minds of the newly enfranchised are wonderfully clear
                        as to who their deliverers. They have already given abundant evidence of
                        their proper understanding of the real situation, and we have no fear as to
                        the manner they will exercise their newly acquired power. They are not
                        vindictive, as their past history has established, but they are just.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor praises the passage of the Fifteenth Amendment and congratulates
                    blacks on their new-found political voice. At the same time, he denounces the
                    Democrats for all the woes of slavery and ridicules their sudden kindness to
                    blacks now that the latter have the vote. Finally, he predicts that blacks will
                    always remain true to the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.04.13.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. Agnew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Keehan</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lenegan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindline</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Will S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grier</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. Logan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curriden</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pauli</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clellan</ln>
                        <fn>Jack</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lanahan</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>Enos B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of members of the First Presbyterian Church wrote an open letter
                    praising the service of Rev. J. Agnew Crawford. He recently turned down a more
                    lucrative offer to stay in Chambersburg, where he is making less money than he
                    should. The congregation members express their wish to retain him if at all
                    possible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>More About the Sneak Thieves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alfred</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alfred and Collins, the two men arrested for theft at the Montgomery House,
                    also stand accused of robbing Dr. Clugston's store in Doylesburg of $800. They
                    had some of his property in their posession and the rest was recovered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grossman</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weict</ln>
                        <fn>W. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Filson</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An exhibition of drawings done by the students of John H. Grossman was held
                    in the school room at Marion on April 8th. Addresses were delivered by a number
                    of prominent individuals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. G. Schaff will hold religious services in his house on Sunday and
                    Rev. J. P. Bishop will preach in the evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Remp</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Erhart</ln>
                        <fn>T. John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sirike</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suters</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heart</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perry</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loudenslager</ln>
                        <fn>P. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindner</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loudenslager</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. E. Culbertson installed a number of officers of Chambersburg Lodge No.
                    175, I.O.O.F.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtzworth</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>George G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Copp</ln>
                        <fn>J. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenwood</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mong</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>F. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>D. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Columbus Lodge No. 75, I.O.O.F., installed a number of officers on
                    Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Temperance Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>J. Everist Cathell, "the Boy Orator of the Potomac," will speak in the
                    Court House on the subject of Total Abstinence. He is an agent of the Grand
                    Division of the Sons of Temperance and hopes to organize a chapter in
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Just Act</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Directors of the Poor, at their last meeting, increased the pay of the
                    physician by $200. The paper endorses the move, and praises Dr. Boyle who
                    presently holds the post.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Clugston thanks Chief of Police Capt. Houser for helping aprehend the
                    thieves and recovering the merchandise stolen from his store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three rowdy drunks abused an African American man on Market street last
                    week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staley</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip Reilly of Waynesboro and Mrs. Ellen Staley of Maryland were married
                    on March 15th by the Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Werner</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Werner and Miss Sarah C. Wilkeson, daughter of Jacob Wilkeson, both
                    of Guilford, were married on April 5th by the Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Duncan died near Fayetteville on March 27th. She was 74 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.04.13.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
