
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.12.14">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/10/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-12-14">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.12.14.01" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints President Grant's annual message to Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.12.14.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Educational Interests</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The facilities for educating the rising generation in this fair and
                        flourishing portion of our State - the Cumberland Valley - are being rapidly
                        brought to a high degree of perfection. From the Susquehanna to the Potomac,
                        and thence South under the name of Shenandoah Valley, stretches as fine a
                        vale of country as can greet the eye of the traveler. The Cumberland Valley
                        Railroad through the heart of the valley, completed as far south as
                        Hagerstown, and in progress of completion indefinitely south, gives to this
                        section of country a prominence which must attract the attention of those
                        who desire to settle on a great line of travel, and at the same time to be
                        surrounded with all the advantages of the agricultural resources and
                        manufacturing conveniences. But especially does our valley invite the
                        attention of those who desire the very best facilities for the education of
                        their children.</p>

                    <p>In addition to the flourishing condition of the common schools in Franklin
                        and Cumberland counties, which was evidenced by the very full attendance of
                        the teachers in both counties at the County Institutes, and the very general
                        desire of the enlightened citizens of the two counties to still further
                        elevate their schools, until in every district a well regulated and well
                        taught school shall furnish a suitable education to those who are unprepared
                        to attend school from home; we say that, in addition to the common schools,
                        nearly every town and village in the valley has one or more well supported
                        and well taught select <orig reg="schools">schoolr</orig>, academy, or
                        female seminary. Mechanicsburg has her academy and female seminary. Carlisle
                        has Dickinson College, whose reputation as a literary institution is well
                        sustained under its present president, Dr. Dashiel. Shippensburg is now
                        founding and will soon push to completion a first class Normal school, under
                        the act of Assembly providing for State Normal schools. This Normal school
                        district, comprising the counties of Adams, Cumberland, Franklin, Bedford,
                        Fulton, Huntingdon and Blair is able and will no doubt put this school on a
                        firm foundation, and will make it a school from which thoroughly trained
                        teachers will be furnished to our common schools. Chambersburg has already
                        in successful operation an academy for boys, in which, they can be fitted
                        for an advanced class in any of our colleges. Here also has been founded the
                        Wilson Female College which has opened with a marked appearance of success.
                        Mercersburg also has a college, which will, as soon as the new railroad
                        connecting the point with the Cumberland Valley railroad is completed,
                        command a liberal share of patronage. All these flourishing institutions
                        offer to our citizens, and to those who may be on the lookout for
                        educational advantages the very finest, inducements to continue, or to make
                        their residence in Cumberland Valley. Our resources, both in regard to
                        agriculture and other industrial pursuits, will bear a much heavier
                        population than we now have, and the prices of property offer great
                        inducements to those in other portions of our State who are not so well
                        situated in regard to any of the interests to which we have alluded.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article touts the quantity and quality of educational institutions in
                    the surrounding area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The President's Message is given in our columns this week in full. It is the
                        plain, practical production of a straight forward, upright Executive, and is
                        concise, direct and clear, and in most particulars must be satisfactory to
                        the people. We have already given a large space to the comments made by the
                        press of both parties upon the message, and there is therefore little reason
                        why we should discuss it at length. Few Executives could point with more
                        satisfaction to the results of a year's work than can President Grant to the
                        facts and figures of last year's financial management, and few would have
                        done it with more modesty than he has. In less than two years his
                        administration has placed the credit of the nation, shattered and shaken by
                        Johnson, alongside of the highest and best in Europe. And this has been done
                        too without detriment or damage to the domestic interests of the country.
                        The country never was more prosperous than last year, and never gave better
                        assurance of continued <orig reg="prosperity">prospesity</orig> than now.
                        While on this subject the President administered some plain talk on the
                        subject of "revenue reform" which delighted the people, and which the
                        reformers can put in their pipes and smoke. Our relations to other nations
                        were briefly discussed. The Alabama claims do not seem to be any nearer a
                        settlement than they were a year ago, nor does there seem to have been any
                        effort made to push them to a settlement. The President suggests that the
                        question would be greatly simplified if the Government were to settle the
                        claims for losses with individual claimants, and thus have the whole case
                        for adjustment in its own hands. Great care has been taken to preserve
                        intact the long established policy of the United State with regard to
                        European complications. Strict impartiality has been exercised towards
                        France and Prussia and the highest respect of both people has been
                        preserved.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> praises President Grant for his
                    handling of the nation's finances and other affairs of state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.12.14.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> of last week fabricated the following.</p>

                    <p>During the campaign, the Radical leaders of Franklin County were willing to
                        foot all the bills the payment of which was necessary to qualify the negroes
                        to vote. All they asked of them was that they should vote for Cessna and the
                        whole ticket. Accordingly in the Borough of Chambersburg, out of the
                        $100,000 corruption fund, they paid the taxes of over two hundred colored
                        suffragists. All but a few who were property holders, were assessed
                        twenty-eight cents and this was the amount that had to be forthcoming in
                        every case.</p>

                    <p>Now, all this was cheerfully paid under the expectation and in the hope of a
                        glorious triumph. But when defeat was their lot instead of victory, they
                        began to regret the useless expenditure of this money, and, after casting
                        about for some time to reimburse themselves, they hit upon the idea of
                        assessing each colored voter <emph rend="italics">seventy-five cents</emph>.
                        They knew that a large portion of them could not, and would not pay
                        anything, and they thought that by assessing three quarters of a dollar,
                        they might raise from those who were able to pay as much as they had
                        expended for all. Colored agents were selected to go among the negroes and
                        collect this assessment. One of these agents got from the poor darkies for
                        this purpose about <emph rend="italics">twenty dollars</emph> which he
                        "salted down" in his own pockets, saying, "if I hab to do de dirty work,
                        I'se gwine to be paid for it.</p>

                    <p>The darkies say it isn't <emph rend="italics">cheap</emph> work voting the
                        Radical ticket.</p>

                    <p>For ourselves we would not deem it necessary to deny such a palpable
                        falsehood, but at the request of several of the most responsible colored men
                        of Chambersburg we pronounce it just what it is, an unmitigated lie. Since
                        the article appeared in the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> there has
                        been such a change in that office as will probably prevent the publication
                        of such slanders hereafter. The <emph rend="italics">attache</emph> of the
                            <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> who furnished such stories as the
                        above and was thought by many to have written them, was a few days ago
                        arrested by the proprietors and put under bonds for his appearance at the
                        next term of court, on the charge of stealing the newspapers of that
                        establishment and selling them.</p>

                    <p>It is probable that with his withdrawal from the <emph rend="italics"
                        >Spirit</emph> newspaper there will be an end of those slanderous articles
                        upon his people.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> denies the Spirit's accusation
                    that Republican agents first tried to bribe black voters and then, after the
                    election, attempted to make the money back.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Marshall Literary Society of Mercersburg College will hold their fifth
                    anniversary celebration in the Reformed Church on December 21st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>George D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George D. Bonebrake of Quincy and Miss Mary A. Funk of New Guilford were
                    married in Chambersburg on December 8th by the Rev. J. Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buhrman</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beam</ln>
                        <fn>Beckie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kieffer</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Hiram M. Buhrman of Quincy and Miss Beckie Beam of Guilford were
                    married at the Adams House, Greencastle, on November 24th by the Rev. M.
                    Kieffer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>John O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Honoddle</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kieffer</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John O. Hoover and Miss Ann Honoddle, both of Waynesboro, were married on
                    December 6th by the Rev. M. Kieffer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Himes</ln>
                        <fn>James J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Rosie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James J. Himes of Massachusetts and Mrs. Rosie J. Skinner of Dry Run were
                    married on November 22nd by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rummell</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Kate A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William M. Rummell of Shirleysburg and Miss Kate A. Shearer, daughter of
                    Elias Shearer of Spring Garden Mills, were married on November 24th by the Rev.
                    William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myer</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alfred H. Myer of Fayetteville and Miss Elizabeth Winger from near
                    Chambersburg were married on December 8th at the residence of the bride's
                    father, Rev. Michael Winger, by Rev. H. C. Lesher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John A. Jacobs died in Chambersburg on December 4th. He was 66 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Ruhamah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Ruhamah Campbell died at Spring Run on November 28th. She was 53 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.12.14.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
