
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.03.23">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/29/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-03-23">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.23.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.23.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Gentleman from Africa</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Several years ago, during the session of Congress, a number of members from
                        both the North and South were at dinner together at Willard's. Several of
                        the Southerners, who were never unconscious of the singular fact that they
                        were Congressmen, addressed one another repeatedly as "The gentleman from
                        Mississippi," "The gentleman from South Carolina," &amp;c., the form of
                        address common to legislative halls, but a silly affectation elsewhere.
                        Thaddeus Stevens, we think it was, becoming more and more disgusted, at last
                        turned to a colored waiter and said, loud enough to be heard by the entire
                        table, "Will the gentleman from Africa please hand me a glass of water." Of
                        course this "set the table on a roar," to the infinite discomfiture of the
                        Southern brethren. Wondrous changes have transpired since then. <orig
                            reg="Today">To-day</orig> the "gentleman from Africa" is on the floor of
                        the Senate. In striking contrast with the fair European faces around him,
                        his sable complexion proclaims him a child of Africa, but they call him "the
                        gentleman from Mississippi." Ten years ago "the gentleman from Mississippi"
                        walked forth from his place in that chamber in the person of Jefferson
                        Davis, his soul bartered for the promised reward of treason, and his mouth
                        stained with its utterance. He went forth to set his life and fame upon a
                        cast. He threw from him as worthless things his honor, his truth, the sacred
                        trust which his country had committed to him as her legislator, and went
                        forth to let loose the dogs of war, to bear the torch and guide the steel to
                        the homes and hearts of his countrymen; all this to perpetuate the infamy of
                        human slavery and maintain the brutal doctrine that the test of manhood is
                        the color of the skin, and for this he shall bear the mark of Cain until the
                        earth shall kindly hide him in her bosom. With terrible significance "the
                        gentleman from Mississippi" returns to his place in the person of Mr.
                        Revels, one of the despised race, whose chains melted away in the heat which
                        was meant to weld them more firmly.</p>

                    <p>Who would have thought our Democratic friends would support themselves as
                        they have under this affliction. "The nigger in Congress!" they used to cry,
                        and you would have thought something terrible would follow such a
                        consummation. But they have all survived it; they really have.</p>

                    <p>Saulsbury looked a little pale the first few days, and used several bottles
                        of perfumery, but he is beginning to get his color again.</p>

                    <p>Some few have not yet succeeded in bringing back their noses to the normal
                        angle of elevation, but most of them will come straight. We are surprised to
                        see what a degree of composure the Democracy at home have preserved. It was
                        more excited over the burning of the town, that little misdemeanor of their
                        Southern brethren.</p>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> has done some coughing and sneezing
                        over the nigger in Congress, but it has been as seriously affected before,
                        and we have strong hopes for it this time. We congratulate it that it has
                        borne it so well. Let it bear in mind that the negroes will soon have a vote
                        and that it will assist wonderfully to preserve its composure. "Ay! there's
                        the rub."</p>

                    <p>Right behind Mr. Revels as he goes to his place in the Senate, there comes
                        the stately procession of thirty States hearing the Fifteenth Amendment to
                        its place in the Constitution, and while he takes the oath to support that
                        Constitution, they swear that his race shall have the rights of citizenship.
                        And now endowed with the franchise, the negro becomes less obnoxious.</p>

                    <p>Indeed, the Democracy tips its hat and says, "The gentleman from Africa has
                        my best wishes. We have met before, sir. I have always been your friend;
                        won't you do me the favor to vote this ticket?" The negroes hardly see it in
                        that light. They don't reciprocate the gushing affection of the Democracy
                        and we see the humiliating spectacle of a once honorable and powerful party
                        supplicating the favor of the race it has so long and cruelly abused. But
                        Mr. Revels has made a speech. Yes, this man, but little higher than the
                        monkey, they say, has made a speech, they would like to say Mr. Sumner wrote
                        for him, and which would do credit to any member of the Senate under similar
                        circumstances. Every means will no doubt be used to debauch the newly
                        enfranchised citizens, and induce them to vote with their life-long enemies.
                        In some cases they may be successful, but we have faith enough in their
                        intelligence and integrity to believe that they will, almost to a man, help
                        to keep moving this great engine of progress, the Republican party, which
                        has raised them to their present dignity, and which promises for them, yet
                        the full fruition of an educated and refined manhood.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial sarcastically notes Democratic attempts to gain the favor of
                    blacks now that the latter can vote. The author predicts that blacks will see
                    through the mockery and vote with their true allies, the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Word on the Border Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>You know the anxiety felt by the people of Franklin county in relation to the
                        passage of the Border Claim bill now before the Legislature. You know--and
                        every one here knows--that if some bill for the relief of the sufferers be
                        not passed this session, financial ruin will speedily follow to many of our
                        citizens. Their losses were so great and the demands upon them are now so
                        pressing, that they cannot much longer bear up unless relief of some kind be
                        afforded them.</p>

                    <p>Under these circumstances, is it not remarkable that there are some persons
                        in our midst who are so heartless and so regardless of the calamities
                        pressing upon their neighbors, as to desire to defeat the legislation asked
                        for; and to secure their ends join our opponents from abroad in <emph
                            rend="italic">lying and misrepresentations</emph> of what has been done,
                        and is to be done, to obtain remuneration for our people.</p>

                    <p>To show your readers, and the sufferers of the county, how these <emph
                            rend="italic">lying</emph>, back-biting knaves in their midst are
                        acting, I have cut out of the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Press</emph>
                        of last Saturday, the 19th inst., the following, which I wish you to insert
                        entire in your paper:</p>

                    <p>GREENCASTLE, March 16, 1870</p>
                    <p>I have been watching with some interest the progress of the border claims
                        bill, how before our Legislature, as well as the efforts made by the
                        different papers for and against. Your own effort has been severe--mistaken
                        in some respects, and very nearly correct in others, although denied by our
                        county papers. I refer to the charge that many of the claims have been
                        bought up, and that the real sufferer will get but little benefit if the
                        bill does pass. You are mistaken that these claims have been bought to any
                        considerable amount; but that the real sufferer will get but little is true,
                        if the bill passes in its present form. The money is to be put into the
                        hands of gentlemen named in the bill (all lawyers) who have the power to cut
                        down the amount of damages already allowed by commissioners appointed by the
                        State, (and it is fair to think their awards are just and correct), but they
                        cannot increase the amount, judging by the blanks sent me to be filled
                        before a magistrate, appointing an attorney to collect the amount of my
                        claim. On first reading, twenty <orig reg="percent">per cent</orig> is the
                        amount asked, but, on a second and more careful reading, I agree to pay all
                        expenses attending the collecting of my claim in addition to the twenty
                            <orig reg="percent">per cent</orig>. It is well understood that those
                        who refuse to be thus imposed upon get nothing, as their claims will not
                        pass the committee, and many who have not lost one dollar get the money.
                        That we along the border have suffered heavily, is true and that either the
                        State or General Government should pay us is but just, but owing to the
                        means employed at Harrisburg for the passage of the bill, and the imposition
                        referred to above for the disbursing of the money, very many of our best
                        citizens and heaviest losers by the war prefer to give their claims to the
                        State rather than receive it in the way proposed.</p>

                    <p>If our claims be just, why have to pay for gentlemen staying at Harrisburg
                        for weeks--why? And why pay for commissions to disburse this money when we
                        have, at Harrisburg, all the officers needed? Better allow but fifty <orig
                            reg="percent">per cent</orig>. of our claims, and let the money come in
                        a legitimate way. The people better suffer loss in dollars than, as a
                        people, suffer in reputation. Can we ask God's blessing upon us as a people
                        when we condescend to such means as are present resorted to for the passage
                        of this border bill? I ask, can we? I join many in the wish that it may be
                        defeated in its present form, and that our Legislature will then pass a bill
                        equal and just to the real sufferers.</p>

                    <p>FRANKLIN COUNTY FARMER</p>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">pious</emph> author of this article is almost as well
                        known to your readers as if he had added his name to his bantling. It
                        contains at least half a dozen distinct and well known <emph rend="italic"
                            >lies</emph>--lies that the writer knew to be <emph rend="italic"
                        >lies</emph> when he penned them, and for the dissemination of which he
                        cannot plead even the paltry excuse of a mistake of judgment.</p>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">first</emph> lie is that the <emph rend="italic"
                            >money</emph> is to be put into the hands of gentlemen <emph
                            rend="italic">named in the bill</emph>. Now there is no such provision
                        in the bill, and no persons named to receive any thing that may be
                        appropriated, whether certificates or money. On the contrary the act says
                        the certificates shall be delivered to the <emph rend="italic"
                        >claimant</emph>, or his <emph rend="italic">legal representatives</emph>.
                        Many of the claimants you will recollect have died since the losses were
                        sustained.</p>

                    <p>There were at least <emph rend="italic">five</emph> different sets of
                        Commissioners who examined and adjudicated these border claims. The first
                        set was appointed by Governor Curtin, without any authority of law--to
                        ascertain the losses occasioned by <emph rend="italic">Union</emph> troops.
                        The <emph rend="italic">second</emph> were appointed by the courts, under
                        the Act of 16th April, 1862; the <emph rend="italic">third</emph> under the
                        Act of 22d April, 1863; the <emph rend="italic">fourth</emph> under the Act
                        of 15th February, 1866, and the <emph rend="italic">fifth</emph> under the
                        Act of 9th April, 1868.</p>

                    <p>It is well known that because of the want of authority in the <emph
                            rend="italic">first</emph> commissioners, and because of uncertainty
                        about the proceedings of some of the other commissioners being sanctioned,
                        quite a number of claims were again presented to the latter commissioners;
                        and <emph rend="italic">duplications</emph> of claims have thus occurred,
                        without any intention on the part of such claimants to demand double
                        payments. And to correct any such duplications, the various commissioners
                        named in the present bill have been selected so that the Commonwealth shall
                        be protected against unjust, or duplicated claims. The gentlemen named in
                        the bill are able men of high standing in their respective counties, and
                        there is no reason to think, or say, that they would not do exact justice to
                        every one. It is only the <emph rend="italic">sneaks</emph> among the
                        claimants who have any thing to fear from having their claims <orig
                            reg="reexamined">re-examined</orig>.</p>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">second</emph> lie of this <emph rend="italic"
                        >pious</emph> FARMER is that he is asked to pay <emph rend="italic">all the
                            expenses</emph> that may be incurred in procuring relief, in addition to
                        such amount as he may agree to give for getting his share of whatever the
                        liberality of the Legislature may award to our people. He <emph
                            rend="italic">knew</emph> this to be a <emph rend="italic">lie</emph>
                        when he penned it. The lawyers of our county did not <emph rend="italic"
                            >seek</emph> this business. After the claimants had done all they knew
                        how and failed of success, they, of their own motion, in convention
                        assembled in our Court House, passed a resolution requesting the
                        Chambersburg Bar to take charge of their claims, and they have done
                        so--asking as a remuneration for their services only what they conceive to
                        be a fair compensation, and upon the <emph rend="italic">distinct
                        condition</emph> that if nothing is received, not one cent, for trouble or
                        expense, is to be expected from any claimant.</p>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">third</emph> lie is that "it is well understood that
                        those who refuse to be thus imposed upon are to get nothing." Upon what
                        authority our <emph rend="italic">pious farmer</emph> makes this assertion,
                        I know not. I am sure the Franklin County Commissioners never told him so. I
                        am also sure they never told any person so, and I am sure our <emph
                            rend="italic">lying</emph> farmer does not know the Commissioners from
                        the other counties, and only evinces the depravity and malignity of his evil
                        heart by making the unfounded assertion.</p>

                    <p>It would be <emph rend="italic">well</emph>, indeed, if this <emph
                            rend="italic">sanctimonious</emph> FARMER could thus be deprived of any
                        claim he may profess to have. The man who would expect his neighbor to pay
                        for getting <emph rend="italic">his</emph> money; or who could rest content
                        when he knew that his neighbor had paid for the recovery of any thing due
                        him, <emph rend="italic">ought to get nothing</emph>. His claim should be
                        carefully scrutinized, for he would have no scruples about putting in <emph
                            rend="italic">duplicate</emph> bills, nor of charging three prices for
                        property that he never lost. His hired men should be on their guard in their
                        dealings with him, or they too will get cheated.</p>

                    <p>I know that there are a few such "skunks" as these in our county. I could
                        name the most of them if I wished. They have been telling their neighbors
                        "not to join their fellow claimants in any efforts to get redress; that if a
                        bill is passed <emph rend="italic">all</emph> must be paid, and they will
                        get their share without its costing them anything." They don't want their
                        claims <orig reg="reexamined">re-examined</orig>, because they know and feel
                        that the were corruptly made up. They would rather take "<emph rend="italic"
                            >fifty per cent</emph>," and well they might, for they would be cheating
                        the treasury even then, and receiving more than they lost.</p>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">fourth</emph> lie--and a senseless and useless one
                        too, so far as I can see the purpose of penning it, is that "many who have
                        not lost a dollar" are to get the money that our <emph rend="italic"
                        >pious</emph> FARMER, and his fellow sneaks, refuse to have upon the terms
                        he states. Is not this ridiculous? After stating that "it is fair to think
                        that the awards made (by the various commissions) are <emph rend="italic"
                            >just</emph> and <emph rend="italic">correct</emph>, how could this be?
                        Our <emph rend="italic">foolish</emph> farmer contradicts himself, and
                        demonstrates his own folly.</p>

                    <p>Notwithstanding the hypocritical whinings of this <emph rend="italic"
                            >sanctimonious Cain</emph> and his dolorous repinings over the improper
                        measures he says are being used to secure the passage of a Border Claim
                        Bill, I venture the prediction that if a Bill does pass <emph rend="italic"
                            >he</emph> will be amongst the very first to apply for his share of the
                        appropriation. No doubts about "God's blessing" resting upon the
                        certificates or the money will restrain him from "gobbling up" all he can
                        get, and cheating those who get it for him out of a just and fair
                        compensation for their labor, trouble, and expenses in getting it.</p>

                    <p>But these are only a <emph rend="italic">part</emph> of the many lies
                        embraced in this communication of our <emph rend="italic">pious
                        farmer</emph>. I have not the time, nor you the space, to answer the
                        balance. They stand out in bold, <emph rend="italic">bald</emph> relief all
                        through it, and the purpose of the writer is openly declared. Why did he not
                        give us his name? Our people would like to know who it is in their midst
                        that have been egging on the newspapers in Philadelphia, Lancaster and <orig
                            reg="Pittsburgh">Pittsburg</orig> against their relief, and who have
                        been writing to members of the Legislature to defeat the Border Claim Bill.
                        Come out of your privacy, you dirty, lying slanderer. Let the people know
                        who you are, and you will receive the well merited reward of your labors. We
                        promise you a popularity of contempt equal only to that of Benedict Arnold
                        or Andy Johnson, and a free pass to travel any where beyond the confines of
                        these seven border counties. The English language will not be strong enough
                        to convey the greetings you will receive from your suffering fellow
                        citizens--and you will need--"God's blessing" to descend upon you and
                        preserve your worthless head and hide from the <orig reg="flagellations"
                            >flagelations</orig> they so richly deserve. A SUFFERER.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In this letter, an anonymous contributor denounces those who spoke against
                    repaying border damages. The author takes issue with claims made by another
                    writer and attempts to correct what he considers to be "lies." The long note
                    suggests the divisive nature of this issue in state politics at the time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.23.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Chambersburg Nursery Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the glowing account of a visitor to the Chambersburg
                    Nursery Association. The association recently purchased two nurseries with
                    100,000 growing trees. "Order for trees, plants, etc., are coming in from all
                    parts of the country, and there is no reason why Chambersburg, with its improved
                    railroad facilities, can not be as good a post for this business as Geneva or
                    Rochester."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society met on March 15th. The group
                    dicussed gathering and storing fruit. The society is flourishing, especially now
                    that "the election of ladies to membership in the society is exerting a
                    favorable influence, and they now frequently grace its meetings by their
                    presence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Madamoiselle Zoe's dramatic troupe performed in Repository Hall on
                    Thursday, Friday, and Saturday. The paper pronounces the performance superior to
                    any theatrical show before seen in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Arrest of Chicken Thieves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Streets</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A black man named William Streets sold a lot of chickens at the Union Hotel
                    on Friday. Mr. Huber and Mr. Feldman suspected they were dishonestly acquired,
                    bought them, and found them to belong to George Rice. Streets was arrested when
                    he attempted to sell another lot belonging to H. B. Davison and Rev. L. A.
                    Gotwald. Streets "implicated two more of his race" in the plot, resulting in the
                    arrest of Thomas Green.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donohue</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curns</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. Barnes, pastor of the First M. E. Church of Chambersburg, was
                    appointed presiding elder. Rev. E. D. Kirby has been appointed to the First
                    Church and Rev. J. R. Donohue to the Second Church in Chambersburg. Rev. Mr.
                    Curns, presiding elder of the district, has been removed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>P. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth F. Rice of Mercersburg, widow of P. A. Rice who died during
                    the war in Libby Prison, has been granted an annuity by the state senate. Rice
                    was Justice of the Peace in Mercersburg when he was captured during General
                    Stuart's October, 1862, raid.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Feldman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Huber and Henry Feldman have taken posession of the Union Hotel and
                    promise to entertain their guests in style.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vink</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter Vink, long-time foreman of the Hollywell paper mill on the
                    Conococheague, has moved to Adams County where he is manufacturing straw paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>M. H. Bovee of Wisconsin will address the citizens of Chambersburg on
                    Wednesday on the abolition of capital punishment. Ladies are especially invited
                    to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wineman</ln>
                        <fn>Kate A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Kaufman and Kate A. Wineman of Rocky Spring were married on March
                    17th by the Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diener</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Sherman of Greenvillage and Miss Annie E. Diener of Chambersburg were
                    married on March 17th by the Rev. L. A. Gotwald.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Werner</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. C. Aughinbaugh of Chambersburg and Miss Annie Werner of Guilford were
                    married on March 8th by the Rev. D. Townsend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.23.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
