
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.05.11">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/30/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-05-11">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.11.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.11.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Too Late</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>There is rarely anything comes under our observation which pleases us more
                        than an example of pure, unmitigated, self-sacrificing, mulishness. Some
                        persons call it firmness, some obstinacy, old ladies denominate it
                        "contrariness." They all mean the same thing. When we find a person do
                        something for no reason under the sun, save that he ought not to do it, when
                        all the circumstances, and all his friends would advise and prompt him to do
                        just the opposite it sort of pleases us, and we find ourselves saying that
                        man has got grit in him. For our part we never could see any particular
                        merit in doing what it is one's interest to do, or what every person
                        approves, or what one's own sense of justice and right commends. Any person
                        can do this. There is no sacrifice in it, no heroism, no martyrdom. But to
                        go against all these, merely for the sake of being perverse, with the full
                        knowledge that the common judgment of the community will write you down an
                        ass, is such a rare example of that quality which human beings sometimes
                        possess in common with that noble quadruped, the mule, that we give it our
                        full meed of admiration.</p>

                    <p>If for example a journalist should express his preference for, and advocate a
                        return to, the nomadic mode of life instead of the civilization of the
                        present age, or should pronounce himself in favor of a white man's party in
                        politics, and urge his readers to join him after the negroes have secured
                        the right of suffrage, we should accept these as instances of the highest
                        development of mulishness. The latter is just the case it was our good
                        fortune to witness. Almost any person knows, who knows anything that such a
                        policy would have about the smallest chance of any in the world to succeed,
                        not to take into consideration its unmitigated iniquity if it could. There
                        was a time when it seemed to have an equal chance to carry the day with the
                        other policy of equal rights and justice. That was years ago, before the war
                        of the rebellion. Since then the party which made it the essence of its
                        creed, the Democratic party, met defeat whenever the two questions came in
                        conflict, growing weaker with every defeat, until at last the whole matter
                        was taken out of the sphere of politics by making all men, native born and
                        naturalized, citizens by constitutional guaranty.</p>

                    <p>Not being strong enough to prevent this set of justice, after it was done and
                        the party which secured it had been still further strengthened by means of
                        it to the extent of nearly a million of votes, the Democratic part ceased
                        all opposition, and accepted the changed condition of things as a matter of
                        course. This was natural, and what every person had expected. But we were
                        not to be cheated out of our spectacle of sublime mulishness. The Carlisle
                            <emph rend="italics">Volunteer</emph>, graduated we suppose for the
                        Democracy of Cumberland county, finds in this circumstance of the
                        Constitutional Amendment only an incentive to continue the conflict alone.
                        More than ever is it determined that only white men shall rule. That it was
                        weighed the question calmly and without prejudice one would infer from the
                        opening sentence of its article, which says, "Whitemen must rule. This
                        appears to be the motto of every white man worthy the name of an American
                        citizen." This cool way of declaring the unworthiness of more than half of
                        the American citizens might not be relished, nor even believed by them, but
                        it is the kind of thing that always accompanies extreme mulishness.</p>

                    <p>But we prefer to let our readers judge the article themselves:</p>

                    <p>"White Men Must Rule."<lb/> This appears to be the motto of every white man
                        worthy the name of an American citizen. Let it be emblazoned on our banners,
                        and serve as a text for our speeches and our meetings. This negro mania that
                        is now rampant in our land will soon die out. Like Known Nothingism in a
                        couple of years there will none to do it reverence, and the very men who are
                        now making speeches in favor of negro equality, will deny their <emph
                            rend="italics">colors</emph> and declaim against the infamous doctrines
                        they pretend to defend. The WHITE MAN'S PARTY will triumph finally. Courage,
                        Democrats! White men - men of honesty - true Americans will ere long be at
                        the head of affairs in our once glorious but now disgraced country. In the
                        language of that able defender of the people's rights, the Bellefonte <emph
                            rend="italics">Watchman</emph>, we say come one, come all who feel like
                        keeping negroes from our places of public trust, and join the glorious WHITE
                        MAN'S PARTY. Too long already have ye reposed in fancied security. Years ago
                        this thing should have been strangled in its swaddling clothes, but ye
                        dreamed a dream of peace, and now you are surrounded by your enemies, who
                        wait, with ropes in their hands, to bind ye hand and foot. But it is not yet
                        too late. The "Old Guard has never yet surrendered," and it will form the
                        nucleus of a mighty army to break the ranks of the hordes that threaten us,
                        and restore to the <orig reg="people">peo</orig> the pristine purity of
                        their institutions.</p>

                    <p>With the white men of the country united, Radicalism, with its negroes and
                        its deadly purposes, will be overthrown. Who will not aid in this mighty -
                        this glorious work? Are not the people tired of the party and will they not
                        aid us people tired of the party and will they not aid us to stay the
                        impending ruin? Shall negroes be Senators and Representatives and Judges and
                        Jurymen? Shall white men be hauled up before negro magistrates, and the laws
                        of the land be crippled and enfeebled by the silly interpolations of negro
                        legislators? White men, for the sake of your children, for the honor of the
                        past and by your hopes of the future, we charge you to crush this evil now.</p>

                    <p>There is hope for the country, and joy for the people in the binding together
                        of white men for the good of white men - nay, for the good of ALL Let us not
                        allow the negroes to hold the balance of power as the Radicals fondly hope
                        they will, and all may yet be well. For the sake of the country and our
                        race, break the bonds of party fealty and cling to the rock that offers us
                        safety from the storm.</p>

                    <p>Three cheers, then, for the White Man's Party! Let this be the slogan with
                        which the people will hereafter march to victory, and at the sound of which
                        the enemies of the country and their negro allies will flee in great
                        affright.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> mocks an anti-black editorial
                    from a Democratic paper, comparing the authors to stubborn mules who refuse to
                    accept the fact that blacks now have equal rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The New Field of Anti-Slavery Labor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>When the millennium comes what will become of the preachers, Sunday-schools,
                        Societies for the Conversion of the Heathen, Tract distributors, and the
                        rest? Surely they will be as unfortunate as the anti-slavery reformers, who
                        are now like Charles Lamb when he was pensioned by the East India House, and
                        are lost for want of occupation. A few years ago the most that the
                        anti-slavery men could hope for was the repeal of the Fugitive Slave Law.
                        Now, as if by miracle, they see more than their dreams realized - the slave
                        not only free, but a citizen; the slaveholder driven from the Government he
                        controlled; a negro Senator in the seat of Jefferson Davis. It seems as if
                        so much has been done that nothing is left to do.</p>

                    <p>It is impossible for those who have but a recent part in the anti-slavery
                        contest to understand the feelings of such men and women as Wendell
                        Phillips, Garrison, Frederick <orig reg="Douglass">Douglas</orig>, and
                        Lucretia Mott. Few reformers who undertake such a gigantic work live to see
                        it half completed, but they planted the seed in tears and reap the harvest
                        in glory. They have seen an idea despised and rejected by the American
                        people grow into the sternest of facts, with the whole world to hail it. We
                        might expect Mr. Phillips to feel like Alexander, when he lamented there
                        were no more worlds to conquer. Mr. Garrison seemed to have something of
                        this feeling when after emancipation he desired the anti-slavery societies
                        to dissolve, thinking their work completed.</p>

                    <p>But you cannot limit the reforms of a born reformer. Many of the
                        abolitionists are still young, and could not, if they would, give up their
                        habit of trying to benefit the world. They would hardly change the direction
                        of their efforts. The colored race has freedom and citizenship, it is true,
                        but it has not yet equality. Except in New York, Boston, Philadelphia, and
                        other <orig reg="centers">centres</orig> of intelligence and wealth, the
                        colored people are, as a race, inferior in education and influence to the
                        whites. Their influence in the seventeen States must be great; they knew
                        enough to be loyal during the war, but there are other conditions of
                        intelligent citizenship than patriotism. On the other hand, though the
                        ballot is given them by the Constitution, it is not certain that they will
                        peaceably be allowed to use it. There is still enough of negro-hating in the
                        North to make election riots probable this fall, and enough passion and
                        cunning in the South to justify us in believing that the negroes will either
                        be persecuted or swindled. To watch and guard the future of the race they
                        have been instrumental in liberating is certainly the appointed work of the
                        antislavery leaders and one of vast importance to the Republic. It is not
                        probable that they will suffer from want of occupation, for the field is
                        open before them. The day of tearing down is ended, and now we must all
                        begin to build up. Democrats and Republicans are equally concerned in the
                        labor; for, as the negro has a vote, even those who think it was unwisely
                        given are interested in having it intelligently used. - <emph rend="italics"
                            >N. Y. Standard</emph></p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial from the <emph rend="italics">New York Standard</emph>
                    argues that even though slavery has been destroyed, there is still work to do in
                    order to gain equality for the freedmen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Mrs. Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper chastizes the Senate for tabling a measure that would have
                    provided Mary Todd Lincoln with a comfortable widow's pension.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Pennsylvania Anti-Slavery Society disbanded on Thursday after "an
                    active and aggressive warfare on slavery of thirty-three years." They felt
                    nothing was left to accomplish after passage of the 15th Amendement. "It was a
                    body composed of the purest patriots, the most upright men and women in the
                    land, and their faith and truth and sincerity and justice were tried and tested
                    in a thousand ways during the long thrity-three years of the society's
                    existence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.11.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Official Visitation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stokes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heiss</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bertram</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trinnick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Grand Officers of the Grand Encampment of Odd Fellows of Pennsylvania
                    made an official visit to Olive Branch Encampment No. 13 in Chambersburg. A
                    delegation also attended from Shippensburg. The event included speeches by the
                    officers and an elegant dinner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Re-Union of the Officers of the 126th Reg. Penn'a Vols.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>On Tuesday, the 3rd inst, a number of the officers of this favorite regiment
                        of Franklin county, held their first <orig reg="reunion">re-union</orig> in
                        the parlors of the National Hotel, in the place. This particular day was
                        selected on account of it being the anniversary of the battle of
                        Chancellorsville, in which the regiment participated and lost heavily.</p>

                    <p>The meeting was organized by electing Col. Elder President and Lieut G. W.
                        Welsh Secretary. Adj't Stewart stated that the object of the meeting was to
                        make preparations for a grand <orig reg="reunion">re-union</orig> of the
                        entire regiment, in this place, on the 13th of December next.</p>

                    <p>Adj't. Stewart, Lieut. Col. Rowe and Lieut. Platt were appointed a committee
                        to draft constitution and by-laws, which they were to report at the meeting
                        in December.</p>

                    <p>Private Mahon, Sergt. Seiders, Lieuts. Cook, Fletcher and Platt, were
                        appointed a committee to make arrangements for the celebration in December.</p>

                    <p>The business having been transacted, those present and their guests repaired
                        to the dining rooms, where their host and hostess of the National had
                        prepared an elegant banquet, which was exceedingly enjoyed by those who
                        partook of it. Letters of regret were read from those who were unable to
                        accept the invitation to be present. Toasts appropriate to the occasion were
                        offered and replied to. The company dispersed at a late hour in the
                        afternoon, feeling well satisfied with their first <orig reg="reunion"
                            >re-union</orig>.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article reports on a small reunion of the 126th Pennsylvania
                    volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Bible Society keeps its depository at the residence of
                    Rev. F. Dyson. They have a supply of German and English Bibles. The society
                    provides Bibles free of charge to the destitute and sells them to schools for 40
                    cents, testaments 20 cents. Anyone wishing to make donations should contact
                    treasurer Jacob Hoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Turnpike</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Good of Quincy has raised $3,000 for a turnpike between Waynesboro
                    and Quincy. Alex Hamilton is also promoting the road. The cost is estimated at
                    $10,000 and citizens and businessmen are called upon to contribute.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For the Penitentiary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Columbus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Filkill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sheriff Fletcher took the following prisoners to the Eastern Penitentiary
                    in Philadelphia: African Americans Columbus Green and John Filkill sentenced to
                    one year for stealing chickens; white man Andrew Unger sentenced to one year for
                    robbing Clugston's store in Doylesburg; and African American Henry Gray
                    sentenced to two years for robbing the Chambersburg post office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Perry A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gov. Geary refused to sign the bill granting a pension to Mrs. Elizabeth F.
                    Rice, widow of Perry A. Rice of Mercersburg on the grounds that it would
                    establish a dangerous precedent. He also refused, with the support of the paper,
                    to sign the bill raising the salaries of the associate judges of Franklin
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Decoration Day--Attention Soldiers!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimison</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sgt. T. J. Grimison will host a meeting of Franklin soldiers on May 12th to
                    make arrangements to decorate the graves of the fallen on May 30th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A game of baseball was palyed on Saturday between the Shumaker Nine of
                    Chambersburg and the Mercersburg College Nine. Mercersburg won 49-16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merklein</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Charles Merklein will sail from New York to Europe today for the
                    purpose of attending medical schools in France and Germany.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Masonic Hall on Second Street has been recently renovated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monks</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strothers</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Monks of Chambersburg and Moses Anderson and William Strothers of
                    Greencastle attended a meeting of the Pennsylvania State Equal Right League at
                    Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Showman</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mills</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Showman and Miss Mary E. Mills, both of Horse Valley, were
                    married on March 10th at the residence of the bride's mother by the Rev. A. E.
                    Fulton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckenrode</ln>
                        <fn>David E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>S. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David E. Eckenrode and Miss Rebecca J. Stake, both of Amberson's Valley,
                    were married on March 16th at the residence of Mrs. S. E. McLaughlin by the Rev.
                    A. E. Fulton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neely</ln>
                        <fn>J. Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmucker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Upton Neely of Hunterstown and Miss Mary Shively, daughter of Peter
                    Shively of Adams County, were married on May 3rd by the Rev. Dr. Schmucker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vondersmith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Vondersmith died near Church Hill on May 2nd. He was 90 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob H. Kauffman died on May 5th. He was 30 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.11.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
