
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.02.09">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/28/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-02-09">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>09</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.02.09.01" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Where the Wages Go--Sober Thoughts for Workingmen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asserting that many workingmen live in poverty because a large
                    portion of their wages is spent on alchohol.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.02.09.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper celebrates the ratification of the 15th amendment by Georgia,
                    assuring its adoption. "At last the Constitution and the Declaration of
                    Independence are one in spirit, and our Government is what it was represented to
                    be, but never was until now, a government of equal rights to all."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.02.09.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downing</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society met on Tuesday. Eighteen members
                    attended, including three ladies. President Suesserott anounced that the next
                    meeting of the Pennsylvania fruit growers association will be held in
                    Chambersburg. An exhibition of produce was held.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Third week, His Honor, Judge Rowe, presiding:</p>

                    <p>Jacob B. Cook, vs. Jesse Keaner, appeal. Verdict for plaintiff, for $4,52.</p>

                    <p>Levi Sanders, vs. David Miller and David Miller, Jr. - Summons in debt.
                        Verdict; $27,00 for plaintiff.</p>

                    <p>John Miler vs. John Wage. - Ejectment. Jury failed to agree.</p>

                    <p>David Guyer vs. William Forbes. - Summons in Assumpsit. Jury failed to agree.</p>

                    <p>Alexander E. McDowell vs. Peter Brough, Samuel F. Greenawalt and John A.
                        Brough. Verdict, $5,442.38, for plaintiff.</p>

                    <p>M. G. Huff vs. F. C. Weidlich. - Appeal. Verdict, $50,39 for plaintiff.</p>

                    <p>Jacob Lantz and Bell his wife, vs. Jacob Lemaster. - Slander. $1,500 amount
                        of damages claimed by plaintiffs.</p>

                    <p>Wm. Gelwicks, assignee of W. C. McNulty in Bankruptcy, vs. Samuel Lesher. -
                        Summons in Assumpsit. Verdict for defendant.</p>

                    <p>Jacob Kyler vs. Jacob Heisey and Mary Heisey, owners and contractors.
                        Mechanic's lien. Judgment confessed for $62,00 and one-half of the costs.</p>

                    <p>Elizabeth Breckenridge vs. Curtis McNeal. - Ejectment for a lot of ground in
                        Lurgan township, containing about two acres. Verdict for plaintiff.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keaner</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanders</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weidlich</ln>
                        <fn>F. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lemaster</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heisey</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heisey</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckenridge</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNeal</ln>
                        <fn>Curtis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This weekly article describes the court cases for the county, including
                    defendants, verdicts, and punishments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italics">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository.</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>In the last issue of your paper you materially misstate the proceedings of
                        the Pennsylvania Annual Conference of the United Brethren in Christ,
                        respecting myself and Rev. J. P. Bishop. The facts in the case are simply as
                        follows:</p>

                    <p>After our views respecting the "future everlasting punishment of the wicked"
                        had been overhauled by an inquisitorial committee, and the Conference had
                        passed a paper expressing its <emph rend="italics">"sense"</emph> in the
                        case, and most emphatically condemning our views, and demanding of us a
                        promise of entire silence in regard to then, after they themselves had <emph
                            rend="italics">published</emph> them, we felt we could no longer remain
                        in connection with the Conference and respect ourselves. We therefore
                        proposed to the Conference that, if they had any <emph rend="italics"
                        >law</emph> for their proceedings they should expel us. This, for good
                        reason, no doubt, they declined to do. In order, therefore, to end the
                        matter, we proposed to withdraw on condition that we should receive a
                        certificate of good moral character, and that the withdrawal was occasioned
                        by our belief that "the wicked would have no conscious living existence
                        after this life," which proposition was promptly accepted by the Conference.
                        Then, <emph rend="italics">after we had publicly withdrawn from the
                            conference and the Church</emph>, they gave us an exhibition of their
                        good faith in the matter, by passing a paper requesting that we surrender
                        our certificates of license and ordination. I claim no authority to act
                        under those certificates as a United Brethren preacher; but they are my own
                        individual property; nor have I ever done anything to render them void so
                        far as the <emph rend="italics">duties</emph> of an <emph rend="italics"
                            >ordained minister</emph> are concerned. The case might be different had
                        they expelled us; but for this we did, and do yet claim they had no law.
                        Respectfully J. G. SCHAFF.<lb/> CHAMBERSBURG, Feb. 3, 1870.</p>

                    <p>The statement alluded to was taken from what was believed to be a correct
                        report of the proceedings of the Conference. - EDITOR.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter to the editors corrects an earlier <emph rend="italics"
                        >Repository</emph> report regarding the Pennsylvania Annual Conference of
                    the United Brethren of Christ.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Watch Them</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that groups of strangers have been taking up lodgings in
                    the pine woods north of Waynesboro. Their departure from the area has
                    suspiciously coincided with the commission of a theft or crime int he county.
                    There are currently five or six persons in the woods who should be watched
                    carefully.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. G. Schaff announces a schedule for sermons he plans to preach throughout
                    Franklin County. A collection will be taken up at each one for the support of
                    his family.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mormons</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thornton</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Bishop</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rigdon</ln>
                        <fn>Sidney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two Mormons, Levi Thornton and Bishop Hess, have been proselytizing near
                    Tomstown, Franklin County. They have already made 12 converts. Several families
                    in the area have sympathized with Mormonism ever since Sidney Rigdon visited
                    Greencastle in 1846. "No one of intelligence or standing in that section will be
                    identified with the movement."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Peak Family Bell Ringers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Peak family of Swiss Bell Ringers will give an entertainment in
                    Repository Hall on Thurdsday. The company has been in existence for 30 years,
                    and have entertained the citizens of Franklin many times. Tickets are 35 cents,
                    25 cents for children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shinafield</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clintock</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Phin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dehaven</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reymer</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Nulty</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfkill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shinafield</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Brumbaugh took his seat as commissioner of Antrim on Monday in place of
                    Mr. Palmer. He joins Mr. Shinafield and Mr. Lehman on the board. A number of men
                    are suggested as candidates for clerk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bilheimer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Conference of the West Pennsylvania Lutheran Synod
                    will meet in the Evangelical Lutheran Church in Orrstown on the 14th. Rev.
                    Bilheimer will discuss infant baptism. The Sabbath School Institute will convene
                    on Tuesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzleman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frederick Long of Fannett took his seat on the Board of Directors of the
                    Poor in place of Mr. Heintzleman. He joins John Gillan, Jr., of St. Thomas,
                    Jacob R. Smith of Antrim, and Frederick Long of Fannett. The following officers
                    were also reelected: Samuel Brandt, steward; Dr. William H. Boyle, physician;
                    John R. Orr, attorney and clerk; and Alexander Martin, treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pastor Installed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>Luther A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. B. C. Suesserott was installed as pastor of St. John's Lutheran Church
                    in Lancaster. Rev. Luther A. Gotwald of Chambersburg delivered the sermon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Fayetteville Lodge of the Knights of Pythias will be officially founded
                    on February 11th. "The Pythian Knighthood is making great progress in this
                    country and continually augmenting its numbers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Dr. Niccolls, former pastor of Chambersburg's Falling Spring
                    Presbyterian Church and now of St. Louis, will lecture in Repository Hall on
                    "Cheerfulness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Singley</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William F. Singley, a black man formerly of Chambersburg, was arrested in
                    Gettysburg on charges of stealing a coat and scarf worth $14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Irish Character</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lloyd</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John Lloyd of Orrstown delivered an amusing lecture in Greenvillage on
                    "Irish Character."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham R. Kohler and Miss Lydia A. Kohler, both of Maryland, were married
                    at Hay's Hotel in Greencastle on February 1st by the Rev. J. M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kane</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisoner</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Kane and Miss Jennie C. Reisoner, both from near Fayetteville, were
                    married on February 1st by Rev. John Fohl at his residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoerger</ln>
                        <fn>Elmira Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elmira Louisa Stoerger died in Chambersburg on January 31st. She was
                    87 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.02.09.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
