
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.10.12">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/07/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-10-12">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.12.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.12.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Re-Union of the 77th Regiment Penna. Vols.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>This interesting occasion, which had been duly announced in the REPOSITORY,
                        came off on Thursday of last week. Quite a large number of the old veterans
                        from various parts of the State were in attendance, and the reunion is not
                        likely to be soon forgotten by our citizens.</p>

                    <p>At 12 o'clock, M., the members assembled in the Court House, and were called
                        to order, Col. F. S. Stumbaugh presiding. Capt. H.C. Demming, and Lieut. C.
                        Snively, were appointed Secretaries. A committee on officers for the ensuing
                        year was appointed. Harrisburg was determined upon as the place for the next
                        reunion, in 1871. Adjourned till 2 P.M.</p>

                    <p>AFTERNOON PROCEEDINGS.</p>

                    <p>Meeting called to order at the appointed time. Prayer by Rev. Dr. Robinson.
                        He prayed for the regiment; returned thanks to the God of Battles, who had
                        brought all safe through past dangers; besought His protection for the
                        absent members of the regiment and for the families of all; prayed for our
                        country that it might ever have as true men for its guardians as those of
                        the 77th; that it might be the first love of fathers, the true faith of
                        children, and ever be protected by the strong arm of the people.</p>

                    <p>The address of welcome was then delivered by Col. F.S. Stumbaugh. He bid all
                        a hearty welcome--the guests--the ladies--a welcome in the name of the
                        officers and men of the 77th; and the regiment in turn a greeting in the
                        name of the widows and orphans of the war, in the name of the good citizens
                        of Chambersburg. He spoke of the time that the regiment was mustered into
                        service, October, 1861, and the time that it was mustered out, August, 1865.
                        He adverted to the changes that the regiment had undergone as a military
                        body, and the dreadful changes war had wrought. He recalled the names of
                        Housum and M'Kesson, of Stevens and McDowell, and the memory of others whose
                        names shall never be forgotten. He spoke in glowing terms of the trip down
                        the Ohio, the plaudits of the people along the route, and the reception at
                        Louisville, the march through Tennessee and Kentucky, North Georgia and
                        Mississippi, Louisiana to Texas, and of the first and last battles of the
                        war. He was glad to see that other regiments were having reunions, and hoped
                        that more would be encouraged to work for them, so that there might be one
                        grand reunion of all. In conclusion, he thanked the ladies for their
                        presence and again bid one and all a hearty welcome to the second reunion of
                        the 77th regiment of Penna. Volunteers.</p>

                    <p>Capt. G.W. Skinner, then proceeded to deliver the annual oration, somewhat as
                        follows: It is as much a matter of regret to me as it can possibly be to
                        you, that the gentleman first selected to deliver this address could not
                        perform the duty. Not knowing till within the last few days that Col. Pyfer
                        would not be here, and that I was to take his place, my opportunities for
                        preparation have not been as great as I could have desired. I therefore ask
                        your pardon for anything that may to you seem amiss. On the 12th day of
                        April, 1861, that fearful civil war, which had for so many months been
                        protending, unclasped its purple leaves at <orig reg="Sumter"
                        >Sumpter</orig>. Dark as were the clouds which in these months had overhung
                        our Country's Southern horizon, our people were as yet unprepared for the
                        shock of battle. But the Flag of our Union was assailed, and from every
                        section of the North there went up the cry "to arms." Companies and
                        regiments were speedily formed. States vied with each other in their haste
                        to succor the cause of our own imperiled flag. Pennsylvania, true to her
                        instincts and true to her own time honored position as the first among the
                        foremost in this patriotic world. She sent out regiment after regiment, and
                        in October, 1861, she sent out the 77th, and briefly as possible let its
                        history speak for itself. On the 1st day of August 1861, Col. Stumbaugh
                        received authority to recruit the regiment. On the 18th of October it was
                        transported to Louisville, by way of the Ohio river; thence to Nolin's
                        river, where it encamped for several weeks. Here it was assigned to General
                        Buell's army, and participated with it in the advance on Nashville. From
                        Nashville it advanced in the direction of Savannah; arrived at Savannah, it
                        was announced that General Grant was in sore peril on the field of Shiloh.
                        Part of Buell's forces were already on the field and the rest were hurried
                        forward, the 77th arriving at the scene of conflict at 8 o'clock on the
                        morning of the 7th of April, 1862. On that field the regiment received its
                        baptism of blood, leaving three killed and several wounded. After Shiloh it
                        participated in the siege of Corinth; then in the long, wearisome race
                        between Bragg and Buell to Louisville. It was at Stone River when that
                        battle began, and to a member of the 77th belongs the honor of firing the
                        first shot in the fight. Many of its bravest men were killed and wounded
                        there, and some of its best officers. It was there that Housum fell at the
                        head of the regiment. Brave, gallant fellow, he met the stern messenger of
                        Death with the same coolness and inflexible courage which had characterized
                        every other act of his life. I speak no words of superfluous praise when I
                        say that he was one of the most honorable of men, one of the best
                        commanders, and one of the bravest soldiers. Over his grave, in yonder
                        cemetery, stands a monument whose simple inscription tells the story of his
                        courage as a soldier. "Davis, I am wounded; stay by the brave boys of the
                        77th," were his last words. At Stone River the 77th did its duty well, and
                        needs no other compliment of the fact than the words of Gen. Rosecrans:
                        "Colonel, I see that your regiment is all right; give my compliments to the
                        boys, and tell them that I say it was the banner regiment at Stone River,
                        they never broke their ranks." The regiment moved South again with the army;
                        was at Liberty Gap on the 25th of June, 1863, and, although the battle there
                        lasted but ten minutes, our loss in killed and wounded was fifty. Time will
                        not permit me to follow up closely the history of the regiment. After many
                        long and tiresome marches, the regiment again come face to face with the
                        enemy at Chickamauga, on the 19th of September. That was its most terrible
                        struggle. Entering the battle with 18 officers and 215 men, it came out with
                        but 6 officers and scarcely fifty men. By myself nothing is more clearly
                        remembered than the conflict there on the night of the 19th. The scene was
                        fearful. The heavens were dark and cloudy, and the air through the woods in
                        which we fought was murky with the smoke of battle. The conflict was hand to
                        hand, and it was only by the light of slashing muskets that friend could be
                        distinguished from foe. Our colors were taken, but only when the brave
                        fellow who bore them was pinned to the earth by a rebel bayonet. After
                        participating for a month in the defence of Chattanooga the organization
                        went into camp, where it remained until the close of 1863. In January, 1864,
                        most of its survivors <orig reg="reenlisted">re-enlisted</orig> and the
                        regiment was sent home. After remaining in the State a little over a month,
                        it again returned to the front in time to take part in the Atlanta campaign.
                        In that campaign which might justly be termed the hundred miles and hundred
                        days fight from Resaca to Atlanta, the regiment must have been engaged
                        twenty times. When Sherman began his march "From Atlanta to the Sea," the
                        77th followed the fortunes of the 4th army corps, to which it was then
                        attached, back through Georgia, through northern Alabama and through middle
                        Tennessee, until on the 30th of November, 1864, it found itself facing Hood
                        at Franklin. Seven times in succession did the united forces of Hood's army
                        hurl themselves against the temporary breastworks we had erected, each time
                        to be driven back with fearful slaughter. Retiring from Franklin under cover
                        of night we fell back to Nashville, where on the 15th and 16th of December
                        our little army of scarcely two corps again met Hood's forces in battle. In
                        those two days we almost destroyed his army. On the 5th of March, 1865, we
                        began preparing to join in the last great "On to Richmond." But ere we were
                        ready for the forward march "the last ditch" of the enemy was found and
                        emptied by our boys in the East. At Appomattox Court House, on the 8th day
                        of April, 1865, the head of that army which had struggled against us for
                        four long years, surrendered. With Lee's surrender the war virtually closed,
                        many regiments being soon after mustered out. Not so, however, with the
                        77th. A few weeks before the surrender the regiment had been reinforced by
                        the addition of five new companies. These companies arrived too late to take
                        part in any engagement, but soon enough to see some hard service. There
                        being no further work for it in East <orig reg="Tennessee"
                        >Teennessee</orig>, it was sent back to Nashville, where it lay until the
                        17th of June, when it was ordered along with others to Texas. On the 13th of
                        July it embarked for Matagorda Bay, Texas, where it landed on the 20th. The
                        intervening time from July 20th till the 17th of the following December, was
                        spent in that far distant State. We were now three thousand miles from home,
                        in an inhospitable clime. Many a gallant soldier fell there in that far off
                        land a victim of disease. Leaving Galveston on the 17th day of January,
                        1866. Among the first to enter, it was one of the last to leave the service.</p>

                    <p>Time has allowed me to give but a synopsis of its history, but enough to show
                        its record. Who will say that the record is not one of which every member
                        may justly feel proud? How pleasant to all of us is this <orig reg="reunion"
                            >re-union</orig> here <orig reg="today">to-day</orig>. It is like
                        brothers long parted meeting together again. And are we not brothers?
                        Members for years of the same great family, eating from the same table,
                        drinking from the same fountains and streams, reposing together on the same
                        fields, companions in camp and on the march, comrades in battle, the tie
                        that binds us is almost as strong and indissoluble as that which links
                        together the hearts of those, who, in childhood's hour, knelt at the same
                        parental knee. All was not hardship and danger. There were, really, many
                        pleasant evenings spent round the camp fire. There were those whose spirits
                        no amount of hardship could dampen. In the camp, on the march, and even
                        where great dangers lurked, they were always in a jolly mood. Who does not
                        remember Neal Foy, of Co. A? always lively, always ready with a joke, no
                        matter where it was. Poor fellow, he died in Texas, just before our time of
                        service expired. I wish I could stop <orig reg="today">to-day</orig> to
                        pronounce a eulogy upon each one of our cherished dead. Our <orig
                            reg="reunion">re-union</orig>
                        <orig reg="today">to-day</orig> is not for them. Our festivities this
                        evening will carry no enjoyment to the place where they are resting. It is
                        meet, therefore, that we should speak of them, if not by name, at least in
                        general terms, for</p>

                    <p>"A debt of gratitude we owe,<lb/> To them 'tis justly due,<lb/> And till our
                        nation's latest day<lb/> Our children's children still shall say,<lb/> They
                        died for us and you."</p>

                    <p>There are those too who have come back to us mere shattered wrecks of their
                        former selves. These are to a certain extent the nation's care, yet it seems
                        to me sometimes that some of them are unkindly dealt with. This should not
                        be, the man who laid a limb upon the field of battle, has a claim upon his
                        country and his people which cannot be ignored. Nor should I forget to-day
                        that there is still another class to whom the nation owes its meed of
                        praise, not of those who endured the danger and fatigue of the camp and
                        march. This class is still perhaps to be held in more grateful recollection
                        than any other. Unfitted for the bivouac of actual army life, its silent
                        watch was kept by the side of the dying. All honor then to that noble army
                        of Christian women which carried its ministrations to the bed aide of the
                        suffering one. Back along the past we find many instances of the heroism of
                        women, but it remained for our great civil war to develop the brightest type
                        of nobility in her sex. Oh! my comrades, if true devotion is to be found
                        anywhere, it is to be found in the hearts of such as these. If there is hope
                        for our country in the uncertain future it rests on the altar they have
                        erected. Somebody has fitly remarked, "If woman be with us who can be
                        against us," woman who was last at the Cross and first at the Sepulcher. To
                        the crippled ones then, to the mother in her sorrow, to the widow in her
                        loneliness of her heart, to the orphan in its bereavement, let our
                        sympathies go out. Let our thanks and benefactions be showered on their
                        heads.</p>

                    <p>It may not be inappropriate, my comrades, to call to mind the fact that we
                        meet to day in a place which has suffered more than the ordinary evils of
                        war. Many of you doubtless remember the day (I remember it well,) when the
                        news was brought that Chambersburg had been burned. I remember how deep was
                        the indignation that ran through our ranks; how our boys vowed vengeance and
                        how they fought that evening in remembrance of it. "Oh! if the 77th had only
                        been there," was the expression heard on every lip. Yes, if the 77th only
                        had been here, I feel free to say the unholy work would only have been
                        accomplished when the power to defend had been taken away from our arms.</p>

                    <p>Briefly, my comrades, I have traced the history of our regiment. In a feeble
                        manner, I have essayed to pay tribute to the memory of our dead; and to the
                        faithful services of others, who, though still living, are but wearing out
                        lives of sadness. I have spoken too of the peculiar sufferings of the people
                        you have come among to day, so I am about to leave the subject with you.
                        This history we will remember while we live, and when the last one of us has
                        obeyed the bugle call to another world, the lids of the great volume will
                        still stand open for those to read who are to come after us.</p>

                    <p>It may be permitted many of us to meet together again, on future occasions of
                        this kind, so while the opportunity remains let us come to these re-unions
                        wherever they may be held. True in the past, I know each one of you will be
                        true in the future. Tried in the furnace of battle, your country knows now
                        of what stern material you are made. She knows that in any just cause she
                        may again rely on the same strong arms and stout hearts which had saved her
                        in the hour of her greatest peril. In the future she may need you again. Let
                        us resolve then, that whatever others may do, we, at least, will stand by
                        the Union of our fathers, they founded it, their best blood cemented it. It
                        was good enough for them, it is good enough for us, and it will be good
                        enough for all those who are to come after us. In order, then, that it may
                        be perpetuated, let us forget the hatreds and animosities of the late war.
                        This country cannot long exist if bound together only by a paper tie called
                        the Constitution. No, it needs a stronger and far more enduring tie than
                        that. It needs the firmly cemented affections of this people, of all the
                        States. Though deep and wide the wounds may be, heal them all up.</p>

                    <p>Let us take a lesson in this from the gallant dead of both sides. On every
                        battle field they sleep, "the grey and blue," almost in brotherly embrace,
                        their warfare over and forgotten. So let it be with us. Let us join hearts
                        and hands again, and go forward to labor for the fulfillment of what I trust
                        will be a great destiny for our country.</p>

                    <p>After the address of Capt. Skinner, the following business was transacted:</p>

                    <p>Report of the <orig reg="Committee">Committte</orig> on Officers for the
                        ensuing year, as follows:<lb/> President--Capt. H.C. Demming.<lb/> Vice
                        Presidents--Col. F.S. Stumbaugh, Col. Wm. A. Robinson.<lb/> Corresponding
                        Secretary.--M.J. Malony.<lb/> Recording Secretary.--Capt. Miles
                        Zentmyer.<lb/> Treasurer.--Capt. G.W. Skinner.</p>

                    <p>A committee of three, consisting of the following named persons, was then
                        appointed to choose an orator for the next reunion:--Col. Robinson, Private
                        Rhodes, Lieut. Martin. The same committee was also instructed to prepare a
                        badge for the members of the regiment.</p>

                    <p>On motion the meeting then adjourned, and the regiment in a body paid a visit
                        to the tomb of Lieut. Col Housum. Not a word was spoken at the tomb, and the
                        regiment stood with uncovered heads while the band played a solemn dirge.</p>

                    <p>After leaving the cemetery, the grounds of the Franklin County Agricultural
                        Society were visited, and the regiment was there disbanded.</p>
                    <p>At 8 o'clock, P.M., a reception was held in Repository Hall, which was a
                        perfect success, notwithstanding the little misunderstanding which at first
                        existed as to the character of the entertainment. It was <emph rend="italic"
                            >not</emph> a "hop," but merely a social gathering, where a trio of
                        hours passed away very pleasantly indeed. At 11 o'clock supper was
                        announced, and officers and guests repaired to the National Hotel, where a
                        splendid banquet was spread. After the blessing had been pronounced by Prof.
                        Shumaker, Co. Stumbaugh said, "all things are ready and the word is action."
                        It is needless to add what followed. <unclear>Af-</unclear> the meal, Capt.
                        Skinner proposed the following toast:</p>

                    <p>First: "The Pennsylvania Volunteers."</p>

                    <p>Response by Gen. Russell. He expressed his satisfaction at being called on to
                        respond to the sentiment, "The Pennsylvania Volunteers."--Though not one of
                        them, yet he took into account his connection with them. He was proud of
                        them, for when the first time it became necessary to call out troops to put
                        down the rebellion, the State of Pennsylvania, the Keystone of the Federal
                        Arch, responded so promptly. Pennsylvania gave 366,000 men, yes, counting
                        all her enlistments in army and navy, her contributions amount to full
                        400,000. Who were these men? They were the representatives of almost every
                        family in Pennsylvania. In Pennsylvania did the government put its trust,
                        and she vindicated its honor. It was no thirst for territory which incited
                        to this war, the greatest in the annals of the world. No, it was to protect
                        this government, made for the people and by the people, that it should not
                        perish off the earth. Where to-day are to be found better men? When the war
                        was over they returned to society and gave a more patriotic tone to it. His
                        had been the honor of presenting to the 77th, 78th and 79th regiments their
                        first regimental colors, at Allegheny City, in October, 1861. The 77th had
                        been among the first out in defence of the cause, and the last but three
                        mustered out of service. Exposed to captivity and death, again restored to
                        civil life and to the quiet homes from which they had departed, they have
                        the consciousness of knowing that they have served their country well and
                        faithfully. He considered re-unions of regiments eminently proper, and
                        wished the 77th many happy ones.</p>

                    <p>The next toast was "The Army of the Cumberland," to which Gen. Jordon
                        responded. Not having made a public speech for some time, he requested the
                        favor of reading what he had to say, and in a full, strong, soldierly voice
                        he read a glowing eulogy on the Army of the Cumberland, of which army the
                        77th was the only Eastern regiment. He traced the course of this army, and
                        especially of this one regiment through all its wanderings in the South, and
                        closed with a tribute of respect to the memory of Gen. Thomas.</p>

                    <p>The third toast of the evening was "The Ladies," which was responded to by
                        Lieut Snively, in the following happy manner: The ladies, heaven bless them
                        all! The tongue of men can never do them justice. We don't understand the
                        sweet creatures, and, to tell the truth, sometimes they don't understand
                        themselves. They are so perverse and yet so gentle, they always conquer just
                        when they seem ready to yield. As wives they are the sweetest blessings of
                        our lives. Strong minded ladies are one sided in their views. The ladies
                        want no Sixteenth Amendment to our Constitution, they don't want to vote.
                        For how <emph rend="italic">could</emph> Susan Jane vote on age, or Arabella
                        have Charles Augustus know that she could have voted Lincoln's first
                        election. Then they are said to have their foibles, top, of false hair,
                        Grecian hand and high heels. We don't know that they are guilty, we don't
                        want to know. We have seen their little fixings in the shop windows, but of
                        course they are kept there only for show, nobody ever saw the ladies buy
                        them. And the ladies are blamed with being false, fickle and addicted to
                        coquetry. Is this true? No, surely not. They are God's greatest blessing to
                        man and the complement of his nature.</p>

                    <p>The next toast proposed was: "The 126th Regiment Penna. Vols," to which
                        Lieut. Welsh made an impromptu response. He spoke of the sympathy which
                        existed between the two regiments of the 126th's appreciation of the
                        invitation to the evening's entertainment. He could sound no louder praise
                        of the 77th than to repeat the compliment paid it by Gen. Rosecrans: "Give
                        the brave boys my compliments, their's is the banner regiment, the only one
                        that stood at Stone River;" and the last words of Col. Housum, "Stay with
                        the 77th."</p>

                    <p>Capt. Miles Zentmyer responded in a most eloquent manner to the fifth toast
                        of the evening, "Our Country. Her past history and her destiny were his
                        theme. The dread ordeal of war, the woe, and anguish are past, and America
                        basks in the bright sunlight of peace.</p>

                    <p>The toast "Our Fallen Comrades," was drank standing and in silence.</p>

                    <p>The last toast was "Our Guests," and Prof. Shumaker, in response, said that
                        he could understand how there could be a sympathy between soldiers; how
                        those who had gone through the same privations could feel as brothers. There
                        was sympathy at home for the soldier, it was enough for him to say I have
                        fought for the old flag. It was said in Europe "clothe all your women in
                        black, rob them of their ornaments, of all things which makes them
                        beautiful, and your wars will cease." They blamed the wars on the women; but
                        they were wrong. The women have done good. How many are they who have been
                        kept from a cowardly set because some loved woman at home would hear of it.
                        Then there is the record of hospital service. Without women there is a lack
                        of true military spirit. From the spirit the true character of a man can be
                        known. <emph rend="italic">Not one Pennsylvania regiment disgraced the
                        flag.</emph></p>

                    <p>At two o'clock the guest arose and the Reunion of the 77th was at an end.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Demming</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kesson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pyfer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foy</ln>
                        <fn>Neal</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Malony</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zentmyer</ln>
                        <fn>Miles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor described in vivid detail the reunion of the 77th Pennsylvania
                    regiment. Different speakers gave a detailed history of the regiment, including
                    all the battles they fought during the war. The members of the reunion then
                    picked officers to plan the next reunion and offered toasts to the veterans.
                    Within these toasts some of the speakers mentioned the attributes of women and
                    their steadfastness in the cause(at the same time insisting they would never
                    want the vote).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.12.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Olive Logan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper expects a full crowd for the upcoming lecture by Olive Logan, one
                    of the most "brilliant of the female orators of the present day." "Olive is one
                    of the celebrities of the day--one of the products of the nineteenth century,
                    which only this progressive nation can exhibit. To have an opportunity to hear
                    her is a privilege a Franklin county audience does not often have a chance to
                    enjoy." She will lecture on "Girls." "Who does not feel anxious to hear them
                    talked about by one of the most brilliant of their sex, and who knows all about
                    them? What a relief from political harangues, and dry scientific topics! She
                    will tell us some new things about the pretty dears."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>An ardent Democrat, full of devotion to the great White Man's party, thus
                        delivered himself to the patentee of that popular idea on the Court House
                        steps: "I'm a Democrat, yes, I always stood up for Democracy; I got many a
                        black eye for talkin' for that party. I am not for the nigger, no sir-ee. I
                        didn't send my son to the army to fight to free the niggers; he got fifteen
                        hundred dollars for going in the army. I don't go for the nigger
                        Republicans." This bit of raw material no doubt was intended to be worked up
                        by the aforesaid patentee, as an exhibit of the spirit which animates the
                        White Man's party in its struggles to keep the nigger down, but
                        unfortunately it came too late for the present campaign. Lest it should be
                        lost in the excitement of the last hours of the fight with the colored
                        voters, we preserve it for their future use.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor copied some racist remarks made by a Democratic voters to incite
                    black voters to support the Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Gas Company is working on installing gas pipes out North Front Street
                    to Wilson College. This will allow residents on the streets to have gas in their
                    homes. The paper advocates installing gas street lamps as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Shooting Gallery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilvrey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Gilvrey, a "generous, open hearted son of the Emerald Isle," has opened
                    a shooting gallery in the Repository building which has become "the constant
                    resort of the sporting lads of Chambersburg. It presents a good opportunity of
                    becoming proficient at fire arms."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Wilson College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ceremonies "inaugurating Wilson College as one of the Institution of
                    Learning of the land" will be held on Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Church of God Bethel will hold services on Sunday. The topics are "Who and
                    how many are to be saved?" and "Was Dickens a Christian?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Temperance Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. E. W. Kirby of Chambersburg will lecture on temperance in Lyceum Hall,
                    Greenvillage, on the 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Vote of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell><emph rend="italic">Governor</emph>,'69</cell>
                            <cell>
                                <emph rend="italic">Congress,'70</emph>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Geary, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Packer, D.</cell>
                            <cell>Cessna, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Meyers, D.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Antrim</cell>
                            <cell>507</cell>
                            <cell>485</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>26</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, N.W.</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>253</cell>
                            <cell>103</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, S.W.</cell>
                            <cell>256</cell>
                            <cell>271</cell>
                            <cell>152</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Concord</cell>
                            <cell>28</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dry Run</cell>
                            <cell>105</cell>
                            <cell>103</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fayetteville</cell>
                            <cell>220</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenvillage</cell>
                            <cell>183</cell>
                            <cell>114</cell>
                            <cell>84</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Guilford</cell>
                            <cell>182</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>44</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hamilton</cell>
                            <cell>88</cell>
                            <cell>156</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>54</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Letterkenny</cell>
                            <cell>149</cell>
                            <cell>223</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lurgan</cell>
                            <cell>89</cell>
                            <cell>153</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Loudon</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>119</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Metal</cell>
                            <cell>132</cell>
                            <cell>96</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery</cell>
                            <cell>205</cell>
                            <cell>172</cell>
                            <cell>128*</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Orrstown</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peters</cell>
                            <cell>136</cell>
                            <cell>69</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Quincy</cell>
                            <cell>214</cell>
                            <cell>299</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>67</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Southampton</cell>
                            <cell>48</cell>
                            <cell>73</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sulpher Spring</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>St. Thomas</cell>
                            <cell>147</cell>
                            <cell>221</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>104</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Washington</cell>
                            <cell>330</cell>
                            <cell>297</cell>
                            <cell>14</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Welsh Run</cell>
                            <cell>124</cell>
                            <cell>139</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren</cell>
                            <cell>35</cell>
                            <cell>58</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>3698</cell>
                            <cell>4006</cell>
                            <cell>....</cell>
                            <cell>....</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>-Includes Peters box. voting at Mercersburg</p>

                    <p>Returns received from the election districts indicate that the County will be
                        close.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor printed the voter returns from township in Franklin County. He
                    put complete data for the gubernatorial election in 1869 but has incomplete data
                    for the 1870 Congressional election, although he said the outcome would be very
                    close.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mosser</ln>
                        <fn>Robert F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bennet</ln>
                        <fn>Henetta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert F. Mosser of Fulton County and Miss Henetta Bennet of Mercersburg
                    were married on October 6th in the U. B. Church by the Rev. John Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hafer</ln>
                        <fn>Willis P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willis P. Hafer of Cumberland County and Mary A. Stouffer, daughter of E.
                    Stouffer, were married at the home of the bride's parents near Newburg on
                    October 4th by the Rev. J. P. Anthony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. C. Aughinbaugh of Pittsburgh and Miss Lizzie A. Crawford were married at
                    the residence of the bride in Tarentum on September 29th by the Rev. W. D.
                    Stevens assisted by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph H. Willson of New York and Miss Lizzie Culbertson of Chambersburg
                    were married on October 4th by the Rev. Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eiker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tripner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel F. Eiker and Miss Jennie Cook, both of Franklin, were married on
                    October 4th by the Rev. A. Tripner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warnich</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeeks</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tripner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewis D. Warnich and Miss Charlotte Zeeks, both of Franklin, were married
                    on October 9th by the Rev. A. Tripner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Jenkins, son of John D. and Nannie T. Jenkins, died in Hanover on
                    October 3rd. He was three years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>John Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Andrew Schofield, son of Josiah E. and Sarah F. Schofield, died in
                    Chambersburg on September 20th. He was 3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan Reed died on October 6th at the residence of her son-in-law, L. B.
                    Kurtz. She was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.12.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
