<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-02-22">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>8</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="1" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22.01">
            <pageNote>National news on politics.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="2" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22.02">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Assault on Mr. Hickman</head>
                <origin>N.Y. Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article accuses South of bullying North on slavery and overreacting to
                    statements by Rep. Hickman, Rep.-Pa., in Congress on John Brown's raid.
                    Virginians and Southerners considered the statement a matter of honor and were
                    ready to fight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="3" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22.03">
            <pageNote>Ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="4" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22.04">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Need of a Tariff</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The fact that every branch of productive industry is completely paralyzed;
                    that all classes of society are suffering from the effects of the ruinous policy
                    of Federalist locofocoism -which produced the terrible panic in the financial
                    world during the Fall of 1857, as a necessary result of destroying the
                    manufactories of our own, to build up those of foreign countries -should open
                    the eyes of the blindest, and shine in upon the most obtuse intellect in the
                    lower House . . . "</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It seems like a work of supererogation to attempt to urge upon Congress the
                        necessity for a good, wise, protective tariff. The first principle of nature
                        -self-preservation- should furnish the one great, powerful argument in favor
                        of remodeling the present nominal impost laws -amounting almost to Free
                        Trade. The fact that every branch of productive industry is completely
                        paralyzed; that all classes of society are suffering from the effects of the
                        ruinous policy of Federalist locofocoism -which produced the terrible panic
                        in the financial world during the Fall of 1857, as a necessary result of
                        destroying the manufactories of our own, to build up those of foreign
                        countries -should open the eyes of the blindest, and shine in upon the most
                        obtuse intellect in the lower House; as these facts set forth, unmistakably,
                        the imperative demand for action, by that body, on this all important topic.</p>
                    <p>If, however, any further incentive were needed; any greater light required to
                        clear away the mistiness which beclouds the brains of locofoco, Federalist
                        politicians; if any stronger reasons are necessary to convince all men
                        everywhere, throughout our country, of the necessity, the absolute,
                        immediate, requirement for a thorough readjustment of the revenue laws, so
                        as to discriminate in favor of and protect American made goods from the
                        ruinous competition of the productions of pauper labor on the other side of
                        the Atlantic, we think the following will suffice. If is clipped from a late
                        number of the London <emph rend="italic">Times</emph>:</p>
                    <p>"The importation of cotton into this country has, since the import duty was
                        abolished, increased sixteen fold. Having been 63,000,000 lbs., it is now
                        1,000,000,000 lbs. This is one of those giant facts which stands head and
                        shoulders higher than the crowd -so high and so broad that we can neither
                        overlook it nor affect not to see it. It proves the existence of a thousand
                        smaller facts that must stand under its shadow. It tells of sixteen times as
                        many mills, sixteen times as many English families living by working those
                        mills, sixteen times as much profit derived from sixteen times as much
                        capital engaged in this manufacture. It carries after it sequences of
                        increased quantity of freights and insurances, and necessities for sixteen
                        time the amount of customers to consume, to our profit, the immense amount
                        of produce we are turning out. There are not many such facts as <emph
                            rend="italic">these</emph>, arising in the quiet routine of industrial
                        history. It is so large and so steady that we can steer our national policy
                        by it; it is so important to us that we should be reduced to embarrassment
                        if it were suddenly to disappear. It teaches us to persevere in a policy
                        which has produced so wonderful a result; its beneficent operation makes it
                        essential to us to deal carefully with it now that we have got it."</p>
                    <p>What a commentary on the blindness and folly of the wise-acres of locofoco
                        federalism? England's leading organ boasts of the free importation of cotton
                        into British ports as resulting in the increase of industry throughout Great
                        Britain sixteen fold. The greater part of this raw material was grown upon
                        American soil.--Its manufacture at home would have given constant employment
                        to sixteen workmen at home, and perhaps more, for one now employed without
                        that raw material to work up. English journalists proclaim to the world the
                        secret of British prosperity; showing that industry promoted is the chief
                        source of their success, and yet other nations, whose people are equally as
                        dependent upon the labor of their country, see these statements, believe in
                        their truthfulness, and foolishly refuse to apply the proper remedy,
                        although suffering unheard of privations in consequence of Governmental
                        neglect.</p>
                    <p>The policy of Great Britain, controlled as the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Times</emph> says by the effects produced upon the masses of her people, is
                        to abolish duties or increase Tariffs in proportion to the benefit thereof
                        upon English manufactured wares seeking a market upon British soil, the
                        law-makers lost no time in placing upon the statute Books of her majesty's
                        realm such laws as the people demanded. Here, however, where the people are,
                        or profess to be, the real sovereigns, the loud earnest demands and
                        supplicating appeals of the masses to their servants, the Representatives in
                        both branches of Congress, do not seem to weigh a feather with these
                        dignitaries, elevated for a brief period by the votes of the thousands whom
                        they heartlessly refuse to relieve.</p>
                    <p>We are well aware that there are noble, honorable exceptions to this rule;
                        that there are a large number of the present Congress who are anxious to
                        arrest the madness of the system of transporting all our raw material to
                        foreign work shops to be made up, as is now the case, and who will vote for
                        any fair, honest Tariff laws; but our surprise is that any American citizen;
                        any lover of his country, can be found so blind as not to see the necessity
                        of prompt action in the present crisis.</p>
                    <p>The disgraceful notice of the departure of a vessel for England, with a
                        certain number of passengers, and upwards of an hundred thousand dollars in
                        gold and silver, which meets the indignant eye of the constant reader of
                        daily papers, almost every few weeks, will be forever disposed of if
                        Congress makes the necessary arrangements for keeping the precious metals at
                        home; by passing laws for the protection of home labor -which will keep the
                        money at home also.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Congress should pass a tariff on imported manufactures to
                    ensure that domestic goods remain competitive.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Traitors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The descendants of the Revolutionary tories of South Carolina, who are so
                    zealous for the breaking up of the present confederacy of States, . . . are
                    guilty of treason."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The descendants of the Revolutionary tories of South Carolina, who are so
                        zealous for the breaking up of the present confederacy of States; and all
                        their aiders and abettors, from any portion of the Union, are guilty of
                        treason. The Congressmen, and the members of the State legislatures, who
                        take part in the treasonable movements of the nullification State, who have
                        sworn to uphold the Constitution of the U.S., are guilty of perjury, as well
                        as treason. They all trample under their unhallowed feet the 2nd clause of
                        the 10th section of Article 1st of the Constitution of the United States,
                        which reads as follows:</p>
                    <p>"No State shall, <emph rend="italic">without the consent of Congress,</emph>
                        lay any duty on tonnage, keep troops or ships of war in time of peace, ENTER
                        INTO ANY ARRANGEMENT OR COMPACT WITH ANOTHER STATE, <emph rend="italic">or
                            with a foreign power, or engage in war.</emph>"</p>
                    <p>What could be plainer? How could the framers of the Constitution -the
                        document for which Southern members of Congress profess to entertain so much
                        reverence -have more fully expressed their disapprobation of all such
                        movements as are now on foot in the sunny South? It looks as though the
                        founders of the great Republic, the last, lone asylum of sweet, sweet
                        liberty, were gifted with prophetic vision which enabled them to predict,
                        and provide for, the doings of bad men in these latter days.</p>
                    <p>To hear grave, Southern Senators declaring that the Union is only of value
                        while the constitution is preserved; that it is the Constitution which gives
                        power to the Union, and then witnessing their acquiescence in the wicked
                        schemes of baseborn tories to up-turn the whole temple of American liberty;
                        wantonly violating the Constitution (the Southern Senators' political Bible)
                        with impunity -not one of them daring to say a word in its defense, shows
                        most clearly the necessity for wresting the whole machinery of government
                        from the keeping of such men in the Union is to be kept sacred. As well
                        might we set wolves to watch sheep as such creatures to guard the temple of
                        American liberty, of the palladium of the basis of the Union of the
                    States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial condemns South Carolina as treasonous for continuing to press for
                    disunion.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frfeb60.html#2.22b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Register and Recorder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Voters of Green Township</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lego</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter to the editors nominating C. W. Lego for the position of Register
                    and Recorder of the People's Party Nominating Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="5" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22.05">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Non Sectarian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S. Lewis</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hay</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bausman</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>Philip B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schenck</ln>
                        <fn>B.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauliflower</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Book recommendation from the editors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Last Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of clothing company in Chambersburg for sale.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Self Ruling Envelopes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ligget</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of new envelopes available through John Ligget, postmaster of
                    Chambersburg</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Good Penmanship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn>O. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of extraordinary penmanship of the Cumberland Valley R.R. clerk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="6" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22.06">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Disunion Party</head>
                <origin>Providence Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Democratic party has passed into the hands of the nullifiers. The
                    little black cloud, no bigger than a man's hand, that appeared on the verge of
                    the horizon, has spread over the whole sky -and its dark shadow is on all the
                    land."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Democratic party has passed into the hands of the nullifiers. The little
                        black cloud, no bigger than a man's hand, that appeared on the verge of the
                        horizon, has spread over the whole sky -and its dark shadow is on all the
                        land. The benignant recognition of human rights; the generous regard for
                        progress that once distinguished the party, and compensated in some degree,
                        for its errors and its radicalism, have given place to intolerance,
                        despotism, nullification, and to an indifference to all the interest of the
                        country, except slavery. To the extension and the strengthening of that
                        institution, all its efforts are directed, and all its policy is bent. The
                        favorite remedy which it proposes for any evil under the Constitution is to
                        dissolve the Union, and the leaders of the party bring up that remedy on
                        every occasion. They propose to go into the Presidential election under the
                        form of the Constitution and the laws. If they succeed, they will claim, as
                        they will have the right to claim, the acquiescence of the other party, and
                        its cheerful obedience to the just authority of the new administration; if
                        they fail, they propose to break up the Union, to prevent, by force the
                        inauguration of the President elected by the people, and to destroy the
                        Government when they cannot control its policy and dispense its patronage.</p>
                    <p>This is the position of the Democratic party; his is the plan which the
                        Democrats hope to carry, and which is held up in the other States to
                        frighten people from voting according to their own deliberate judgment. The
                        triumph of a party on this doctrine and under this threat, would be the
                        triumph of nullification. The government would cease to be elective, in any
                        proper sense of the word. It would be the rule of the minority. The
                        administration would be given, not to the party that cast the greatest
                        number of votes, but to that which made the loudest threats and manifested
                        the most disloyal temper. The precedents once established would be followed
                        up; the party that could retain the government by such cheap and easy means
                        as threatening to overthrow it, would rule as a spoiled child rules the
                        house. Had Gen. Jackson given up to nullification under the threats of South
                        Carolina, the authority of the government, once successfully defied, would
                        never have been restored except by a struggle greater than the constitution
                        has yet passed through. Far beyond all his military services stands out the
                        firm and patriotic conduct of Gen. Jackson at that period; when he declared
                        that the Union must and should be preserved, and followed up his declaration
                        by preparations to enforce it, and rallied the whole country around the
                        standard of the constitution. How different is the Democratic party of
                        to-day from that which then responded to the patriotic summons of its chief,
                        standing firmly by the constitution, and bearing aloft the flag of the
                            Union.--<emph rend="italic">Providence (R.I.) Journal.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial argues that Democrats in the South are using the threat of
                    disunion to win the presidential race in 1860.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frfeb60.html#2.22c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Native African</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He will be taken care of and sent to the coast of Africa by a vessel which
                    is expected to sail during the present week. Pabla expresses a great desire to
                    return to his home, that he may again see his wives and father."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Yesterday afternoon a native african was placed in charge of captain
                        Brashears, at the central Police Station, to await the order of Dr. Hall,
                        the agent of the Colonization Society. It appears that he was born at a
                        point at considerable distance south of Monrovia, and where, by frequent
                        stoppage of English vessels the people are partially civilized. Having
                        reached the age of twenty years, Pabla, as the man calls himself, obeyed the
                        custom of his land and took five wives, with all of whom he says he lived
                        happily. A few months ago, the ship Exchange touched at the native town of
                        Pabla, and having a desire to see the world, he shipped as a sailor and come
                        to Baltimore. An idea has lately haunted him that some of his own color
                        wanted to sell him as a slave, and having been born a free man, he became
                        terribly excited by fear.</p>
                    <p>The custom of that part of Africa is to mark all who are born free, and Pabla
                        was quick to exhibit his marks to all who approached him. The centre of his
                        forehead from the hair to the nose bears the mark of the branding iron, and
                        at the outer corner of each eye there are three distinct marks made by the
                        same means. Besides these the iron was placed on his left arm, reaching from
                        the wrist neatly to the elbow, leaving a corrugated surface. Those are his
                        marks of freedom. His dialect is entirely unintelligible in this region, and
                        the English words he has learned, are so badly spoken that it is difficult
                        to understand what he says. He is about six feet high, of fine proportions,
                        and his hands look as if they had been but little used to labor.--He will be
                        taken care of and sent to the coast of Africa by a vessel which is expected
                        to sail during the present week. Pabla expresses a great desire to return to
                        his home, that he may again see his wives and father.--<emph rend="italic"
                            >Baltimore Sun,</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports the story of an African visitor to the U.S. who found
                    himself threatened with enslavement.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frfeb60.html#2.22d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="7" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22.07">
            <pageNote>All Ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="8" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.02.22.08">
            <pageNote/>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Harrison Jones married Miss Elizabeth Rosenberry on February 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCreary</ln>
                        <fn>Aurelia M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John Rebert married Miss Aurelia M. McCreary, both of Adams Co. on
                    February 16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearman</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Samuel H. Gillan married Miss Susan Catharine Shearman on February 16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Adam Piper married Miss Kate Henderson on February 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Elmira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James E. Henderson married Miss Elmira Snively on February 16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodrock</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Donnell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Daviel Rock married Miss Mary J. O'Donnell on February 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jospeh Martin, age 20, died on February 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbons</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbons</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Gibbons, consort of Mr. Charles Gibbons, died at the age of
                    60 on February 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. ----- Zeigler, age 80, died at the home of her son, Samuel Zeigler on
                    February 11. On February 19 Mrs. Mary Zeigler, wife of Samuel Zeigler, died at
                    the age of 36.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"How soon this lovely child followed her sainted mother to Heaven!"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Jennette Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Florence M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jennette Martha Duncan, daughter of Augustus and Florence M. Duncan, age 2
                    years 6 months and 9 days, died on February 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
