<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02">
     <header>
          <title>Franklin Repository</title>
          <tagger>
               <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
               <tagDate>10/28/96</tagDate>
               <tagNote>First Pass</tagNote>
          </tagger>
          <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
          <date n="1860-05-02">
               <year>1860</year>
               <month norm="05">May</month>
               <day norm="02">2</day>
               <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
          </date>
          <frequency>weekly</frequency>
          <extent>8</extent>
          <editionNote/>
     </header>
     <paperBody>
          <page n="1" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02.01">
               <pageNote>Report of John Hickman, Chairman of the Committee on the
               Judiciary.</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="2" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02.02">
               <pageNote>Article on Education. Advertisements.</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="3" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02.03">
               <pageNote>Article in the New York Christian Advocate and Journal advocates Judge
                    McLean for the Presidency.</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="4" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02.04">
               <pageNote/>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>1</column>
                    <head>Law and Order</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt>"Under the banner of 'Law and Order,' in Kansas, that outraged portion
                         of our land, the Locofoco, proslavery tools of the national administration
                         perpetrated every species of wantonness--every description of wickedness."</excerpt>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>Editorial accuses Democratic Party of disobeying law and promoting
                         disorder from Kansas to Baltimore, where the previous week Democrats broke
                         up the Republican's nominating meeting for the Chicago convention.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>3</column>
                    <head>Strike for Freedom</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt>"Republicans of Franklin!--You have a part to perform in the grand
                         achievement--the enfranchising of your Southern bretheren."</excerpt>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>REPUBLICANS OF FRANKLIN!--You have a part to perform in the grand
                              achievement--the enfranchising of your Southern brethren. Every right
                              which a freeman holds dear, has been there stricken down by the
                              co-horts of Slavery. Liberty of speech is unknown; the Press--which is
                              formidable only to tyrants--is muzzled; and every impulse that
                              ennobles humanity and beautiful freedom, is dwarfed, smothered,
                              crushed out by the reign of terror which has been inaugurated by the
                              Southern leaders of the Locofoco party. It therefore behooves every
                              lover of Freedom to buckle on his armor to do many battle in the great
                              contest for Free Principles that we are now about entering upon. Truth
                              has often been stricken down, but "truth, crushed to earth, shall rise
                              again." Give your best exertions to exalt her, and if victory crown
                              our combined efforts, one very satisfactory reflection will be, not
                              that we have asserted and maintained our own rights as freemen, but
                              that we have assisted in giving others the same boone--clothed others
                              with the same mantle of glorious freedom.</p>
                         <p>The election of a Republican President would be the signal for the
                              uprising of Republicanism in the South. The masses, who have been so
                              long down-trodden by the Slave Oligarchy, would arise in their might
                              and emancipate themselves from a bondage that is even worse than
                              slavery of the body--the loss of their birth-right as American
                              citizens. As an evidence of this, we ill here quote the language of
                              Mr. JENKINS, of Virginia, who but a few days ago, while addressing
                              Congress, deprecating the success of the Republican party, as a
                              misfortune, said:</p>
                         <p>"Another misfortune would be the dispensation of patronage throughout
                              the South by a Republican President, in such a way as to build up and
                              strengthen Republicanism." It was a great mistake to suppose that
                              southern men would not be found to take office under a Republican
                              President, and thus the germ of a Republican party would spring up in
                              the very bosom of the South."</p>
                         <p>This accounts for the violence of the Nigger Democracy against the
                              organization of the White Man's of Republican party in the South--"men
                              would be found to take office under a Republican President, and thus
                              Republicanism would spring up in the very bosom of the South"!--Like
                              Demetrius of old, the leader of the silver smiths who made silver
                              shrines for Diana, apprehending that the Apostle's teachings would
                              interfere with their trade, assembled his co laborers and addressed
                              them thus:--"Sirs, ye know that by this craft we have our wealth," and
                              they were filled with wrath and cried out, "Great is Diana of the
                              Ephesians," and a mob was raised to assault Paul, similar to that
                              raised in Baltimore, and other localities in the South, against
                              peaceable assemblages of Republicans. They fear the organization of a
                              Republican party in the South--not that it would conflict with the
                              development of their resources, mechanical, manufacturing,
                              agricultural, or commercial--but the Government patronage would slip
                              out of their hands, and it is by that "craft they have their wealth."
                              This is the secret of the whole opposition; but you might as well try
                              to dam up a rapidly flowing stream of water with sand as to attempt to
                              prevent the spread of truth, religious or political. Republicanism is
                              political truth, and the fates have decreed its triumph over the
                              combined opposition of ignorance and fanaticism, backed by the corrupt
                              patronage of the General Government and the misrepresentation of the
                              Nigger Democracy.</p>
                         <p>The Republican Conventions held in Maryland, Missouri, Virginia,
                              Delaware and Kentucky, to send Delegates to the Chicago Convention,
                              are the entering wedges that will eventually split the log that has
                              heretofore interposed as a barrier to the propagation of political
                              truth in the South, and when the triumph is complete, no people will
                              rejoice more than the Southern people themselves, when fully clothed
                              in the glorious habiliments of political freedom.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>Editorial suggests that the Republican party will win the presidential
                         election and spread into the South.</summary>
                    <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.2a</note>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>3</column>
                    <head>Sectionalism</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt>"In the present state of affairs in the South, it requires brave men to
                         be Republicans, not that its princoples are antagonistic to the interests
                         of that or any other section of the country. . . but because the men and
                         measures of the party have been so misrepresented, maligned, traduced, and
                         villified by the Nigger Democracy."</excerpt>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>Editorial praises the efforts of Republicans in Maryland in the face of
                         violence and intimidation to form their party.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>4</column>
                    <head>The Census</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt>"Many have refrained from giving correct answers to the persons
                         appointed to take the Census, supposing that, if they did so, it would lead
                         to an increase of taxation."</excerpt>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>"The decennial census of the United States will be taken in the present
                              year. Agents will be appointed for every district in the States and
                              Territories, and every farm house and cabin within their limits will
                              be visited. The census-taker will have many questions to ask. Every
                              farmer will be expected to give a concise and accurate statement of
                              the number of acres occupied by him, and each crop raised during the
                              year ending June, 1859. These reports will be called for in June, and
                              it would be well for every farmer to write down, in advance, the
                              number of acres under cultivation, including the wheat, etc.,
                              gathered. The number of acres of each kind, the amount per acre, and
                              the gross amount will be required. The milk products also, and the
                              amount of poor, beef, etc., will all be asked for."</p>
                         <p>Heretofore, many have refrained from giving correct answers to the
                              persons appointed to take the Census, supposing that, if they did so,
                              it would lead to an increase of taxation. This is not so; and persons
                              who are better informed, should take occasion to disabuse the minds of
                              all on this matter. Correct answers to all questions in the matter of
                              taking the Census is very desirable, as showing by comparison, the
                              progress our country is making not only in population, but in every
                              department of her Industrial Pursuits--Agriculture, Manufacturers,
                              Commerce, &amp;c., the increase of the field, the mine the shop,
                              and of every other branch of industry that tends to develope our
                              untold national wealth and resources. If all could be made to
                              understand the importance, in this respect, of correct answers in this
                              matter, the aggregated wealth of our young nation when summed up,
                              would astonish the world.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>Editors ask citizens to cooperate in the census and advertise the
                         wealth of the nation.</summary>
                    <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.2b</note>
                    <look/>
               </div>
          </page>
          <page n="5" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02.05">
               <pageNote/>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>1</column>
                    <head>Unexpected, but Welcome Visitor</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Tyler</ln>
                              <fn>Edmund</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Lull</ln>
                              <fn>O. N.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Col.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Carpenter</ln>
                              <fn>James</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Dr.</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Accident victim, Edmund Tyler, run over by train recovers.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>1</column>
                    <head>Excelsior</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt>"Any young man who can secure a situation under so faithful an
                         instructor as MR. HULL, cannot fail to make a first-class workman, if he
                         has brains enough to retain the necessary instructions he will receive."</excerpt>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>Not long since we gave an account of the manufacturing of a locomotive
                              at the work- shops of the Cumberland Valley Rail Road, in this place.
                              It is now our duty to record the fact that another one is being built
                              in the same establishment.</p>
                         <p>We claim for the Chambersburg works a high place in the role of machine
                              shops. No engine of its size--and it was made for certain work--can
                              surpass the "Enterprise," the engine which was turned out by this
                              concern last Fall.</p>
                         <p>We had the pleasure of inspecting some of the beautiful specimens of
                              workmanship intended for the new engine, and say, without hesitation,
                              that we never saw anything more perfect--the product of man's skill.</p>
                         <p>These beautiful samples of handicraft, which we examined were made by
                              MR. JULIUS F. GIBBS, and MR. JACOB FULLER, under the supervision of
                              MR. ABRAHAM HULL, the Master Mechanic of the establishment, with whom
                              both these young gentlemen learned their trade. Any young man who can
                              secure a situation under so faithful an instructor as MR. HULL, cannot
                              fail to make a first-class workman, if he has brains enough to retain
                              the necessary instructions he will receive.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Fuller</ln>
                              <fn>Jacob</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Gibbs</ln>
                              <fn>Julius F.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hull</ln>
                              <fn>Abraham</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Cumberland Valley Railroad machine shop in Chambersburg will construct
                         a locomotive engine.</summary>
                    <note>frbrowser/frmay60.html#5.2c</note>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>1</column>
                    <head>Praiseworthy</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Lull</ln>
                              <fn>O. N.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hull</ln>
                              <fn>Abraham</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Reilly</ln>
                              <fn>Wilson</fn>
                              <sf>Jr.</sf>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Article complements the "manly independence" of Wilson Reilly who is
                         working to become a mechanic on the Cumberland Valley Railroad.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>1</column>
                    <head>Wicked Robbery</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt>"Bring back the money and cheat the devil out of victims whom he now
                         feels sure of receiving into his gloomy regions of eternal woe. You will
                         have no peace in this life if you keep this ill-gotten treasure; and your
                         misery hereafter will be everlasting."</excerpt>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>Certain heartless villains, who had not the fear of an all-seeing,
                              vengeance-taking God before their eyes, broke into the Sabbath School
                              Room connected with the Presbyterian Church, of this place on Monday
                              night last, and stole therefrom all the money--amounting to nearly, if
                              not quite, eighty dollars--which the children have been contributing
                              for the past year.</p>
                         <p>The hardened scamps--there were three of them--will have a thorny bed to
                              lie upon when they come down to the end of their brief existence.
                              "Thou shalt not steal," will ring through their terrified souls as the
                              death-knell of their guilty spirits.</p>
                         <p>Bring back the money and cheat the devil out of victims whom he now
                              feels sure of receiving into his gloomy regions of eternal woe. You
                              will have no peace in this life if you keep this ill-gotten treasure;
                              and your misery hereafter will be everlasting.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>Article laments the robbery of the Presbyterian Church of $80.00.</summary>
                    <note>In Browser</note>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>1</column>
                    <head>Barn Burned</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Baker</ln>
                              <fn>Daniel</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Daniel Baker's log barn burned--cause was "a very young lad, with a
                         match, who was not conscious of the destruction that would follow the act."</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
          </page>
          <page n="6" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02.06">
               <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="7" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02.07">
               <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="8" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.02.08">
               <pageNote/>
               <div type="s">
                    <column>4</column>
                    <head>Married</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Carothers</ln>
                              <fn>Andrew G.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Fitzgerald</ln>
                              <fn>James D.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                              <fn>M. Lucy</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                              <fn>David</fn>
                              <sf>Esq.</sf>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Rev. James D. Fitzgerald of Martinsville, Ohio, married Miss M. Lucy
                         Witherspoon, daughter of David Witherspoon, on May 26.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="s">
                    <column>4</column>
                    <head>Married</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>George</ln>
                              <fn>H. H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>McLean</ln>
                              <fn>Robert</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>McNeil</ln>
                              <fn>Mary</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Robert McLean married Miss Mary McNeil, of Cedarville, Greene County,
                         Ohio, on May 5.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="s">
                    <column>4</column>
                    <head>Married</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Bishop</ln>
                              <fn>Jas. M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Bishop</ln>
                              <fn>J. Philip</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Snively</ln>
                              <fn>Ellie E.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Rev. J. Philip Bishop of Penn. Conference married Miss Ellie E. Snively
                         on May 1.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="o">
                    <column>4</column>
                    <head>Died</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                              <fn>John</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Mr. John Witherspoon, a Ruling Elder in the Presbyterian Church of
                         Mercersburg, died age 79 on May 26.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="o">
                    <column>4</column>
                    <head>Died</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Brown</ln>
                              <fn>Cornelius</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Brown</ln>
                              <fn>Bridget C.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Sellers</ln>
                              <fn>Leonard</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Mrs. Bridget C. Brown died of paralisis at the home of Mr. Leonard
                         Sellers on May 24.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="o">
                    <column>4</column>
                    <head>Died</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <commentary/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Mills</ln>
                              <fn>Mary</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Mills</ln>
                              <fn>William</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Mrs. Mary Mills, relict of the late William Mills, died after a
                         protracted illness, age about 74 on May 1.</summary>
                    <note/>
                    <look/>
               </div>
          </page>
     </paperBody>
</hwp>
