<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-05-23">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Republican National Convention! Full Particulars! Glorious Platform! Great
                    Enthusiasm! Abraham Lincoln! For President! Hannibal Hamlin! For Vice President!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of the Republican Convention which met in Chicago on May
                    16th--May 18th. Within that time, bickering and misunderstands occurred, the
                    Platform was established and, after three ballots and many transfers of votes,
                    Abraham Lincoln beat out William H. Seward. Hannibal Hamlin was elected after
                    two ballots.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Coverage of the convention is continued on page 8.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Notice To The Tax-Payers Of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAfee</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliot</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullen</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowden</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pauling</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tankersley</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The County Treasurer, John Stouffer, announces he will be at the following
                    places (at various times from May 23 to June 12) to collect the County and State
                    Taxes for 1860: in Montgomery Twp.--James McAfee's home in Mercersburg and Jacob
                    Elliot's home in Welsh Run; in Peters Twp--the store of James D. Scott in
                    Bridgeport and James Mullen's house in Loudon; in Quincy Twp.--the home of
                    Andrew Shank in Funkstown and the home of George A Anderson in Quincy;
                    Washington Twp--at the home of Francis Bowden in Waynesboro; in Antrim Twp.--at
                    the home of Thomas Pauling in Greencastle; in St. Thomas Twp.--at the home of
                    John R. Rankersley in St. Thomas; in Green Twp.-- at the house of Martin
                    Shoemaker in Greenvillage and at John Brown's house in Fayetteville; in Hamilton
                    Twp.--at the house of John Gordon; in Guilford Twp.--at the house of James D.
                    Richardson in New Franklin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Serial Fiction; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Synopsis Of The Proceedings Of The Fifth Semi-Annual Meeting Of The Franklin
                    County Teachers' Association.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. Rhea</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Omwake</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Emerson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwaine</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwaine</ln>
                        <fn>J. Shannon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckhart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoeler</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bridenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glenn</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weir</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>J. W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Recording Secretary, J. Rhea Gaff, writes a synopsis of the Franklin
                    County Teachers' Association meeting that met on May 9 to May 11. The First Day:
                    Vice President Cook called order in the morning, and Vice President Omwake
                    chaired in the afternoon. Discussion on School Government were led by Messrs.
                    Newman, Gaff, Omwake, S. H. Eby, Cook, J. L. P. Detrich, C. B. Wolf and D. W.
                    Hoover, of Ringgold, Md. In the evening, Rev. E. Emerson led a prayer. A.
                    McElwaine, J. R. Gaff and J. L. P. Detrich were appointed to solicit a copy of a
                    lecture. J. Shannon McElwaine read. Second Day: Vice President Cook chaired and
                    A. McElwaine prayed. A. McElwaine reported on Orthography and discussions were
                    led by Messrs. Gaff, Omwake and Eckhart. J. L. P. Detrich spoke on Reading, A.
                    B. Stoeler spoke on Oral Arithmetic, and W. H. Hockenberry on Fractions. In the
                    afternoon, C. B. Wolf prayed. Mr. Cook proposed that a committee solicit the
                    legislature for summer school funding, and J. Cook, A. McElwaine and J. L. P.
                    Detrich were chosen to do so. J. S. McElwaine spoke on Position, A. McElwaine on
                    Alligation and J. R. Gaff on powers and roots of numbers. J. L. P. Detrich, W.
                    H. Newman and W. H. Hockenberry were appointed a committee on resolutions. In
                    the Evening Session, J. W. Coble chaired, and Rev. E. Bridenbaugh prayed. Rev.
                    T. G. Apple lectured on Education. A. McElwaine, J. L. P. Detrich and J. R. Gaff
                    were appointed a committee to solicit a copy for publication. J. L. P. Detrich
                    read on Apologies at the meetings. The Third Day: Lewis W. Detrich spoke on
                    Geography, and a debate on studying at home involved L. W. Detrich, J. R. Gaff,
                    and J. S. Smith. C. G. Glenn and Mr. Omwake also spoke on Geography. J. S.
                    Smith, T. M. Richards, A. McElwaine and C. B. Wolf spoke on English Grammar. In
                    the Afternoon Session Messrs McElwaine, Omwake, Smith, Weir and others discussed
                    Grammar. J. W. P. Reid spoke on Algebra, Andrew McElwaine spoke on Geography. In
                    the Evening Session, Rev. T. G. Apple prayed and a resolution was passed, that
                    included thanking the lecturers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description and history of the Republican ticket, Abraham Lincoln from
                    Indiana and Hannibal Hamlin from Maine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Almost A Fatal Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fritz</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article describes how Alexander Fritz of Chambersburg, while working
                    as Baggage Master on the train on May 18th, was shot in the thigh by a drunken
                    passenger. Dr. Richards dressed the wound.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Caledonia Springs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A note that Mrs. H. Cooper has leased the Caledonia Springs for the ensuing
                    season.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Biddle</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major General E. M. Biddle, of Carlisle, has appointed A. D. Caufman, of
                    Chambersburg, as his aid, with the rank of Major.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 19th, the people of Fannettsburg presented a silk flag to Commander
                    John H. Walker and the Washington Blues, which has existed since 1828. The
                    company is on its way to the encampment in Waynesboro on May 28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Noble Game</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heefner</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Levi Heefner shot an eagle, whose wingspan measured 7 feet 6 inches.
                    The Repository expressed regret that this symbol of freedom had been shot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A notice that an academy in Fannettsburg recently started under the
                    direction of Rev. John C. Wilhelm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Engineer's Report</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goodyear</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baughman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Hother</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Muterspaugh</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hahn</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sholl</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wandorff</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzleman</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craiger</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mickley</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittenhaffer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besecker</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Downey and J. B. McElroy submit the Engineer's Report describing the
                    possible railroad route from Gettysburg to Chambersburg, listing the homes and
                    buildings the road will pass by.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>A letter from Lancaster</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Interview Between Mr. Lincoln And The National Convention Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lincoln gives a humble acceptance speech to the Committee that announced to
                    him his nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Speech Of Hon. Hannibal Hamlin On The Announcement Of The Nomination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"What is it but the labor of your country that spreads out your canvass on
                    the distant sea? What is it but labor that delves in your mines, and toils in
                    your workshops, and upholds the government under which you live? Who is there
                    that should receive the forstering care and kind regards of the Government, if
                    it be not the man that toils and adds, by his industry, to the wealth of the
                    Republic?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Hannibal Hamlin gives an acceptance speech that notes the Republican
                    support of the white free laborer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Description of the government's reception of the Japanese Embassy;
                Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23.06">
            <pageNote>Serial Fiction; news and anecdotes; Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.05.23.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keagy</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Anna E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 15th, in Chambersburg, Rev. F. Dyson married Franklin Keagy to Anna
                    E. Funk, both of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>Kate M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Lily C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Over</ln>
                        <fn>William Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Over</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slyder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slyder</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slyder</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zullinger</ln>
                        <fn>Sasrah Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zullinger</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zullinger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 12th, in Loudon, Miss Kate M. Burgess died of Scarlet Fever, at age
                    21 years and 24 days. On May 4th, in Upper Strasburg, of Scarlet Fever, Lily C.
                    daughter of Daniel and Sarah Gelwix, died at age 2 years, 3 months, and 9 days.
                    On May 4th, in Upper Strasburg, of Scarlet Fever, Benjamin Franklin, son of
                    George and Mary Foreman, died at age 6 years and 4 months. On May 7th, in Upper
                    Strasburg, of Scarlet Fever, William Isaac, son of David Over, died at age 9
                    years, 9 months and 21 days. On May 17th, in Strasburg, of Scarlet Fever, James
                    son of Mr. J. S. and Catharine Slyder, died at about 9 years old. On May 18th,
                    in Upper Strasburg, of Scarlet Fever, Sarah Jane, daughter of Frederick and Mary
                    Ann Zullinger, died at about 4 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Continuation of the Chicago Convention from page 1; Advertisments.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
