<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-09-26">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Read! Read! Read!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>A Synopsis of the Great Speech of Carl Schurz, delivered at the Cooper
                    Institute, in New York, on Thursday Evening, September 13, 1860.</commentary>
                <excerpt>"'If it is statesmanship to subvert the principles of the Constitution,
                    undermine the liberties of the people, to place the security of the individual
                    at the mercy of the centralized government, then, indeed, he is one of greatest,
                    and his statue deserves to be erected side by side with that of the illustrious
                    Cataline of Rome, and the patriotic Stafford of England'. . .The enthusiasm with
                    which Carl Schurz was received by the meeting when he was first introduced
                    increased when he began to speak of the little Giant--his manner adding much to
                    the matter of the speech. As he continued to make his telling points, his
                    prepossessing delivery and his slightly German accent seemed to find increased
                    favor with his vast army of auditors;"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A two-page synopsis of Carl Schurz' speech that primarily discusses Douglas
                    and his political career--criiticizing his character, and his claims as
                    'Champion of Freedom' and the 'greatest of living statesmen.'</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26.02">
            <pageNote>Continuation of Carl Schurz' speech from page one.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>True Patriotism</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"That by no word, no act, no combination into which I might enter, should
                    any one human being of all the generations to which I belong, much less any
                    class of human beings of any nation, race, or kindred, be oppressed and kept
                    down in the least degree in their efforts to rise to a higher state of liberty
                    and happiness."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpt of Mr. Seward's speech in Madison, Wisc., in which he promotes
                    freedom and happiness to all humans, of any race or class.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Banner Presentation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Squires</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleming</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greer</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kellog</ln>
                        <fn>W. Pitt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paine</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>P. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An article describing the ceremony and participants of the presentation of
                    a banner to the Wide Awakes of Monmouth, by the Ladies Cub. Anna Fleming, a
                    native of Franklin Co., presented the banner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Good Idea</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expression of the opinion that women's colleges should teach domestic
                    skills.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Ball Rolling</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dennerline</ln>
                        <fn>John G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Casey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreichbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebbert</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dernfeldt</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Description of a Republican rally at which Col. A. G. Curtin and Carl
                    Schurz, Esq., a Wisconsin German orator, spoke. Wide Awakes from Fayetteville,
                    Greenvillage and Scotland, in a meeting later that day, elected officers, and
                    the speakers of the earlier rally spoke again.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Speaker's Stand</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shepler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Durbarrow</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merklein</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of committee members and participants in the construction of a stand
                    for speakers, and a description of the stand, itself.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Herschel V. Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He there, audaciously, placed the working people of the North, Free
                    Whites, on a level with slaves at the South, and, for doing so, Col. Forney, who
                    was then Chairman of the Locofoco State Committee, is reported to have said:
                    'For God's sake, take that man out of the State, or he will ruin us.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors mention that Johnson spoke in Chambersburg on Sept. 20th, and
                    remind their readers that, in the past, he had compared white laborers to slaves
                    and that his own Democratic party had realized that he could jeopardize their
                    success in the coming elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Shameful Treatment Of A Candidate!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>Democratic Conventions Controlled by the "Town Clique."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We intimated in our last issue, that the <emph rend="italic">Valley
                        Spirit</emph> and the "town clique," with which it co-operates, had treated
                        a gentleman of Fayetteville, who desired to be a candidate before the late
                        Democratic Nominating County Convention, in a very contemptuous and
                        overbearing manner. We could not refrain from noticing the fact, for the
                        reason that the gentleman who had been thus summarily <emph rend="italic"
                            >choked off,</emph> had been a life-long member of the Democratic party.
                        Our remarks, it appears, fell under the eye of the gentleman to whom we
                        particularly alluded, and he has sent us the following communication:</p>
                    <p>Fayetteville, Sept. 21, 1860.</p>
                    <p>MESSRS EDITORS:--I observed in the <emph rend="italic">Repository and
                            Transcript</emph> of the 19th inst., a notice of the hostility of the
                        Editors of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> towards "an humble
                        member of the Democratic party of Fayetteville, who aspired to fill one of
                        the Court House offices." I presume I am the individual alluded to, and in
                        order that you and the public may be made better acquainted with the facts,
                        and of the manner in which I was ruled out, permit me to make the following
                        statement:</p>
                    <p>Sometime about the 1st of May last, I gave a short advertisement to Mr. F.--
                        S-----, of your place, requesting him to hand it to the Editors of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Valley Spirit.</emph> The substance of that advertisement
                        was, that I was a candidate for the office of <emph rend="italic">Register
                            and Recorder,</emph> subject to the decision of the Democratic
                        Convention. I looked for it carefully in the next issue of the paper, but
                        found it not. I wrote another of the same, about two weeks after, and gave
                        it to Mr. J.--- M----- to hand over to the Editors of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit.</emph> He told me since that he positively gave it
                        to them. I then confidently expected to see my Card in that week's paper,
                        but found none. I then sent another through the Post office, and it was
                        treated as the others were. I then thought I would try them with a little
                        money, and sent them a silver dollar with Mr. J.--- B-----, of our village,
                        who was about visiting Chambersburg, begging them to insert my Card in their
                        paper as many times as a dollar would pay for. They took the money, and
                        after consulting awhile among themselves, returned it to Mr. B----, with the
                        remarks, that I should come in myself. I went to Chambersburg, but in reply
                        to my request that they should insert my advertisement, announcing myself as
                        a candidate, they told me that none of the County Candidates intended to
                        publish their intentions--all was to be left to the Delegates in Convention.
                        I then saw how the pot was boiling. On the day of the Convention I spoke to
                        several of the Delegates, but they appeared all to be committed, and there
                        was no chance for me. They said they had understood that the three
                        respectable gentlemen who now fill the Court House offices were to be
                        re-nominated for their present positions.</p>
                    <p>This is the manner in which <emph rend="italic">equal rights</emph> are
                        extended to all by the worthy editors of the <emph rend="italic">Valley
                            Spirit.</emph></p>
                    <p>On the Sunday before the Delegates met in Convention, I was accosted in the
                        town of Fayetteville by two very respectable gentlemen from Chambersburg,
                        who wished to learn who the delegates from our place were. I informed the
                        inquirer. I also told him that I was a Candidate for Register and Recorder,
                        when he replied, <emph rend="italic">"You are too late, the whole thing is
                            fixed--we intend to keep the same Officers in the Court House that are
                            in now."</emph> I replied by saying: "Then there is no use in holding a
                        Convention."</p>
                    <p>Such has been the wire-working of the "town clique." I have been as firm a
                        Democrat as any of the combined conspirators, and have done more labor and
                        spent more of my own money in behalf of the cause than any man in the
                        "clique," and had a right to expect better treatment of men professing to be
                        Democrats than that which I have received. All I asked was a fair hearing,
                        and, if I failed to obtain the nomination, well and good; but to be choked
                        off and trodden down in the manner I was, by the paper professing to be the
                        mouth-piece of the party, and by a few individuals who have set themselves
                        up as leaders, is a little more than my spirit can bear or than my
                        democratic teachings would warrant me to expect. But enough. I expect them
                        to be defeated, with all their intrigue.</p>
                    <p>Yours, &amp;c., <lb/>WILLIAM PIPER.</p>
                    <p>So much for the manner in which Mr. PIPER was treated by the <emph
                            rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> and the Democratic leaders of
                        Chambersburg. There is no denying the facts--there is the evidence from his
                        own pen; and if any one will undertake to say, that it is anything less than
                        mean and shabby treatment, such an one [sic], like the whipped cur, could
                        "lick the hand that scourged him." After this we trust the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> will cease its clamor about the Republican
                        Party of Franklin county being controlled by a "clique." The public will
                        hereafter know, that when it sets up such a howl, it is only done to screen
                        its own guilt--to cover the political trickery of its own "town clique"--and
                        to mislead the public mind from a scrutiny of its own debauchery.</p>
                    <p>But more: Mr. PIPER is not the only man who came under the political ban of
                        these Chambersburg Democratic leaders, who have constituted themselves the
                        managers, rulers, and dictators of the party throughout the county. A very
                        worthy and intelligent gentleman of Greencastle, of unimpeachable private
                        character and of undoubted Democratic antecedents, who, in 1857, was a
                        formidable candidate for the nomination of Prothonotary, and was beaten only
                        3 or 4 votes by his opponent, (Mr. Keyser, the present incumbent,) was most
                        grossly, cruelly bamboozeled [sic] also by this Democratic "town clique."</p>
                    <p>The gentleman to whom we refer, came to Chambersburg for the purpose of again
                        announcing himself as a candidate for the office of Prothonotary; but it
                        appears he came upon "a fool's errand," for he had not consulted the
                        "clique," which was a great breach of their assumed prerogative,--When his
                        intentions became known, he was immediately taken in charge by the gentleman
                        in authority, who at once put their wits to work to circumvent him, and get
                        him out of their way, so that he should not come in contact with their
                        already nominated County Ticket.</p>
                    <p>Every imaginable argument and inducement was held out to dissuade him from
                        his purpose, and he succumbed to their desceptive [sic] words--promises made
                        only to be broken, which he has since learned.--He was told that if he would
                        withhold his announcement for the office for which he desired a nomination,
                        they would place him in nomination for the Legislature.--The day for the
                        assembling of the Convention came, and with it this gentleman from
                        Greencastle, full of hope, confidently expecting to wear proudly the honors
                        to be conferred by his party. Well, he was placed in nomination, the
                        balloting commenced, and the anxious expectant awaited, not doubting that
                        the announcement would be, that Mr. FRANCIS NORTHCRAFT was the unanimous
                        nominee for the Democracy of Franklin county for the Legislature. But what
                        was the result? Why he failed to receive <emph rend="italic">one single,
                            solitary, beggarly vote</emph>--the Delegate who nominated him did not
                        vote for him! Who, but the Democratic leaders of Chambersburg could treat
                        any member of its party in such a cruel, heartless manner! Things thus
                        assumed an uglier shape than the leaders had intended, and on second ballot
                        they allowed <emph rend="italic">three</emph> Delegates to vote for Mr. N.,
                        and then he had his name withdrawn.</p>
                    <p>We submit to the candid reader, whether in view of the foregoing indisputable
                        facts, the masses of the Democratic party of Franklin are not led as sheep
                        to the shambles, by a few intriguing, selfish men of Chambersburg. The
                        County Ticket was matured by them before the Convention assembled, all it
                        had to do was to ratify the nominations already cut and dry. Is this not
                        so?--and has the same thing not been done by these same leaders of the
                        Democracy for the last ten years or more? The truth of the matter is simply
                        this--the bone and sinew of the Democratic party are used by their leaders
                        to <emph rend="italic">vote</emph> but not <emph rend="italic">think</emph>
                        and <emph rend="italic">act</emph> for themselves; they use them as the
                        nigger-drivers of the South use their Slaves-- they must come when they are
                        called and go when they are bidden. It is to this deep depth of degredation
                        [sic] and humiliation that the great Democratic Party has at last fallen;
                        and strange to say, many otherwise high-spirited men--men of intelligence
                        and observation, still maintain their connection with it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Northcraft</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A follow-up on a previous Repository article that accused the Valley Spirit
                    and a clique of Democrats of controlling which Democrat candidates were allowed
                    to run publicly for office, and a letter from one such candidate, William Piper,
                    whose name was omitted from election ads.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept60.html#9.26a</note>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Col. Curtin And The Dog Story</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>An Old Franklin County Whig</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from a Franklin County Whig who repudiates both the story of
                    Curtin killing a dog, and the rumor that Curtin had slandered Dutchmen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Two articles reminding Republicans to vote only for Republican candidates; a
                letter from Iowa that states that most of Iowa (and almost all its German citizens)
                will be voting for Lincoln.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Grand Rally In Fayetteville!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donnelson</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Camp</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dennerline</ln>
                        <fn>John G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republicans of Green township met Sept. 19th, where several people
                    spoke, including one speech, by John G. A. Dennerline, in German.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Montgomery And Peters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shough</ln>
                        <fn>P. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Friends of Freedom and Protection was held a few nights
                    ago at Clay Lick, in Montgomery township, and one at White Church Hill, in
                    Peters township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Camp</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrew</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaldson</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Caledonia and Fayetteville Wide Awakes met and organized at the Log
                    School House, in Fayetteville, on Sept. 22nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Attention Wide-Awakes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Lafayette</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lafayette Wood offers to equip Wide Awakes with their uniforms with a
                    payment of forty dollars per fifty people.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Metal Township</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>R. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The teachers of Metal Township have organized in an Institute with
                    officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Large Porkers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyster</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors went to see Jacob Oyster's two very large hogs that weigh over
                    fifteen hundred pounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>New Suction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Town Council of Chambersburg has received the new Suction machine, from
                    Cowing &amp; Co., of Seneca Falls N. Y.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26.06">
            <pageNote>A Postmaster's opinion of Lincoln; Advertisements; The Proclamation of the
                General Election.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26.07">
            <pageNote>Sequel to Kansas Trouble; How to make Good Coffee; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.09.26.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craley</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knode</ln>
                        <fn>Ann A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Clarinda A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Jason M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. Gideon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haulman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hissong</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Aug. 30th, Rev. J. Rebaugh married Jacob Crider to Isabella Koontz, in
                    her father's home in Franklin County. On Sept. 13th, in Greencastle, Rev. J.
                    Rebaugh married Jacob B. Craley to Ann A. Knode, of Franklin County. On Sept.
                    12th, Rev. William A. West married William J. Harrison to Clarinda A. Johnston,
                    daughter of D. C. Johnston, all of Dry Run, Path Valley. On Sept.13th, at
                    Pleasant Retreat Parsonage (near Chambersburg), Rev. Jason M. Bishop, married
                    Rev. J. Gideon Shoaff, of the Pennsylvania Conference, to Sue Peters, of
                    Bendersville, Adams Co. On Sept.13th, Rev. G. Roth married Jacob Haulman to
                    Hannah Hissong, both of Franklin Co.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Varner</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Varner</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Varner</ln>
                        <fn>Margeret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bigham</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bigham</ln>
                        <fn>Grizelda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinley</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kobler</ln>
                        <fn>Eve</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detwiler</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brant</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 3rd, at Dry Run, Susan, daughter of Solomon and Margeret Varner,
                    died at age 1. On Sept 7th, Grizelda Bigham died at her mother's home near
                    Fayetteville. On Sept. 14th, at Dry Run, Ellen Brinley, wife of John Brinley,
                    died. On Sept. 17th, in Chambersburg, Eve Kobler died at age 71. On Sept 20th,
                    Margaret Detwiler, formerly of McConnellsburg and in recent years a resident of
                    Chambersburg and a member of the German Reformed Church, died at age 72. On
                    Sept. 20th, in Chambersburg, William Brant died of consumption at age 31. On
                    Sept. 19th, near Chambersburg, Susan Snively, wife of Samuel Snively, Esq., died
                    at age 57.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements; land and estate sales.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
