<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-11-14">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Secession Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Resolved, That the election of Lincoln and Hamlin to the Presidency and
                    Vice Presidency of the United States ought not and will not be submitted to."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Actions of rebellion and expressions of desire for secession from several
                    states--South Carolina, Louisiana, Washington D.C., and Georgia: resignation of
                    Senators and Federal officers, calls to establish minute men companies,
                    arson,the flying of the state flags, and organized meetings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Important News From Georgia</head>
                <origin>Milledgeville, Ga.</origin>
                <commentary>Special Message of Gov. Brown--He does not Recommend the appointment of
                    Delegates to the Secession Convention, but Advises Laws for the State
                    Protection.</commentary>
                <excerpt>"Let us meet unjust oppression and unconstitutional State legislation with
                    just retaliation."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since Gov. Brown expects few Southern states to actually organize a
                    secession movement, he suggests passing laws that will hurt the Northern states
                    (who have been most active in passing laws that oppress the South), ie. taxes on
                    their goods, seizing their property, repeal of penal and civil codes that
                    protect their safety. He also wants money for a military fund. The Repository
                    editors comment that "These Southern People are a terrible set--on paper."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Exodus Of Negroes From South Carolina</head>
                <origin>The Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In reaction to disunion of the Democratic party, and the Chicago
                    nominations, among other things, South Carolina passed laws against free negroes
                    that oredered them to wear identification badges and put them under the
                    supervision of a white man, who could re-enslave them at a whim. Any free
                    negroes that could, left the state in a mass exodus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Woman's Right Practically Carried Out.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Mrs. Dr. Lydia Sayer Hasbrouck, of Orange county, New-York, who insists
                    that a woman should not be taxed unless she is allowed to vote, has thought to
                    shame the collector out of his demand by offering to work out her road tax."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mrs. Dr. Lydia Sayer Hasbrouck, of Orange county, New-York, who insists that
                        a woman should not be taxed unless she is allowed to vote, has thought to
                        shame the collector out of his demand by offering to work out her road tax.
                        The doctress, having somewhat passed the bloom of youth, made no impression
                        upon the stony official, and therefore, instead of paying under pretest
                        [sic], as some of her sisters do, she went upon the road and drove a
                    cart.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story of a woman, Dr. Lydia Sayer Hasbrouck, of New York, who insists that
                    a woman should not be taxed if she cannot vote.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frnov60.html#11.14a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Letter From Kansas; stories from around the country.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Peter's Pence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The question is raised as to whether American Roman Catholics will pay a
                    tax required by the Pope.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>stories and articles of general interest; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14.03">
            <pageNote>Stories and articles of general interest; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Value Of The Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>". . . there was some other cause for froming the Union than the building
                    up and spreading of slavery; that there were other and higher motives for
                    forming a confederation of the various divisions of our country;"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An argument that the Union was established to protect the liberty of the
                    people--not the institution of slavery--, and a secession (of even only one or
                    two states left) would seriously damage that liberty and happiness that has come
                    from the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Prophecy Fulfilled</head>
                <origin>Albany Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"For the present, however, we would say, soothingly, to the South--'Do
                    thyself no harm'--the bugaboos won't hurt you."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that the Southerners have worked themselves up to be
                    terrified of Lincoln et al. Republicans--that they are friends of John Brown.
                    The editors argue that after a year or two under Lincoln's fair administration,
                    the South will calm down.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Victory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"All who desire the beautiful prairies of the far West preserved sacred
                    from the polluting foot-prints of a slave, will feel their hearts bounding with
                    joy as they read, not only in the public prints of the day, but in the sparkling
                    eyes of Freedom's honest devotees, the glad news of the Victory of liberty over
                    oppression; of truth and justice over falsehood and cruelty."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The battle has been fought and the victory won! The spirit of the people rose
                        with the fierceness of the contest!--The loud, wild, angry war-whoop of
                        disunion did not frighten the brave sons of liberty! The more terrible
                        appeared the foe, the more valliant [sic] became the army of the free! No
                        struggle, since the formation of our Government, was fraught with such
                        important principles! A long list of abuses, frauds, peculations and crimes
                        filled up the measure of the party in power. Bankruptcy, as a necessary
                        consequence of the ruinous policy of the dominant party, covered the land
                        with its sable pall since the inauguration of the existing Dynasty.
                        Idleness, want and starvation, the necessary adjuncts of a depression of the
                        industrial interests of any nation, were obtruding their unwelcome form into
                        the dwellings of our working people. Endurance ceased to be a virtue, and
                        resistance became an absolute duty. The times required decisive action; the
                        people rose in their might and applied the proper remedy.</p>
                    <p>After the 4th of March, 1861, another administration, another class of men
                        will take hold of the helm of the old ship of state. They will begin with a
                        clean sheet; no foul blots mar the pages of their record. No party ever was
                        more loyal to the whole country--more devoted to the best interests of all
                        classes of society, than is the Republican party. The poor man, desirous of
                        employment, has the prospect of work in the Tariff policy of our
                        party--which seeks to foster every branch of American industry against
                        ruinous foreign competition. He who wants a home for himself and little
                        ones, who has no means to procure one, is cheered with the expectation of
                        the speedy passage of a Free Homestead bill--knowing that "honest old Abe"
                        will never veto such a measure. All who desire the beautiful prairies of the
                        far West preserved sacred from the polluting foot-prints of a slave, will
                        feel their hearts bounding with joy as they read, not only in the public
                        prints of the day, but in the sparkling eyes of Freedom's honest devotees,
                        the glad news of the Victory of liberty over oppression; of truth and
                        justice over falsehood and cruelty.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A cry of victory--that an new, honest administration will take control, and
                    the poor man will get a job due to the protection Tariff, and the Free Homestead
                    bill will provide opportunities for Western livelihoods free of slavery.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frnov60.html#11.14b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Our Hopes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Honest Old Abe will do all that his friends expect, all that they
                    promised, to bring the country back to the beaten path of rectitude and
                    honor--as travelled by the earlier administrations. His warning voice will be
                    plainly heard, from the helm, above the fierce raging of sectional storms and
                    partisan strifes, commanding the old vessel, in calm tones, giving a word of
                    encouragement to the wary, and inspiring new confidence into all around by the
                    dignity of his bearing."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Great as has been the triumph of Republicanism, much as is the good that will
                        result therefrom, we must not permit our hope of reform to blind our reason
                        to the true state of the facts. We have, it is true, elected our candidate
                        to the Presidency; but he will go into power under somewhat adverse
                        circumstances. Both branches of Congress contain a majority arrayed in open
                        hostility to his administration. No matter how wise, how patriotic, how
                        necessary the measures he may recommend, they have the power to thwart him
                        at every point. If they undertake to act the part of the dog in the manger,
                        the people will see and know with whom rests the responsibility of
                        nonaction.</p>
                    <p>As matters stand, we must not expect too much--we must not look for as great
                        results as if we had a working majority in each house of Congress. Honest
                        Old Abe will do all that his friends expect, all that they promised, to
                        bring the country back to the beaten path of rectitude and honor--as
                        travelled by the earlier administrations. His warning voice will be plainly
                        heard, from the helm, above the fierce raging of sectional storms and
                        partisan strifes, commanding the old vessel, in calm tones, giving a word of
                        encouragement to the wary, and inspiring new confidence into all around by
                        the dignity of his bearing. If we do not accomplish all that we could
                        desire-- pass a fair, equitable Tariff; carry the Free Homestead bill, and
                        build a railroad to the Pacific--we can at least rejoice to know that none
                        of these great measures will receive injury at the hands of Mr. Lincoln; for
                        such bills he has no vetoes in reserve. Holding the country in peace,
                        preventing any further injury to the people, is cause for bright hopes for
                        us in the near future. The day of bribery and corruption; of buying
                        unrighteous congressional enactments is gone. The future, therefore, looks
                        bright and cheerful. Lincoln's administration will prove the harbinger of
                        better things to come.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reminder that, although the Republican candidates have been elected, both
                    houses of Congress have a Democratic opposition and will make things difficult
                    for the new administration.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frnov60.html#11.14c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Messrs. Editors:</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No! No! my voice would be for letting them go, and their niggers too, if
                    that is what they really desire.--The Union is of infinitely more use to them
                    than they are to the Union;"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from 'Patrick Henry' that argues that there are probably very few
                    men who actually favor secession, and he suggests that they should be allowed to
                    leave, rather than starting a war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>War Vessels To Be Altered Into Steamers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Board appointed to examine what ships of the navy could be converted to
                    steamers have decided that a line of battle ships could be altered for over
                    three million dollars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Resignation of Southern Senators.--A South Carolina Convention Called.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Senators from South Carolina, Georgia, and Alabama have resigned from
                    Congress. A Southern convention will meet on Jan. 15th (and the delegates
                    elected on the 8th).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Articles on the election around the country; secession notes;</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Staging On The Sabbath</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reside</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Expression of astonishment that J. A. Reside, the mail carrier between
                    Chambersburg and Bedford, is required to work on Sunday--the Sabbath.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Northcraft</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At a recent Sheriff's sale, John F. Croft, of Chambersburg, bought the
                    Tavern Stand in Greencastle, formerly owned by F. Northcraft. C. C. Foltz , of
                    Chambersburg, has leased it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hicks</ln>
                        <fn>Speakman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>G. K.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>R. P. Hazelet, auctioneer, sold for Speakman Hicks (present occupant) the
                    residence on East Market St. (formerly owned by G. K Harper, Esq., dec'd), and a
                    lot on Second St. to J. Allison Eyster, Esq. The Eysters plan to build a two
                    story brick building on the lot.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. S. Everett, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. Everett, Esq., asked the editors to remind a few people to return twenty
                    or more volumes loaned out from Mr. Everett's library.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The General Result</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list of the states and how their electoral votes went: 169 votes for
                    Lincoln; 74 for Bredkinridge; 35 for Bell; 3 for Douglas; 44 doubtful or not
                    heard from. (Pennsylvania gave its 27 to Lincoln.)</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The "Irrepressible Conflict." An Avalance of Victory! The Country Has Spoken!
                    There Is A North! Freedin Batuibak! Slavery Sectional! Douglas Played Out! The
                    Agitators Rebuked! The Keystone. . .</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors proudly print the voting results (for Governor and President)
                    of the counties of Pennsylvania-- Franklin County's votes: Curtin (R) 4,053
                    Foster (D) 3,379 Lincoln (R) 1,666 Reading Ticket (D) 0.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Presidential Election. November 6, 1860. Official Vote Of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The list of the votes for the four candidates in the districts of Franklin
                    County. The totals for each candidate: Lincoln--4151, Breckinridge
                    Straight--2485, Douglas Straight--625, and Bell--76.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Election Results from all the states; market reports;
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14.06">
            <pageNote>World and National news stories; Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14.07">
            <pageNote>National news of interest; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.11.14.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A note that, although South Carolina is calling for a convention and
                    Secession, the majority of people in the other Southern states are opposed to
                    disunion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Cabinet Meeting</head>
                <origin>The Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A note of the present Administrations consternation at the resignation of
                    several Southern Senators, including Jefferson Davis. Gen. Cass expects the
                    Gov't will not last beyond March 4th, 1861. But the editors are pleased that
                    these senators, who would have caused problems for Lincoln, are and will be gone
                    (and can be replaced by Republicans).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Union Men Of The South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note of various men in Southern states (all Douglas Democrats) who would
                    want to replace the resigned senators' seats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>Moses A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elightfoot</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roths</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kriner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haulman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haulman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Angle</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harden</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtis</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>Leah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Martin Van Buren</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 6th, at the German Reformed Parsonage, in Chambersburg, Rev. Samuel
                    Philips married Moses A. Foltz to Charlotte S. Etter, both of Chambersburg. On
                    Nov. 8th, at the German Reformed Parsonage, in Chambersburg, Rev. Samuel Philips
                    married James O. Alexander to Mary Elightfoot, both of Scotland. On Nov. 8th, at
                    the bride's parents' home, in Guilford Twp., Rev. Samuel Philips married George
                    Dittman, of Chambersburg, to Sarah J. Vaneraw. On Nov. 1st, Rev. G. Roths
                    married John Kriner, of Peters Twp., to Catharine R. Haulman, daughter of Jacob
                    Haulman, near Bridgeport, Franklin Co. On Nov. 8th, in Greencastle, Rev. J.
                    Rebaugh married Martin Hurst, of Welsh Run, to Mary E. Angle, of Washington Co.
                    Md. On Nov. 11th, Rev. William Harden married David Miller to Susan Curtis, all
                    of Chambersburg. On Nov. 8th, at the home of the bride's mother, in Green Twp.,
                    Rev. S. McHenry married Adam Diehl, of Hamilton Twp., to Leah Zook, all of
                    Franklin Co. On Nov. 8th, at the home of the bride's father, Rev. J. Philip
                    Bishop married Martin Van Buren Hoover to Mary Jane Paxton, both of Lurgan Twp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>David Edger</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 7th, in Chambersburg, David Edger McCurdy, son of R. C. and Mattie
                    A. McCurdy, died at 6 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements; land and house sales.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
