<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-10-24">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Hon. A. K. McClure And The United States Senatorship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter to the editors from 'A Working Man,' suggesting that A. K. McClure
                    is the suitable successor to Hon. Beef Bigler, whose term expires March 4th,
                    1861.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Speech Hon. Thaddeus Stevens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>Delivered at Cooper Institute, New York City, on Thursday evening, Sept.
                    27, 1860.</commentary>
                <excerpt>"To do this he has perverted the meaning of their immortal words. He
                    contends that 'all men' means less than one third part of the human race; that
                    'people' means 'white folks;' that the authors of the Declaration of
                    Independence and of the Constitution, while inaugurating a new and startling
                    epoch in the science of government--an epoch of liberty and equality--were
                    preparing a system which denied that a whole race of God's immortal creatures
                    had 'any rights that white men were bound to respect.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Stevens begins his speech with the argument that tariffs are the normal,
                    intelligent means of protection for a country's (especially a young one's)
                    economy. He examines the four Presidential candidates' records on support for a
                    tariff--that Douglas and Breckinridge are against it, and that Bell is such a
                    good man and an enemy of Democrats and so he should join forces with the
                    Republicans. Stevens then discusses the slave issue, Douglas' stance on it,and
                    Judge Taney's misinterpretation of the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Col. McClure At The Wigwam Again: Fusion Entombed And Epitaphed. The Moral Of
                    The Victory.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>McClure gives praise for the newly elected governor, Andrew G. Curtin. He
                    points out that Democrat candidates lost elections due to back-stabbing by the
                    supposedly fused (by a sort of bartering) divisions of the Party and Bell's
                    supporters. He also stated, noting the recent election successes, that Lincoln
                    will succeed where Henry Clay did not.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Continuation of Steven's speech from page 1.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24.03">
            <pageNote>Humorous articles; Republican Platform; Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mark The Difference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>". . . although the leaders, and all others who care about examining the
                    matter for themselves, are well aware that ruin, degradation and sorrow to the
                    poor whites of the land is, and must be, the inevitable consequence of the
                    triumph of slavery throughout our beloved land; which is the wicked object and
                    design of the pro-slavery agitators, and the foolish, purblind partisans of the
                    North are assisting in its horrid consummation."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors argue that the difference between the Republicans and Democrats
                    lies in either promoting the welfare of the poor whites (Republicans) or the
                    welfare of the wealthy, especially the rich slaveholders (Democrats)</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Middle Ground</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors discuss three camps of thought: The Abolitionist who want
                    slavery abolished, or at least disunion from the South; The Southern fire-eaters
                    who want to spread slavery into all parts of the country; and the Republicans
                    who want to protect the South's institution of slavery, but prevent it from
                    spreading into the Territories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sound And Fury</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An argument that the disunionists of the South are actually few in number,
                    and that the Republicans will not permit these few to cause the splitting of the
                    country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The War Of The Bills</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "Some months since, a company of Chambersburg Douglas men purchased the
                    good-will and fixtures of a printing office in this place and started a paper
                    advocating the exclusive claims of the "little giant" for the Presidency. Is
                    Editor, Bunty Bill, pulled off his coat, rolled up his sleves [sic] and pitched
                    fiercely into Gimlet-nose Bill, the puke that scribbles for the <emph
                        rend="italic">Spirit,</emph> the other organ of the Nigger Democracy of this
                    County." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some months since, a company of Chambersburg Douglas men purchased the
                        good-will and fixtures of a printing office in this place and started a
                        paper advocating the exclusive claims of the "little giant" for the
                        Presidency. Is Editor, Bunty Bill, pulled off his coat, rolled up his sleves
                        [sic] and pitched fiercely into Gimlet-nose Bill, the puke that scribbles
                        for the <emph rend="italic">Spirit,</emph> the other organ of the Nigger
                        Democracy of this County. The puke returned blow for blow; the war grew
                        fierce; the puke became braver and more defiant as the battle progressed;
                        Bunty Bill, at first so courageous, soon began to show the white feather;
                        Gimlet- nose Bill discovered his advantage and gave the challanger [sic]
                        several home-thrusts, which, together with the fizzling of its
                            leaders--<emph rend="italic">the bold, brave, straight-out Douglas
                        men</emph>-- who assembled, in Philadelphia, a few days since, caused Bunty
                        Bill to strike his colors, and this week we are to have him supporting the
                        same electoral ticket which his foe has all the time advocated, and next
                        week we may expect to see him on his back begging for quarter from the puke,
                        whom he at first affected to despise. He who fights and runs away, may live
                        to fight some other day--a great while after the first fight, however.</p>
                    <p>How will Gimlet-nose Bill act toward his fallen foe, Bunty Bill, now that the
                        latter has surrendered? Will he permit him to return to the fold of the
                        faithful? Will he allow him to be placed among the notables, who figure in
                        capitals, in the <emph rend="italic">Spirit,</emph> as supporters of
                        Breckinridge and Lane? Or, as a punishment for joining those who dared to
                        have an opinion of their own, when Southern dictators willed otherwise, will
                        he and they be kept out in the cold <emph rend="italic">when Breckinridge
                            becomes President.</emph> We trust that peace and harmony may be
                        restored between these two bloody belligerents <emph rend="italic">before
                            the inauguration of Breckinridge.</emph> Bunty Bill admits, virtually,
                        that Douglas has no chance, and, since Foster carried Pennsylvania, so
                        gallantly, he too must be calculating upon the election of Breckinridge,
                        else why support men on his electoral ticket who say: "That under no
                        circumstances will they vote for Douglas?"</p>
                    <p>The battle between the Bills, though fierce, was short. Douglas spent all his
                        money, many thousands dollars, carrying his election to the Senate, in
                        1858--which was accomplished, in defiance of the popular will, by the manner
                        in which the State of Illinois is distracted--and the friends of
                        Breckinridge and Lane hold the offices, and wield the patronage of the
                        Government, and as the Nigger Democracy are very fond of "spondulics," and
                        have none of their own, the Douglas boys are trying to get hold of the
                        government udder; but Gimlet-nose Bill will make Bunty Bill suck the hind
                        teat. Nevertheless Gimlet-nose Bill had better keep a sharp look out; for
                        old Mr. Buchanan, the present, and the last locofoco, dispenser of Federal
                        bounty, is proverbial for rewarding his enemies and neglecting those who
                        were his warmest friends.</p>
                    <p>If there is any private understanding between you, boys, keep it to
                        yourselves; for <emph rend="italic">"Andy can't keep a secret."</emph> There
                        is no use fighting any longer. The deed is done. The fiat has gone forth.
                        The hand-writing is on the wall. Your corrupt party is doomed to
                        destruction--even "Rankin's prayers" cannot save it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A battle between the editors (both named 'Bill') of two opposing Democratic
                    newspapers, in which 'Gimlet-Bill,' the editor of the Spirit, apparently won,
                    and 'Bunty Bill' has cast his support to Douglas.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/froct60.html#10.24a</note>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Voting For Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Stephen A. Douglas, of Illinois, writes that 4/5 of Democrats in Pa. will
                    vote for him, and that his true supporters will not be led astray.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Next Senate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prediction that the next Senate will have 61 Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Articles urging Republicans to vote.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fayetteville Jubilee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Camp</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>H. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Ed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 18th, the Republicans of Fayetteville met to celebrate the election
                    of Oct. 9th. A procession of Wide awakes and speeches were part of the evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Bayard Taylor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bayard Taylor, a traveler and orator, spoke in Franklin Hall on Oct. 22nd,
                    at which he lectured on "Life in the Arctic Regions."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>California Potatoes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funkhouser</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of very large and prolific California Mercer Potatoes raised by
                    David Funkhouser, near Rocky Spring.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>As the Chairman of the Republican County Committee is absent from home,
                    communications should be sent to the secretary, P. Hamman, Esq.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Robbery Of The Express Company</head>
                <origin>Hagerstown Torch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On Oct. 6th, the Merchant's Bank of Baltimore sent a package of bank
                    notes-$9,445--to the Hagerstown Bank. When it arrived, $3,300 had been stolen,
                    but the Pa. Division of the Express Company reimbursed the Hagerstown Bank.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Census Returns</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. W. H. Blair, a Deputy Marshal for the Census, shared some census
                    returns with the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Stolen Goods Recovered</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The property and money (except for $65) stolen from Frederick B. Snively's
                    store--reported in the 10/17/60 issue--was recovered on Oct. 19th, in Mrs.
                    McCoy's haystack, by Mr. Snively himself.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Business On The Railroad</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaffhirt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Messrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The opening of the Railroad has caused a great increase in Forwardings and
                    Commissions, and the need for larger storage buildings, the reason for the
                    enlarging of Schaffhirt &amp; Co.'s house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Pennsylvanians In the 37th Congress.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Ed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The list of members elected to the 37th congress, including Ed. McPherson
                    as representative of the 17th District. There are a total of 20 Republican
                    representatives and 5 Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>XVIIth congressional District--Official</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the counties' votes for McPherson (11,673) and Schell
                    (11,144)--McPherson won by 529 votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Official Vote. Curtin's Majority</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list of the votes of all the Pennsylvania counties for the governor and
                    Auditor General.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Legislature Complete</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the State Senators and Representatives--with a Republican
                    majority of 21 in the Senate and 63 in the House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24.06">
            <pageNote>Proclamation of the Presidential Election; Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24.07">
            <pageNote>Advertisements; List of Traverse and Grand Jurors--see entry for
            10/3/60.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.10.24.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>An Abstract Of The Election Laws Of Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of Qualifications of Voters, definition of a citizen,
                    Evidence of Naturalization, and Evidence of the Payment of a Tax.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>*</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Important Opinion From Mr. Lincoln Before His Nomination</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a speech in Leavenworth, Kansas, Lincoln warns those Democrats who
                    threaten to dissolve the Union (if Lincoln is elected) that the government will
                    deal with them in the same manner as John Brown was dealt with.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krotel</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>D. Webster</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Essom</ln>
                        <fn>Lu. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embly</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weicth</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colestock</ln>
                        <fn>Z. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shanebrugh</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swaim</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elderdice</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabler</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hambleton</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coursey</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkett</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everly</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shettron</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 16th, in Lancaster City, Rev. J. F. Krotel married D. Webster Diehl
                    to Lu. F. Essom, both of Chambersburg. On Sept. 16th, Rev. Jacob F. Oller,
                    married Lewis Embly to Eliza Weicth, both of Carrtown, Washington Twp. On Oct.
                    3rd, Rev. Z. A. Colestock married Charles Shanebrugh to Mary A. Harmony. On Oct.
                    18th, Rev. Z. A. Colestock married George W. Swaim to Anna M. Baker, both of
                    Chambersburg. On Oct. 11th, in Carlisle, Rev. James M. Elderdice married Solomon
                    Gabler to Sarah Ann Hambleton, both of Franklin Co. On Oct. 16th, in
                    Shippensburg, Rev. Wesley Howe married John Ott to Elizabeth Barr, both of
                    Scotland. On Oct. 18th, near Caledonia Furnace, Rev. William R. Coursey married
                    David C. Burkett to Rebecca E. Everly. On Oct. 18th, Rev. S. McHenry married
                    Samuel D. Lehman, of Guilford Twp., to Martha Ebersole, of Green Twp. On Oct.
                    18th, at the home of the bride's parents, Rev. S. McHenry married Samuel B.
                    Wingert to Eliza Snider, both of St. Thomas Twp. On Oct. 18th, at the home of
                    the bride's parents, Rev. S. McHenry married Daniel Shettron to Susan Gelwicks,
                    both of St. Thomas Twp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheiry</ln>
                        <fn>John Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheiry</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheiry</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Magdalena</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roemer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>John Bayly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept 12th, in Funkstown, John Henry, son of Henry and Catharine Sheiry,
                    died at age 3. On Oct. 10th, in Hamilton Twp., Susan Hege, wife of Henry B.
                    Hege, died at the age 23 of consumption. On Oct. 16th, near Middleburg,
                    Magdalena, daughter of Isaac Shank, died at age 1. On Oct. 18th, in Loudon,
                    Henry Roemer died of Lock-jaw at age 70. On Oct. 11th, at his father's home in
                    Greenwood, Franklin Co., John Bayly Black died at age 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertsiements; land and house sales.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
