<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-25">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Civil War In Syria</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Coverage of the war between Christians and Moslems, the atrocities
                    committed on the Christians by the Moslems, the Turkish and other nations'
                    involvement, and of the American citizens present Syria.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Way To Do It</head>
                <origin>The New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A plea to not only elect Lincoln and Hamlin, but also a Congress that will
                    support their clean up of the executive office and the spending practices of the
                    government. By disseminating speeches of Lincoln--especially the debates between
                    Lincoln and Douglas--the Republicans make clear and emphasize the differences in
                    the platforms of the two parties. It is suggested that the Democrats are afraid
                    to do the same, because publishing the truth would make them look bad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At a meeting in Schenectady, N.Y., Gen Houston with Com. Stockton were
                    nominated to run as independents for the Presidency and Vice Presidency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Facts And Fancies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>One brief observation that a woman can speak as many languages as she
                    likes, just as long as she doesn't speak too long a time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poem; Facts And Fancies; a note of Breckenridge's standings in New
            Yor.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction story of a Widower remarrying; Christian parables; political news from
                different regions; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25.03">
            <pageNote>Christian story for children; advertisements; story of army company saved from
                Indians by a dog.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Feast Of Blood</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Observation that the Democrats plan to disregard the rule of election that
                    majority wins, and that the Democrats have a pathetic plan to refuse Lincoln's
                    appointee to the Southern Post Master position, that this will only
                    inconvenience the South and save the Treasury's money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Mails South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complaint that Post Master Holtz is favoring with better rates the
                    Cumberland Valley Railroad over the much better southern route via the new
                    Franklin Rail, and a demand that Holtz change this policy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The People In Motion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Use of a naval illustration to discuss the ship of Lincoln and Hamlin
                    cruising along steadily into port, all the while looking for those boats of
                    piracy that include Douglas, Bell and Everett.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Old Whigs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The opinion of Senator Benjamin, that LINCOLN is infinitely more
                    conservative than DOUGLAS, and is greatly to be preferred by the thinking
                    portion of society, is fully concurred in by the old Whigs, and their power will
                    be felt on the right side during this very important campaign."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are many men in the United States, who, since the disbanding of the old
                        Whig party, do not claim to belong to any of the political organizations of
                        the day. Many of these, in 1856, were of the opinion that the Republican
                        party was sectional in its character, and, fearing the consequences of
                        arousing violent sectional feeling in the land--which they dreaded as the
                        result of the election of the gallant Col. Fremont--they believed their true
                        policy was to cast their votes for Millard Filmore, the American candidate
                        for the Presidency. Others, feeling that age and experience had done great
                        things for themselves, naturally supposed that the election of James
                        Buchanan, a man bordering upon three score years and ten, would be the best
                        possible way of allying public excitement, voted for and helped to elect the
                        present incumbent. They find, too late, that they have been deceived in this
                        expectation; that the man who could basely defame Henry Clay was not the man
                        in whom they should have placed any confidence; that he who could permit a
                        patriot, such as the sage of Ashland, to go down to the tomb with a calumny
                        of <emph rend="italic">his own making</emph> upon an otherwise untarnished
                        reputation, should never have received their votes. They see this error, and
                        not being able to correct it do not desire to commit another blunder like
                        it. They are, therefore, seriously pondering over their proper course in
                        this campaign. The result is easily predicted, a second Henry Clay; another
                        old Whig is in the field. They see in honest ABRAHAM LINCOLN the embodiment
                        of all their old political principles, and they will rally as one man to his
                        support.</p>
                    <p>The meeting at Union Square, in the city of New York, a few evenings since,
                        which was addressed by the old Whig leader HORACE GREELEY, and by DANIEL
                        ULLMAN, ESQ., (one of the number who, like many others), supported Mr.
                        Fillmore, four years since,) was an assemblage of earnest-thinking men of
                        the old Whig like themselves, all their hearts can desire in a President,
                        and they are determined to vote for him.</p>
                    <p>The opinion of Senator Benjamin, that LINCOLN is infinitely more conservative
                        than DOUGLAS, and is greatly to be preferred by the thinking portion of
                        society, is fully concurred in by the old Whigs, and their power will be
                        felt on the right side during this very important campaign.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prediction that the former Whigs who have not yet joined a party will
                    finally join the Republican party when they see Lincoln as another Henry Clay,
                    as an excellent representative for Whig ideals.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frjuly60.html#7.25a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A request that people continue the local tradition of sending capable and
                    successful representatives from this district to the State Legislature; James R.
                    Brewster and James C. Austin have done well, and it is wise to return such
                    experienced men rather than risk choosing green representatives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>a</column>
                <head>He Is Welcome</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An expression of delight as Hon. John Hickman offers to canvass for Lincoln
                    in the western states, and a call for others to do the same and make their mark
                    in aiding in this historically significant election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Dwarfed Giant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Observation and excerpt of a Southern Democrat's comment on the general
                    opinion of Douglas by Southern Democrats---that he is currupt, even though he
                    helped them by repealing the Missouri compromise. If this is the case, that the
                    Southerners won't support him, and the Northern Democrats see him as a traitor
                    to Free Labor, then who will support him?</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Despotism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pritts</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Note of a Missouri newspaper was mobbed and the Editor, S. Harbaugh, forced
                    to leave the offices because he promoted Lincoln and Hamlin. Harbaugh is a
                    native of Waynesboro, Franklin county, and worked under Joseph Pritts for the
                    Franklin Repository and Transcript. Comment that this is how the Democrats in
                    the South operate--by mobbing anyone who dares support a Republican, and yet the
                    Democrats accuse the Republicans of sectionalism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Rather Sensible</head>
                <origin>The Cumberland (Md.) Civilian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A complaint the Democrats are unwilling to stand up for the candidate Bell
                    during the popular election, although if the vote goes to the House, they would
                    urge his election there. And so the newspaper would rather vote for Lincoln,
                    rather than settle for one of the Democrat candidates over Bell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Visit To A Centenarian Couple</head>
                <origin>The Missouri Statesman</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention by the Missouri editor of his visit with a married couple aged 109
                    and 102, respectively; both alive well before the American Revolution. The
                    editor of the Franklin Repository notes a visit to Mrs. Cowan, aged 102, who
                    lives in Cowan's Gap, northeast of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>So They Go</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reference to an article in the Louisville Journal about the disruption at a
                    Breckenridge ratification meeting, caused by Bell supporters and animosity
                    between Breckenridge and Douglas supporters</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Monsieur Tonson Come Again</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Atlanta Southern Confederacy, a paper supporting Douglas, urges that if
                    Lincoln wins, then the South should secede. Clearly Douglas has not been able to
                    quiet these suggestions among his own supporters. Also a mention that should the
                    South secede the Government will respond with hangings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Accidental Hanging</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A three year old boy, Patrick Riley of Norristown, accidentally hung
                    himself while playing with a rope hanging on a low wall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Joseph Culbertson, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>M. Simpson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Anne M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of Joseph Cubertson in Crosby's Annual Obituary Notices of Eminent
                    Persons who died in 1858. Summary given: died 7/26/58, age 79; born in
                    Culbertsons Row 2/27/1779; in the mercantile business, High sheriff of Franklin
                    Co., President of the Bank of Chambersburg, member of the Presbyterian Church of
                    Chambersburg. Second son, Alexander, connected with American Fur Company and has
                    made donations to the Smithsonian. Another son, M. Simpson, went to West Point
                    and is now a missionary in China. Another son, Thaddeus, was a Reverend, but
                    died 8/28/50. His daughter, Anne M., died 2/8/58.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Wire Walking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noel</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stickell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of a tight-rope act by Prof. Price on July 23rd, on a rope strung
                    between John Fisher's hotel and Jacob P. Noel's house. Also mention of Antrim
                    native, John Stickell, while working in Maryland, walked a rope in order to save
                    an employee hanging from it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Montgomery All Alive&gt;</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Afee</ln>
                        <fn>Mark</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Members of the People's Party met at Mark M'Afee's Public House in
                    Mercersburg on July 21st to organize a Lincoln and Hamlin Club. Col. F. S.
                    Stumbaugh delivered a speech.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nichols</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The pastor-elect of the Presbyterian Church of Chambersburg, Rev. Preston,
                    of Virginia, a few weeks ago declined the position due to poor health. Rev. S.
                    J. Nichols, of Westmoreland Co. is the newly chosen pastor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Ball Is Rolling</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushman</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stotler</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swigert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shough</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note>The People's Party of Guilford met in Marion at Col. J. Burk's Public House on
                    July 21st, to organize a Lincoln and Hamlin Club. The following were elected:
                    Solomon Bushman, President; Andrew Stotler, Vice President; John Swigert,
                    Secretary. Speeches were made by P. H. Shough and R. Crooks, of Greencastle.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Meeting In Fayetteville</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Lincoln and Hamlin Club of Fayetteville met at John
                    Brown's Public House July 21st. Mr. William G. Mitchell, of Pleasant Hall,
                    Letterkenny township, and E. J. Bonebrake, Esq., of Chambersburg, spoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rail Road Survey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>Dunlap</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sim</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stinger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickhout</ln>
                        <fn>Hartman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. R,</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Comittees appointed in the several districts to collect money to pay for
                    the survey for a railroad between Chambersburg and Burnt Cabins. In
                    Chambersburg: Emanuel Kuhn, William Seibert, and J. W. Fletcher. In St. Thomas
                    Township: Dunlap Dickson, Peter Hollar, and Samuel Sim. In Peters Township: H.
                    Easton, George Stinger, and Hartman Dickhout. In Metal Township; Charles
                    Campbell, Samuel Walker, and Jas. R. Brewster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Boat Ride</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A suggested local entertainment is an excursion on Mr. Sollenberger's
                    "Young America" on the Conococheague.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Almost A Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A fire in Barnitz' Old Brewery was started by children and extinguished by
                    a passing gentleman. Another fire in an alley between Queen and Market St. was
                    also extinguished.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Meteor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A large meteor passed through the sky around 10 o'clock pm July 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="0">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Sad Occurence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Null</ln>
                        <fn>Isaiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaiah Null, age 27, drowned in the milldam of Messrs. S. &amp; G.
                    Small, in Quincytown, and leaves a wife and two children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Almost A Fire</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A fire in William Garner's flour mill, caused by the friction of the
                    hopper's burrs, was luckily put out by Garner in time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Good Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A commendation to A. Hurst and W. F. Smith who cut nine acres of oats in
                    seven hours on July 21st on Hurst's farm in Guilford township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Banners For The Free</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announcement of a meeting July 26th of the Lincoln Ladies of Chambersburg
                    to adopt measures for providing flags and banners to the People's Party of
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Bush Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stinger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Bush meeting held by the United Brethren will meet on Peter Stinger's
                    lands near Loudon, Aug. 3rd to the 5th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Another Oats Curiosity&gt;</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The newspaper has been brought a sample of oats from J. Watson Craig's
                    field where every stalk has two heads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>African Negroes Openly Imported Into Mobile</head>
                <origin>The Mobile Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We take it that the trade is to all intents and purposes, opened. Why not?
                    Why should not those who are in want of negro labor import it at a low cost,
                    when they are civilizing and Christianizing a set of barbarians by the same
                    course which redounds to their interest?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An excerpt from an Alabama paper praising the recent successful import of
                    African slaves--that slavery benefits the owners, and also the slaves by
                    civilizing them and saving their souls with Christianity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Population Of Lebanon</head>
                <origin>Courrier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The population of Lebanon has greatly decreased; due to the stagnating
                    market, mechanics and laborers must leave to find work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Apple Tree Blight</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ohio papers report a blight on apple trees, similar to a pear tree blight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Washington has sent Dr. Thomas Antisell, an eminent chemist and naturalist,
                    to investigate the cattle disease affecting the Eastern states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A List of Grand and Traverse Jurors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirts</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckman</ln>
                        <fn>J. C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eberly</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finafrock</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grover</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gossert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karper</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miley</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middour</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McColloh</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Royer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richer</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witmore</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn>Caleb</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Angle</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>Jerome</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brant</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushey</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colby</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cell</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fetter</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Alonza P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleagle</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrister</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuss</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hade</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hambright</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawk</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irvin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Abram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leckron</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leckrone</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middour</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Means</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slotliour</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Morrow</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weir</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weister</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wyncoop</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The list of Grand and Traverse Jurors drawn for a Court of Oyer and
                    Terminer, Court of Quarter Sessions of the Peace, and Court of Common--to be
                    held in Chambersburg August 13th. Grand Jurors include: John Shirts,
                    Mercersburg; John Bonebrake, Washington; S. A. Bradley, Mercersburg; John Croft,
                    St. Thomas; James Conner, Warren; J. C. R. Eckman, Quincy; Henry Eberly,
                    Montgomery; Daniel Finafrock, Green; James Gilbert, Montgomery; Thomas Grove,
                    Mercersburg; John Gilmore, Letterkenny; Jacob Gossert, Jr., Quincy; Benjamin
                    Johnston, Southampton; John Oler, Washington; Philip Karper, Letterkenny; S.
                    Mohler, Southampton; George Milay, Washington; Jacob Middour, Quincy; James
                    McColloh, Peters; Daniel W. Royer, Quincy; John Ramsey, Letterkenny; Richard,
                    Richer St. Thomas; James D. Scott, Peters; Jacob Witmore, Montgomery. Traverse
                    Jurors include: Caleb Atherton, Chambersburg; Jeremiah Angle, Southampton;
                    Jerome Beaver, Waynesboro; Willam Brant, Green; William Burgess, Peters; Michael
                    Bushey, Peters; W. S. Bard, Southampton; John Crawford, Guilford; George Colby,
                    Green; John S. Cell, Peters; Abraham Dull, Guilford; John Ditzler, Green; Andrew
                    Detrich, St. Thomas; Christian Fry, Jr. Green; William Fetter, Letterkenny;
                    Alonza P. Fry, Chambersburg; Adam Fleagle, Metal; John Forrister, Letterkenny;
                    Joseph Fuss, Peters; William Hade, Antrim; David Hays, Southampton; Martin
                    Hoover, Letterkenny; Michael Hoover, Peters; Cyrus Hambright, Green; Jacob
                    Henninger, Chambersburg; Ruben Hawk, Green; John Irvin, Jr., Waynesboro; Daniel
                    Johnston, Fannett; Abram. Knepper, Quincy; Simon Leckron, Washington; Daniel
                    Leckrone, Washington; John Middour, Quincy; James R. McCurdy, Green; Daniel
                    Myers, Antrim; Marshall Means, Southampton; William Orr, Southampton; Joseph
                    Reed, St Thomas; Michael Rider, of A., Peters; Robert Parker, Mercersburg; F.
                    Skinner, Fannett; Michael Slotliour, Antrim; Daniel Skinner, Fannett; Jacob
                    Shaffer, Chambersburg; Morrow Skinner, Lurgan; A. K. Weir, Greencastle; Jacob
                    Weister, Greencastle; John Wyncoop, Lurgan; Jacob Young, Montgomery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Market report; articles of facts and interest; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25.06">
            <pageNote>News from Europe; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25.07">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>story of a man who drugged a woman in order to marry her; she sued to have
                    it set aside, and to the surprise of the husband, the Supreme Court decided in
                    her favor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A man in New Orleans was arrested for beating his wife to death with his
                    fists and a club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A remonstration of the inappropriateness of women joking about suicide.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Republican Platform; advertisements; facts of interest an humor</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.25.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sound Sentiments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A response that the editors will not abuse either Douglas or
                    Lincoln--especially in the tasteless style of belittling their humble
                    beginnings. The type of people who do mock in this way, are usually of the same
                    class, but have not escaped and risen to a higher level.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Stampede Commenced</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The party has arrived at that perplexing fork in the road described by the
                    colored preacher, where 'one leads to hell, and the other to d--nation.' If
                    Douglas and Breckinridge are both withdrawn, Lincoln will be elected. If both
                    remain in the field he will be elected. If either of them remain in the field
                    Lincoln will be elected. But neither of them will withdraw unless the other
                    does, and Lincoln will be elected anyhow. That is the whole mathematics of the
                    campaign."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The evidence of a determination on the part of the Douglas men to vote for
                        Lincoln, says the Harrisburg <emph rend="italic">Telegraph,</emph> and thus
                        kill two birds with one stone, are multiplying on every hand. This is the
                        case here and all over the country. Scores of men who have for years cited
                        with the Democratic party are daily ranging themselves under the banner of
                        Lincoln and Hamlin, determined to crush out the southern disunionists and
                        the northern traitors who fraternize with them. It is conceded, and justly
                        too, that every vote cast for Douglas in the Free States is a vote for
                        Breckenridge or old Joe Lane, just in the proportion that it is effective in
                        carrying the election into Congress. The honest supporters of Mr. Douglas
                        would a hundred times prefer the election of Lincoln to that of either
                        Breckinridge or old Joe Lane. This is the first bird to be killed, by all
                        manner of means. On the other hand, a large number of them are burning with
                        the desire to give a blow to the South in return for the dastardly treatment
                        they have received during the past three years, and particularly at the
                        Charleston and Baltimore Conventions. They see no other way half so
                        effectual in accomplishing their revenge, as voting Lincoln into the White
                        House. The country is swarming with this class of Douglas men, and among
                        them may be counted some of the most efficient politicians of that
                        persuasion.</p>
                    <p>The Douglas organs are laboring desperately to hold them back--for the
                        purpose, we suppose, of carrying the election into the House and insuring
                        the success of the "disunionists." as the term the supporters of
                        Breckinridge. But the stampede has commenced, and it cannot be stopped. We
                        have no doubt a large majority of Democratic <emph rend="italic"
                        >politicians</emph> in the North are anxious for some kind of a compromise
                        which may possibly save the offices to themselves--but the <emph
                            rend="italic">people</emph> who want no offices, are in for the fight on
                        principle. The party has arrived at that perplexing fork in the road
                        described by the colored preacher, where "one leads to hell, and the other
                        to d--nation." If Douglas and Breckinridge are both withdrawn, Lincoln will
                        be elected. If both remain in the field he will be elected. If either of
                        them remain in the field Lincoln will be elected. But neither of them will
                        withdraw unless the other does, and Lincoln will be elected anyhow. That is
                        the whole mathematics of the campaign. Joint electoral tickets will not
                        avail the warring factions, because that sort of thing implies that one or
                        the other is to be cheated, and the people are bound <emph rend="italic">not
                            to be cheated.</emph></p>
                    <p>Turn it which way you will, Lincoln comes uppermost every time. If anybody
                        doubts it let him just hold his breath till the 6th day of November!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A number of Douglas supporters consider voting for Lincoln, since it will
                    help defeat Breckenridge and be a revenge on the Southerners for their
                    mistreatment of their Northern allies at the conventions in Charleston and
                    Baltimore.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frjuly60.html#7.25b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Proposed Mormon Emigration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A proposal that the Mormons emigrate to Oceanica, one of the East Indies
                    islands, so that the wealth on the islands can be tapped by the U. S.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>North And South</head>
                <origin>The Baltimore Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"When southern merchants want northern manufacturers, or southern planters
                    seek change and a colder climate, they will go north to find them, just as they
                    of the north seek health, or cotton or rice, or sugar in the southern states."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Patriot</emph> says: At the north the
                        watering places are rapidly filling up, and especially with southern
                        visitors. The twaddle, so much in vogue a few years ago, of southerners
                        shunning the northern States, and seeking only the rendezvous within their
                        own borders, has died out, notwithstanding the present "impending crisis" of
                        Messrs. Yancey &amp; Co. People of sense, both north and south, go just
                        exactly where their interest and inclination leads them. And in this they
                        follow that universal law and custom which binds everywhere alike. When
                        southern merchants want northern manufacturers, or southern planters seek
                        change and a colder climate, they will go north to find them, just as they
                        of the north seek health, or cotton or rice, or sugar in the southern
                        states.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notwithstanding the present friction between the North and the South, the
                    Patriot observes that Southerners have started coming North again when in need
                    of manufactured goods, and the Northerners are going South for cotton, rice or
                    sugar.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frjuly60.html#7.25c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alexander Hamilton's son states that Judge Taney's belief that the
                    Constitution does recognize property in a man is wrong, but, instead, that the
                    authors were very careful to keep out any mention of a right to own another man.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Consistency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pres. Buchanan says, that considering the irregularities of the Democratic
                    conventions, Democrats should vote as they please, and not feel bound by any
                    particular nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Abner D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 19th in Chambersburg, at the German Reformed Parsonage, by Rev.
                    Samuel Philips, Abner D. Kuhn married Rebecca Stover</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hosler</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heffelfinger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Parthena W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 10th, Sarah Maria Allen, wife of Josiah Allen, of Hamilton
                    township, died at age 50. On July 19th, in Metal township, William Elliott died
                    at age 81. On July 23, in Guilford township at the home of Mrs. Catharine
                    Hosler, Rev. David Heffelfinger, who was pastor of the German Reform
                    Congregations of Fayetteville, Funkstown, Marion and Grindstone Hill, died at
                    age 45. On July 24th, in Chambersburg, Mrs parthena W. King, wife of James King,
                    died at age 40.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements; land sales</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
