<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-08-01">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mention of Milwaukee, Wisconsin, that in the past has voted Democrat, but
                    that in recent elections, the Republican candidates have been winning, and that
                    the 2,000 German-born citizens are supporting Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Address Of The Republican Executive Committee Of Maryland</head>
                <origin>Baltimore, Maryland</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The assertion, either so ignorantly or maliciously made, that the
                    Republican Party proposes by force to abolish Slavery and elevate the negro to a
                    social equality with the white man, we denounce as a most unfounded accusation.
                    This party is essentially the white man's party. Its sympathies are enlisted in
                    behalf of the white race, and its fundamental object is to protect and ennoble
                    free labor."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>William E. Coale, the chairman of the Republican Executive Committee of
                    Maryland while submitting their electoral ticket for Lincoln and Hamlin,
                    addresses some crucial issues: confinement of slavery to the present states,
                    support of the Homestead act and support of a tariff to protect industry, both
                    an encouragement for free labor, and the tariff would be revenue for a bankrupt
                    government. He urges support for Lincoln and the Republican Party and ideals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Hints As To Political Meetings</head>
                <origin>The New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>We clip the following sensible remarks from the New York Tribune, of a
                    recent date. They are national in their application; suitable for every
                    latitude. They know no North, no South, no East nor West. All can profit by
                    their perusal:</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggestions on how to organize for a successful meeting, such as: Get your
                    speakers first, before advertising the meeting; keep the number of prominent
                    speakers to two; have meetings indoors; get quickly to the business of the
                    meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Speech Of Hon. John Hickman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>On The Great Issues Of The Day, Before the Republican Club of
                    Philadelphia, on Tuesday Evening, July 24, 1860.</commentary>
                <excerpt>"I appeal to you to know whether the honesty, intelligence, and unmixed
                    blood of the off-spring of Northern mothers can ever accept an excuse for those
                    who would endeavor to fasten such a ruler upon us."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Hon. John Hickman gives an impassioned speech on the evils of slavery, its
                    effects on labor, and the Democrat and Southern promotion of slavery. He then
                    discusses the positions of several presidential candidates--that Breckenridge
                    promotes slavery, that Stephen Douglas is unsafe and treacherous (his dealings
                    with Kansas indicate that), and that Bell promises nothing. Hickman will support
                    none of these, but instead Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Story of women trapped by a cave-in in a coal mine; poem</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01.02">
            <pageNote>Continuation from page one of John Hickman's speech; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01.03">
            <pageNote>Serial Fiction story; train schedules; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Douglasism Waning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The vaulting ambition of Douglas which led him, in his eager pursuit of
                    presidential honors, to dash a flaming fire-brand into the political magazine of
                    the nation, resulted as would a similar act, by any other madman--literally
                    speaking--in an awful explosion."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One after another the leading politicians of every section of the land,
                        especially that portion in which the Nigger Democracy have their chief
                        strength, the South, are falling into the Breckinridge and Lane ranks, and
                        are turning their backs upon the "little giant." Different causes have
                        united in producing this result. It is seen that Douglas and Breckinridge
                        are contending for the same thing,--the unlimited spread of slavery--but by
                        very different means. The one openly declares that the Supreme Court has
                        already decided that Slavery is the normal condition of the poor man, and
                        that his rich neighbor may <emph rend="italic">justly</emph> reduce him to
                        bondage for their mutual benefit; and that, such being the proper condition
                        of poor men, slavery is the highest type of civilization, and rightfully
                        enters into every portion of our domain; and where it does not now exit,
                        Congress should speedily send it . The other says that the highest judicial
                        tribunal has not yet disposed of this question, but when it does, if in the
                        way the other indicates, (and he knows that a majority of all Judges are
                        slave-owners) we are all bound to obey its inhuman, its unnatural decree.
                        The one is openly fighting for oppression; the other is covertly seeking to
                        accomplish the very same object. All, therefore, who desire to see the fair
                        surface of our beautiful Territories blasted, as with mill-dew, by the
                        withering blight of slavery, and who have the courage to advocate their
                        principles, are losing no time in joining the Breckinridge wing of the
                        distracted, rent party. Those who desire the overthrow of Freedom, and the
                        crushing of poor white laboring men, but who are ashamed to declare their
                        purpose openly, are seeking to accomplish their wishes in a sneaking,
                        underhanded way by voting for Douglas.</p>
                    <p>Both branches of the Nigger Democracy are sufficiently inimical to the
                        happiness of the working classes, and to the prosperity of the whole
                        country; but, what that of Breckinridge is openly proclaiming its poisonous
                        sentiments, the advocates of Douglasism are endeavoring to accomplish all
                        that the other seeks for, only they fight behind a masked battery; they
                        refuse to permit the people to see what they wish to accomplish.</p>
                    <p>The Douglasites have sought to cover up the bane to Freedom--the oppression
                        of free laborers by the spreading of slavery, which destroys all demand for
                        free labor--by sugar- coating the pill with the peculiar covering of
                        Squatter Sovereignty, which appears to be the right of the people to decide,
                        but which, as explained by its father, Stephen Arnold Douglas, means that if
                        the people are not willing to have slavery, and if the Supreme Court says
                            <emph rend="italic">they must,</emph> then as loyal subjects of this
                        kid-glove, black-gown aristocracy, they have nothing to do but submit.</p>
                    <p>The slavery propagandists of the South greatly prefer the Breckinridge
                        doctrine--that the question has been settled by the Supreme Court--to that
                        of Douglas, which leaves the matter for future decision. The dough-faces of
                        the North, who have long been accustomed to obey Southern dictation, seeing
                        what is most likely to give satisfaction to their masters, are has tening
                        [sic] to array themselves on the side of Breckinridge. Thus the Douglas
                        ranks are steadily becoming weaker and weaker. So it will go on, until that
                        wing of the party becomes so weak in the knees that it will be utterly
                        unable to stand upon its feet.</p>
                    <p>The vaulting ambition of Douglas which led him, in his eager pursuit of
                        presidential honors, to dash a flaming fire-brand into the political
                        magazine of the nation, resulted as would a similar act, by any other
                        madman--literally speaking--in an awful explosion. His political hopes and
                        aspirations have received a shock from which they will never recover. It is
                        utter madness for him to see to be President of the United States, by the
                        votes of the People.</p>
                    <p>While Douglas was fighting the administration of James Buchanan, the time he
                        was seeking his re-election to the Senate, he drew around him many admirers
                        in the North; but when he so meanly succumbed to the leaders of the
                        slavery-expansion dogma, who also control the administration, as he did on
                        his return to the Senate, they found out the extent of his sympathy for the
                        masses of society, and in their indignation at his insincerity, will now do
                        everything in their power to expose to public gaze the band of infamy which
                        his perfidy has fastened upon his brow. He is, of all the candidates in the
                        field, the least likely to win, and the least worthy of the confidence of
                        the great, indusrious [sic] American people. That his cause is waning, is
                        becoming more and more apparent every day. If something is not soon done to
                        create a reaction, there will scarcely be enough votes cast for him to swear
                        by.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Nothern Democrats and others are choosing to support Breckenridge instead
                    of Douglas, because Breckenridge claims the Slave issue has been validated by
                    the Supreme Court, whereas Douglas says that it has yet to be decided. Douglas
                    lost many Northern supporters during his battles with the Buchanan
                    administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>State Agricultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A mention that the Agricultural Society of the State of Pennsylavania's
                    list of Premiums, and the rules and regulations for the annual exhibition have
                    been published. There are twelve divisions of the stock and articles, subdivided
                    in fifty-two classes. The exhibition will take place on the battle-ground of
                    Wyoming, near Wilkesbarre, which is very accessible by railroad in all
                    directions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Hickman's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article providing some background on the speaker of the speech from
                    pages one and two. He was a long-time Democrat, who has left the party due to
                    the ideals held by the present leaders and candidates of the party. He now
                    supports the Republicans and their beliefs in Free Labor and the Homestead Act.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is every way important that all districts in the North which are now
                    represented by able champions of Free Speech, Free Labor, Free Homes for free
                    men, Freedom of the Press, and proper Protection to American industry should
                    continue in the same hands."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Republicans of this Congressional district will soon be called upon to
                        place in nomination a candidate for Representative to the national
                        Legislature. It is every way important that all districts in the North which
                        are now represented by able champions of Free Speech, Free Labor, Free Homes
                        for free men, Freedom of the Press, and proper Protection to American
                        industry should continue in the same hands. We have as eloquent, as talented
                        and as worthy a member of Congress--in the Hon. EDWARD McPHERSON--as is to
                        be found in the country. Every dictate of prudence and patriotism teachers
                        us that where we are faithfully represented, and can again procure the
                        services of honest, reliable men, we should never hesitate for a moment
                        about our course.</p>
                    <p>Let us then nominate the gifted young advocate of our cause, who has won for
                        himself so enviable a reputation during the one term he has served in
                        Congress, without a dissenting voice. This district is entirely too doubtful
                        for us to run any risks about carrying it. Mr. McPHERSON has carried it
                        once, and his name is surrounded with the prestige of success which will add
                        materially to his prospects again. Let us have, then, the gifted McPHERSON
                        for our candidate, and there will be no doubt of his election.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors urge that the local congressional district re-elect Hon. Edward
                    McPherson for his reliability, honesty and staunch support of Republican ideals,
                    so that he can be of support to Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"Honest Abe"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Democrat minister of Franklin county visited Lincoln in Springfield, Ill.
                    and considered Lincoln an "extraordinary" man. The editors urge other Democrats
                    to visit Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Negro Voters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We remember having seen, upon more than one occasion, in this county,
                    certain Locofoco township politicians leading up their "culled brethren" to the
                    polls and voting them for Jackson, for Van Buren and, generally having them to
                    go "the whole hog" for the D-e-m-o-c- r-a-c-y."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Several times, recently, the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> has harped
                        upon the subject of negroes voting The sap-heads are to dumb to know that a
                        few years since negroes had the right to vote in Pennsylvania; that they
                        exercised the right, and that <emph rend="italic">they voted the Locofoco
                            ticket.</emph> We remember having seen, upon more than one occasion, in
                        this county, certain Locofoco township politicians leading up their "culled
                        brethren" to the polls and voting them for Jackson, for Van Buren and,
                        generally having them to go "the whole hog" for the D-e-m-o-c- r-a-c-y.</p>
                    <p>The right of suffrage was never denied to negroes in this State till after
                        the adoption of the present constitution, when they were deprived the
                        privilege of assisting to fasten locofocoism upon the people. The
                        Legislature which provided for the revision of the Constitution was composed
                        of a majority opposed to the heresie of locofocoism. The Governor who
                        approved the law--honest old Joseph Ritner--will scarcely be claimed by the
                        locofocos as belonging to their party. The Convention which framed the
                        present Constitution, <emph rend="italic">depriving the SPIRIT'S friends of
                            their former privilege,</emph> was composed of a majority of Whigs.
                        After giving the whiners of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit,</emph> who
                        lounge around the street corners in idleness, no person appreciating their
                        professional worth, all this <emph rend="italic">"light"</emph> upon their
                        favorite theme, we shall not be surprised to see them wearing crape in their
                        distress over the loss of their sable coadjutors.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticism for the Spirit's discussions on negroes' voting. The Repository's
                    article reminds the Spirit that negroes did have the right a few years ago, and
                    they voted for the Democratic Party. The Whigs took away their right to vote, so
                    as to take away some support of locofocoism in Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Lincoln Among The Children</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Retelling of a Sunday-school teacher's surprise guest to her class. Lincoln
                    spoke with the children and captivated his young audience.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Messrs. Editors--Gentlemen:</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>David M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Pherson</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Tries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immel</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Longenecker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Farland</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleagle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shade</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleming</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An observation that Antrim has been honored with only one nomination for
                    the Republican County Convention in the past four years, and yet Antrim has one
                    of the largest Republican districts. He lists the voting records of the
                    districts for the last four years, and the candidates from each district.
                    Chambersburg: 1856-W. Crooks for Senator, John Huber for Associate Judge, L. S.
                    Clarke for District Attorney; 1857-A. K. M'Clure for Assembly; 1858-A. K.
                    M'Clure for Assembly, J. Allison Eyster for Commissioner; 1859-A. K. M'Clure for
                    Senator, John Stouffer for County Treasurer. Fayetteville: 1856-J. S. Brown for
                    Sheriff; 1859-John Downey for Auditor. Hamilton: 1856-David M. Leisher;
                    1859-George Eyster for District Attorney. Letterkenny: 1856-J. B. Cauffman for
                    County Surveyor; 1857-Samuel Longenecker for Register and Recorder; 1859-J. B.
                    Cauffman for County Surveyor. Mercersburg: 1856 &amp; 1857-James O. Carson
                    for Associate Judge; 1859-Doctor John S. King for Coroner. Metal: John Witherow
                    for Assembly; 1857-W. S. Harris for Commissioner; 1858-James R. Brewster for
                    Auditor; 1859-James R. Brewster for Assembly. Southampton: 1856-D.H. M'Pherson
                    for Auditor; 1859-David Spencer for Director of the Poor. St. Thomas: 1856-Dr.
                    John Van Tries for Coroner, Jacob Weaver for Director of the Poor; 1857-John
                    Shade for Prothonotary. Washington: 1856-George Jacobs for Assembly; 1859-Jacob
                    S. Good for Commissioner. Greenvillage: 1857-John Ditzler for Clerk of the
                    Courts. Guildford: 1857-G. W. Immel for Director of the Poor; 1858-Jacob
                    Strickler for Director of the Poor. Peters: 1857-R. P. M'Farland for Treasurer;
                    1859-William M'Grath for Sheriff. Quincy: 1857-William Fleagle for Auditor. The
                    writer notes that Andrew Davidson of Antrim did fill the unexpired term of James
                    R. Brewster on the Board of Auditors in 1859, when Brewster was nominated to the
                    Assembly.. He reminds the readers that Antrim has a candidate this year--William
                    W. Fleming--for Register and Recorder, and urges his election. Quincy</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Messrs. Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>K. Shannon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter from Guilford urging the election of Major K. Shannon, who has
                    served as a Deputy Sheriff, for Prothonotary at the People's County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>County Commissioner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Montgomery urges the support of Joseph Winger of the Welsh Run district for
                    County Commisioner</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Work Of The Campaign</head>
                <origin>New York Independent</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A warning against apathy in the Republican party, that even though it looks
                    promising that Lincoln will be elected, there are still the attitude and beliefs
                    regarding slavery that need to be corrected-- by canvassing in every district to
                    inform people of the evils of slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Important Southern Testimony</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The testimony of conscientious men who have observed the influence of
                    slavery at the South, is that instead of Christianizing the slaves, it
                    heathenizes the masters. The white population of the South is 'undergoing a
                    process of intellectual and moral deterioration,'. . . "</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An argument referring to a speech by Mr. Sumner to the Senate and a
                    document by the Presbyterian Synod of South Carolina and Georgia in 1833, both
                    of which talk of the corrupting influence of slavery on the masters, who are
                    (supposedly) trying to make Christians of their slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note of a Rev. Dr. Daily, who was deposed from the Presidency of
                    Bloomington College, Indiana, and expelled from the Methodist Church for
                    Drunkeness and adultery, has been nominated for Congress by Democrats in
                    Tennessee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01.05">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Delegate Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Sol.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sol. Huber, Chairman of the County Executive Committee writes that the
                    Republicans of the North Ward of Chambersburg will meet on Aug. 4th at the Court
                    House to elect three delegates to the County Nominating Convention. Those of the
                    South Ward will meet at the Friendship Engine House to elect three delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Guilford Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Members of the People's party of Guilford will meet at Lesher's School
                    House on Aug. 4th to elect delegates for the County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Serious Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herchelrode</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Senseny, age 19, son of Dr. A. H. Senseny, was injured on
                    Greencastle Road when his horse fell and kicked him as the horse struggled. Mr.
                    Herchelrode found him, took him to the Herchelrode home, and the injured man's
                    brother, Dr. William Senseny, came and helped him to recover.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Nathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles McDowell, youngest son of Nathan McDowell of Hagerstown, injured
                    himself while climbing the iron fence of the Presbyterian cemetery in
                    Chambersburg. Dr. Richard was able to treat the wound successfully. A reprimand
                    followed about boys climbing iron fences.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Old Antrim In The Field</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pauling</ln>
                        <fn>Thos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>T. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clippinger</ln>
                        <fn>Hampshire</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ilgenfritz</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter by Samuel Eby and T. S. Riley mentioning that "The Antrim
                    Republican Club" was formed at Thos. Pauling's house July 27th. Elected were:
                    Samuel Eby, President; W. H. Davison, Vice President; T. S. Riley, Secretary.
                    The constitution appointees were Hampshire Clippinger, W. H. Newman, John
                    Ruthrauff, and Samuel Ilgenfritz.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Almost A Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heid</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 30th, J. Heid returned to his barber shop in Chambersburg, in the
                    building of Mrs. Gilmore, to find a fire in his spitoon. He promptly put it out.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Leg Broken</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George B. Myers, 12 yr. old son of Samuel Myers, Esq., of Chambersburg,
                    broke his thigh bone while running. Dr. Burkholder treated the injury.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>New York Post Office</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swank</ln>
                        <fn>George Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>There is a new Post Office at Carrick Furnace, of Franklin Co., and George
                    Washington Swank is the Post Master.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yockey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yockey</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coursey</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. M. Coursey announces that the United Brethren in Christ's Camp Meeting
                    for the Greencastle circuit will meet at Daniel and John Yockey's lands starting
                    Aug. 27th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Irrepressible Conflict At Occoquan, Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A battle is ensuing between Democrats and Republicans in Occoquan, Prince
                    Williams County over the raising of a Lincoln and Hamlin Flag. Large numbers of
                    armed men on both sides plan to attack or defend the banner. Governor Letcher
                    has ordered Gen. Hutton to protect the flag.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Northern Locofoco Leaders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An accusation that the editors of Northern Democrat newspapers publish
                    support for Democrat candidates in return for Federal Offices--citing a few
                    editors and their government appointments and salaries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A follow-up story on the improving morals of the Democrats and the expelled
                    Rev. Daily, who is a Democrat candidate in Tennessee, that describes how he was
                    hissed at and prevented from speaking at a meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements; small articles of advice and factual interest.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Quadrangular Contest</head>
                <origin>The Philadelphia Daily News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The administration faction, which is now styled the Breckinridge party,
                    learned a lesson from the Japanese, and finding Democracy in disgrace resorted
                    to the hari caru. It ripped open its own bowels, and if the relatives had been
                    discreet enough to remove the unsightly remains the country would have had much
                    for which to be thankful. But the divided body yet exists, and presents its
                    disagreeable fragments to public view."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The argument that the Democrats (ie. Buchanan, Breckenridge, Douglas, et
                    al) have committed a very messy political suicide with their corruption and
                    divisions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Prospect Before Us</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Once the doors of the Democratic fold are wide open, the freed flock are
                    ready to go at once to "fields and pastures new." The stampede has begun already
                    and in all parts of the country, old-line Democrats are coming out by thousands
                    in favor of Lincoln and Hamlin."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The demoralization of the Democratic party caused by the recent serious
                        division into opposing and bitterly relentless factions, is likely to do
                        more damage, says the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">City Journal,</emph>
                        than the original engineers of the movement ever calculated upon. The split,
                        however easily effected, and however unavoidable under the pressing
                        contingencies of the case, was an undoubted surprise to the great mass of
                        Democratic voters. Outside of the immediate leaders and the mercenary camp
                        followers, whose only watchword is, "To the victor belong the spoils!" and
                        whose only principles are the traditional "loaves and fishes," there is a
                        large element of the party which really is imbued with true patriotism, and
                        whose devotion to the Democratic standard is based upon an earnest
                        conviction that the aims of the organization are elevated and beneficent. IF
                        they have adhered to candidates, becase [sic] regularly indorsed by the
                        conventions of the party, this adhesion has not been through any servile
                        attachment to men, considered apart from certain well-recognized principles.
                        If they have rejoiced over well-won victories, it has not been from personal
                        satisfaction at the elevation of particular leaders, but only because the
                        successful candidates have been identified, by a consistent record, with the
                        cardinal ideas of true Democracy.</p>
                    <p>We make no account of an equally large fraction of the Democratic forces who
                        have no fervent, but who, through ignorance or indifference, have been
                        content to go to the ballot-box and blindly vote any ticket, the names on
                        which are sanctified by the aroma of "regular nominations." This floating
                        element in the present embarrassment of two Democratic Presidantial [sic]
                        candidates, will be about equally divided between Breckinridge and Douglas.
                        This supposition is based on the fact that, not knowing the essential
                        difference of principle between the two candidates, they will select either
                        side which promises the surest success. As the result is doubtful between
                        the two chiefs, so far as the numerical show of votes is involved, the
                        prospect is certain that the inert mass of the substratum of the Democracy
                        will be severely exactly in two.</p>
                    <p>But of the intelligent element--the truly conservative portion, to which we
                        have already made allusion--the future disposition in the canvass is by no
                        means certain. The ties of traditional harmony, which have bound the party
                        into a powerful and constantly victorious unit, have ceased to have any
                        longer the power of cohesion.</p>
                    <p>The party obligations of fealty to party nominations cease as a matter of
                        course, and all the members of the organization are free as air to vote for
                        any candidate they may please to choose. Their minds are equally free to
                        study and examine the patriotic platform of the Republican candidates, and
                        to recognize there the ancient cardinal principles of old-fashioned
                        democratic faith. The conservative record of Mr. Lincoln, the moderation of
                        the Republican leaders in their political views, and the universal devotion
                        of all Republicans to the Constitution and the Union must, as a matter of
                        necessity, draw off to the Republican standard a very large portion of those
                        who have hitherto been affiliated with the Democracy. Once the doors of the
                        Democratic fold are wide open, the freed flock are ready to go at once to
                        "fields and pastures new." The stampede has begun already and in all parts
                        of the country, old-line Democrats are coming out by thousands in favor of
                        Lincoln and Hamlin. The indications are abundant that the campaign of 1860
                        will resemble the tornado of 1840. The probabilities are, that the
                        Republican ticket will carry in November a larger popular vote than was ever
                        accorded before to any national candidates. The cause is onward and upward,
                        and every day and hour the political skies grow brighter and brighter.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A discussion of two types of Democrat voter: one that is patriotic, and
                    holds to the Democratic ideals, and the other is ignorant and only votes for
                    whoever seems to promise to be successful. The ignorant have already banded in
                    equal parts behind Douglas or Breckenridge. The intelligent, patriotic voters
                    should, and some are starting to, examine the Republican candidates and the
                    Platform, and hopefully support them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements; political advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01.07">
            <pageNote>The Republican Platform---see entry 6/6/60; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.08.01.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Facts And Fancies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Four pieces of advice or information: that good girls don't keep secrets
                    from their parents; a twenty-three yr. old man shouldn't sleep with a
                    seventy-eight yr. old man; the carver at the table should serve the women by
                    rank--mother before daughter, oldest daughter first, married before single; in a
                    survey of several states' prisons, the proportion of female felons to male is
                    one to ten.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ullerich</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Helen M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the Luther Parsonage on July 22nd, Rev. J. Steck married Alfred W.
                    Houser to Charlotte Ullerich, both of Chambersburg. On July 4th, near Auburn
                    Kansas, Rev. J. E. Moore married Cyrus Foltz, formerly of Chambersburg, to Helen
                    M. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yodder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrow</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrow</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Melissa Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>David D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parish</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parish</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Mary R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Judith Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Barnard</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 13th in Columbiana Co. Ohio, John Yodder died at age 50. On July
                    14th at Dry Run, Nancy Morrow, widow of Richard Morrow, formerly of
                    Chambersburg, died at age 80. On July 17th near Dry Run, Melissa Ann Skinner,
                    daughter of David D. Skinner, died at age 16. On July 19th in Chambersburg,
                    Margaret Parish, wife of John Parish, died at age 29. On July 25th in Lancaster
                    County while visiting his brother, Jacob Young, of Montgomery township, died at
                    age 75. On July 27th in Chambersburg, Mary R. Smith, daughter of Henry Smith,
                    dec'd, died of consumption at age 16. On July 28th in Chambersburg, Judith Ann,
                    wife of Barnard Wolf, Esq., died at age 66.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
