<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1860/pa.fr.fr.1860.07.04">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-04">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote>Independence Day</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.04.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Messrs. Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A recommendation by Guilford for John E. Crawford, of Guilford township,
                    for the Legislature when elections occur at the People's County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Rosedale Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Principal and teachers have the reputation of being well qualified for
                    their trust, and must necessarily command public attention."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Messrs. Editors:--It was my privilege to attend the examination of the pupils
                        of Rosedale Seminary, in this place, under the care of the Rev. Henry
                        Reeves, on the 28th inst. The examination was highly creditable to the young
                        ladies and teachers.</p>
                    <p>The teachers manifested considerable tact in the examination of the various
                        classes. They were perfectly at home in the different branches upon which
                        their examinations were based. Rosedale Seminary is in a flourishing state.
                        The Principal and teachers have the reputation of being well qualified for
                        their trust, and must necessarily command public attention.</p>
                    <p>Its location is a lovely one, sufficiently retired for a Young Ladies
                        Seminary, and it would seem only necessary that its position should be
                        known, in order to secure a large amount of public patronage.</p>
                    <p>On the evening of the same day the graduating class, composed of five
                        interesting young ladies, each of whom read an original essay in Franklin
                        Hall to a large and intelligent audience. Their subjects were well chosen,
                        and the compositions chaste and elegant, and would have done credit to much
                        older heads.</p>
                    <p>Before the Valedictory Essay was read, Diplomas were severally presented to
                        the graduates by Rev. Dr. B. S. Schneck, with the accompanying degrees. It
                        might be deemed invidious to draw comparisons between the several Essays. I
                        feel that I am not exaggerating, when I say they were of the first order. I
                        hope Rosedale Seminary may enjoy the patronage it so justly deserves.</p>
                    <p>H--R.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Note commenting the qualifications and capabilities of the teachers and
                    students of this female Seminary school, as seen during the recent exams and the
                    graduation ceremony which all took place on June 28th. Rev. Henry Reeves is in
                    charge of the school, and Rev. Schneck gave out diplomas during the ceremony.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frjuly60.html#7.4a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Speech of Hon. Abraham Lincoln: Delivered February, 1860, Before The Cooper
                    Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But no such right [the right to take slaves into the territories] is
                    specificaly written in the Constitution. That instrument is literally silent
                    about any such right. We, on the contrary, deny that such a right has any
                    existance in the Constitution, even by implication. (Applause) Your purpose,
                    then, plainly stated, is, that you will destroy the Government, unless you be
                    allowed to construe and enforce the Constitution as you please, on all points in
                    dispute between you and us. You will ruin or rule in all events."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A speech almost two pages in length, primarily a discussion of the
                    constitution and its authors and whether the two allowed for Federal control in
                    Federal Territories. Lincoln argues that because a large number of the authors
                    voted for prohibition of slavery in the Northwestern territory, then they gave
                    clear indication that the territories were not free from federal control.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>poems; the U.S. Constitution; article on a man's escape from
            Indians</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.04.02">
            <pageNote>continuation of page one--Lincoln's speech on slavery and Federal control of
                the territories</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.04.03">
            <pageNote>Serial Fiction; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.04.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Liberty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reminder that the U.S. is unique in its freedoms, and to not forget the
                    God that has blessed this country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deserved Compliment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Note of a beautiful silver service made by Wilson &amp; Son at Fifth
                    and Cherry in Chambersburg for Col. Thomas A. Scott, Vice President of the
                    Pennsylvania Railroad, and a native of Mercersburg, Franklin county. Note of his
                    outstanding character as is given by the example of aiding a dying woman who
                    wanted to travel home directly to Mercersburg to die, without the numerous train
                    connections that could delay and further tax her remaining health.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"Not Been Here Yet"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The man who gives the orders had better soon come along or the nigger
                    democracy of Franklin County will not know how to vote."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A comment that Democrats can't think for themselves, that they band
                    together, often at the expense of people within their own party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>S-A-D</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Democrats face a possible, uncomfortable position; as Douglas has received
                    the nomination, then the supporters of Buchanan will have to support the man
                    whose actions and opinions their President and they criticized --especially re.
                    Kansas</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Prospects Of Mr. Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Now if a nomination, at the expense of a division of the party, by States
                    which cannot give him their Electoral votes, is cause for gratulation, then the
                    burning of powder and tar-barrels was "all right;" if it is not, the aforesaid
                    burning was a foolish waste of property."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Question of whether Douglas, nominated at the expense of a divided party,
                    will receive any of the votes of the seceding delegates who preferred
                    Breckinridge and Lane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>People's Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Sol.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A reminder from Sol. Huber, Chairman of County Committee for the People's
                    Party, that the members need to meet on Aug. 4th to elect delegates for the
                    County Convention on Aug. 7th. for the nomination of candidates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Railroad Meeting In Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A letter was read by the Secretary from an influential party in New York,
                    stating that the citizens of Sherman's Valley had subscribed five hundred
                    dollars towards a survey of their route, and urging upon the citizens of
                    Franklin county to be up and doing, that now was the time to show the advantages
                    of the route from Chambersburg."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In pursuance of the call advertised in our last issue, there was held a
                        public meeting in the Court House, on Saturday last, at 11 o'clock, A. M.,
                        in furtherance of the contemplated railroad from Chambersburg west, through
                        the counties of Fulton, Bedford and Somerset, to Connellsville. Emanuel
                        Kuhn, Esq., was chosen President, and J. W. Douglas Secretary. A letter was
                        read by the Secretary from an influential party in New York, stating that
                        the citizens of Sherman's Valley had subscribed five hundred dollars towards
                        a survey of their route, and urging upon the citizens of Franklin county to
                        be up and doing, that now was the time to show the advantages of the route
                        from Chambersburg. After some remarks from the Hon. Wilson Reilly, William
                        Seibert, Esq., and Hon. A. K. M'Clure, the following resolution was offered
                        by J. W. Douglas, Esq., and agreed to:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That the Hon. Wilson Reilly and Hon.
                        George Chambers be appointed a committee, with instructions to make a
                        statement of the advantages of our route, and the necessity for a survey of
                        the same; and that they are hereby empowered to appoint committees in each
                        township of Franklin county to receive subscriptions to defray the expense
                        of a survey, it being the opinion of experienced surveyors and engineers,
                        that such survey will cost five hundred dollars.</p>
                    <p>Meeting adjourned to the call of said committee.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summary of a meeting held June 30th where a letter was read urging a survey
                    of the proposed valley route. Elected officers include: Emanuel Kuhn,
                    Esq.-President; J. W. Douglas-Secretary. Wilson Reilly, William Seibert, and A.
                    K. MClure made some remarks. The Hon. Wilson Reilly and Hon. George Chambers
                    were appointed to appoint committees in each township--to receive subscriptions
                    to help defray the cost of the survey estimated at five hundred dollars.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frjuly60.html#7.4b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>"The Last Rose Of Summer"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immel</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of the purchase of the Manny Reaper by Col. D. O. Gehr and that he
                    will find he did not get a deal. Apparent competition between two reaper
                    machines--the Manny and the McCormick--the machines will compete in C. W.
                    Eyster's field, and then in G. W. Immel's field. Mr. Hurst is the agent for the
                    Manny and S. Brandt the agent for the McCormick machine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Hail Storm</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latchaw</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stine</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A hailstorm near Greencastle seriously damaged the wheat and corn crops--
                    Messrs. Latchaw, Carr and Stine sustained some of the greatest losses due to the
                    storm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Young Astronomer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>Jason Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jason Andrew Davidson, son of Andrew Davidson Esq. of Antrim township,
                    discovered a comet in the northwest evening sky on June 29th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Able Effort</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. B. Sharpe, Esq. of Carlisle, whose name (along with Col. D.O. Gehr's
                    name) is on the Republican electoral ticket, was visiting his cousin J. McDowell
                    Sharpe. He attended the Lincoln club and was asked to give a speech--which
                    lasted an hour and received high praise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Installation Services</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmucker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krauth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 8th at the Lutheran church, Rev. Dr. Schmucker will preach and Rev.
                    J. Steck will be installed by Rev. Dr. Krauth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Fruit And Nurseries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A call to plant profitable fruit orchards in the Franklin county area. Note
                    of Mr. Rider, near Loudon, has planted such a nursery, but it is too far from a
                    town to be easily accessible. It is suggested that Jacob Heyser, who recently
                    established a nursery of trees and shrubbery near Chambersburg, expand his
                    business to include fruit trees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.04.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Comet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Clark explains that the comet was visible on June 22nd, and, due to
                    cloudiness, then again on the 29th and 30th. He suggest that it may be the same
                    comet seen in 1847, that was predicted to return in 1859 or 1860.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bate's Letter In Support Of Abraham Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"And as to his views about 'the pestilential negro question,' I am not
                    aware that he has gone one step beyond the doctrine publicly and habitually
                    avowed by the great lights of the Whig party, Clay, Webster, and their fellows,
                    and indeed sustained and carried out by the democrats themselves, in their wiser
                    and better days."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter written by Edward Bates who did not win the Republican nomination,
                    but whole-heartedly supports Lincoln and Hamlin. He criticizes the democrats'
                    abuses of power and recklessness, and praises the merits of Lincoln, whom he has
                    known for twenty years, and lists Lincoln's stance on the slavery issue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.04.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Literary Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Note of the weekly publication, Scientific American, of its useful coverage
                    of improvements in various machinery, and that it is the inventor's advocate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Women And Weddings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>a humorous observation of women's fascination with weddings, their
                    criticisms and commentary of other people's ceremony</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>various short, general, humorous or informative articles;
            advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1860.07.04.07">
            <pageNote>Republican platform; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1861.0.00.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin>Valley Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huntsberger</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>North</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Doctor</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Jonas Huntsberger, of Chambersburg, was kicked by a horse of Mr. Wm.
                    North. Dr. Robinson treated the minor injury inflicted on Huntsberger's left.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin>Valley Star</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryson</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>While working on Mr. T. B. Bryson's house, several miles from
                    Mechanicsburg, a board fell on the head and shoulder of Samuel Sollenberger, of
                    Mechanicsburg, and broke his collar bone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Busey</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cramblitt</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerns</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupley</ln>
                        <fn>F. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Friese</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Doctor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reichstine</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peed</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Henry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Solleberger</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Baltimore on June 12th, The Rev. E. F. Busey married Geo. H. Cramblitt
                    to Miss Anna Gerns, formerly of Chambersburg. In Shippensburg on June 21st, Rev.
                    F. A. Rupley married Dr. Michael Friese, of Mechanicsburg, to Mararet A.
                    Reichstine, of Shippensburg. On June 21st, Rev. William Owen married John H.
                    Peed to Susan Guyer, both of Franklin County. On June 28th, Rev. S. M'Henry
                    married Samuel Martin to Elizabeth Solleberger, both of Hamilton township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Ruth S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Doctor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebok</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grafton</ln>
                        <fn>Wilhelmina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heart</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 3rd in Rossville, Indiana, Mrs. Ruth Thompson, wife of William J.
                    Thompson, formerly of Roxbury, Franklin county, died of Typhoid Fever at age 58.
                    On June 25th, at the home of Mr. Henry Rebok in Hamilton township, Miss
                    Wilhelmina Grafton died at age 19. On June 26th in Chambersburg, Mrs. Elizabeth
                    Green, widow of John Green, died at age 78. On July 1st in Chambersburg, Jacob
                    Heart, Jr., died at age 32.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements; a letter from China; note of boy devoured by a bear</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
