<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.03.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/14/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm=""/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.03.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.03.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Organization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The organization under the new constitution is very simple and more complete
                        and effective than under the old system. In the first place the qualified
                        voters of the county elect a sheriff, an attorney for the Commonwealth, who
                        represents the State both in the County and Circuit Courts; a county clerk,
                        who discharges also the duties of the Circuit Court clerk, except where the
                        population of the county is fifteen thousand, then there will be an
                        additional clerk for the Circuit Court, a county treasurer and one
                        superintendent of the poor. In addition to the above county officers, the
                        Board of Education, composed of the Governor, Superintendent of Public
                        Instruction and the Attorney General shall appoint one superintendent of
                        schools, subject to the confirmation of the Senate, unless the county
                        contains less than eight thousand inhabitants, and then it will be necessary
                        to attach it to another county to form districts for superintendents for
                        public schools, and if a county contains thirty thousand inhabitants, an
                        additional superintendent of schools will be appointed.</p>
                    <p>All officers must be elected on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in
                        November, and enter upon their offices the first day of next January -- and
                        shall hold their offices for three years, except the county and circuit
                        clerks, who shall hold their offices for four years.</p>
                    <p>In addition to the officers enumerated as county officers, the supervisors of
                        townships shall constitute a Board of Supervisors for the county, which
                        shall meet at the Court House on the first Monday of December of each year,
                        and audit the accounts of the county, examine the books of the assessors,
                        regulate and equalize the valuation of property, fix the county levy for the
                        ensuing year and apportion the same among the different townships. We
                        believe we have enumerated all the county officers except one, which is by
                        far the most important, and that is the county judge, which officer is
                        elected by a joint vote of both Houses of the General Assembly and whose
                        necessary qualification is to be "learned in the law," and whose
                        jurisdiction shall be the same as County Courts under our old system, except
                        as modified by the county organization clause, and which we have noted
                        above, and as may be changed by law. A county judge is to hold his office
                        for six years, except under the first election they should hold their office
                        for only three years. If a county contains less than eight thousand
                        inhabitants it must be attached to another county in order to have a county
                        judge. Within the county organization is an inferior division with a
                        complete set of officers, known as</p>
                    <p>TOWNSHIPS. -- Each county shall be divided into compact townships of not less
                        than three, each of which shall be named, and sue and be sued in that name.
                        These townships answer to our former divisions or districts but with more
                        distinctive features. In each township, there shall be elected annually one
                        Supervisor; one Township Clerk; one Assessor; one Collector; one
                        Commissioner of Roads; one Overseer of the Poor; one Justice of the Peace,
                        who shall hold his office three years; one Constable, who shall hold his
                        office three years; Provided, That at the first election held under this
                        provision there shall be three Justices of the Peace and three Constables
                        elected, whose terms shall be one, two and three years, respectively. All
                        regular elections for township officers shall take place on the fourth
                        Thursday in May, and all officers so elected shall enter upon the duties of
                        their respective offices on the first day of July next succeeding their
                        election. Then, again, each township shall be divided into</p>
                    <p>SCHOOL DISTRICTS. -- Every school district must contain one hundred
                        inhabitants, but may be divided as it seems necessary. In each of these
                        districts there will be elected annually one School Trustee, who shall hold
                        his office for three years, except at the first election, when there shall
                        be three elected and hold office for one, two, and three years respectively.
                        Again, these townships are divided into</p>
                    <p>ROAD DISTRICTS. -- There shall be one or more in each township, and one
                        Overseer of Roads shall be elected annually, who shall keep the roads in
                        repair in the manner to be provided for by law.</p>
                    <p>The General Assembly is clothed with the power by the Constitution providing
                        by law for any additional officers. -- <emph rend="italic">Virginia
                        Advance.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Virginia Advance explained the organization of county officers under
                    the new state Constitution. Each county is divided into townships, road
                    districts, and school districts. In addition, the article listed various court
                    officials assigned to each county and the term limits for these offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.03.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sixteen persons joined Staunton Presbyterian Church on Sunday. William E.
                    Baker is the pastor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Harris, son of Dr. C. R. Harris of Staunton, graduated from the
                    University of Maryland Medical School.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Charles F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Samanthia E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles F. Fisher of Augusta and Miss Samanthia E. Harris of Nelson were
                    married on February 22nd by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaver</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob H. Shaver of Rockbridge and Miss Annie E. Coiner of Augusta were
                    married on February 24th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Follansbee</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah W. Hall and Miss Elizabeth H. Blakemore, both of Augusta, were
                    married in Mt. Solon on February 24th by the Rev. James M. Follansbee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Row</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Row, postmistress at Moffet's Creek, died at her residence on
                    March 2nd. She was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Jane S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hattie Jane Harlan, daughter of George and Jane S. Harlan, died in Staunton
                    on March 2nd after a protracted illness. She was 15 years old. A prayer
                    accompanied the notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Fuller died near Waynesboro at the residence of her
                    son-in-law, J. S. Ellis, on February 14th. She was 77 years old. "Thus has
                    passed away one of the purest and best of God's saints--one of the brightest
                    ornaments of the Church of Christ."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.03.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
