<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.08.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/22/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="09"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.09.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Grand Tournament and Fancy Ball at Stribling Springs, Wednesday, Aug. 17</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Knights of Augusta challenged the Knights of Rockingham "to a friendly
                    contest of skill" at the tournament at Stribling Springs. The winner will have
                    the right to crown a queen of love and beauty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>To the People of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Conservative members of the Legislature have in conference resolved that
                        the organization of the Conservative party, maintained during the last
                        gubernatorial canvass, be revived and perfected for action in the
                        approaching fall elections, and to that end have constituted "The Central
                        Executive Committee of the State of Virginia" to continue in office until
                        superseded by a regular convention of the people. In assuming its
                        responsible duties, the committee deems the occasion suitable for some brief
                        reflections on the conditions and future prospects of the Conservative
                        party.</p>
                    <p>In the chart laid down for the committee it will be seen that no new
                        political combinations are conceived, nor is any new political policy
                        avowed. We only resume the work of the Conservative organization as it was
                        in 1869, and seek to perfect it. We aim to perpetuate the triumphs of that
                        year; to consolidate the strength then acquired; to secure in the hands
                        which then won, and now hold it, the political power of the State.</p>
                    <p>In a conjuncture like this it may be of use to review the past and draw from
                        it, as we may, encouragement and hope for the future. The opening days of
                        the past year were heavy indeed for our beloved State. Thick gloom covered
                        her like the pall thrown over the dead. Turn where the eye would, "darkness
                        was on the face of the deep." Military power was supreme. Her Government had
                        been stricken from existence, and by the blow, as by the shock of paralysis,
                        her very animation seemed suspended. Her sovereignty, which for centuries
                        had bound up in auspicious union the blessings of freedom, law and order,
                        had been suffered to pass into a new body politic -- her former slaves,
                        allied with a set of wretched adventurers, seeking profit from their
                        ignorance and suggested crimes. A convention, sprung from this source, and
                        fitly representing it, had decreed the political slavery of the mass of her
                        white population. Taxation secured in such hands would have been organized
                        robbery, and Government itself a standing conspiracy against the public
                        peace. Civil law, which for a time had been permitted to speak with bated
                        breath, was now wholly silenced. -- All the officers of the State, elected
                        or appointed by the will of the people, went out of their offices at a fixed
                        day, and the people were thus left without law, because without officers to
                        execute the law. Power seemed to have passed beyond recall into the new
                        dispensation, which, defiant and secure in organized strength, stood ready
                        to inflict on its old possessors, divided in council and almost apathetic
                        from despair, the fate, of all most intolerable, to live in slavery to their
                        former slaves. Anarchy or the bayonet seemed the only alternatives to the
                        threatened iniquity.</p>
                    <p>But with the incoming of a new Administration a new policy towards the States
                        then excluded from the Union and lying under military restraint, was
                        shadowed forth. General Grant had already declared the opinion, that these
                        States were entitled to be restored to civil government and to readmission
                        into the Union.-- His special and first message to Congress held out the
                        first sign of conciliation -- the first olive branch, over the yet
                        unsubsided waters of civil strife. It recognized the political
                        enfranchisement of the negro (now an accomplished fact in all the States,)
                        but to the whites was yielded the opportunity to secure for themselves the
                        control of the State forever -- the power to levy and expend revenues, to
                        provide for it wholesome laws, to develop its resources, to change, if so
                        advised, its organic law, and in all respects to shape its future; added to
                        which would be readmission into the Union and escape from the bayonet, the
                            <emph rend="italic">carpet-bag</emph>, the League!</p>
                    <p>A Convention of the members of the Conservative organization assembled in
                        April, 1869, under these novel circumstances, greatly changed from those
                        which attended the original delegation of its power. The notable
                        characteristics of its action, was its total abnegation of authority to
                        decide upon the new and momentous questions which confronted it. The
                        Convention felt that it no longer represented the sentiment of unconditional
                        opposition to the Constitution, for it could not be blind to the growing
                        inclination of the popular mind to accept it in its proposed altered form.
                        It was acknowledged that a new political departure must be taken; that the
                        people in their original capacity must be consulted on the issues now for
                        the first time presented. Never was there a popular appeal, with which old
                        parties and party questions and names had so little to do. It was the
                        uprising of a <emph rend="italic">race</emph> for its own redemption. Of
                        this movement the ruling conservatism of to-day was born. Sprung from that
                        race, it exists by its <emph rend="italic">fiat</emph>, and embodies its
                        expressed will.</p>
                    <p>It is inseparable, perhaps, from the human disposition to overrate the evils
                        of the present, which are sensible and felt, compared with those which are
                        past, and of which the memory has become obscured. No revolution, however
                        successful, ever brought with it the unmixed good, which in the ardor of
                        hope it was expected to achieve. The triumph of Conservatism in Virginia is
                        no exception to the general law. It has not, in some unexplained way,
                        relieved the people from the pressure of debt, nor repaired as by miracle
                        the desolations of war. It has not, unaided, built up our railroads and
                        canals, nor developed the hidden wealth of the field, the forest, and the
                        mine. Hercules, as of yore, will aid only those who put the shoulder to the
                        wheel. But we were strangely insensible not to acknowledge such blessings as
                        the restoration of civil law in the place of irresponsible military power;
                        the pure and equal administration of justice by judges of our own choosing;
                        the enactment of laws and their enforcement by a Legislature and an
                        Executive, freely elected; in a word, the autonomy of a self-governing
                        people. Were incentives wanting to value such advantages at their proper
                        worth, we need only survey the condition of those unhappy States which, in
                        their struggles with Radicalism, have been less fortunate in throwing off
                        the incubus of that gross and truculent domination. The story of one of
                        these is the story of all. Vice, ignorance, and corruption usurp the State.
                        Adventurers, sordid and shameless, whom, in great part, their crimes have
                        expelled from other communities, with the aid of an inferior race seduced
                        and debauched by their teaching and example, exercise authority which is
                        without a show of common interest with the Commonwealths they assume to
                        rule. Public credit gone; public debt heaped mountain high; taxation
                        inordinate and insupportable; profligate waste of public money; liberty,
                        property, life, insecure; systematic libel and detraction, designed to
                        provoke the commission of crimes, that they may be profitably punished;
                        popular elections suppressed by fraud, chicane, or force; persistent
                        misrepresentations at Washington of the wishes and purposes of the people,
                        that they may be kept or brought again under military rule; such, with
                        little variation, are the incidents which have marked their experience for
                        five weary years! In North Carolina, as is well known, the government of the
                        State is in Radical hands, and there the Government is this moment engaged
                        in an effort to prolong its power, by stifling and overawing the voice of
                        the people in a State election, which, left free, would pronounce its doom.
                        "The State judicial power," it is proclaimed, "though in the hands of
                        energetic, learned, and upright men, has not been able to bring criminals to
                        justice;" and upon that false and shameless pretense whole counties are
                        declared to be in a state of "<emph rend="italic">insurrection</emph>", and
                        are overrun by military violence -- thus confounding all the inhabitants,
                        men, women, and children, in one indiscriminate and lawless proscription.
                            <emph rend="italic">Habeas corpus</emph> is stricken down in the teeth
                        of the Constitution, and a ruffian Governor and corrupt Judge collude to
                        deny its benefits to the people. We feel for these, our unhappy brethren,
                        with all our hearts. We pray God to hold up their hands in the contest with
                        their terrible enemy. But let us also lay the warning to heart. What better
                        or worse would have been the condition of this Virginia people, had
                        Conservatism failed in the great struggle in which their all was imperilled,
                        and what fate is now in reserve for them should its efforts be relaxed?</p>
                    <p>In reviewing our situation, as it was and as it is, simple justice requires
                        us to acknowledge our obligation to the Executive and Legislature of our
                        choice, for the capacity, integrity, and zeal, with which they have
                        discharged their arduous and responsible duties. Rarely have public
                        representatives been placed in situations so novel and difficult. Theirs was
                        not the common, easy route through ways made smooth before them by precedent
                        and routine, but rather the rough course of the woodman, who, axe in hand,
                        blazes his way through the trackless, unbroken forest. Society itself had
                        been disrupted; political institutions subverted; and every want and
                        interest of the community called for the exercise of wise and careful
                        statesmanship. In the ordeal through which the State passed again into the
                        Union (involving the attempted exaction of the test-oath from the
                        Legislature,) in resisting the re-assertion of military authority in the
                        organization of government, under the enabling act -- in prudent and
                        sagacious recommendations to the Legislature, and sound views of State
                        policy; in the just and constitutional construction of the novel power of
                        the veto; the humane yet firm and considerate exercise of the power of
                        pardon, as in the general administration of office, the Executive has fully
                        met the expectations and redeemed the confidence of those who placed him in
                        power. In the composition of the Legislature, the prevailing political
                        disqualifications so narrowed the sphere of selection, that there was
                        necessarily many members who were young or untried in the forms and
                        functions of legislation. But they quickly mastered the difficulties of
                        their situation. Zeal, energy, and conscientiousness marked their
                        deliberations; in which some, before unknown in public life, shone with
                        ability such as promises high distinction and usefulness in the future
                        councils of the State. To say that in dealing with subjects so deeply
                        involving conflicting interests and passions, they have done everything that
                        is pleasing, and nothing that dissatisfies, is simply to affirm
                        <sic>and</sic> impossibility -- what never occurred in the proceeding of any
                        such council in the world. But let all that has been done, and the
                        difficulties of doing it, be fairly and candidly estimated, and then let
                        those who know they could have done better cast the stone of censure. Upon
                        the Legislature of 1852 was devolved the legislation made necessary by the
                        adoption of a new Constitution for the State. It sat from the 12th of
                        January to the 7th of June following, and then took a recess to the 22d of
                        November following. When it reassembled it was congratulated by the
                        Executive upon returning to its labors "refreshed by a few months of
                        recreation, and after a full and fair interchange of opinion with its
                        constituents," it sat thenceforward until the 11th of April following, being
                        about six months for its first session and five months for its second. The
                        present Legislature, under circumstances far more difficult, began its
                        working session on the 7th of February, and took its recess on the 11th of
                        July. Of these five months several weeks were necessarily consumed in the
                        election of judges. In the short remaining time, there was crowded an amount
                        of important legislation which justly wins for it the merits of being a
                        working body.</p>
                    <p>Charged with the duty of promoting the efficiency of our organization, we
                        warn you earnestly that what we have achieved by such arduous labor must be
                        maintained by equally enduring and persistent effort; and the common but
                        fatal delusion must be avoided of underrating the vigor and resources of a
                        beaten adversary; for the Radical party was beaten, not conquered last year.
                        We have "scotched the snake, not killed it." Figures show (in round numbers)
                        that of the 101,000 votes cast for Wells for Governor, 97,000 were colored
                        vote, solidly cast, leaving about 5,000 whites as the "Republican party,"
                        so-called; for the poor negroes were the "<emph rend="italic">inpaid
                        capital</emph>" with which they boasted they would begin the canvass, and
                        with which they hoped to disfranchise and despoil the white population of
                        the State. And the calculation is still the same. The scheme will be quietly
                        pursued in every county, town, and township, to organize this vote, and cast
                        it in compact mass in the elections. But inroads upon the Conservative
                        majority of 18,000 are expected to be made in several ways: interested
                        conversions will be counted on; fallings off from the relaxation effort
                        following on success; the revival of distinctive party names and party
                        prejudices; and most potent influence of all <emph rend="italic"
                            >distractions and rivalries arising from competitions for office!</emph>
                        These last have ever been the bane of successful parties. Last year
                        principle united, and no selfish interests divided the Conservatives. Now,
                        numerous offices are to be bestowed, and doubtless the competition for them
                        among an impoverished people will be excited and keen. The conference
                        recommends that suitable nominations be made for all these offices -- county
                        clerks, attorneys, sheriffs, treasurers, tax-collectors, superintendents of
                        the poor. These are most important offices, and to fill them properly is of
                        the highest public and private concern. There are other offices of higher
                        authority and more imposing names, but these come closer to man's business
                        and bosoms, and affect more nearly the happiness and comfort of individual
                        life. Let these nominations be made, in all cases, by the organized,
                        accredited action of the party in each locality; and when made, let them
                        receive the unreserved and active support of all. In no case should more
                        than one Conservative candidate for an office be allowed. By the opposite
                        course, divisions will lead to defeat, or by making the adversary the
                        arbitor of our dissensions, will lead to the obliteration of party lines and
                        the ultimate destruction of Conservatism itself. How humbling the spectacle
                        of a people, fresh from successful defence of their altars and firesides,
                        who should spend in ignoble contests among themselves the energy necessary
                        for the defeat of the common enemy.</p>
                    <p>It is further recommended by the conference that suitable nominations be made
                        for representatives of the State in Congress. These cannot be made, with
                        accurate reference to territory, until by redistricting the State, the gross
                        inequalities of the present arrangement shall be redressed. But attention
                        will naturally be directed to such men as will worthily represent the State.
                        Virginia owed her former weight in the councils of the country to the
                        disinterested patriotism and exalted character, no less than the political
                        ability, which distinguished her representatives. By no other means, can any
                        share of that influence be regained. With such aid, the favorable regard of
                        Congress may be asked to the relief of the South by a more just and
                        equitable distribution of the national currency; the relief of the great
                        staple, tobacco, from ruinous specific taxation and those galling and
                        oppressing restrictions which depress and deter the fair dealer, while they
                        tempt the unfair to fraudulent evasion; money appropriations for the
                        internal improvements of the State, bringing them in connection with the
                        great trans-continental lines of communication, and an equal share in all
                        the benefits of general legislation for the Union.</p>
                    <p>Thus have we discharged the representative duty of recommending for Virginia
                        a <emph rend="italic">State</emph> policy free from outside influence or
                        intervention, the prime condition of which is the <emph rend="italic"
                            >conservation</emph> of the power of the State in conservative hands,
                        and between which and social anarchy and misrule we discern no alternative;
                        a policy of peaceful restoration, and development of the internal resources
                        of the State, as the best security for her present well-being and future
                        weight and influence; a policy in which the States of the South have been
                        instructed by common interests, suffering, and danger; which, at a juncture
                        ominous of political change, guards and provides for the present, but
                        reserves the power of decision in the future formation and movements of
                        national parties.</p>
                    <p>R.T. DANIEL,</p>
                    <p>THOS. BRANCH,</p>
                    <p>JAMES NELSON,</p>
                    <p>ALBERT ORDWAY,</p>
                    <p>H. H. MARSHALL,</p>
                    <p>M. L. STRAUSS,</p>
                    <p>P. T. MOORE,</p>
                    <p>JAMES R. FISHER,</p>
                    <p>A. M. KEILEY,</p>
                    <p>WILLIAM H. PALMER,</p>
                    <p>T. W. MCCANCE,</p>
                    <p>Committee,</p>
                    <p>RICHMOND, August 4, 1870.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Leaders of the Conservative party sent out a circular announcing the
                    organization of an executive committee to prepare for the autumn elections. They
                    want to rally all Conservative men in order to maintain Conservative control of
                    the state government. Described the ills suffered by other southern states under
                    the Radicals and urged Virginians not risk such a scenario by quibbling for
                    offices. Called on all Conservatives for unity to keep their own party in power
                    and resist Radical control.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Board of Education appointed Maj. Jed Hotchkiss Superintendent of
                    Augusta Schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Downey will open an English and classical school for boys in his home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawrence</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper called attention to Deerfield School in Augusta County, run by
                    Prof. S. A. Harris and Miss Virginia Lawrence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The election which occurred in this county, on Saturday last, on the question
                        of subscribing $300,000 to the stock of the Valley R. R. Company was
                        defeated, as the required three-fifths majority was not obtained. The defeat
                        of the subscription is due chiefly, as was apprehended, to the fact that the
                        Shenandoah Valley R. R. Company succeeded in making the impression in the
                        Eastern portion of the county that their road will be constructed through
                        that portion of the county without cost.</p>
                    <p>We regret, on many accounts, the defeat of the subscription, but do not
                        despair yet of having the Valley R. R. built.</p>
                    <p>We have faith that some means will be adopted which will ensure the
                        construction of this road. It is too important an improvement to fail of
                        being constructed. The following is the vote:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>PRECINCTS.</cell>
                            <cell>FOR SUB.</cell>
                            <cell>AG'ST SUB.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Staunton No. 1,</cell>
                            <cell>304</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Staunton No. 2,</cell>
                            <cell>305</cell>
                            <cell>48</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Beverly Manor Township.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sandy Hollow,</cell>
                            <cell>129</cell>
                            <cell>27</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peaco's Mill</cell>
                            <cell>19</cell>
                            <cell>25</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bolivar,</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                            <cell>14</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Folly Mills,</cell>
                            <cell>25</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hebron,</cell>
                            <cell>109</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">River Heads Township.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Middlebrook,</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                            <cell>89</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Port,</cell>
                            <cell>43</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Midway,</cell>
                            <cell>44</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenville,</cell>
                            <cell>159</cell>
                            <cell>63</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">The Pastures Township.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Churchville,</cell>
                            <cell>54</cell>
                            <cell>64</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Buffalo Gap,</cell>
                            <cell>79</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Craigsville,</cell>
                            <cell>29</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Deerfield,</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lebanon W. Sulphur</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell>12</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">South River Township.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Barterbrook,</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>41</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sherando,</cell>
                            <cell>54</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Waynesboro,</cell>
                            <cell>89</cell>
                            <cell>231</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fisherville,</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>76</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Middle River Township.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Sidney,</cell>
                            <cell>91</cell>
                            <cell>132</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Meridian,</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>96</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Hope,</cell>
                            <cell>25</cell>
                            <cell>203</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Red Mills,</cell>
                            <cell>0</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Verona,</cell>
                            <cell>39</cell>
                            <cell>13</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">North River Township.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Parnassus</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                            <cell>89</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Spring Hill,</cell>
                            <cell>53</cell>
                            <cell>81</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Solon,</cell>
                            <cell>42</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Centreville,</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                            <cell>56</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sangersville,</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                            <cell>57</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>1983</cell>
                            <cell>1760</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The total vote being 3,743, it required 2,246 votes to be cast in the
                        affir----mative to carry this subscription; and as there were but 1,983
                        affirmative votes cast, the subscription failed to be carried by 263
                    votes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announced the defeat of the Valley Railroad subscription and printed the
                    results of the vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.08.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
