<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.04.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm=""/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.19.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.19.02" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>WAYNESBORO', April 13th, 1870.</p>
                    <p>I wish to ask two or three questions in regard to the vote to be taken in
                        this County on the 28th inst., for $300,000 to aid in making the Valley
                        Railroad.</p>
                    <p>1st. What majority is requisite to carry the subscription? Will it require
                        simply a majority vote, or will it not require a two-thirds vote to carry
                        the subscription?</p>
                    <p>2nd. How, or upon what property will the tax for the $300,000 be levied? Will
                        it be upon all persons and property, or only upon real estate?</p>
                    <p>3rd. Who are entitled to vote on this subscription? Will those only who are
                        not disqualified by the 14th Amendment, or those who pay the tax, or all?</p>
                    <p>Be kind enough to answer these questions for the information of many in and
                        around</p>
                    <p>WAYNESBORO';</p>
                    <p>By way of answer to our correspondent, we say that since the order of the
                        County Court directing the vote to be taken, it has been ascertained that,
                        under existing laws and owing to the change in the County Court system, new
                        legislation may be necessary in order that the sense of the people may be
                        properly taken on the subject of the subscription, and that, therefore, the
                        vote must necessarily be postponed. -- We presume that the tax will be
                        assessed on <emph rend="italic">all</emph> property, and that therefore all
                        legal voters will be entitled to vote. That was the case under the old law,
                        and we presume it will be the same under the new. We will, however, publish
                        the act for the information of our readers when it is passed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Waynesboro'" asked a series of questions on the subscription to the Valley
                    Railroad. The Spectator answered Waynesboro's questions and announced that the
                    vote has been postponed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad and Mike</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Or rather Mike and the Valley Rail Road, for it will hardly be denied but for
                        Mike the Road would be a thing so far in the future as to attract very
                        little attention at this time. -- But superior foresight coupled with
                        unremitting energy and perseverance presents the scheme for the present so
                        necessary, so easy and so certain, that we feel sure the intelligent voters
                        of Augusta will support it almost without division. There are persons
                        however in the county with an eye single to their own advantage, who will
                        not support the Road unless it is to be made through their immediate
                        section. They will admit the general importance of the work, but, if they
                        are not certainly to receive the most benefit, why then they are opposed to
                        it. The tax necessary, if it shall be made their route is a very small
                        matter, and the county should pay it cheerfully. A child sometimes refuses
                        to take bread because it cannot have the largest piece with the most butter
                        on it, but such conduct from grown men is hardly excusable. It is true that
                        an individual should guard his own interests with zealous care, but it is
                        equally true that, whatever contributes to the general good confers
                        corresponding benefit upon the individual. The desire to have the largest
                        piece or the most benefit, is both natural and laudable, but to make it a
                        condition precedent, is we think absolutely wrong.</p>
                    <p>It is said that only those who pay the tax should vote, and there are voters
                        influenced by the argument. Of all the arguments in opposition, this is
                        seemingly the most plausible -- the most reasonable, but when examined by
                        the experience of the past and the light of the present, none will be found
                        so worthless, so hideously erroneous. Apply it effectually to all those
                        secular affairs in the creation of which the laboring man and the mechanic
                        do not contribute directly, and the meanest despotism is hard by. The time
                        was, and it was a long time when the people had no vote or say, in the
                        affairs of the world, because they were slaves -- because they were not
                        taxed or because they were not "lords to the manor born." And you may to-day
                        track that time by its bloody foot prints.</p>
                    <p>But in the case before us it is enough for the laboring man and the mechanic
                        to know that the law gives them the right to vote. Do not let your employees
                        keep you from the polls by telling you you are voting against their
                        interests. Baldwin, Stuart, Sheffey, and many other competent gentlemen tell
                        us that it is in the interest of all to vote for the subscription.</p>
                    <p>NEXT TIME.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Next time" wrote to the Spectator in favor of the Valley Rail Road
                    subscription. He chided those who would vote against the railroad simply because
                    they do not gain as much from it as their neighbors. Also argued against those
                    who will not vote because they would not pay the tax if the subscription was
                    passed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.19.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The State Council of the Friends of Temperance will meet in Waynesboro on
                    Tuesday. Encourages subordinate delegations to attend as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture at the Baptist Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. John W. Jones delivered an address on "Religion in the Army of
                    Northern Virginia" to a small audience. The editors praised the lecture and
                    lamented the sparse attendance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Commissioners of the Revenue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William F. Taylor, auditor of Public Accounts, appointed John Towberman and
                    John G. Stover Commissioners of the Revenue for Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The superintendent of Staunton's Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution went
                    before a committee of the General Assembly to plead for the importance of
                    funding his school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemmer</ln>
                        <fn>J. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>S. Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Henry Clemmer and Miss S. Jennie Snider, daughter of Adam Snider, all of
                    Augusta, were married on March 24th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rivercomb</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Follansbee</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Rivercomb of California and formerly of Augusta and Miss Mary Jane
                    Blakemore of Augusta were married in Mt. Solon on April 7th by the Rev. James M.
                    Follansbee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colhoun</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Catharine Colhoun died at Glen Allen, Augusta County, at the late
                    residence of her brother-in-law, Gen. Kenton Harper, on March 27th. She was 76
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Willie Welch</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Welch Bumgardner, infant son of Capt. James and Mollie Bumgardner,
                    died near Staunton on April 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn>Justis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Justis George died at his residence near Waynesboro on April 8th. He was 78
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazel</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garner</ln>
                        <fn>David P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Ann Hazel, daughter of David P. Garner, died near Sherando on
                    April 8th after suffering an illness of 12 hours. She was 17 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Henry T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry T. Sheets, son of Benjamin E. and Mary A. Sheets, died in Spring Hill
                    on March 11th. He was 2 years old. "Little Henry was a very interesting
                    child--the darling of the rest of the family. O, how he is missed at home!" A
                    poem of mourning accompanied the notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.04.19.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
