<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.12.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="20"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.12.20.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter which alerted the Spectator to an article in a Texas newspaper
                    praising Capt. James Boyd, a young district attorney in that state. Boyd, a
                    veteran of the 25th Virginia Infantry, left Augusta County after the war and
                    studied law in Texas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.12.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Future of our County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the last forty years the people of our county have been indulging in
                        bright dreams of a better day that was to come to them, in a material point
                        of view. Like the children of Israel during their forty years of sojourn in
                        the wilderness, they never lost hope. Disappointment after disappointment
                        followed each other, but they continued to cherish a lively hope that, at
                        some future day, the great highways of commerce and travel -- those fruitful
                        sources of wealth and prosperity -- would eventually be made through the
                        central portions of our county. Thanks to a kind Providence and the
                        intelligent enterprise of our people, we are now on the eve of having our
                        wishes, in this respect, fulfilled. Like the Israelites of old, we now stand
                        on the banks of the Jordan and have a glimpse of the promised land.</p>
                    <p>The report of Mr. Huntingdon to the recent meeting of the Stockholders of the
                        Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Rail Road gives the most satisfactory assurance of
                        the completion of that great work within two years. It would be aside from
                        the immediate purposes of this article for us here to dwell on the many
                        advantages which will accrue to our people from this important channel of
                        trade and travel. We cannot forbear however from remarking, that its
                        completion will be followed by the establishment of many Furnaces and
                        Foundries between Staunton and Covington, and the development of a traffic
                        in iron and coal, which will surpass the expectations of the most sanguine.</p>
                    <p>This road will ultimately be the Eastern link in the great chain of
                        communication between the navigable waters of the Atlantic and Pacific
                        Oceans. Richmond and San Francisco are on nearly the same parallel of
                        latitude, and a line drawn along the great circle which indicates the line
                        of latitude from East to West between those two cities, will nearly coincide
                        with the line of our Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Road and its extension
                        Westward. This fact proves, conclusively, that our great line of
                        communication from East to West, is the shortest possible route, and,
                        therefore, that it cannot be superseded, or materially interfered with by
                        any other line. These facts assure us that we shall always be on the great
                        highway between the East and the West, and enjoy the benefits of the trade
                        and travel between the East and the West, which will seek the most
                        convenient transit by that route.</p>
                    <p>This being accomplished, the next thing we desire is, a similar great
                        thoroughfare, passing through our borders from North to South, thus securing
                        the advantages of commercial intercourse through our county, between the
                        Northern and Southern divisions of our country.</p>
                    <p>In looking for the natural and most advantageous route for such a national
                        thoroughfare, we have only to take the map, and draw a line from Washington
                        city, or any of the commercial cities North of Washington, to New Orleans,
                        and we will find that the line will pass, lengthwise, along the Valley of
                        Virginia, from Winchester through the county of Augusta to Salem, where it
                        connects with the Lynchburg and Tennessee R. R., and thence Southwardly to
                        New Orleans. It thus appears, that nature has marked out the Valley of
                        Virginia as presenting the best and shortest line for a railway from Boston,
                        New York, Philadelphia, Baltimore and Washington, to New Orleans, which is
                        recognized on all hands as the proper Southern terminus of such a line.</p>
                    <p>Now, by singular good fortune, it so happens, that the point of intersection
                        of the two great thoroughfares, from East to West and from North to South,
                        must be in the county of Augusta, and at or near her county town --
                        Staunton. When, therefore, these two lines shall have been finished, we will
                        be at the central point, from which Railroads will radiate to the four
                        cardinal points of the compass. Eastward we will have a look-out along an
                        unbroken line of railway to Richmond and Norfolk -- Westward, to San
                        Francisco -- Northward, to Portland, Maine, and Southward to New Orleans.
                        Was any county ever so peculiarly favored by Providence.</p>
                    <p>It would be a waste of time to dwell on the manifold advantages which result
                        from such a conjunction of Railroads, and the transmit and exchange of
                            <sic>merchandize</sic> and passengers along the various routes. The city
                        of Atlanta in Georgia -- the offspring of converging local roads --
                        furnishes an illustration stronger than any words could afford, of the
                        vivifying effects which such a combination of influences tends to produce.</p>
                    <p>Now, if the junction of two or three <emph rend="italic">local</emph> roads
                        at Atlanta could cause a city of fifteen or twenty thousand inhabitants to
                        spring up like magic in the sandy plains of Georgia, what may we not expect
                        from the coming together of the two most important national thoroughfares on
                        our continent, in a county so fertile -- so healthful! -- so picturesque,
                        and in all respects so desirable as Augusta?</p>
                    <p>We forbear from enlarging on this topic, for fear that we may be deemed
                        enthusiasts -- but we will, in passing, venture the prediction that within
                        ten years from the completion of these roads, the population and the
                        property of Staunton will be doubled, and that the wealth of the county will
                        be augmented in a corresponding ratio.</p>
                    <p>The realization of all these brilliant prospects now rests with the people of
                        Augusta. -- We venture to affirm, that if they will vote the $200,000
                        subscription, which is now asked from them to secure the three millions
                        which is dependent on their decision, the great Northern and Southern line
                        will be finished contemporaneously with the Eastern and Western line. The
                        benefits of the enterprise rest not in the remote future. They will be
                        enjoyed within the next two years. And in the meantime the incidental
                        advantages resulting from the lavish expenditures of money in the
                        construction of the road will give to our farmers a pleasing foretaste of
                        what they are to enjoy after the road is finished, and the current of trade
                        and travel has begun to flow along the lines.</p>
                    <p>Shall this rich harvest of prosperity be gathered by our people? It is for
                        them, by their votes, to determine.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editor urged Augusta voters to vote in favor of a $200,000 subscription for
                    the completion of two railroads. Painted a glowing picture of immense trade and
                    wealth flowing through Staunton from all sections of the country within two
                    years if the railroads were financed and completed. All these possibilities
                    rested in the hands of the citizens of Augusta and Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Conservative Party--Its Shibboleth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Just three years ago, the representatives of all shades of political
                        sentiment in this State in opposition to Radicalism met in Convention in
                        Richmond, and there, on that occasion, formally organized the Conservative
                        party, which since then has been, and is yet, the <emph rend="italic">only
                            organized party in this State in opposition to the Radical or Republican
                            party.</emph> Those who were before the war classified as Whigs and
                        Democrats respectively were about equal in number in that part of the State
                        which remained as "Virginia" after the dismemberment of the State -- there
                        being, we believe, a small majority of Whigs. The Conservative party
                        embraced alike both Democrats and Whigs who were opposed to the Republican
                        party. The Convention which organized that party was the largest, and the
                        most harmonious which ever assembled in the State, and embraced the talents,
                        patriotism, wisdom, character, and public spirit of <emph rend="italic"
                        >both</emph> the Democratic and Whig parties in the State.</p>
                    <p>It presented a grand and sublime spectacle, Whigs and Democrats, actuated
                        alike by patriotic motives, met in friendly council in the interests of
                        their State and in behalf of the rights and liberties of the people, and,
                        burying past differences in the grave of oblivion, with concord and harmony
                        and unity banded themselves together, like brothers, in a fraternal
                        political organization, which all then agreed in a spirit of friendly
                        compromise, should be called the "CONSERVATIVE" party. The object was to
                        embrace in that organization all who were opposed to the Republican party,
                        whatever their political antecedents might have been, and knowing, as wise
                        men, that many were influenced by their prejudices against even the name of
                        the party to which they had been opposed, the representatives of each of the
                        old parties deemed it wise, politic and patriotic to give up the name to
                        which they were partial, and adopt, for the new party, a name against which
                        neither party was prejudiced, and thus the party, composed of both Whigs and
                        Democrats alike, came to be called the "CONSERVATIVE" party.</p>
                    <p>If this were wise then, (and we humbly think it was,) as the same reason
                        still applies, men being still more or less under the influence of their
                        prejudices -- however foolish many may deem them -- we cannot see how it can
                        be wise or politic to discard the name thus adopted, and substitute for it
                        either of the names which it was thought wise to give up, as neither could
                        strengthen, and either might weaken the party, in consequence of the
                        prejudices against it which many would entertain.</p>
                    <p>We have neither a "Whig" nor a "Democratic" party, as such, in this State,
                        and we have <emph rend="italic">co nomine</emph>, no need for such. We have
                        a party organization which embraces the members of both, and all others, if
                        any there be, who are opposed to the Radical or Republican party. The time
                        may come, but it has not yet arrived, when it may be wise to reorganize our
                        party in this State and call it by another name. The defeat of the Radical
                        party is the object which patriotic duty now demands that we should use all
                        honorable and just means to accomplish. And to do this, we hope to see
                        united, in opposition to that party, former Whigs and Democrats and a
                        portion of the present dissatisfied Republicans; for we must look to the
                        best portion of the Republican party for recruits. The shibboleth of our
                        party should be: "OPPOSITION TO THE REPUBLICAN PARTY." All who will unite
                        with us in opposition to that party should be welcomed to our party. Let the
                        invitation be general, and the welcome cordial.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praised the past exploits of the Conservative party, which combined former
                    Democrats and Whigs in united opposition to Radical rule. Gave reasons why a
                    switch in names would only hurt the party in upcoming elections. Claimed the
                    main purpose of the party was to defeat the Republicans and to recruit anyone,
                    from any party, willing to accomplish that goal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Word of Counsel to our Farmers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Farmers of Augusta:</emph> --Like yourselves I am a
                        farmer, and, like yourselves, I feel the evils that are brought upon us by
                        the low prices of the production of our farms. The present prices of flour,
                        corn, oats, and rye will hardly pay the cost of production. Beef and pork
                        are rather better, but, still, they are too low. Our granaries are filled
                        with wheat, and our cribs with corn; but ninety cents or a dollar for the
                        former, and fifty cents for the latter will not pay.</p>
                    <p>The question then presents itself, what shall we do with the large surplus on
                        hand? Shall we sell it at the present ruinous prices, or shall we hold on in
                        the hope of doing better?</p>
                    <p>My advice to you is to hold on for a while, and I will now tell you why:</p>
                    <p>We have every reason to believe that before the 1st of April next, the Valley
                        Railroad will be under contract, and a remunerative market opens for us for
                        everything we have to sell.</p>
                    <p>I have talked with Mr. Garrett, the President of the Railroad Company, and he
                        informs me that it is his purpose and wish to commence operations on a large
                        scale, on the road, within the next three months. I learn from him that the
                        Baltimore &amp; Ohio Railroad Company are just about finishing a
                        railroad which they have been building from Connellsville to Pittsburg, and
                        as soon as that work is completed (which will be in February) the company
                        proposes to transfer a corps of three thousand workmen, with all their
                        outfit of carts, wagons, horses, mules, oxen, and tools of every kind to the
                        Valley R. R. The whole force will come in a body, with their families and
                        stock. They will come like an army with banners, organized and equipped for
                        action, without delay.</p>
                    <p>Assuming that there are 3,000 working men, they will, in all probability,
                        bring with them not less than 1,000 women and children and camp-followers.
                        They will also bring not less than a thousand head of horses, mules, oxen
                        and milch cows. This will make an aggregate of 4,000 people and 1,000 work
                        animals. All these will have to be fed and supported from our granaries,
                        corn-cribs, meat houses, and hay and fodder stacks.</p>
                    <p>You can form as good an idea as I can of the immense quantity of flour, corn,
                        rye, oats, hay, fodder, beef, bacon, potatoes, cabbage, onions, apples,
                        poultry, whiskey, brandy, milk, butter, eggs and fuel which would be
                        required to feed and render comfortable such an army of people and live
                        stock. I doubt if the entire surplus remaining in the county would meet the
                        demand. This new demand would largely enhance the prices of every production
                        of our farms.</p>
                    <p>But these people must not only be supplied with bread, and meats, and
                        vegetables, but they must also be clothed and buy their dry-goods, tea,
                        coffee, sugar, rice, salt, pepper, spices, &amp;c., from our merchants.
                        The effect of these things will be to throw a vast amount of money into
                        circulation, and largely to relieve the distresses of our people.</p>
                    <p>The annual surplus flour of Augusta county is estimated at 80,000 barrels,
                        and of corn at from 200,000 to 300,000 bushels. I have no accurate data on
                        which to estimate the surplus of beef, pork, potatoes, cabbage, apples, hay,
                        rye, oats or straw. But we know that there is a large excess of all these
                        articles over the home demand.</p>
                    <p>Now let us see how this matter will work in practice. I think no one would
                        think it extravagant to estimate the new and extraordinary demand, arising
                        out of the support of 4,000 people and 1,000 head of stock, would add one
                        dollar a barrel to the price of flour, and 25 cents to the value of every
                        bushel of corn. In my opinion, the addition would be much larger. But, to be
                        on the safe side, I will make my calculation on the basis of an increase of
                        a dollar on each barrel of flour, and 25 cents on each bushel of corn. The
                        amount would stand thus:</p>
                    <p>Increase of $1 on each barrel of surplus flour, 80,000............$80,0000</p>
                    <p>Increase of 25cts, on each bushel of surplus corn, 200,000...........$50,000</p>
                    <p>Increase on meats, rye, oats, hay, potatoes, vegetables, say...$30,000</p>
                    <p>Making an aggregate of.................................$160,000</p>
                    <p>This profit will be realized, in great measure, as soon as it is known that
                        the work will certainly be commenced in March or April. It will begin long
                        before a blow is struck on the road. As soon as it is certainly known that
                        4,000 people and 1,000 work animals are to be fed from our supplies, produce
                        of every kind will begin to rise, in anticipation of the increased demand.
                        Speculators will be on the lookout; but my advice to our farmers is to hold
                        on to their crops, and realize the profits themselves. I am neither a
                        prophet nor the son of a prophet, but it would not surprise me (provided
                        this large force is put to work by the 1st of April) if flour rose two
                        dollars per barrel, and corn from 40 to 50 cents per barrel, before the
                        close of 1871.</p>
                    <p>At army rations this number of people would consume over 20 barrels of flour
                        per day, and 4,000 lbs of meat, and the 1,000 animals would consume 500
                        bushels of grain and seven tons of hay, daily.</p>
                    <p>When we add to these articles rye, oats, fodder, vegetables, fruits, whiskey,
                        brandy, &amp;c., it will be seen that the aggregate consumption is
                        enormous.</p>
                    <p>In view of this prospective market, I think all who can should hold on to
                        their crops and cattle, and salt their pork instead of selling it. But some
                        may inquire what assurance have we of this coming market? My answer is, that
                        it depends on yourselves. If you will vote the subscription of $200,000 to
                        the Valley Railroad, it is <emph rend="italic">absolutely certain</emph> to
                        come. All the residue of the subscriptions ($3,000,000) have been made
                        conditionally, and you have it in your power to make them absolute, by
                        voting the $200,000. Mr. Garrett, the President of the road, and his father
                        -- gentlemen of unquestionable character -- give the most positive assurance
                        that if Augusta votes the $200,000, the work will be actively commenced
                        within three months.</p>
                    <p>Should we hesitate to do so? I think not. I verily believe, for the reasons
                        above stated, that the profits that the county will make on the sale of her
                        products <emph rend="italic">now on hand</emph>, will not only pay the
                        interest, but a large part, if not the whole, of the amount she is asked to
                        subscribe.</p>
                    <p>A FARMER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anonymous writer argued that, despite falling prices, Augusta farmers
                    should hold onto their surplus goods in anticipation of a booming market in the
                    near future. He claimed such a market was forthcoming because the owners of the
                    Valley Railroad promised a vast workforce would come to Staunton once work on
                    the railroad started up. The writer revealed his actual motive at the end of the
                    article by urging voters to pass the $200,000 subscription to the Valley
                    Railroad to ensure the arrival of the promised workforce and subsequent market
                    for surplus goods.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Sixth Congressional District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper printed the totals "as cast" along with the official totals of
                    the Congressional election for the 6th District. Staunton and Augusta cast 1,346
                    of 5,056 votes for C. M. Reynolds (Ind); 507 of 7,112 for John T. Harris (Con);
                    and 543 of 2736 for C. Douglas Gray (Rad). The Board of State Canvassers,
                    however, threw out results from 18 precincts in Augusta County. The official
                    totals registered 7,006 votes for Harris; 4,591 for Reynolds; and 2,604 for
                    Gray.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.12.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Religious Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hott</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. G. W. Hott and the Rev. J. J. Engle will lead a protracted meeting
                    at Churchville beginning on Christmas Eve.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Mt. Horeb Church will hold a fair at Mt. Meridian to raise
                    money for their congregation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The fair held by the Baptists raised $265.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Revival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Clay Hill Church in the Pastures recently held a revival meeting.
                    Twenty-two new members joined the United Brethren Church and five received
                    baptism by immersion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Scharf will give a series of readings at Mt. Vernon Forge. He will
                    perform the "Rivals," "The Critic," and "Loan of a Lover." Music will also be
                    provided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserted that, with the possibility of another vote on the
                    subscription of stock to the Valley Railroad, the onus was now on the company to
                    demonstrate that they were serious about building the road. Only action would
                    inspire the necessary support.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawes</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. H. H. Hawes, Presbyterian pastor of Mt. Horeb Church, received
                    eleven new members of the faith last Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. James Norris, Staunton insurance agent, lost sight in one eye and was
                    steadily losing sight in the other. He travelled to an infirmary in Baltimore,
                    where he will undergo an operation in an attempt to restore his sight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Grand Concert and Reading</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruhl</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apperson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Madame Ruhl, Prof. Schneider, Miss Apperson, Prof. Turner's orchestra, and
                    a number of amateur singers will hold a concert at the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind
                    Institution on December 21st. The evening will also include Prof. Scharf's
                    reading of "Bumble's Courtship" from Oliver Twist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>M. Erskine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>Harriette</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. Erskine Miller of Huntsville, Alabama, and Miss Harriette Echols,
                    daughter of Gen. John Echols of Staunton, were married in Staunton's Trinity
                    Church on December 15th by the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stogdale</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hott</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Stogdale and Miss Margaret J. Brown, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Parnassus on December 15th by the Rev. G. W. Hott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Philippina Behn</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James P. Hawkins of Danville and Miss Philippina Behn McDowell of
                    Charleston, S. C., were married on December 19th at the Staunton residence of
                    Mr. Richard Hawkins by the Rev. William H. Williams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conway</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Julia E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. W. B. Conway of Weyer's Cave and Miss Julia E. Thomas, daughter of Col.
                    William Thomas, were married in Blacksburg on December 14th by the Rev. William
                    F. Wilhelm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blain</ln>
                        <fn>I. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Rusmisel and Miss Mattie D. Clayton, daughter of the late Thomas
                    Clayton, were married near Deerfield, Augusta County, on December 1st by the
                    Rev. I. S. Blain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>Esta C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>Archie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Handy</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin Bell and Miss Esta C. Trotter, daughter of the late Archie
                    Trotter, all of Augusta, were married on November 22nd at the residence of the
                    bride's uncle, Cyrus Brown, by the Rev. Isaac Handy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.12.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
