<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.11.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="22"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.22.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Suggestive Points</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph> says that an analysis of the
                        votes of the States in which elections have recently been held, and a fair
                        and impartial estimate of the political complexion of the five States which
                        are yet to return members to the Forty-second Congress, present some very
                        suggestive points.</p>
                    <p>First. The amended returns show that the Republican majority in the
                        Forty-second Congress, including both wings of that party, will not, in any
                        event, exceed thirty-one, and may possibly, in the elections yet to come
                        off, be reduced still more. The same returns show further that the Radical
                        wing is, numerically, much weaker than the Liberal wing and the Democrats
                        combined, and as the control of the important questions now before the
                        country will necessarily pass into the hands of the strongest section of the
                        House, the Radicals will not now be able, as heretofore, to dictate those
                        measures of legislation by which they hoped to perpetuate their power.</p>
                    <p>In respect to the Tariff question, the strength of the combined opposition to
                        a high protective tariff indicates a most remarkable change. In the
                        Forty-second Congress, the Democrats, all of whom are pledged to a reform of
                        the revenue, will number one hundred and six -- whilst the Liberal
                        Republicans, who are quite as stoutly opposed to a high protective tariff,
                        count up twenty-nine, making in the aggregate one hundred and thirty-five
                        revenue reformers against one hundred and eight Radical protectionists --
                        thus giving to the revenue reform members a clear majority in the House of
                        twenty-seven votes, and the ability, at the very opening of the session, if
                        they have the wisdom to use it, to elect the Speaker and control the
                        organization of the House.</p>
                    <p>Turning next to the question of the probable electoral vote in the
                        Presidential contest of 1872, and assuming that in the new apportionment of
                        members of the House of Representatives the increase in the electoral vote
                        of the Northwestern States will be equalized by a corresponding increase in
                        the electoral vote of the Southern States, there seems to be every reason to
                        believe that the Democrats will have, as the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Herald</emph> table indicates, a clear majority of five in the Electoral
                        College, or a majority of six, if we throw out the six votes of Connecticut,
                        which may be classed as doubtful, and transfer the seven votes of New Jersey
                        to the Democratic column, where they properly belong, notwithstanding the
                        loss of the State at the recent election by local quarrels.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor gave a report of current and future electoral trends based on
                    the recent election returns from around the country. Predicted the Democrats
                    would increase their power if they could ally with Liberal Republicans. Even
                    thought the Democrats could win the presidency in 1872.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Last Ten Years</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarized the key events of world history over the previous ten years,
                    including France crowning an emperor in Mexico, Prussia crushing France and
                    uniting Germany, the abolishment of serfdom in Russia, and the convening of an
                    Ecumenical Council in Rome.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGlaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reported that the Circuit Court of Augusta County, Judge William L.
                    McGlaughlin presiding, was still in session.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>I. O. O. F. Concert To-Night</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruhl</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apperson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alby</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Madame Ruhl, Miss Apperson, Prof. Schneider, Dr. Brown, J. W. Alby, the
                    Stonewall Band, and Prof. Turner's Institution Orchestra will hold a concert
                    tonight for the benefit of the Odd Fellows.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelly</ln>
                        <fn>John H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quiesenberry</ln>
                        <fn>Marinda A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. M. Shelly and Miss Marinda A. Quiesenberry, both of Augusta, were
                    married in Staunton by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Silas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boone</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawes</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Silas H. Walker of Augusta and Miss Laura Boone of Rockingham were married
                    on November 9th by the Rev. H. H. Hawes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smeltz</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. F. Downey of Rockbridge and Miss Mary E. Smeltz of Augusta were married
                    at Variety Springs on November 8th by the Rev. M. A. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Johnson E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Johnson E. Bell of Lewisburg and Miss Lucy M. Guy of Staunton were married
                    on November 10th at the residence of R. M. Guy by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Chapman, wife of William Chapman of Waynesboro, died at the
                    residence of her husband on November 16th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Patterson, wife of the late Alexander Patterson, died at her residence
                    near Waynesboro on November 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn>Robert R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert R. Ruff, son of the late Jacob Ruff, died near Swoope's Depot at the
                    residence of John Wilson on November 18th of consumption.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
