<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.11.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="08"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.08.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Virginia Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>Johns</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garrett</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Key supporters of the Valley Railroad met in Baltimore last week. They
                    offered Johns Hopkins the presidency of the company but he declined. They
                    appointed county officials and elected Robert Garrett president in place of
                    Hopkins. Col. M. G. Harman made a speech in favor of the road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>LEWISBURG, GREENBRIER CO., W. VA.,</p>
                    <p>November 4th, 1870.</p>
                    <p>We are now here in the midst of the most happy and jubilant people we have
                        ever seen. This state of feeling has been caused by the recent unexpected
                        and triumphant success in the recent State election, of the Conservative
                        party of this heretofore Radical-ridden and outrageously misruled State.
                        These people, who have been, since the war, wearing the chains of political
                        bondage, and have been violently gagged, and mercilessly tyrannized over,
                        now feel that the day of their redemption has dawned with a bright aurora
                        presaging the early enjoyment of the blessings of liberty. Their jubilation
                        is natural, and it makes our heart thrill with pleasure to witness their
                        exultation at their release from the galling yoke of political bondage.
                        Their victory is one of the most important which has ever been won in the
                        annals of political party contests. It secures the enfranchisement of the
                        thousands of the most worthy and intelligent citizens of this State who
                        have, since the war, been denied a voice in the administration of their
                        Government. -- This class were denied the right of suffrage, whilst that
                        right was conferred upon the negroes, and their <emph rend="italic"
                            >inferiors</emph> in character -- the "<emph rend="italic">loil</emph>"
                        -- so-called. The conservatives have had the pleasure of seeing the Radical
                        engineers "hoist upon their own petard" -- and this adds increased triumph
                        to their victory. The Radicals conferred the right of suffrage upon the
                        negroes whilst they withheld it from the best portion of the whites,
                        believing that the negro vote would ensure, beyond peradventure, the
                        perpetuation of Radical rule.</p>
                    <p>"But the best laid schemes o' mice and men</p>
                    <p>Aft gang agley."</p>
                    <p>Though the negroes, as was to be expected, voted foolishly and wrongfully,
                        the Radical ticket, yet the triumph of the conservatives is justly
                        attributed, in good part, to the fact that suffrage was conferred upon the
                        negroes. This was so distasteful to many who had heretofore voted with the
                        Radical party that the Radicals lost more than they gained by this advice,
                        involving such palpable wrong and outrage. -- This result should teach the
                        negroes the estimate in which they are held by the Radicals -- who dislike
                        them, and but use them to subserve their own selfish and diabolical
                        political purposes.</p>
                    <p>The result of the recent elections in this State was about equally surprising
                        to both parties. This adds to the joy of the victors, and to the
                        mortification of the defeated. The Radicals having been fairly defeated,
                        they would have acted wisely if they had gracefully submitted to the verdict
                        of the voters as expressed at the polls. But, like all great sinners, they
                        die hard, and are now trying to change the result by throwing out of the
                        count such precincts as gave Conservative majorities. The Board of
                        Supervisors were engaged in this work yesterday at the Court-house. The
                        conduct of a majority of the Board was shameful, though we do not believe
                        that they experienced any sense of shame; for we doubt whether they have
                        enough virtue in their characters to enable them to feel ashamed at the
                        commission of a mean act.</p>
                    <p>As the Board adjourned yesterday evening, the Marshal, O. P. Hoover, under
                        the instructions of Capt. C. A. Sperry, United States Commissioner, arrested
                        three members of the Board -- Argabright, Snedegar and McMillein, who,
                        failing to give bail, were sent to jail, where they are now. They will be
                        tried before the Commissioner to-day. They were arrested, we understand, not
                        for their conduct yesterday, but for acts heretofore perpetrated in refusing
                        to allow persons duly qualified to register and vote. M.</p>
                    <p>P.S. -- SATURDAY, NOV. 5th. -- The trial of those members of the Board of
                        Registration who have been arrested under charges of having violated the
                        enforcement act by refusing to register persons who possessed the loyal
                        qualifications, did not take place yesterday before the U. S. Commissioner
                        as had been expected. Two more persons -- C. A. Thatcher and John Hughart,
                        the latter an Inspector, not a Registrar, were arrested yesterday, and like
                        the other three mentioned above, in default of giving bail, were confined to
                        jail to await their trial before the Commissioner. To-day, the trial is
                        going on, and up to this time, 1 o'clock, but two cases have been tried --
                        those of C. A. Thatcher and Jno. L. Snedegar. In these cases, the
                        Commissioner required the parties to give bail for their appearance to
                        answer indictments before the United States Court, which will meet in
                        Charleston, in December next. Warrants have been issued for the arrest of
                        several other parties for the same offence. The Government is represented by
                        Capt. A. F. Mathews and A. W. Walker, and the prisoners by Wm. P.
                    Rucker.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reported on the recent conservative victories in West Virginia. The editor
                    cited the Radical policies of giving blacks the vote as the main reason for
                    their defeat because it cost them more white votes than they gained with black
                    voter support. Expressed gratitude for West Virginia voters who finally ended
                    Radical power in the state and thus ensured the enfranchisement of all white
                    voters in the state. Also denounced the Radicals who were at that time
                    attempting to reverse the election by throwing out conservative votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the M. E. Church South will hold a fair at the Town Hall
                    during Christmas week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Concert on Friday Night</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruhl</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apperson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drake</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Madame Ruhl, Prof. Schneider, Miss Apperson, Mr. Drake, Mr. Hunter, and
                    Prof. Turner's orchestra gave a concert at the chapel of the Deaf, Dumb, and
                    Blind Institution. The editor praised the performance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Sufferers" wrote an article complaining about disorderly conduct in
                    Staunton. "Our streets have recently been made hideous by the screams and yells
                    of disorderly persons, at a very late hour of the night. Rowdies have been seen
                    to go around and knock at people's doors, fire off their pistols, and disturb
                    the peace and quiet of our city."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gold</ln>
                        <fn>S. McD</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirkpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. S. McD Gold of Augusta and Miss Emma Hamilton, daughter of John W.
                    Hamilton, were married on November 2nd at the residence of the bride's father in
                    Rockbridge by the Rev. J. L. Kirkpatrick.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Handy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. David W. Hanger and Miss Sallie A. Crawford, daughter of Maj. James
                    Crawford of Augusta, were married on Nov. 1st at Mt. Pleasant, the residence of
                    the bride's father, by the Rev. Dr. Handy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbaum</ln>
                        <fn>T. Marion</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bane</ln>
                        <fn>Nanie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bane</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. Marion Rosenbaum of Smythe County and Miss Nannie V. Bane, daughter of
                    George B. Bane of Montgomery County, were married in Mt. Tabor Church, Augusta
                    County, on October 26th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Vines died in Greenville on October 23rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James F. Patterson and Newton Argenbright pass resolutions of sympathy and
                    respect on behalf of Staunton Lodge No. 45, International Order of Odd Fellows
                    upon the death of Edwin M. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
