<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.10.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/18/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="18"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.10.18.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>More Freshet News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editor commented further on the extensive damage in Page County due to the
                    recent flood.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This issue's columns have black borders as a symbol of mourning for the death
                of Robert E. Lee.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.10.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Congressional Nominee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Judge John T. Harris of Rockingham was nominated for representative of the
                    district including Augusta at the Conservative Congressional Convention. The
                    editor accused Harris of not working for the interests of the voters. "Had the
                    delegates in that Convention fairly and truly represented the sentiments of
                    their constituents, he could not have been nominated, for it is palpably evident
                    that he is not the choice of the District." Although he opposed Harris'
                    nomination, the editor still endorsed his campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of Robert E. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announced with sorrow the death of Robert E. Lee. The columns of
                    this week's issue have black borders as a sign of mourning. The editors issued
                    lavish praise of his character, a brief biography, and an account of his
                    funeral.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.11.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Southern Pantomime Troupe will perform Wednesday at the Deaf, Dumb, and
                    Blind Institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Trimble shot James Hoover through the thigh and the hand in an
                    altercation near Staunton on Monday. Dr. A. M. Henkel extracted the ball from
                    Hoover's leg. Fortunately for Hoover, the wounds appeared to be merely flesh
                    wounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Augusta County Fair opened today. The county expected smaller crowds
                    than usual because of the recent flood.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Memorial Association for the Confederate Dead will assemble in
                    the rotunda at the fair grounds on October 19th to fully organize the
                    association. James H. Skinner, president, will preside.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>An Omission</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper added Reuben D. Hill to the list of those commissioned as
                    directors of the Western Lunatic Asylum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>In Memoriam</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The bells of Staunton tolled upon receiving news of the death of Robert E.
                    Lee. Citizens met at the Court House to mourn his loss. The Mayor of the city
                    closed all businesses on Saturday and ordered the citizens to display badges of
                    mourning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tribute to Gen. R. E. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the citizens of the town of Staunton, held in the Court-house
                        on Friday the 14th inst., to express their deep concern at the death of Gen.
                        Robert E. Lee, and to appoint a Committee to represent the town on the
                        occasion of his funeral.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. B. Christian, Thomas J. Michie, Esq., was called to the
                        Chair,and Col. Jas. H. Skinner was appointed Secretary.</p>
                    <p>The object of the meeting was feelingly announced by the Chairman.</p>
                    <p>Thereupon the following preamble and resolutions were offered and their
                        adoption moved by Hon. A. H. H. Stuart, who, in presenting them, paid an
                        appropriate tribute to the exalted genius and virtues of the illustrious
                        dead:</p>
                    <p>The citizens of Staunton having learned that the family of the late Gen. R.
                        E. Lee have expressed a desire that his mortal remains shall, for the
                        present, be deposited in the Memorial Chapel of Washington College, and that
                        the funeral obsequies will take place on Saturday, 15th inst., at 12
                        o'clock.</p>
                    <p>And the citizens of Staunton feeling a strong desire to testify in some
                        public manner, their profound love and veneration for the memory and
                        character of this illustrious man, who has shed so much honor, not only in
                        his native State, but upon human nature;</p>
                    <p>It is therefore resolved that a delegation, on behalf of the citizens of
                        Staunton, be appointed to visit Lexington and unite in the ceremonies
                        intended to mark the deep sense of the great calamity that has befallen
                        Virginia in the death of him, who, next to Washington, enjoyed in the
                        largest measure the affection and confidence, esteem and gratitude of his
                        fellow citizens.</p>
                    <p>Col. B. Christian seconded the resolution and briefly explained to the
                        meeting the resolutions of the General Assembly of Virginia, which had been
                        transmitted through him by the Legislature of Virginia, to the family of the
                        deceased, and the response made by Gen G. W. Custis Lee to the request
                        therein contained.</p>
                    <p>The preamble and resolutions were then unanimously adopted, and the following
                        gentlemen appointed a Committee to attend the funeral obsequies: A. H. H.
                        Stuart, Bolivar Christian, J. B. Baldwin, Dr. F. T. Stribling, F. M. Young,
                        N. K. Trout, Chas. D. McCoy, Wm. L. Bumgardner, Dr. Chas C. Phillips, Chas.
                        T. Arnall, Dr. Carter Berkley, Wm. H. Gorman, Frank Berkley, Wm. N. Bumpus,
                        L. S. Henry, J. Howard Wayt, J. Wayne Spitler, Reyd. H. H. Kennedy, Ed.
                        Echols.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Charles D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Charles C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>Carter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumpus</ln>
                        <fn>William N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendry</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn>J. Howard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayne</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>Ed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reported on meetings held to commemorate the passing of General Robert E.
                    Lee. Printed the resolutions adopted and the names of those selected to attend
                    the funeral ceremonies at Lexington</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Russell N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Batis</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Russell N. Wallace and Mrs. Mary Batis, both of Augusta, were married at
                    the American Hotel on October 15th by the Rev. H. H. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo S. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dill</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lorenzo S. K. McCutchen of Augusta and Miss Hattie Dill of Rockbridge were
                    married on September 22nd by the Rev. Mr. Riley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyner</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Jr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Coyner, Jr., and Miss Lizzie V. Vanlear, both of Augusta, were
                    married on October 3rd at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev.
                    William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCommon</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel D. McCommon of Rockingham and Miss Mattie D. Hailman, daughter of B.
                    F. Hailman of Augusta, were married on October 11th by the Rev. A. A. J.
                    Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>Josie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Josie B. Richardson, wife of C. A. Richardson, died in Staunton at the
                    residence of her husband on October 13th. She was 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Mayer, son of William and Mary A. Mayer, died near Parnassus on
                    September 26th. He was 17 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porterfield</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca F. Kinney, wife of William Kinney and daughter of the late
                    Gen. Robert Porterfield, died in her Staunton residence on October 7th. She was
                    73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Ast died in his Staunton residence on October 17th. He was 70 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frenger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter Frenger died at Arbor Hill on October 7th. He was 66 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MESSRS. EDITORS: -- In your paper of the 11th inst., there is a short
                        article, copied from the <emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph> over the
                        signature of "Observer," in which the writer complains of the manner in
                        which the Female Schools of our Town make their purchases. He calls it a
                            "<emph rend="italic">perilous custom</emph>." We fully agree with
                        "Observer," but how can we remedy it. By the way, it is a pernicious custom
                        not entirely confined to the Schools; other institutions, and even private
                        citizens make all their purchases at one or two stores. We think this thing
                        altogether wrong, at least so far as it concerns the public institutions and
                        Female Schools of the Town, especially, when we consider that these public
                        institutions and large Female Schools were gotten up, for the exclusive
                        benefit of the mercantile community of the city of Staunton. -- No doubt the
                        Legislature of Virginia, when it chartered them, had that object solely in
                        view. We have thought seriously over the matter, and talked with friends
                        about it, and believed we had fixed upon a plan, which would entirely break
                        up this "pernicious custom." The plan we had agreed upon was this: The
                        merchants all to meet in the Town Hall, the handsomest man among them to be
                        called to the chair, and the next handsomest to be Secretary; pass
                        condemnatory resolutions, get a number of circulars printed, and send them
                        to the friends of the pupils of the different Female Schools in this place.
                        No doubt, the Principals of the Schools would take great pleasure in
                        furnishing their addresses, and any other information that might be wanted,
                        such, for instance, as the amount of clothing, book and stationery, jewelry,
                        cakes and candies, &amp;c., &amp;c., that each pupil might probably
                        purchase during the session. Such information being obtained, it could the
                        better be shown forth in the circulars, how great the advantages to be
                        gained by making all the purchases in Staunton. The custom should be
                        distributed among our merchants, in proportion to the capital employed in
                        their business. As the pupils would not need any articles in the grocery,
                        hardware, or tobacco line, the other merchants should be required to lay out
                        a certain per cent of their incomes derived from the Schools, with these
                        branches of trade. Some of the friends of our scheme think it would be well,
                        through the circulars, to request the patrons of the Schools not to bring
                        any more clothing with them for the pupils than one change of garments, of
                        the cheapest sort. This would do away with the necessity, which every
                        traveller knows is a great bother; as trunks, clothing, cakes, and candies
                        are everything else needed to make a complete outfit for young ladies
                        entering first class Seminaries, can be had in Staunton on the best terms,
                            <emph rend="italic">especially</emph> if they have the money to pay down
                        for them. We thought, after reflecting over our plan that it was first rate,
                        and would soon effect the desired reform -- but alas!</p>
                    <p>"The best laid schemes o' mice an' men.</p>
                    <p>Gang aft a-gley."</p>
                    <p>On our way to the printing office, to get some handbills printed, calling on
                        the merchants to meet at the Town Hall, we stepped in to see an old friend
                        and laid our plans before him. We had a rough draft of what we intended
                        doing, which he read. After a short pause he raised his head, threw his
                        spectacles up and quietly remarked, "that our plan was not worth the paper
                        it was written upon." Said he -- "Don't you know the Principals of our large
                        Schools are persons of some independence, and like many others of our
                        citizens, make their purchases where they think best, without any regard to
                        what some of our merchants may say, or think about the matter."</p>
                    <p>We then asked him, if he thought our City Council or the Virginia Legislature
                        could do anything to remedy this <emph rend="italic">terrible evil</emph>.
                        He said what I was well aware of before, that, "our City Council and the
                        Virginia Legislature were very important bodies indeed, and possessed of
                        great powers, but did not think that they could render us any aid whatever;
                        but would advise us to apply to the Congress of the United States to have
                        the Schools reconstructed; he thought it might come in as the Seventeenth
                        Amendment of the Constitution." We asked him why not as Sixteenth. He said
                        -- "he believed it was generally reserved for an article on <emph
                            rend="italic">woman's rights.</emph>" And there it seemed would be
                        another difficulty in our way; we feared this Seventeenth Amendment would be
                        an infringement on <emph rend="italic">woman's rights</emph>, though he
                        thinks there would be no difficulty on that score, as it could all be
                        managed very well on old Thad. Stevens' plan, outside of the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>FAIR PLAY.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"FAIR PLAY" wrote a satirical article responding to another contributor who
                    complained about the way Female Schools make their purchases at only one or two
                    stores. Offered as a solution to the problem the idea that merchants should all
                    get together and print up circulars to pass out to the schools so that the
                    principals will buy from everyone equally. Claimed he ran this by a friend and
                    the latter found the idea ludicrous</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.10.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
