<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.01.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/11/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="18"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.01.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.01.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Admission of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the re-assembling of Congress the question of the admission of Virginia
                        has been the chief subject of interest, and has elicited considerable
                        discussion. It would seem that the end has been nearly reached. Though it is
                        not very probable, yet it may be that even before we go to press, we <emph
                            rend="italic">may</emph> learn that the Senate, like the House, has
                        adopted the resolution declaring "that the State of Virginia is entitled to
                        representation in the United States." On Friday last, the motion in the
                        House to substitute the preamble and resolution offered by Bingham for the
                        bill reported by the Reconstruction Committee was adopted by the vote of 98
                        to 95. The preamble was then adopted by a rising vote 76 to 74. The bill was
                        then adopted by 142 to 49. The announcement of the result was received with
                        applause on the floor of the House. The bill, as passed, is as follows:</p>
                    <p>Whereas, The people of Virginia have adopted a Constitution republican in
                        form, and have in all respects conformed to the requirements of the act of
                        Congress entitled "An act authorizing the submission of the Constitutions of
                        Virginia, Mississippi and Texas to a vote of the people, and authorizing the
                        election of State officers, provided by the said Constitutions and members
                        of Congress," approved April 10th, 1869, therefore,</p>
                    <p>Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United
                        States of America, in Congress assembled, That the said State of Virginia is
                        entitled to representation in the Congress of the United States.</p>
                    <p>The House adjourned until Monday.</p>
                    <p>In the Senate, on the same day, the joint resolution for the admission of
                        Virginia having been taken up, Mr. Willey, Senator from West Virginia,
                        offered an amendment that the members and officers of the Legislature shall
                        take the oath prescribed in the 3rd section of the Fourteenth Amendment, but
                        also allowing the immediate admission of the State.</p>
                    <p>The amendment of Mr. Willey was adopted by yeas 45, nays 13, Messrs. Fowler,
                        Stewart and Trumbull voting in the negative with the Democrats.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Wilson moved, as an additional proviso, the fundamental conditions
                        imposed by the bill reported to the House by the Reconstruction Committee,
                        which was rejected -- yeas 23, nays 35.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Drake moved an additional proviso, that the Legislature shall have no
                        power to rescind the ratification of any amendments to the Constitution of
                        the United States, which, after debate, was rejected -- yeas 11, nays 44.</p>
                    <p>At the night session, a message was received from the House announcing the
                        passage by that body of the bill for the admission of Virginia, which was
                        read.</p>
                    <p>The Senate decided not to consider, at that time, the bill adopted by the
                        House, and proceeded with the consideration of its own bills. At 10 o'clock
                        P. M. the Senate adjourned till Monday -- yesterday -- with the
                        understanding that a vote would be taken at 4 o'clock on that day.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator reported on the House of Representative's adoption of a bill
                    admitting Virginia into the United States. Additional amendments to the bill
                    were introduced and voted upon, and the Senate decided not to consider the
                    question at that time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.01.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britt</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General Canby removed George W. Britt from his office as Staunton flour
                    inspector.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. George Kramer supervised a revival meeting at Staunton's Methodist
                    Church that has interested the entire town and gained a number of converts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Canby</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>David G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General Canby appointed the following men to posts in Augusta County: David
                    G. McGuffin replaced Henry H. Peck in the first magisterial district and Robert
                    G. Bickle replaced Edwin M. Cushing in the second magisterial district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Circulating Library Meeting"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Staunton have formed an organization aimed at establishing a
                    circulating library. A number of subscribers have already joined at $3.50 for
                    the year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>La Rue's Minstrels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>La Rue's Carnival Minstrels performed in the Town Hall on Friday and
                    Saturday. "All seemed to be pleased, especially the ladies, who seemed to enjoy
                    these entertainments with remarkable zest." The paper praised the talents of the
                    "Ethiopian comedians."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Berry and Miss Mollie E. Shultz were married on January 11th at the
                    residence of the bride's father in Greenville by the Rev. William Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Altaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas E. Gilkeson and Miss Sallie J. Altaffer, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Parnassus on January 11th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Josie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bullock</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. A. Richardson and Miss Josie Brooks, both of Staunton, were married at
                    the Eutaw House in Baltimore on January 12th by the Rev. Dr. Bullock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Caroline Bryan, wife of Reuben Bryan, died suddenly at her residence
                    in Sangersville on January 6th. She was 52 years old and a long-time member of
                    the Presbyterian Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Beard died in Augusta County at the residence of his daughter, Mrs.
                    Baylor, on December 30th. He was 85 years old. "Mr. B. was an active, zealous
                    and consistent member of the Mt. Tabor Evangelical Lutheran Congregation for
                    more than 35 years; the greater part of which he served as an elder in that
                    church." His last words were "as for the kingdom, I am sure of that."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.01.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
