<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.09.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/23/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="27"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.27.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Republican State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weissler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jefferson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper printed an account of the Republican State Convention that met in
                    Richmond. Three delegates from Augusta attended: Maj. John A. Harman, Jacob
                    Weissler, and Thomas Jefferson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The State Board of Education appointed Capt. Jed Hotchkiss Augusta County
                    School Superintendent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Church Dedication</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The new Southern Methodist Church in Mt. Crawford will be dedicated on
                    October 23rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Board of Education</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. Byron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Asher W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Leigh R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>B. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Kasper B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>B. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davies</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plecker</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Board of Education named Capt. Jed Hotchkiss County Superintendent of
                    Augusta Schools. They also selected school trustees for the various townships.
                    Staunton: Maj. H. M. Bell, William J. Nelson, and P. Byron Hoge. Beverly Manor:
                    John Towberman, Col. Asher W. Harman, and Leigh R. Waddell. Pastures: B. O.
                    Ferguson, James H. Heizer, John S. Guy. Riverheads: A. S. Turk, Capt. C. G.
                    Merritt, William Thompson. South River: C. H. Withrow, Rev. C. Beard, Dr. J. M.
                    Watson. Middle River: William Wilson, Kasper B. Koiner, B. J. Craig. North
                    River: Dr. William H. Davies, Samuel Forrer, Jacob H. Plecker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Hon. A. H. H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The distinguished gentleman whose name heads this article is no doubt the
                        most prominent candidate for Congress before the Harrisonburg Convention on
                        the 5th proximo. Indeed it would be very gratifying to the friends of Mr.
                        Stuart that the nomination should be by acclamation.</p>
                    <p>Mr. S. made a spirited canvass in opposition to Mr. Lewis, and was elected by
                        a large majority, but was deprived of his seat in Congress by the reason
                        that he could not take the Iron-Clad Oath. We think now in common justice to
                        him that he should receive a unanimous nomination from the Convention. He
                        has experience. He has talents of a high order. Is a statesman of ability,
                        though advanced in years, his intellect was never stronger. He is fully
                        identified with the people of the district. Is a large property holder. His
                        interests are their interests. He has but one incentive, that is to promote
                        the welfare of an oppressed people with whom he is a common-sufferer. The
                        writer, in ante-bellum days belonged to the Democratic party, to which Mr.
                        S. was always opposed, and is a Democrat still, therefore we cannot be
                        accused of political sympathy with Mr. Stuart in former years. It is true
                        that the writer has always liked Mr. Stuart personally, and has received
                        many acts of courtesy and friendship. We have known him for a long term of
                        years and whilst we have as a Democrat ever contended for every inch of
                        ground in opposition to the party with which Mr. S. has acted, we have been
                        ready at all times to accord him the credit of being honest and consistent.
                        But now in the South we have no organized Democratic or Whig party. Old
                        issues between parties if no <emph rend="italic">effete</emph> are dead for
                        the present. All are merged in a common interest and common destiny to
                        defeat Radicalism in Virginia. Old party lines have been swept away -- long
                        cherished principles of States Rights and Constitutional liberty have been
                        yielded up to appease an exacting and desperate foe who are our conquerors,
                        in order to save our people from carpet-baggers and scalawags holding the
                        offices and destroying our judiciary system and to enfranchise the best and
                        large part of our voting population. Conciliation then and harmony in our
                        councils are at this time imperiously demanded. The best men, too, should be
                        selected for office regardless of former party antecedents. This is the
                        opinion at least of</p>
                    <p>"JUSTICE."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"JUSTICE" endorsed Mr. Lewis over A.H.H. Stuart for nomination as
                    Congressmen for Augusta's district. Admitted Stuart's honesty and qualifications
                    but claimed Lewis would better serve the district. Also called on voters not to
                    choose their candidate based on old party loyalties because the old parties did
                    not exist anymore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Railroad Freights</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>S. B. P. wrote to the Richmond Whig urging the Chamber of Commerce of that
                    city to take steps to lower freight rates on the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fretwell</ln>
                        <fn>James Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fretwell</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fretwell</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Edwin Fretwell, infant son of William W. and Sarah Fretwell, died on
                    September 20th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Hall and George Hall, children of James and Maria Hall of
                    Augusta, died on July 23rd and August 18th. They were three years old and 18
                    months old respectively.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.09.27.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
