<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.10.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/25/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="04"/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.10.04.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.10.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Precinct Committees of the Augusta Memorial Association for the Confederate
                    Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>STAUNTON -- WARD NO. 1 -- John S. Moorman, Wm. L. Bumgardner, Mrs. Capt. D.
                        McCoy, Miss Avery Covell, Miss Eleanor Baylor.</p>
                    <p>STAUNTON -- WARD NO. 2 -- Capt. R. H. May, James Ker, mrs Josie Eyster, miss
                        Fannie Skinner, miss Florence Phillips.</p>
                    <p>SANDY HOLLOW -- Capt. L. Harman, H. L. Opie, mrs Wm Donaghe, mrs J N Opie,
                        miss Lorena Williams.</p>
                    <p>BOLIVAR. -- Jos Merriken, Geo R Bell, miss Hattie McGuffin, miss Nannie Bell,
                        miss Katie Smith.</p>
                    <p>PEACO'S MILL. -- E M Cushing, David Speck, miss Sallie Kinney, miss Sallie S
                        Henderson, miss Eliza Shuey.</p>
                    <p>FOLLY. -- Col Jas C Cochran, W Harvey Marshall, mrs Mary Lewis, miss Sallie
                        Gilkerson, miss Bettie Eskridge.</p>
                    <p>HEBRON. -- Geo H Eidson, Alpheus Cook, mrs Rev D B Ewing, miss Emma V Taylor,
                        mrs G W Swoope.</p>
                    <p>GREENSVILLE. -- Dr Wm Gillum, John B Smith, miss Mary Smith, miss Augusta
                        Bumgardner, miss Lizzie Pilson.</p>
                    <p>MIDDLEBROOK. -- M W D Hogshead, Jas W McCorkle, mrs Sallie Junkel, mrs George
                        Rusmisel, miss Maggie McCutchen.</p>
                    <p>NEWPORT. -- Dr Chas Berry, Thomas M Smiley, miss Lorena McChesney, miss Lucy
                        Turk, miss Ellen Steele.</p>
                    <p>MIDWAY.-- Nelson Bell Jr., John H Rush, miss Betty Henry, miss Willie
                        Pinkerton, miss Florence McGuffin.</p>
                    <p>WAYNESBORO'. -- Artemus Patterson, J P Smith, mrs Geo A Bruce, miss E
                        Withrow, mrs Sallie McGuire.</p>
                    <p>FISHERSVILLE. -- Capt. F. Bateman, John E Hamilton, mrs Virginia Hamilton,
                        miss Jennie Bell, miss Bettie Caldwell.</p>
                    <p>BARTERBROOK. -- A G Christian, Dr T W Shelton, mrs Martha Doid, miss Ophelia
                        Wilson, miss Emma Moffett.</p>
                    <p>SHERANDO. -- Clinton Hall, Daniel Heiserman, mrs J M Lewis, mrs David G
                        Hyden, miss Mary Coiner.</p>
                    <p>NEW HOPE. -- Capt Chas Grattan, Dr B F Walker, miss Lucy Stout, miss Lucy
                        Waddell, mrs Lizzie Hinton.</p>
                    <p>MT SIDNEY. -- Capt Thos J Burke, C S Roller, miss Sadie Crawford, miss Jennie
                        McCue, mrs Mary Wilson.</p>
                    <p>VERONA. -- Wm H Moorman, Ed Crawford, miss Mollie Gilkeson, miss Sallie
                        Crawford, miss E W Edmondson.</p>
                    <p>MT MERIDIAN. -- Capt Tom McClung, J D Craig, miss Cornelia Patterson, miss
                        Hanna Walker, miss Laura Boone.</p>
                    <p>RED MILLS. -- Sinclair Keiner, Wm Hanger, miss Catharine Yount, miss Hetty J
                        Barnhart, miss Barbara Baylor.</p>
                    <p>MT SOLON. -- Col J M McCue, Capt E L Curtis, mrs Maggie T Lockridge, miss
                        Bettie Forrer, mrs Robt Kyle.</p>
                    <p>SPRING HILL. -- Wm H Gamble, Dr Van Lear, miss Mary Plecker, miss Lizzie
                        Herring, miss Fanny Bell.</p>
                    <p>PARNASSUS. -- Ad Cochran, Robt Byers, miss Lizzie Kinne, miss Mary Hamrick,
                        miss Lucy Blair.</p>
                    <p>SANGERSVILLE. -- J W Crist, N L Blakemore, miss Mary S Gregory, mrs Dr Wm
                        Davis, miss Ann L Humbert.</p>
                    <p>CENTREVILE. -- Clement Fulton, H V Bell, mrs Dr J M Trevy, miss Mody Fulton,
                        miss Sallie Wheeler.</p>
                    <p>CHURCHVILLE. -- Capt Joseph A Wilson, Lit Waddell, mrs Wm H Bell, miss
                        Rebecca Sterrett, miss Jennie Stover.</p>
                    <p>BUFFALO GAP. -- Dr James F Tate, Magnus S Cease, mrs Saml H Bell, miss Ada
                        Sibert, miss Florence Lightner.</p>
                    <p>CRAIGSVILLE. -- Dr D Bashaw, Robt S Craig, miss Josephine Hedge, miss Mary
                        Thomas, miss Amanda Woodward.</p>
                    <p>DEERFIELD. -- David V Taylor, John S Guy, miss Agnes Montgomery, miss Nannie
                        McCutchen, miss Mary Montgomery.</p>
                    <p>LEBANON SPRINGS. - Thos H Cross, Frank E Irvine, miss Jennie Lange, miss
                        Belle Pauly, miss Susan Rhyan.</p>
                    <p>(Circulars will be sent to each Committee defining its duties.)</p>
                    <p>BOLIVAR CHRISTIAN,</p>
                    <p>Chairman, Ex. Com.</p>
                    <p>S. TRAVERS PHILLIPS, Sec'ty Ex. Com.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bolivar Christian sent out a circular listing the members of local
                    committees for the Memorial Association in each town of Augusta county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.10.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Conservative Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorsed the following candidates for the conservative ticket in
                    the November 8th elections: Charles T. Cochran for treasurer, William A. Burnett
                    for county clerk, Joseph N. Ryan for circuit clerk, James Bumgardner, Jr., for
                    commonwealth's attorney, George W. Fauber for superintendent of the poor,
                    William L. Mowry for sheriff, and Col. John D. Lilley for surveyor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advertised a daily stage line between Staunton and Harrisonburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyner</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. S. F. Coyner, formerly of Staunton, has been appointed Clinical
                    Assistant at Washington University.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Staunton Southern Methodist congregation will have dinner and
                    refreshment tables at the fair grounds during the Augusta County Fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Scharf will deliver the inaugural reading of the course at Mt. Vernon
                    Forge. On the 12th, Sheridan's "grand old Comedy the Rivals" will be performed,
                    with admissions at $1.00 apiece.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Grand Tournament</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The knights of Augusta and adjacent counties were invited to participate in
                    a Grand Challenge Tournament held on the last day of the fair. Prizes included a
                    fine saddle-horse and equipments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reprinted a warning against allowing personal feuds to stand in
                    the way of Conservative unity in the upcoming elections. "This is no time for
                    divisions among ourselves."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbs</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Shafer and Miss Laura Gibbs, both of Staunton, were married on
                    September 21st at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. Mr. Williams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gladke</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Rosetta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stempel</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles A. Gladke of Staunton and Miss Rosetta Rosenbaum, daughter of Henry
                    Rosenbaum of Washington, were married on September 17th at the residence of the
                    bride's father by the Rev. Isaac Stempel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>Loretta Julie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Loretta Julie Gorman, daughter of W. H. and J. C. Gorman, died on September
                    15th. She was 4 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.10.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
