<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1870/va.au.ss.1870.02.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/11/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date>
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm=""/>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1870.02.22.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1870.02.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The School System</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In nothing, says the Norfolk <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph>, has the
                        folly and incompetency of the Underwood Convention been more clearly shown
                        than in the attempt to introduce into a sparsely populated and comparatively
                        unsettled country, the county organization and educational systems as they
                        exist in the densely peopled and teeming communities of the Northern and
                        Eastern States. There these methods have gradually been introduced, subject
                        to such changes and modifications as the increasing wealth and population
                        from time to time suggested, until they have attained their present
                        proportions and development. In such a community, and with such a
                        population, it is not to be denied that the educational facilities are such
                        as to enable the citizens to educate their children in an economical, if not
                        a thorough manner; but to transplant the system here, and expect its
                        machinery to work with the same efficiency and smoothness, argues both
                        ignorance and folly. There all the people are taxed equally to defray the
                        expenses incident to the plan; here the burthens will fall with ruinous
                        weight upon a few; there the school districts are small and compact, each
                        containing, however, a sufficient number of inhabitants to fill the school
                        houses with a sufficient number of pupils to give employment to the teacher,
                        and secure the dissemination of the rudiments at least of an education to
                        the masses of the people; here the introduction of the plan will cause one
                        of two results: either the school districts will be so large that the
                        distance will deter half the pupils from attending, or the State will be
                        dotted over with empty school houses, and the people be taxed to death for
                        the construction of the buildings and the salaries of the teachers, when
                        half a dozen children, on an average, will receive the benefits of the
                        so-called education, and the whole thing will be a farce.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Norfolk Virginian criticized the Underwood Convention's plan for public
                    schooling as compared to the educational system in the Northeast. Claimed that
                    differences in population density make this system unsuitable for the more rural
                    populations of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Virginia Politics</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>With the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>, we think that the election
                        of good, honest, capable men to office, the passage of wise, wholesome, and
                        constitutional laws, and the care of our industrial affairs and of our works
                        of internal improvement, should for the present constitute the politics of
                        Virginia. We have more to fear from a heated, bitter and premature political
                        contest than from any other cause. It would be a contest between divisions
                        of our own people over mere shadows, when we should all be united and
                        harmonious in fostering common and solid interests. It ought to be the wish
                        of every good citizen of Virginia, native and adopted, white and black, to
                        place her once more on the high road to prosperity, and influence. Party
                        divisions will come soon enough without our attempting to force them
                        prematurely.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors of the Spectator agree with the Richmond Whig that Virginia
                    politics should remain nonpartisan; instead focusing on electing honorable men
                    and passing just laws. Party divisions would merely divide the people over
                    unimportant issues.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In an article on the probable political results of reconstruction, the
                        Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Statesman</emph> says: "We discern victory in
                        the next Presidential election plainly within our grasp, upon the
                        consideration that the Democrats and Conservatives of the whole country, the
                        South included, act as a unit, cast overboard obsolete issues and obsolete
                        men, and go before the people on living practical questions, such as
                        involves the preservation of good faith and the revival of all our great
                        interests.</p>
                    <p>In the meantime, and as an essential preliminary to a successful effort for
                        the redemption of the Republic, we earnestly hope that the South will
                        continue to exercise the greatest prudence and moderation in its most trying
                        and critical circumstances. The hour is big with the future fate not alone
                        of the South, but of the whole country."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Baltimore Statesman predicted a Democratic victory in the next
                    Presidential election, so long as the Conservatives unite and act as a unit.
                    Also cautioned the South to exercise prudence and moderation until the election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Virginia Bible Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The object of this society, though generally known, it may be well to state,
                        is the distribution of Bibles and Testaments to the poor in our own State,
                        and to the heathen. Owing to the impoverishment incident to the late war,
                        the spiritual care of our own State, however, has more than required all the
                        resources of the organization. Persons of every religious creed or
                        denomination may become members of this society upon paying $2 annually; the
                        payment, however, of $30 in advance, will, without any further contribution,
                        constitute a person a member for life. None of its officers receive
                        pecuniary compensation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explained the purpose of the Virginia Bible Society, and how people can
                    become members.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.02.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the Episcopal Church will hold a fair in Union Hall. The
                    proceeds will help pay the debt incurred in erecting an iron fence around the
                    church yard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Library Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We publish below a letter issued to our citizens by the Library Association.
                        We are glad to know its prospects of success are very flattering, and we
                        hope so laudable and advantageous an enterprise will meet with encouragement
                        from all.</p>
                    <p>Staunton, Va., Feb. 19th, 1870.</p>
                    <p>SIR: -- It is sought to create a Circulating Library in this place, which it
                        is believed will be of great advantage to the community. Few of us can
                        afford to supply ourselves with large private collections of books, but by
                        the establishment of a well-selected Circulating Library every person, in
                        return for a small annual contribution, may have <sic>consant</sic> access
                        to a large and valuable collection, which will be rendered every year more
                        and more complete. Our effort has so far succeeded that we have already
                        opened a Library containing over a hundred volumes, which we hope you will
                        assist us by your subscription to increase, until finally a Library will be
                        established which will be a permanent institution -- a credit to our town
                        and an unfailing source of improvement to our people.</p>
                    <p>The terms of annual subscription have been sized at $3.50, of which only two
                        dollars thus far have been required. If one person in each household will
                        subscribe, the members thereof will have the use of one or two volumes a
                        week from the Library.</p>
                    <p>The benefit of your contribution and example is solicited. If the majority of
                        the families of the town will aid this scheme by one year's subscription,
                        its success will undoubtedly be secured.</p>
                    <p>THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS</p>
                    <p>Of the Staunton Library Association.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Library Association asked citizens to contribute to the
                    Library. In exchange, they will be allowed to check out volumes from the growing
                    collections of the library.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Carry Me Back to Old Virginia</head>
                <origin>Lynch. Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reported that a number of African-Americans who emigrated to
                    work on farms and railroads farther south now wish to return to Virginia. "It is
                    the experience, we believe, of whites and blacks alike, who emigrate from
                    Virginia, with the hope of bettering their fortunes, that they had better
                    remained at home."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogsett</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamrick</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>T. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vincent</ln>
                        <fn>F. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of a meeting in Moscow to thank the supporters of the Valley
                    Railroad and urge continued work to get the road built.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Timberlake</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. L. Timberlake and Miss Mary Ellen Humphreys, both of Staunton, were
                    married at the residence of S. N. Bagby on February 15th by the Rev. Mr.
                    Williams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drumheller</ln>
                        <fn>Napoleon J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gollady</ln>
                        <fn>Pennina E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Napoleon J. Drumheller and Miss Pennina E. Gollady, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Cline's Mill on February 17th by the Rev. A. A. P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Martin B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holland</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin B. Grove of Augusta and Miss Sallie A. Miller, daughter of the late
                    Joseph Miller of Rockingham, were married in Harrisonburg on February 10th by
                    the Rev. G. W. Holland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Alice Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alice Jefferson Whitmer, daughter of Daniel A. and Lizzie J. Whitmer, died
                    of pneumonia in Long Glade on February 12th. She was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaver</ln>
                        <fn>James Emory</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaver</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaver</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Emory Shaver, son of Andrew and Elizabeth E. Shaver, died of
                    pneumonia at Cline's Mill on February 16th. He was 5 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Fuller died at the residence of Mr. John S. Ellis on
                    February 14th. She was 76 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.02.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
