<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.04.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/15/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-04-11">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.04.11.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The War Declared at an End--Restoration of the Authority of the
                    Government--The Political Equality of all the States Declared</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the text of a resolution signed by President Johnson
                    declaring the rebellion of the Southern states over. The resolution asserts that
                    those states should be returned to equality under the constitution, and that
                    military occupation, suspension of the rights of habeas corpus, and other war
                    measures should be ended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The delegates appointed by the various Counties in the Valley, interested in
                        the organization of the Valley Railroad Company, assembled in Staunton on
                        the 4th of April, 1866.</p>
                    <p>Colonel Bolivar Christian, of Augusta, called the meeting to order, and on
                        his motion Judge H. W. Sheffey, of Augusta, was called to the Chair; and on
                        motion of Dr. T. W. Shelton, of Augusta, S. M. Yost, appointed Secretary.</p>
                    <p>The Chair briefly explained the object of the meeting, to be to take some
                        steps to secure the subscription of sufficient stock to comply with the
                        conditions of the Charter, precedent to the organization of the Company.</p>
                    <p>The following gentlemen reported as delegated from the counties named.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Roanoke</emph>--John Trout.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Botetourt</emph>--John J. Anderson, T. Henry Johnston, C.
                        Pendleton, Carey Breckinridge, W. H. McCue, W. E. M. Word and John W. Jones.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Rockbridge</emph>--D. E. C. Brady, William F. Pogue, A.
                        Patterson, H. B. Jones, Jacob Mohler, J. W. Hamilton, Coleman Yellott, J. B.
                        Dorman, J. T. Patton, and J. Whipple.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Augusta</emph>--J. B. Baldwin, T. J. Michie, George
                        Baylor, Franklin McCue, J. Wayt Bell, A. Mohler, D. Kunkle, H. W. Sheffey,
                        B. Christian, W. Allan, M. G. Harman, A. H. H. Stuart, Dr. T. W. Shelton, A.
                        McChesney, W. M. Tate, J. M. McCue, Dr. C. R. Harris, Thomas Gambill, W.
                        Crawford, Thos. Burke, Sr., General John Echols, Major James Walker, Charles
                        Grattan, D. S. Bell, Jacob Schreckhise, George Shuey, A. A. McPheeters, W.
                        A. Bell, W. A. Abney, J. Bell, David Craig, Jed Hotchkiss, Col. A. W.
                        Harman, Dr. John McChesney, A. G. Christian, Major John A. Harman, and Dr.
                        W. B. McChesney.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Rockingham</emph>--Colonel A. S. Grey, M. H. Effinger, P.
                        Bradly, J. C. Hill, J. S. Thompson, J. S. Rohler, A. W. Jones, S. M. Yost,
                        and W. M. Sibett.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Shenandoah</emph>--Dr. J. B. Strayer.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Berkeley</emph>--J. M. Ridgway</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Alleghany</emph>--James Burke.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Richmond City</emph>--A. M. Lee</p>
                    <p>On motion of Colonel Bolivar Christian, the Chairman appointed the following
                        committee to nominate permanent officers of the Convention: Messrs. Word, of
                        Botetourt; Trout, of Roanoke; Letcher, of Rockbridge; Christian, of Augusta;
                        Effinger, of Rockingham; Strayer, of Shenandoah; Ridgway, of Berkeley; Lee,
                        of Richmond City; Burke, of Alleghany.</p>
                    <p>The committee retired for a short time, returned, and reported the following
                        permanent officers, which report was adopted.</p>
                    <p>PRESIDENT--Colonel John T. Anderson, of Botetourt.</p>
                    <p>VICE PRESIDENTS--Judge H. W. Sheffey, of Augusta; Colonel A. S. Grey,
                        Rockingham; Dr. J. B. Strayer, Shenandoah; A. Patterson, Rockbridge; John
                        Trout, Roanoke.</p>
                    <p>SECRETARIES--S. M. Yost, Rockingham; A. M. Garber, Jr., Augusta; S. H.
                        Letcher, Rockbridge.</p>
                    <p>The Chairman appointed Colonel M. G. Harman and W. E. M. Word, to conduct
                        Colonel Anderson to the Chair.</p>
                    <p>Colonel A. returned thanks for the honour conferred upon him in a few
                        felicitous remarks.</p>
                    <p>Hon. A. H. H. Stuart moved that a committee of one member from each county
                        represented, be appointed to prepare and report business for the
                        consideration of the Convention.</p>
                    <p>The Chairman appointed the following gentlemen, as the Committee: Messrs. A.
                        H. H. Stuart, of Augusta; Dorman of Rockbridge; Johnston, of Botetourt;
                        Trout, of Roanoke; Burke, of Alleghany; Effinger, of Rockingham; Strayer, of
                        Shenandoah; Ridgway, of Berkeley; Lee, of Richmond City.</p>
                    <p>The committee, after an absence of an hour, reported the following
                        resolution.</p>
                    <p>REPORT.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> 1st, That it gives strong hope of the
                        success of the great enterprise in which we are engaged to find at this busy
                        period of the year, and in the present straitened circumstances of our
                        people, delegates from so many counties of the State, convened to devise the
                        best means for ensuring the construction of the Valley Railroad.</p>
                    <p>2d, That we deem the construction of a Railroad from the Potomac to the
                        Virginia and Tennessee Railroad, essential to the full development and
                        prosperity of the great Valley of Virginia, a result which can never be
                        accomplished by means of roads passing from mountain to mountain, across the
                        Valley and at right angles to the line of its production and wealth.</p>
                    <p>3d, That we regret that an improvement as essential to the welfare and growth
                        of one third of the State should, by any, be termed antagonistic to the
                        interest of any other part of the Commonwealth, to the commercial prosperity
                        of our cities, or as affecting injuriously the security of her investments
                        in internal improvements, and we think it can be demonstrated by argument,
                        and are sure it will be shown by experience, that such wealth cannot flow
                        from a course so fruitful of blessings to one of the great divisions of the
                        Commonwealth.</p>
                    <p>4th That the first steps to be taken by the friends of the proposed road, is
                        to cause to be opened, at suitable places, books of subscription to the
                        stock of the Valley Railroad Company, and that so soon as one thousand
                        shares of such Stock shall have been subscribed, a meeting of Stockholders
                        should be convened, and the Company organized in accordance with the
                        provisions of its Charter.</p>
                    <p>5th. That books of subscription be opened at such times and places as the
                        Commissioners named in the Charter deem most expedient.</p>
                    <p>6th, That as soon as the Company shall have been organized, its true policy
                        will be to form such connections with the Virginia Railroads between
                        Harrisonburg and the Potomac, as will afford such guarantees, founded on
                        unity of interest and concert of action as will tend to induce capitalists
                        from abroad to invest in this Stock of the Company, in accordance with the
                        regulations to be presented by the Board of Directors, and also to ensure
                        the cooperation of the cities of Baltimore, Philadelphia and other
                        commercial cities, in the speedy completion of the work.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Christian, offered the following amendment, which was adopted.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Stuart explained and enforced the report of the committee, in an able
                        speech of half an hour.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Christian read the provision of the Charter of the Valley Railroad, and
                        offered the following amendment to the report of the committee:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Amendment</emph>--That the Books for subscription of
                        Stock are to be opened <emph rend="italic">now</emph> and <emph
                            rend="italic">here</emph>; and in the opinion of the Convention, the
                        amount necessary to secure the Charter should be taken, and an organization
                        effected without delay.</p>
                    <p>That we hail with joy the prospect, held out by the acts of the Legislatures
                        of Virginia and West Virginia, of the speedy completion of the Covington and
                        Ohio Railroad; a work destined to pour into Virginia a full tide of
                        wealth--giving trade from the Valleys of the Ohio and the Mississippi, to
                        receive and distribute the outgoing and incoming currents of which will tax
                        the capacities of all the improvements of Virginia, including those of the
                        Valley Railroad, which we foresee will be one of the most valuable arteries
                        of the Great Central trunk line of commerce, attracting from districts and
                        cities lying North east as well as Southwest, of the point of intersection
                        of the two improvements, trade and travel which would not otherwise reach
                        the central improvement; and at that point receiving for distribution,
                        freight and passengers, which otherwise would now pass over the central
                        line.</p>
                    <p>7th, That we cannot close these expressions of our views, without declaring
                        the pleasure with which we have read the Proclamation of the President of
                        the United States, restoring Virginia, to the full enjoyment of her rights
                        as a State in the Union, and to her people the unobstructed privilege of
                        pursuing the arts of peace and of reviving the prosperity of the
                        Commonwealth.</p>
                    <p>General Echols, of Augusta, supported the resolution of Mr. Christian, in a
                        forcible, practical and eloquent speech.</p>
                    <p>Colonel M. G. Harman concurred in the able and eloquent remarks of Gen.
                        Echols, and appealed to every farmer and business man in the Valley, to
                        subscribe to the capital Stock to the extent of his ability.</p>
                    <p>The vote was then taken on the report of the committee, and the amendment,
                        and both were unanimously adopted.</p>
                    <p>Col. A. S. Grey, in the Chair. On motion of Mr. Word, of Botetourt, a
                        committee of two was appointed by the Chairman, consisting of Messrs. Word
                        and Christian, to wait upon Col. J. B. Baldwin, with a request from the
                        Convention that he appear to address them.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Stuart again addressed the Convention in a spirited and well conceived
                        Speech.</p>
                    <p>Colonel Baldwin made his appearance, and delivered a brief address, replete
                        with sound, practical sense, and earnest appeal.</p>
                    <p>Messrs. J. B. Dorman and Coleman Yellott, of Rockbridge, having been called
                        upon respectively by the Convention, delivered brief and appropriate
                        Speeches, which were received with evidences of gratification by the
                        audience.</p>
                    <p>At this point, Col. Harman announced to the Chair, that more than enough of
                        stock had been subscribed, to comply with the requirements of the Charter,
                        before the organization of a Company could be effected; and on his motion,
                        the Convention adjourned with a request from the President, that the
                        Stockholders meet in the Court House at 5 o'clock, P. M., to elect a
                        President and Directors.</p>
                    <p>John T. Anderson, President.</p>
                    <p>S. M. Yost, A. M. Garber, Jr., S. H. Letcher, Secretaries.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gambill</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grattan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPheeters</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the proceedings of the Valley Railroad Convention,
                    assembled to "take some steps to secure the subscription of sufficient stock to
                    comply with the conditions of the Charter." A list of delegates and officers
                    elected is also included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Stockholders of the Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Stockholders met at 5 o'clock, P. M.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Echols explained the object of the meeting to be the election of a
                        President and Directors, and the organization of the Valley Railroad
                        Company. On this motion, Col. John T. Anderson, of Botetourt, was called to
                        the chair, and S. M. Yost, of Rockingham chosen Secretary.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Echols, after paying a just and merited compliment to the great energy
                        and financial ability of the nominee, placed in nomination Col. M. G.
                        Harman, of Augusta, as a suitable person for the President of the Company.
                        No other person being in nomination, and the vote being taken <emph
                            rend="italic">vice voce</emph>, Col. H. was unanimously elected
                        President of the Valley Railroad Company.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Mr. Christian, the number of Directors was enlarged to eleven.</p>
                    <p>Mr. McCue, of Botetourt, nominated Edmund Pendleton, of Botetourt, as one of
                        the Directors, who was unanimously elected.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Letcher nominated D. E. C. Brady, of Rockbridge as one of the Directors,
                        who was unanimously elected.</p>
                    <p>Col. Gray nominated Mr. Harvey Effinger, who was unanimously elected.</p>
                    <p>N. K. Trout, of Augusta, nominated Dr. J. B. Strayer, of Shenandoah, who was
                        unanimously elected.</p>
                    <p>John Echols, Boliver Christian, Wm. Allen and John B. Baldwin, were nominated
                        respectively by Col. A. W. Harman, Judge H. W. Sheffey, Maj. J. A. Harman,
                        and Capt. Chas. Grattan, and unanimously elected.</p>
                    <p>Col. Pendleton nominated W. E. M. Word, of Botetourt, who was unanimously
                        elected.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Letcher nominated Jas. T. Patton, of Rockbridge, who was unanimously
                        elected.</p>
                    <p>Judge Sheffey moved that the proceedings of the Convention and the meeting of
                        the Stockholders be published in the newspapers of the Valley and that the
                        papers of the State generally be requested to copy them.</p>
                    <p>On motion the meeting adjourned.</p>
                    <p>J. T. Anderson,<lb/> President</p>
                    <p>S. M. Yost, Secretary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grattan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the proceedings of the meeting of the stockholders of
                    the Valley Railroad Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.04.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Greaver Case</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under orders to investigate the facts and report to him from Gen. Terry, this
                        case was brought before Capt. Tukey, of the Freedmen's bureau for
                        investigation of the so-called persecution of Alex Greaver, reported as a
                        "persecuted refugee and always a loyal Union man"--if he did bale hay and
                        forage faithfully for the Confederate States two years and only deserted
                        when ordered to take a musket. A large number of witnesses were examined and
                        so far the investigation seems to be going against this corn crib refugee,
                        so-called.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Capt. Tukey of the Freedman's Bureau has been
                    investigating under orders the case of Alex Greaver, a Confederate deserter and
                    self-proclaimed Union supporter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Imprisoned Chief</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Washington <emph rend="italic">Chronicle</emph> of the 5th report that a
                        current report says Ex-President Davis has made application for a writ of
                            <emph rend="italic">Habeus Corpus</emph>; his ground for so doing being
                        the President's peace proclamation. And why not? If the war is at an end and
                        a whole people declared restored to their rights, why should their
                        representative head be kept in prison? Jefferson Davis was but the agent of
                        eight millions of people and there is no true man among them who does not
                        feel that his imprisonment is wrong, while they whom he represented go free.
                        In this connection we quote a few sensible remarks on this subject from a
                        late member of the N. Y. <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph>. May we soon be
                        able to chronicle the glad tidings of Mr. Davis' release and return to his
                        home, friends, family and usefulness in the great work before us, The <emph
                            rend="italic">Herald</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>Jefferson Davis is not a criminal in the ordinary sense. His acts are lifted
                        out of the category of crimes by their national character. They are to be
                        judged in a different light from that in which we examine the common
                        offences against society for which we prepare the prison and the halter. In
                        the celebrated debate in Parliament on the American colonies Edmund Burke
                        recognized the difficulty of framing a bill of indictment against a whole
                        people. This same difficulty embarrasses the case of Davis. Where we can
                        allege any act against the United States that was his personally, and that
                        was not done by him as a representative of a people, who, according to the
                        dogmas on which our government is founded, had a full right to the exercise
                        of sovereign powers? Did Jefferson Davis wage war against us at Gettysburg,
                        on July 2, 1863? Then who was it waged war at Vicksburg, on the same day? If
                        we set about accusing of treason the whole people, whose will this man
                        carried out, from what stand-point shall we frame our accusation? Shall it
                        be from the standpoint of those in the government who maintain that the
                        Southern States are conquered territory, and, therefore, that the
                        confederacy was a foreign nation? Doubtless we should frame it from this
                        latter, as this is the view of those who clamor for the trial of Davis. But
                        if he was the ruler of a foreign nation, how shall we punish him for treason
                        against our government?</p>
                    <p>We must take in this case higher ground than any people or government has
                        hitherto had the moral courage to take. We must throw aside the ancient
                        fictions, and deal with facts as facts. We must recognize that men like
                        Davis have had their grand uses in the life of a nation; that they make
                        those stands and cause those wars that purify government and render it
                        impossible for it to become partial and tyrannical. Davis represented some
                        millions of men who believed that they were oppressed, and who rose with the
                        spirit of freemen. Shall we stultify our history--our immortal
                        declaration--by saying that the representative of all those men deserves
                        death for having been their representative? Where does government originate?
                        With the people--we declare by every fact of our history. And with how many
                        people if not with eight millions? We agree with the radical members that
                        Congress should take up the case of Davis, but we believe it should take it
                        up only to set him at large on these high grounds recognizing openly and
                        bravely as the sense of the American people that acts such as his do not
                        deserve death. We shudder as we read of the terrible acts of British
                        officials in Jamaica, who out barbarize barbarism; we shudder to contemplate
                        British judges sending men to twenty years penal servitude for the crime of
                        desiring a better government for their country. Let us be consistent with
                        these feelings, and set an example of national magnanimity that may put that
                        Power to the blush. Our cause does not call for any man's blood, and we must
                        not let partisan hatred put its bloody stains on our national history.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reprints portions of an editorial from the NY Herald supporting
                    the release of Jefferson Davis from prison. The article argues that Davis is not
                    a common criminal and cannot be charged separately from all the southern people
                    "whose will he carried out."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Educational</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that Rev. William A. Harris, President of the Martha
                    Washington College, Abingdon, has been elected and accepted as Principal of
                    Staunton's Wesleyan Female Institute. "We feel gratified to make this
                    announcement, as we feel no hesitancy in recommending him to the people of this
                    place and to those who wish to patronize this Institution as a man worthy in
                    every way of their support, Mr. Harris is a graduate of the Virginia Military
                    Institute at Lexington, and a native of Augusta Co. and ought to receive the
                    ready and hearty support of the people of the whole State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Southern Travel to the Virginia Springs. Importance of Advertising. Letter
                    From Mobile.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mobile, April 3, 1866</p>
                    <p>Lyttleton Peyton, Esq.--Dear Sir: I am indebted to a Richmond paper for your
                        name, and write you with the view of learning the exact locality of the
                        Virginia Hot and Healing Springs, and by what route from Lynchburg they are
                        reached.</p>
                    <p>If there should be mail facilities to that place, I would esteem it a
                        personal favor that you enclose and forward my letter to the Proprietors,
                        with the request that they write me the comparative quality between them and
                        those of Arkansas. My object is to visit those of Arkansas, but being
                        advised to the other--and being from Virginia--at an early age however,
                        prefer my native State. I am so much of an invalid tho' that my health and a
                        sound constitution is my only desire.</p>
                    <p>It would be well were these watering places advertised in this part of the
                        country--thousands would visit them, and many will this year.<lb/> Very
                        Respectfully<lb/> J. F. Saum</p>
                    <p>The above letter has been handed us by the Proprietors of the Virginia Hotel.
                        We publish it to show the importance to our Spring Proprietors, of
                        advertising the fact that they are prepared to accommodate the great travel
                        that wishes to visit our Mountains. The Virginian, having a large and
                        increasing circulation South, owing to our former connection with the press
                        there, is the best medium for the purpose. The route to reach the Hot or any
                        of the Springs from Lynchburg is <emph rend="italic">via</emph>
                        Charlottesville by rail to Staunton, thence by rail to Millboro' or
                        Jackson's River and from the Railroad that energetic stage man James I. A.
                        Trotter can take you, in good coaches to any of the Springs. There are
                        accommodations for all and a warm welcome.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Lyttleton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saum</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>James I. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper publishes a letter from a man in Alabama inquiring about the
                    feasibility of vacationing at the Virginia Springs. The editors stress the
                    importance of advertising to attract tourists to the Staunton area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Miscegenation in Staunton. Nobody Can Deny So Plain A Fact.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. John Scott, of Waterbury, Conn., to whom we alluded under the heading of
                        "Miscegenation in Staunton," in our last issue, sends us a communication in
                        which he makes his explanation of his conduct Sunday week. We give him the
                        benefit of his explanation. He can't see how any one could possibly "deny so
                        plain a fact." He says:--</p>
                    <p>"Under the above title appeared an article in the "Virginian," in which, from
                        a want of knowledge of facts, probably, the writer was <emph rend="italic"
                            >extremely severe</emph> in his denouncement of the conduct, of one whom
                        he called a "Disciple of Miscegenation," &amp;c. The facts were these;
                        which we give, hoping to correct a false impression.</p>
                    <p>At the close of Sabbath School, a pupil, wishing to obtain a hymn book, was
                        told, that those for sale were at our house. Being determined to obtain one,
                        she watched us start and came down the walk at the same time. We thought of
                        asking her to walk behind, lest we might be misrepresented. But the thought
                        that she was, as we supposed, known to be a pupil, and that we were going
                        nowhere else than from School home, and that it was known that our business
                        brings <emph rend="italic">us</emph> necessarily into contact with these
                        people, more than it does citizens, would, we thought, save us from being
                        misunderstood in our motives. As to "Miscegenation in Staunton" we will not
                        deny <emph rend="italic">so plain a fact</emph>; but <emph rend="italic">do
                            most emphatically deny</emph> being a "Disciple" ourselves, as no man
                        can be more opposed to the doctrine than we are, and have ever been."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John Scott writes a letter explaining his reasons for escorting an
                    African American woman down the street, which caused a scandal in Staunton.
                    Scott claims that the woman was a student walking with him to retrieve a hymn
                    book. Scott asserts that he does not support miscegenation, and he alludes to
                    the hypocrisy of many whites in Staunton who practice it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Judge Lucas P. Thompson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints a resolution of congratulations and gratitude from the
                    circuit court for Amherst county upon the appointment of Judge Lucas P. Thompson
                    to the State Supreme Court of Appeals. The resolution holds that "in discharge
                    of his duties as Judge of this, and other Courts of his circuit, he has not only
                    been faithful, but has displayed an ability and learning unsurpassed by few of
                    any age our country, and with a firmness, impartiality and pureness surpassed by
                    none, and which entitles him to the admiration of all." Furthermore, "in his
                    private walks, as well as upon the Judicial bench, Judge Thompson has proved
                    himself to be the honest, upright and honorable man, the patriotic and faithful
                    citizen, and the perfect gentleman."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Ladies Soldiers Cemetery Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The ladies, wish to enclose the ground, have the graves turffed, and marked
                        with stone or board as contributions justify, flowers and shrubbery planted,
                        those lying in unprotected places through the country removed to this
                        Cemetery and the place kept in order. All communications on this subject
                        should be addressed to the Ladies Soldiers Cemetery Committee, Staunton.</p>
                    <p>Papers properly authenticated by this Committee will be given collectors to
                        prevent imposition.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces the plans of the Ladies Soldiers Cemetery Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper remarks that "nearly every town in Virginia is raising funds to
                    enclose and ornament the Soldiers' Cemeteries."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Brutal Murder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krat</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Amos Krat, Esq., "was brutally murdered by a negro
                    at his residence, near Shadwell Depot, Albemarle County, Va., last week. He left
                    a large family to mourn his loss."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper expresses its pleasure to learn "that the work of removing the
                    Confederate dead to the Stonewall Cemetery, in Winchester, is progressing
                    rapidly. All honor to the noble women of Winchester who inaugurated and pushed
                    forward this patriotic work."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles E. Wood and Miss Lizzie M. Ast, both of Staunton, were married on
                    April 5th by the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James McCutchen and Miss Sallie Crist, both of Augusta, were married on
                    April 5th by the Rev. Mr. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. L. Hill and Miss Elizabeth Kunkle, both of Augusta, were married on
                    April 3rd by the Rev. T. Hildebrand.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Devericks</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rogers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. M. Devericks and Miss Mary Rogers, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 29th by the Rev. T. Hildebrand.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chittum</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tresham</ln>
                        <fn>Annie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whisner</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James A. Chittum and Miss Annie A. Tresham were married on March 22nd by
                    the Rev. P. H. Whisner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>William Byron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Byron Ast, aged 7 years, died in Staunton on April 4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.04.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Meredith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that according to "a gentleman, who says he knows,"
                    "every indication of oil has been discovered on the farm of our friend Meredith
                    Hogshead, near Middlebrook."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Progress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that the renovations to the American Hotel are nearly
                    done. "When they are completed and the new furniture arrives, the American Hotel
                    will surpass itself, and under the management of that perfect gentleman and
                    gallant officer, Col. Charles T. O'Ferrall will be second to no house in the
                    United States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Stage Line From Lexington to Bonsack's</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Col. M. G. Harman is planning to "place a line of
                    four-horse coaches on the road from" Lexington to Bonsack's, which is on the
                    Virginia and Tennessee Railroad. "He is a man of energy and enterprise, and we
                    trust his efforts to accommodate the travelling public will be appreciated and
                    adequately rewarded."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Corporation Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherer</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolen</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>T. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reagan</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>H. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the proceedings of the Staunton court. Licenses "to
                    keep hotels and retail spiritous liquors" were granted to: G. A. Peyton and Co.;
                    J. B. Sherer; William Kenney; Mrs. B. Bolen; T. E. Coleman; Beck and Beard;
                    Charles T. O'Ferrall; H. L. Reagan; A. Lynn; Ker, Stevenson and Co.; H. F.
                    Richards and Co.; and J. T. Arnall "to keep private entertainment." The
                    overseers of the poor "were ordered to bind out, according to law, two negro
                    children."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Corporation Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>David A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunch</ln>
                        <fn>George G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports the results of elections in Staunton. The following were
                    elected: N. K. Trout, Mayor; Jacob Parrent, Chief of Police; J. B. Sherer, W. B.
                    Kayser, James W. Crawford, Benjamin F. Points, W. H. Wilson, R. J. Hope, A. M.
                    Bruce, W. L. Balthis, J. M. Hardy, John B. Evans, and Robert G. Bickle,
                    Councilmen. At the April 5th meeting of the Council, the following were elected:
                    James F. Patterson, Clerk; William B. Keyser, Recorder; James W. Crawford, 1st
                    Alderman; John B. Evans, 2nd Alderman; W. H. Wilson, 3rd Alderman; John M.
                    Hardy, 4th Alderman; R. J. Hope, 5th Alderman; A. M. Bruce, 6th Alderman; J. T.
                    Parrent, Chief of Police; W. B. Kayser, Commissioner of Streets; R. W. Smith,
                    Superintendent of Water Works; John R. Kurtz, Assistant to Chief of Police;
                    David A. Keyser, George G. Bunch, and John B. Sherer, Committee of Safety.
                    "There was no excitement at the election, and the only old officer dropped was
                    C. R. Mason, as he was likely to be absent from the town and did not desire
                    re-election."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Mr. Hanger and Mr. Hoover are planning to start
                    "an extensive broom factory" at Churchville in October.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that citizens of the Valley were disappointed at Gov.
                    Wise's failure to attend the Valley Railroad Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper comments that physical improvements to the town of Staunton are
                    continuing. "New fences are being made and the town is generally putting on its
                    Summer suit."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Churchville Oil Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterritt</ln>
                        <fn>F. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Henry E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the results of the meeting of the Churchville Oil
                    Company. The following officers were elected: Dr. Hamilton, President; Gen. John
                    R. Echols, W. Allen, Chesley Kenney, Capt. F. F. Sterritt and Henry E. Hoover,
                    Board of Directors. "Sufficient stock has been subscribed to commence the work
                    and the indications are pronounced most favorable."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Cleaning Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the work on the streets continues, but some people
                    in town refuse to help the Commissioner in his efforts to clean and prevent
                    disease. The Shoe Factory, "commonly called 'Noah's Ark' from the amount and
                    variety of the human family it contains," is one of the worst offenders. "Some
                    seventy-five negroes are living there and can't be got out. We are glad to learn
                    that the Directors will meet to-morrow and give the subject such attention as we
                    hope will abate the nuisance."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Great Valley Railroad Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The proceedings of this Convention will be found on our first page. It was
                        largely attended and after some skirmishing, went to work the right way. The
                        well known energy of the officers elected and the enthusiasm of the people
                        on this subject, give every guarantee that the road will soon be put under
                        contract. One great point is to unite it and the Manassas Gap Railroad, and,
                        we have every reason to hope that object will soon be accomplished. A
                        noticeable feature in the Convention, was, the enthusiasm that the mere
                        mention of the name of the glorious City of Baltimore, gave rise to. In a
                        few days, we feel confident, we can send good news to our people about the
                        Valley Railroad.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the work done at the Valley Railroad Convention, and
                    discusses plans to unite the Valley Railroad and the Manassas Gap Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.04.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Literary items and advertisements appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
