<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.10.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/01/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-10-10">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">10</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.10.10.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Solitude of Single Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that the solitude of single women is not as frightening
                    as many young unmarried girls might imagine it to be. In fact, in old age many
                    people find solitude enjoyable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.10.10.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What are We to Do?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Valley <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph>, though thoroughly State
                        Rights, and southern in its sentiments, has not deemed it necessary or
                        politic to enter into any discussion as to the merits of our "lost cause,"
                        or the course of prominent actors in it. We all, no matter what our
                        sentiments were before the war, now believe we were RIGHT, and as for the
                        particular views of anyone, they are not of enough importance, in the
                        presence of the great practical issues now upon us, to require more than a
                        passing notice. Times have changed, and men change with them. A great
                        revolution, a gallant and glorious struggle for independence, has moulded
                        us, as one man in our confidence in the justice of the cause for which we
                        fought and lost so much. The past is behind us, and the future stares us in
                        the face with no pleasing aspect. We are all in the same boat; breakers are
                        around us, and it behooves every lover of his country to forget past
                        prejudices and work with one heart and hand to reach the shore of safety--of
                        practical independence. How to do this is the question that should occupy
                        the earnest thought of all, and every one should devote heart, soul, and
                        body to its successful solution.</p>
                    <p>The Southern people are placed in a position to fully test their manhood and
                        their greatness. The greater the obstacles to be overcome, the more honor in
                        overcoming them. After a determined struggle for separate independence, the
                        "power of overwhelming numbers and resources" forced us to yield, on certain
                        conditions. The only authorized powers of the U. S. Government offered them:
                        First, Grant, the Commander-in-Chief, paroled the body of our population,
                        and we have faithfully observed the terms of that parole. Next, Andrew
                        Johnson, President of the U. S., issued an amnesty proclamation, and laid
                        down rules for the practical reorganization of the Southern States. We
                        accepted the terms, and have carried out our part of the contract to the
                        letter, and to their satisfaction, and we hoped for peace. But the party
                        which, by its interference with our rights, under the Constitution, brought
                        on the war, is not satisfied. New tests are originated; our plighted word,
                        accepted by Grant and Johnson, they pretended to doubt, and with hellish
                        malignity, they harass us at home and prevent emigration and capital from
                        coming to our relief. Peace, the Radical party does not want, for peace to
                        it means loss of power. They desire the condition of society in the South to
                        be unsettled; and, to accomplish this object, they use every means to incite
                        the ignorant colored population to deeds of violence, which renders life and
                        property insecure among us, and gives their party a rallying cry about our
                        "barbarities." Poor, disarmed, robbed, plundered--nothing but the nerve and
                        iron will of the President has saved us from a fate worse than any people
                        ever met. And, for all this, we have but the consoling, thought that we have
                        done our duty, and come what may, no blame can rest on this people for the
                        result.</p>
                    <p>And, again; the oft repeated question, "What are we to do?" comes up. Ah!
                        "what are we to do?" Every man, every woman, every child in the South,
                        earnestly asks that question, and an almost sickening feeling comes over one
                        at some thoughts it brings us. But still, amid all the doubt, we were about
                        to say despair, of the future, one encouraging fact looms grandly to the
                        front, a beacon of light, a morning star of hope, to this sorely oppressed
                        and troubled people. It is that <emph rend="italic">we have gone to
                        work</emph>. A settled determination has taken possession of us, as a
                        people, that our earthly salvation lies in obeying God's first law, that "by
                        the sweat of your brow you shall live." And there is hope, there is life,
                        there is material and political independence in this stern fact, as hard as
                        has been the way in which it has been forced upon us. There is something in
                        this spirit, too, that should be heeded by the money-loving Yankees; it is a
                        spirit that says we "will fight the devil with fire;" that whatever is of
                        material interest or value in your way of life we will adopt and excel you
                        in, leaving to you the <emph rend="italic">isms</emph> and the crack-brained
                        follies of the day. We will show you that we can and will rise superior to
                        you in every department of trade, manufactures, and commerce; we will, in
                        spite of your oppressions, absorb the best portion of your population, and
                        with our delightful climate, our inexhaustible resources, our unsurpassed
                        water power, demonstrate to the world that the Southern people are to be the
                        people of this continent. This is the feeling that has been created by what
                        the Radicals have done, and time will show whether the Southern race has the
                        nerve, the endurance, the patience, to carry it out.</p>
                    <p>We believe they have; we have a firm faith in the substantial qualities of
                        our people; in their pride, and in the kindness of an All Wise Father, who
                        has permitted us to be oppressed sorely, to show us the true path to follow
                        in the future. And what of the negro in this grand future? some may ask.
                        That question is to be answered by the negro. If he is the man, and has the
                        sense to work with our people, he is safe; if not, then he will be crushed
                        under the feet of the irresistible giant, progress. Our people are ready and
                        willing to employ and help these people, but they must help themselves, and
                        if they do not, God alone can forsee their fate.</p>
                    <p>So amid all the gloom and despondency of the present, we see a bright gleam
                        of hope in the future; and if this people, who have endured so much; who
                        have achieved so much, are only true to themselves; to their past and their
                        honor; and <emph rend="italic">work</emph>, our future will surpass the
                        wildest dreams of the most sanguine.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors declare that the political situation is dire for the South.
                    After meeting defeat on the battlefield, their "independence" is threatened by
                    the policies of Congressional Republicans. The only solution lies in work, and
                    development of the South's manufactures and trade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Proposed Constitutional Amendment--So Called</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We had intended to analyze this "bill of abominations" more particularly, but
                        we find the work so well and ably done by Ex-Governor Wm. S. Sharkey, of
                        Mississippi, in a letter to Gov. Humphries, of that State, dated September
                        17th, that we feel confident we can't do much better than quote from it.
                        Gov. Sharkey was an honest and consistent Union man during the war, and he
                        deems this a question of such importance that he writes his views to the
                        Mississippi Legislature, now in extra session. Mark well what he says!</p>
                    <p>"But let us look, for a moment, at the provisions of the proposed amendment.</p>
                    <p>"The first section declares that 'All persons born or naturalized in the
                        United States, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, are citizens of the
                        United States, and of the State wherein they reside.' It then proceeds to
                        prohibit the States from making or enforcing any law 'which shall abridge
                        the privileges or immunities of citizens.'It does not say what are
                        privileges and immunities; that is left for the next Congress to provide in
                        virtue of the last session which declares 'that Congress shall have power to
                        enforce, by appropriate legislation, the provisions of this article.' We may
                        find Congress conferring 'privileges and immunities' on one class to the
                        exclusion of another class; or we may find Congress assuming absolute
                        control over all the people of a State and their domestic concerns, and this
                        virtually abolishes the State. Perhaps any State that has so little
                        self-respect as to adopt the amendment, deserves no better fate."</p>
                    <p>"The second section, if my construction of it be right, would probably
                        exclude one State from representation in Congress, as I suppose the number
                        of male negroes over twenty one to be nearly equal to the number of white
                        males. It is, therefore, a mere effort to force negro suffrage upon us,
                        whether we are willing or not. Either do this or you shall have no
                        representation. It is presumed that our intelligent people would hesitate
                        long in making their choice.</p>
                    <p>"The third section provides that no person shall hold any office who may have
                        heretofore taken an oath to support the Constitution of the United States,
                        and who afterwards engaged in the rebellion, or who gave aid and comfort to
                        those who did engage in it. This is a sweeping act of disfranchisement,
                        which would embrace, perhaps, a majority of our citizens; for there are
                        probably few who have not, in some way or other, taken an oath to support
                        the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>"Even those who opposed secession, and engaged in the war only under
                        compulsion, would be embraced by this provision, as well as the man who had
                        given to a hungry soldier a meal's victuals or a piece of bread; and also
                        all those who, in charity, had given an article of clothing to a suffering
                        friend or relative in the army. Such a provision would be so contrary to the
                        theory of our Government, and so oppressive towards a very large class of
                        the population of the Southern States, that it cannot be supposed that those
                        who proposed it could have entertained a hope that it would be accepted.
                        They ought to have known, too, that such a provision was calculated to
                        endanger the existence of the Government, as revolutions may always be
                        expected, sooner or later, from acts which disfranchised the enfranchised
                        class. If the people cannot exclude unworthy or undeserving men from office
                        by the instrumentality of the ballot box, then they are unfit for
                        self-government, and the sooner they abandon the experiment the better.</p>
                    <p>"I need say nothing of the fourth section, but the 5th is the Trojan horse
                        abounding in mischief. It provides that 'Congress shall have power to
                        enforce, by appropriate legislation, the provision of this article,' which
                        may be construed to authorize Congress to do whatever it may desire to do.
                        Under this same provision, attached to the emancipation amendment, you have
                        the Civil Rights bill and the Freedmen's Bureau bill. It was construed in
                        the Senate, just as I admonished many members of the Legislature it would be
                        to authorize these odious measures. We should profit by the experience it
                        has furnished us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints and supports ex-Mississippi Governor Sharkey's analysis of
                    the 14th Amendment. Sharkey declares it to mean the destruction of the States in
                    favor of the tyranny of Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Mulatto Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the term "Mulatto" has been used to designate "that
                    despicable set of rascals," white "Southern Loyalists." "We object to the term.
                    It is an insult to respectable colored people, and does not convey a proper idea
                    of the lowest depths reached by this sort of people. 'Southern Yankees,' are the
                    only two words that do."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The 32nd</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The 32nd Regt. of Virginia militia was organized at New Hope on Saturday,
                    and officers were selected. "We are glad to learn that the members of the
                    Regiment showed good sense in electing good officers and leaving the 'ground
                    hogs' out in the cold. We cannot be too particular who we elect to offices now."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Our Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that Staunton's schools are opening "with increased
                    numbers and the most flattering prospects. No town or city in the State can
                    boast of better schools, more refined society, and better health than Staunton."
                    The paper also supports plans of the Catholic Church to establish a college in
                    Staunton if they can purchase Fairy Hill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A correspondent of the Richmond Dispatch comments on the energy, industry,
                    and bustle of Staunton. "Nearly everybody appear to be up to something, and "up
                    to snuff" also. What the Stauntonians don't know isn't worth knowing. During my
                    stay I did not see a man whittling sticks! as in some other towns I
                    visited--Charlottesville for instance."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.10.10.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper comments that "interesting religious revivals still continue
                    throughout the Valley."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Post Office at Willow Spout, Augusta County, has been closed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that marriages are on the increase, while emigration to
                    California is decreasing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Fire Company's Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Fire Company is arranging a fair to raise funds for a library, "and the
                    Ladies should aid them. Let it be a Fair and Supper worthy of the Company and of
                    the Town."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Old Barber Shop</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have intended for some time to notice that Thos. Campbell, the well-known,
                        obliging and respected colored barber of Staunton, is still holding forth at
                        his old stand under the Virginia Hotel. Tom, like his father before him, is
                        a Conservative colored gentleman, in every way worthy of the large patronage
                        he receives. He is an example of what good manners, honesty and correct
                        deportment will do for a colored man.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper discusses a prominent African American business in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Hire Your Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our country friend would do well to look about them now for the hands they
                        intend to work the coming year. Search out the most reliable and industrious
                        among the negroes, and make your contracts with them at once. Be fair and
                        just in the wages offered; pay them promptly according to the terms of your
                        contract, and many of the difficulties of which complaint is made of this
                        kind of labor will be avoided.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper offers advice for contracting with freedman laborers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Encourage Home Manufactures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds T. L. Hoover for his "enterprise and energy" in opening
                    a broom factory in Churchville. "He opens a new field for the profitable
                    industry of our farmers, and he will sell as cheap or cheaper than Northern
                    merchants. The road to independence lies in sustaining such enterprises, and the
                    sooner our people see it the better."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Police Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duglas</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barrister</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Deputy Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew Taylor, "colored, was arrested on complaint of Henry Duglas, for
                    stealing his coat." Justice Evans discharged him for lack of evidence. Henry
                    Duglas and Marshall Barrister, "colored, were arrested for whipping Andrew
                    Taylor and taking the coat from him." They failed to "give security for good
                    behavior" and were sent to Jail and the coat was returned to Taylor. John Hurley
                    was arrested for being drunk and disorderly and was placed in Harlan's Hotel.
                    All the arrests were made by Deputy Sergeant Kurtz.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Colored Churches</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The congregation under charge of Parson Lawson have the foundation for their
                        large Church, on the Sceely lot, finished. The plans for a fine Church have
                        been drawn by Prof. Oltman, and an estimate of the cost is being made. This
                        congregation has some $2,000 on hand, part of it a donation from Mr. Scott,
                        of Philadelphia. They are very sanguine of soon creating a building that
                        will accommodate their large congregation and be a credit to the town. They
                        have the best wishes of the community in their undertaking. Work will be
                        commenced on the Bethel Church next month. It is situated on the road to the
                        Cemetery. They expect to erect a small, but handsome Church. The manner in
                        which the colored people have managed to raise the means for building these
                        Churches, and the enterprise they show, reflects great credit on them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Parson</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oltman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on church building activities in Staunton's African
                    American community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Town Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the meeting of the town council. Mayor Trout presided
                    and all the justices were present except Wilson, Balthis, Hope and Points. The
                    Commissioner of Streets issued a directive requiring anyone having a cellar
                    entrance on any of the streets to furnish it with an iron door on a level with
                    the pavement. The Committee appointed to examine Lewis Creek reported on the
                    survey and level, and were next instructed to estimate the cost of widening and
                    deepening the stream between Spring Lane and the Tilt Hammer. The Overseers of
                    the Poor were requested to repair a report on the number of paupers in town, and
                    the amount of money being expended on them. H. H. Peck, who leases the Gas
                    Works, was allotted $21 per annum in coin for each lamp post in the town which
                    should be lit with gas until 12 o'clock at night "during all dark nights." The
                    Commissioner of Streets was asked to prepare a report estimating the probable
                    cost of repairs to all the town's streets. The Superintendent of Water Works
                    reported the works in good condition with 12 inches of water above the pipe at
                    the spring. Bills were sent to citizens for hydrant repairs to the amount of
                    $118.70.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bedinger</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bedinger</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rust</ln>
                        <fn>A. T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perkins</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry B. Michie, of Staunton, married Virginia Bedinger, daughter of the
                    late Henry Bedinger, of Jefferson County, on October 3rd. The wedding was held
                    in Loudon County at "Rookland," the home of the bride's uncle, Col. A. T. M.
                    Rust. The Rev. Edmund T. Perkins presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Symington</ln>
                        <fn>W. Stuart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>Lelia W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meade</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. W. Stuart Symington, of Baltimore, and Miss Lelia W. Powers, of
                    Staunton, were married on October 8th at the Episcopal Church, Staunton, by the
                    Rev. William H. Meade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret Lynn</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. George M. Cochran and Miss Margaret Lynn Peyton, both of Staunton,
                    were married on October 4th at the Staunton residence of Col. John B. Baldwin.
                    The Rev. James A. Latane presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Charles D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>J. Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles D. McCoy married Minnie Jenkins, daughter of J. Taylor Jenkins of
                    Baltimore, on October 9th. The Rev. James A. Latane presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hahn</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. A. Whitmore, of Augusta, married Miss Mary A. Hahn, of Rockingham, on
                    September 26th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. J. Gilkeson, aged 78 years, died at his residence near Mint Spring,
                    Augusta Co., on October 9th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeago</ln>
                        <fn>Jane T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Jane T. Yeago died on October 9th in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.10.10.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
