<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.02.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/27/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-02-14">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.02.14.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Admiral Semmes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Admiral Semmes has written a bold, manly and eloquent letter to President
                        Johnson, demanding his rights under the parole given by Sherman, at
                        Greensboro, N. C.</p>
                    <p>Frank, fearless and able as is this letter in all its parts, it is the
                        concluding paragraph which will linger longest in the thoughts of most men.
                        Right bravely and worthily does the proud old Admiral, speaking as an
                        American citizen to the Chief Magistrate of the American Republic, say:</p>
                    <p>"We live in times of high party excitement, when men, unfortunately, are but
                        too prone to take counsel of their passions; but passions die, and men die
                        with them, and after death comes history. In the future, Mr. President,
                            <emph rend="italic">when America shall have a history</emph>, my record
                        and that of a gallant Southern people will be engrafted upon and become a
                        part of your history, the pages of which you are now acting; and the prayer
                        of this petition is, that you will not permit the honor of the American name
                        to be tarnished by a perfidy on those pages. In this paper I have stood
                        strictly upon legal defenses; but should those barriers be beaten down,
                        conscious of the rectitude of my conduct throughout a checkered and eventful
                        career, when the commerce of half a world was at my mercy, and when the
                        passions of men, North and South, were tossed into a whirlwind by the
                        current of events of the most bloody and terrific war that the human race
                        had ever seen, I shall hope to justify and defend myself against any and all
                        charges affecting the honour and reputation of a man and a soldier. Whatever
                        else may be said of me, I have at least brought no discredit upon the
                        American name and character."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes part of a letter in which Confederate Admiral Semmes
                    writes to President Johnson to demand restoration of his rights. He includes a
                    vindication of the South and its actions, asserting that "whatever else may be
                    said of me, I have at least brought no discredit upon the American name and
                    character."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Unknown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following, which we take from the Jackson (Mississippi) <emph
                            rend="italic">Standard</emph>, of the 13th Jan., deserves a place in the
                        standard books for reading for the young--aye, and for the middle aged and
                        the old.</p>
                    <p>In the Vicksburg <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph>, of the 11th inst., we
                        find the following couplet said to be an inscription over the grave of a
                        Confederate soldier in Alexandria cemetery:</p>
                    <p>"Unknown," is all the epitaph can tell;<lb/> If Jesus knew thee, all is well.</p>
                    <p>Those touching and simple lines are suggestive of many sorrowful reflections.
                        They bring up from the mighty past thronging memories of the thousands of
                        noble and ardent soldiers of the South, who went forth with flashing eyes
                        and springing steps in defence of their native land, but who never more will
                        return to gladden the hearts of their kindred. Some of them sealed their
                        devotion to liberty with the blood of their young and gallant hearts.
                        Others, toiling through the scorching rays of summer and shivering in the
                        cold blasts of winter, without food or adequate clothing, yielding to
                        privation and disease, and finally perished on the terrible march, in a land
                        of strangers, with no gentle hand to alleviate the agencies of death.
                        Others, taken captives on the red field of battle, were immured in Northern
                        dungeons, and, like caged eagles, dropped and died.</p>
                    <p>All over this broad Southern land are hundreds and thousands of little mounds
                        of earth, beneath which moulder the remains of our gallant defenders, with
                        no stone or monument to designate the pale sleepers. We know they are
                        soldiers' graves--we know nothing more. Many of the nameless dead were
                        volunteers from other States; and in many cases the very mothers who nursed
                        them in infancy are ignorant of their fate. Perchance, even yet, at many
                        distant homesteads, mothers and fathers and sisters, sustained by illusive
                        hope, peer through the gloom of twilight, trusting that they may hear
                        returning footsteps, destined never more to be heard in the walks of men.
                        The little hillocks which mark the resting place of the "unknown" soldiers
                        of liberty will soon be levelled and obliterated. Over their remains the
                        buzzing multitude will tread. The memory of themselves and their deeds of
                        valor, and their terrible suffering and sacrifices, will fade from all
                        minds, and oblivion will add their names to those of the innumerable
                        multitude of Adam's sons who have thus perished and been forgotten. In the
                        language of the epitaph which heads this article, we reverently say:</p>
                    <p>"If Jesus knew thee, all is well."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints an excerpt from an article in the Jackson, Mississippi,
                    Standard memorializing the unknown Confederate dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.02.14" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares that "Congress is still hammering away at the
                    everlasting nigger."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper claims that "the negroes on the Sea Islands, near Charleston,
                    refuse to permit the whites to land."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares that "it would be a public benefit to tie Garret Davis
                    and Thaddeus up in a bag together and let them scratch each other to death. If
                    the contest was not terminated in sixty minutes, throw in Ben Wade."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>How We Are Belied</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We had the pleasure of meeting two respectable gentlemen from New York, last
                        week, who were here on a visit to see the Country and make investments if
                        possible. They told us that the people North, who wished to settle in the
                        Valley, were deterred from doing so, by reports of the unsettled condition
                        of the Country, and the danger of being killed by "blood-thirsty rebels."
                        They left convinced that these stories were all false--and expect to come
                        back and settle in the Valley. We pronounce all such stories false. Since
                        the soldiers have been removed from the Valley, peace and quiet have
                        prevailed. We want the right sort of immigration and a heap of it. Our
                        people will give to them "an old Virginia welcome," and a glance at the
                        "Land Directory" we publish, will show settlers, from the North, the chances
                        for fortunes, and good homes offered.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains that rumors circulating in the North about violent
                    conditions in the South prevent the "right sort" of immigrants from coming to
                    the Valley. The truth of the matter is, state the editors, that "since the
                    soldiers have been removed from the Valley, peace and quiet have prevailed."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Prepare For Cholera</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Staunton residence to follow the lead of other cities in
                    "clearing up and removing filth" to prevent cholera. "It is true that the
                    Cholera never prevailed here as an epidemic, but it or worse, will certainly
                    come, unless our town authorities take steps at once, to remove the last four
                    year's accumulation of filth from our streets and alleys. We call particular
                    attention to the condition of the alleys, and some of the back yards in town."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>A Question of Importance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper, in announcing the printing of "an appeal from the colored people
                    of Selma, Ala.," declare that "the sooner our people turn their attention to the
                    education and management of the Freedmen, the better it will be for all
                    parties."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Ephriam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoof</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ephriam Kerr, aged 54 years, and Miss Margaret S. Hoof, aged 21 years, were
                    married on January 18th by the Rev. Robert Smith. Both bride and groom were from
                    Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ham</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClanahan</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. J. Ramsey and Miss Lucy A. Ham, both of Augusta, were married on
                    February 1st by Rev. W. S. McClanahan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landacre</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Robinson, of Augusta, married Miss Hannah Landacre, of Hardy county,
                    on January 12th. The Rev. Peter Miller presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hart</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel W. Hart, aged about 24 years, died in Greenville on January 26th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.02.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Mr. H. Risk, county liquor inspector, reports that
                    3,871 gallons of whiskey were made in Augusta in the month of January.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "several freedmen" entered William's Shoe Store and
                    stole $60 worth of goods.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Corporation Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>William Scott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ailinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harry</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzgerald</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports the proceedings of the February term of the Corporation
                    Court of Staunton. The Grand Jury returned three bills of indictment for petit
                    larceny against William Scott Graham, alias Ailinger, David S. Harry, and John
                    Fitzgerald. Harry plead not guilty, and Fitzgerald was sentenced to 10 days in
                    the County Jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Home Development</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that H. J. Lushbaugh has nearly completed work on the
                    foundry and machine shop buildings of Roberts, Nelson and Co., on the old mill
                    property. "The building is of the most substantial character, like all the work
                    of these master mechanics. The moulding room is 40 by 90 feet and 30 feet high,
                    estimated cost 3,500. The machinery will cost 4,000. When completed the Foundry
                    will employ some thirty or forty hands. This is the right way to carry on the
                    work of reconstruction."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Good News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Barnett, the leader of the Stonewall Band having arrived in Staunton, it
                        will be rapidly re-organized and by practice, raised to its old high
                        standard. We understand that the patriotic gentlemen composing the band
                        intend to give their first Concert in Staunton, for the purpose of raising
                        funds to enclose our soldiers graves, outside of Thornrose Cemetery, with a
                        neat fence and to give each grave a head board. The Stonewall band was held
                        in high favor in the A. N. Va., and we feel confident their reputation will
                        never diminish under their able leader, Mr. Barnett.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces the re-organization of the Stonewall Band in Staunton,
                    and its plan to give a benefit concert to raise money for the care of soldiers'
                    graves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Dead at Gettysburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A letter, from a Southern lady, from Gettysburg, to the Miss. <emph
                            rend="italic">Clarion</emph> confirms our previous statements in regard
                        to the condition of our dead there. Their graves will soon be ploughed up,
                        and all marks of their last resting places obliterated. A place is set apart
                        in the National Cemetery for them, and their friends can have them removed
                        at a small expense. We have already published a list of Virginia's buried
                        dead there, and have sent for a list of the dead from the more Southern
                        States, which we will publish soon. Any one having friends buried there, can
                        hear about them by writing to L. B. Waller of Staunton.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waller</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the status of Confederate graves at Gettysburg, and
                    gives information for Staunton residents wishing to inquire about friends buried
                    there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>All Right</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Tukey, the Assistant Superintendent of the Freedman's Bureau in this
                        place, has been to Richmond and did not demand troops to be sent here, but
                        only asked enough to enforce a summons if necessary. Now our people might as
                        well look facts in the face and obey the summons of the Freedman's Court. It
                        is folly to commence fighting after the war is over, and we are happy to
                        state that the cordial co-operation of the civil authorities with Mr. Tukey
                        makes it certain that no troops will be brought here. If any one refuses to
                        recognize a summons from the Freedman's court, the civil authorities will
                        make the arrest.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper encourages Staunton residents to cooperate with the Freedmen's
                    Court in order to prevent the return of Federal troops to town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.02.14.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Touching Appeal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A number of Freedmen in Selma have published an appeal to their former
                        masters, concluding in the following earnest but respectful terms:</p>
                    <p>Dear Friends and Former Masters:--We know there is a large number of widows
                        and crippled men, who are well educated, and have no employment by which to
                        make a living. These persons we should be pleased to see taking an interest
                        in teaching our children and training them up in the way they should go. We
                        are greatly in want of schools, and to persons who will establish them we
                        will guarantee our undivided support. Our own people are the proper ones to
                        teach us, and we sincerely wish them to do so. And why should they refuse?
                        They raised and taught us all that we know, as carpenters, blacksmiths,
                        stone and brick masons, painters, &amp;c., including working on the
                        farm, driving &amp;c., and were not ashamed or backward in performing
                        this service. And why should it be considered a disgrace to make a living at
                        this business in the South? We make our living out of the people here, and,
                        therefore, we think it our duty to spend our money with those who sustained
                        and took care of us.</p>
                    <p>The United States Government and your State Convention gave us our freedom,
                        and we prefer you to any other to have the money derived from our daily
                        labor for teaching our children. If you all stand back, strangers will come
                        in and take the money from your hands and carry it away to build up their
                        own country. <emph rend="italic">They</emph> are not ashamed to make money
                        from any class of men.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints an appeal from a group of African Americans in Selma,
                    Alabama, asking their former masters to provide schools and teachers for the
                    children of freedmen. If the Southern whites do this, the writers argue, then
                    they can guarantee "undivided support." If the southern whites "stand back" then
                    "strangers" from the North will step in and fill the role.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
