<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.02.21">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>5/27/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-02-21">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">21</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.02.21.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Straightest Sect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that "the straightest sect" is the new nickname for the
                    "consistent Union men at the South during the war." "The name is very
                    appropriate, when we recollect that the title is scripturally applied to the
                    Pharisees, who were the falsest and most contemptible of hypocrites."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "a delegation of colored men" called on the
                    President and that Frederick Douglass "urged that the right of suffrage should
                    be given the colored race among other rights." The President replied that "he
                    would not adopt a policy which would result in danger to the colored race, and
                    possibly lead to a war of races."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.02.21.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What Are We To Do?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is useless to deny that the course persued by the Radicals in Congress and
                        their evident determination to grind the Southern people into the dust, if
                        they can, has caused a general feeling of distrust in the South, and
                        produced the desire among many of our most respectable and worthy citizens
                        to emigrate to Mexico or anywhere, so as to be relieved of the present
                        painful feeling of insecurity for the future. The Southern people went into
                        the war for independence honestly; they staked their all upon the issue and
                        when they lost it they honestly submitted to the arbitrament of the sword.
                        They were willing to give the North all it won in the fight and they have
                        performed their part of the contract. They were not "erring brethren" or
                        foolish children, who were led off by "scheming politicians" and it is an
                        insult to their intelligence and manhood to think so. One of the most
                        radical mistakes the Northern people have made is to suppose for an instant
                        that we were not in earnest and were led like sheep to the slaughter. Our
                        people went into the war with their eyes open and they forced politicians to
                        do their bidding. It is true they miscalculated the result, but that does
                        not make us fools or any the less men. And the sooner the people North will
                        realize this fact the sooner all will be well in the United States--and
                        President Johnson's policy carried out.</p>
                    <p>It was hard to be conquered; it was hard to furl the banner that had floated
                        in triumph over so many glorious fields; it was hard to give up cherished
                        hopes and fond anticipations of a separate nationality; it was hard to reap
                        such bitter fruits from four years suffering and privation and accept the
                        result; it was harder still to trudge over weary miles, with the shout of
                        the conqueror ringing in your ears, to desolated homes--but all this we did
                        and nothing the Southern people endured during the war adds so much to their
                        honor and glory, as the honorable manner in which they have carried out the
                        pledges made to Grant at Appomattox. But now after all; after we have
                        performed our part and accepted the pledges of Grant and Johnson, it is
                        harder still to be threatened with new penalties and forced to live in a
                        constant state of uncertainty and doubt.</p>
                    <p>It is not that we doubt the will and determination of Andrew Johnson to do us
                        justice, but the fear that the mass of the people North are so imbued with
                        Radicalism, that nothing but our extermination will satisfy them. It is this
                        feeling that creates the desire to leave home and friends and settle in a
                        foreign land. Carry out President Johnson's policy; fulfil the pledges made
                        by Grant at Appomattox and afterwards approved by Johnson, in his amnesty
                        proclamation; then, will the Southern people go to work with a new life and
                        energy and the idea of leaving the country be abandoned. We can not think
                        the people of the North are fools or radicals and we hope soon to see the
                        latter overthrown. If the honest, conservative sentiment, is as overwhelming
                        North as reported we will soon see a change, and we can not see anything for
                        our people to do now but to await the result of the coming conflict between
                        President Johnson and the Radicals as patiently and as bravely as they
                        endured the storms of the last four years. There is much to do in our
                        country; everything is to be "reconstructed" and wealth untold is ours if
                        energy and good sense direct our labors. Let the radicals do their worst, we
                        surely can wait for the development of their policy before we leave our
                        homes and all we hold dear, to be occupied by strangers. And, after all,
                        this is a good country to live in and it is our duty to live and labor here.
                        The widows, the orphans of our dead are left a sacred heritage to us. A land
                        made glorious by the deeds of Jackson, Lee and a host of brave hearts is
                        still ours. By making it prosperous and wealthy; by working as a people
                        never worked before, we can say, come what may, "we have done our duty."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial argues that the course of the radical Republicans in
                    Congress has left Southerners distrustful. Southerners, the editors argue,
                    accepted defeat and kept all the promises made at Appomattox, only to be
                    "threatened with new penalties and forced to live in a constant state of
                    uncertainty and doubt." Nevertheless, the editors urge Southerners to patiently
                    await the result of conflict between President Johnson and Congress in the hope
                    that conservatism will prevail in the North. They owe nothing less to the memory
                    of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Battle Fields of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the "five beautiful maps" of the Battle of
                    Chancellorsville drawn by Jed Hotchkiss and Col. Allan for their book, "Battle
                    Fields of Virginia Topographically Illustrated." "Thoroughly familiar, as these
                    gentlemen are with the subject of which they treat, they bring to its
                    illustration maps from surveys taken immediately after the battles, and with
                    great minuteness of detail, which alone must render their work without equal in
                    interest to the students of history, the visitor to the memorable fields or to
                    those still living, on either side, that, soldier like, in talk must fight their
                    battles over again." Soldiers should "rejoice to know that the record of their
                    deeds is thus impartially transmitted to their posterity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Western Lunatic Asylum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The last report of the Directors of this institution is before us, embracing
                        the fiscal years of 1863, '64 and '65. The report of the Physician and
                        Superintendent is full of interest, to those who have a feeling for our
                        unfortunate fellow man, whom God has afflicted so severely. Notwithstanding
                        the Superintendent labored under all the inconveniences during the war,
                        which fell to the lot of the private citizens and heads of families, the
                        Asylum, under his skillful management, is now in a comparatively flourishing
                        condition.</p>
                    <p>The Asylum was established in the year 1825, with an appropriation of $10,000
                        for the purchase of land and the erection of buildings. At that time, but
                        little attention was devoted to the cause of this class of unfortunates--the
                        friends of the insane, were averse to placing them in "mad houses." The
                        notions of that day were in keeping with the lack of improvements, and the
                        managers of this Institution had many difficulties to contend with.
                        Prejudices and difficulties gradually gave way--the horrors of the "mad
                        house" were applied to the dark ages. As the pick and shovel removed the
                        soil to make room for that noble structure, now the pride of our State, so
                        were the minds of the people and the Legislature cleared of unfounded
                        prejudices, and to-day Insane Asylums are fixed facts.</p>
                    <p>Since the original buildings were constructed, there have been nine additions
                        there-to, and the Asylum has grown from a capacity for <emph rend="italic"
                            >thirty-two</emph>, to a size to accommodate over four hundred persons;
                        supplied with steam, gas, &amp;c., and a chapel with a splendid organ,
                        the gift of W. W. Corcoran, Esq., of Washington City.</p>
                    <p>The History of the Asylum discloses some curious and interesting facts--there
                        have been under treatment, at different times from its establishment to the
                        present report, 1921 patients, of these since 1836, 537 have died, 781 have
                        been discharged, 148 restored, 73 unimproved and 307 remain under treatment.
                        Of patients treated during the last ten years, 23 became deranged because of
                        "the war"--from disappointed love, 7; from intemperance and dissolute
                        habits, 30; from religious excitement, 9; from political excitement, 1; from
                        the use of tobacco, 5; jealousy 4; idleness 5--of those who have died in the
                        last two years, fifty-three resided in the Institute from 5 to 30 years.</p>
                    <p>The able and interesting reports of Dr. Francis T. Stribling disclose the
                        fact, that the cases placed under his care in the earlier stages of
                        insanity, yield much more readily to treatment, than those of long standing.
                        The Statistics of the Asylum clearly prove that, "Home with its
                        associations, is of all other places, the most objectionable as a residence
                        for the insane;" and the Doctor urges his fellow citizens "to watch with
                        care the earliest manifestations of mental disorder" in their families or
                        friends; and use no delay in placing them under the restraints and
                        kindnesses of the Asylum. He deprecates the use of false pretences to decoy
                        them to the Institute, and shows the bad effects of such. He says it
                        destroys their confidence in human nature, and renders the influences of the
                        Asylum of less avail.</p>
                    <p>The Superintendent pays a handsome tribute to the value of the press to the
                        unhappy inmates. He also alludes in fitting terms to the happy results of
                        the labors of the various Ministers of the Gospel, who have from time to
                        time officiated at the Chapel.</p>
                    <p>We extract the following which speaks for itself--"on the 4th of March,
                        General Sheridan's command made an assault upon the meat house, flour house,
                        store room and other buildings, bearing off and destroying about 180 barrels
                        of flour, 10,600 pounds bacon, 300 bushels corn and a considerable quantity
                        of hay--135 bushels of rye and oats--wagon and carriage harness, 50 pairs
                        coarse shoes--many articles or wearing apparel from the Laundry and 3
                        valuable mules. I promptly and earnestly announced to the officer in
                        command, the character and object of the Institution; cited the number of
                        the unfortunate insane under our care--apprised him of the difficulties we
                        had encountered in obtaining the supplies, and the danger, that if removed,
                        they could not be replaced--but without avail! It is gratifying to add, that
                        none of this party intruded within the buildings occupied by patients of
                        either sex--a happy circumstance! for which I felt well assured from careful
                        observation, we were more indebted to the forbearance of the privates, than,
                        to any restraints imposed by their officers."</p>
                    <p>The indebtedness of the Asylum is stated at $25,779. The State is asked to
                        make the necessary appropriations for the support of the Institution, and
                        judging from the remarkably economical manner in which the Institution has
                        been conducted, not a cent more than necessary is asked for.</p>
                    <p>A perusal of Dr. Stribling's reports will repay the reader. The most striking
                        facts connected with the Institution are: the peculiar adaptation of the
                        buildings, and grounds--the astonishingly small sum they have cost the
                        State, (less than any similar building of its capacity in the United
                        States,)--the system of blending kindness with firmness--the gratifying
                        results, in fact the thorough and complete adaptation of this grand
                        Institution and its management to the work in hand.</p>
                    <p>Without detracting from the credit due others, it may be said that to Dr.
                        Stribling belongs the gratitude of the friends of the insane, the State and
                        the Country, for his labors in developing a correct system of treating the
                        diseased mind. His name will occupy a high place upon the honored roll of
                        benefactors of the human race.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corcoran</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article discusses the history and present conditions of Staunton's
                    "Western Lunatic Asylum." Special emphasis is placed on the Director's Report
                    for fiscal years 1863, 1864, and 1865, including a discussion of an encounter
                    with Sheridan's troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loynes</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Loynes, of Shepherdstown, married Miss Harriet Cease, of Staunton, on
                    February 15. The Rev. J. I. Miller presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. J. Greiner, of Rockbridge, and Miss Sallie McGuffin, of Greenville,
                    were married by the Rev. William Pinkney on February 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mays</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James Mays "an old and respected citizen" of Staunton died on February
                    16. He was 60 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Alice Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alice Kate Dull, aged 28 months and 2 days, died near Greenville on January
                    23.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.02.21.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mays</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that "another old citizen has passed away." James Mayse
                    froze to death near his residence. "Being very old and infirm he fell and was
                    found Saturday morning, in forty yards of his own door, a corpse. Mr. Mays was
                    known as one of the kindest hearted and most useful men in Staunton. Peace to
                    his ashes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Direct Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that "some $17 or $18,000 have already been collected"
                    in Augusta County. The whole tax was about $28,000 but exemptions will reduce it
                    by about $1,500. The collector will remain in Staunton two weeks longer, and
                    those who have not yet paid are urged to get out and do it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Where Are the Street Commissioners?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces the "filthy conditions of our streets and alleys," and
                    asks that the street commissioners "look to it at once and take measures to
                    prevent sickness in the Summer." The paper reports that $500 have been
                    appropriated for the purpose, and asks that it be spent at once.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>Urban D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Urban D. Poe and John Paris have been appointed
                    Notaries for Augusta County by the Governor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a Masonic Lodge called Lee Lodge has been organized
                    in Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Painter</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Levell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hare</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Miss Julia Painter, from near Greenville, was jailed
                    for stealing a hog. Also, Mr. James Levell was committed and charged with
                    passing a counterfeit twenty dollar bill in an exchange with John O'Hare.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls on the people of Staunton to join in a mass meeting on
                    Court Day, February 26, in support of President Andrew Johnson and his policy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Water Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that there is a "debt of $17,000 on the Corporation for
                    the water works." The editors note that no general water tax has ever been
                    collected, and argue that the works should earn enough money to help pay the
                    debt. A $1 tax on each hydrant is currently in effect, and the paper supports
                    hiring a regular Superintendent to repair hydrants and pipes, and "furnish an
                    account to the Council for collection."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.02.21.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Ashes of Glory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Fold up the gorgeous silken sun,<lb/> By bleeding martyrs blest,<lb/> And
                        heap the laurels it has won<lb/> Above its place of rest.</p>
                    <p>No trumpet's note need harshly blare--<lb/> No drum funereal roll--<lb/> Nor
                        trailing sables drape the bier<lb/> That frees a dauntless soul!</p>
                    <p>It lived with Lee and decked his brow<lb/> From Fate's empyreal Palm;<lb/> It
                        sleeps the sleep of Jackson now--<lb/> As spotless and as calm,</p>
                    <p>It was outnumbered--not undone;<lb/> And they shall shuddering tell<lb/> Who
                        struck the blow its latest gun<lb/> flashed ruin as it fell.</p>
                    <p>Sleep, shrouded Ensign! not the breeze<lb/> That smote the victor tar,<lb/>
                        With death, across the heaving seas<lb/> Of fiery Trafalgar.</p>
                    <p>Not Arthur's knights, amid the gloom<lb/> Their knightly deeds have
                        starred;<lb/> Nor gallic Henry's matchless plume,<lb/> Nor peerless born
                        Bayard!</p>
                    <p>Not all the antique fables feign,<lb/> And Orient dreams disgorge;<lb/> Nor
                        yet the Silver Cross of Spain,<lb/> And Lion of St. George.</p>
                    <p>Can bid thee pale! Proud emblem, still<lb/> Thy crimson glory shines<lb/>
                        Beyond the lengthened shades that fill<lb/> Their proudest kingly lines.</p>
                    <p>Sleep! in thine own historic night,--<lb/> And be thy blazoned scroll;<lb/> A
                        warrior's Banner takes its flight<lb/> To greet the warrior's soul!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes the following poem by S. J. Requine honoring the
                    Confederate dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
