<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1866/va.au.vv.1866.07.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/21/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-07-04">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1866.07.04.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article announces that engineers from the B. and O. Railroad, under
                    Richard Randolph, have arrived in Augusta County to begin planning a route for
                    the Valley Railroad. They have established headquarters near Mt. Crawford. The
                    editors also take the opportunity to expound upon the importance of the railroad
                    to the Valley economy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1866.07.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Valley Virginian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors of the Valley Virginian celebrate seven months of print and
                    claim that their paper has "a larger circulation in Staunton and the vicinity
                    than any other paper published here and a large and increasing circulation in
                    the Valley." They claim to be surpassing the Spectator as a Staunton
                    institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Historical Parallel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The determination of the present Radical Congress of the United States, to
                        exclude the Southern States from representation; while the people of these
                        States are oppressed and burdened with Federal taxation, has given rise to
                        just and universal complaint upon the part of the people thus outraged--and
                        we trust has aroused the indignation of all good men living North.</p>
                    <p>Our complaints are reasonable and must be so regarded by all men who respect
                        the history of American independence, and reverence the sanctity of the
                        Constitution, for the supposed preservation of which the United States
                        Covenant has just emerged from four years of bloody war. Now that the
                        Constitution and laws are said to have been fully violated when the
                        government, if left alone, would be more firmly established than ever
                        before, we find its rulers, and pretended friends, deliberately setting
                        themselves to work, to undermine and destroy it. The enemies whom the
                        government has just [unclear]; who declared themselves as grieved, and
                        defied her in the field. Now [section unclear]. [Unclear] the legislative
                        branch of the government has been for the time entrusted, have defiantly,
                        and treasonably, combined themselves together, to subject the liberties of
                        the people and do treat that Constitution which each of them has solemnly
                        sworn to uphold and defend. If the grievances of the South were imaginary
                        [section unclear], there can be no question that they are real now, and no
                        government conducted upon the principles proposed by these bad men can long
                        succeed or sustain itself. Look to the Declaration of Independence, the
                        grievances there enumerated, are then literally a catalogue of our wrongs;
                        except the forms are infinitely greater in degree. Let us refer to a few of
                        the principal charges against that [unclear] King George III.</p>
                    <p>[section unclear]. "He has suffered to render the military independent of,
                        and superior to civil power."</p>
                    <p>"For quartering large bodies of armed troops among us."</p>
                    <p>"For imposing taxes on us without our consent."</p>
                    <p>How true a picture this presents of the wrongs of the Southern people; and
                        yet who can fail to recognize in them ample justification for the course
                        taken by our forefathers--who declared at the same time that among the
                        unalienable rights of men, "are life, liberty and the pursuits of happiness;
                        that to secure these rights, governments are instituted among men, deriving
                        their just power from the consent of the governed." These same revolutionary
                        fathers, as soon as the present government was established, engrafted into
                        the Constitution as one of the cardinal features of that instrument, that
                        representation and taxation should go hand in hand together, according to
                        population. And yet in spite of all these plain facts, this Radical Congress
                        are deliberately at work to remodel the government upon principles which
                        were exploded a century ago; and which are opposed to the fundamental idea
                        upon which this government was originally constructed.</p>
                    <p>They may succeed by these desperate means, in retaining for a time power in
                        their own hands; which is doubtless all they look to, and care for; but can
                        anything but evil come from this infamous work? These are not new
                        questions--tyrants and bad men have attempted the same schemes frequently
                        before. In this Country and England however, these are ideas which have been
                        so fully ventilated, and rendered so odious, that for nearly a century no
                        man had been found so wicked and reckless as to avow them, until the meeting
                        of the present Congress. But we will conclude by giving a few sentences from
                        a speech made 100 years ago, by the celebrated Lord Camden, one of England's
                        profoundest jurists and ablest statesmen, delivered in the House of Lords,
                        upon the bill to tax America.</p>
                    <p>"Nor, my Lords, is the doctrine new; it is as old as the constitution; it
                        grew up with it; indeed, it is its support; taxation and representation are
                        inseparably united. God hath joined them, no British Parliament can put them
                        asunder; to endeavor to do so, is to stab our very vitals. My position is
                        this--I repeat it--I will maintain it to my last hour--taxation and
                        representation are inseparable; this position is founded on the laws of
                        nature; it is itself a law of nature; for whatever is a man's own, is
                        absolutely his own; no man has a right to take it from him without his
                        consent, either expressed by himself, or representative; whosoever attempts
                        to do it attempts an injury; whosoever does it commits a robbery; he throws
                        down and destroys the distinction between liberty and slavery. Taxation and
                        representation are coeval with, and essential to, the constitution. I wish
                        the maxim of Machiavel were followed--that of examining a constitution, at
                        certain periods, according to its first principles; this would correct
                        abuses and supply defects. * * * There is not a blade of grass growing in
                        the most obscure corner of this kingdom which is not--which was not
                        ever--represented since the constitution began; there is not a blade of
                        grass which, when taxed, was not taxed by the consent of the
                    proprietors."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial compares the South's grievances with Congress to the
                    grievances of the American revolutionaries of 1776 with King George III.
                    Southerners are facing taxation without representation, and an oppressive armed
                    force in their towns and cities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Examination at the Augusta Female Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grey</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fruston</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Martha C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meade</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>N. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the closing exercises of the Augusta Female Seminary,
                    and prints the names of the students who passed various exams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Virginia Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayers</ln>
                        <fn>M. Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wynkoop</ln>
                        <fn>J. Adelaide</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>L. Nelson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article describes the closing "soiree' at the Virginia Female
                    Institute which was attended by the "beauty and elite of the city." The room was
                    decorated with an emblem of the "conquered banner, in the shape of a shield, red
                    and white, and brilliant with the 'thirteen bright stars.'" Piano and vocal
                    music pieces entertained the audience, and the Rev. Mr. Latane, President of the
                    Board of Directors, addressed the graduates and presented diplomas. The paper
                    prints the names of the graduates. "This deservedly popular seminary is in
                    charge of the Rev. Mr. Phillips, who, together with a competent corps of
                    teachers, spares no pains in the proper education and training of the young
                    ladies committed to his care."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Closing Exercises and Examination at the Institution for the Deaf, Dumb, and
                    the Blind.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ridenhour</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Chiltree</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edwards</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steinspring</ln>
                        <fn>Ida</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pollard</ln>
                        <fn>Paxton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holmes</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clements</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ford</ln>
                        <fn>Martha J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woody</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Childs</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mays</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catlett</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diggs</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamb</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woody</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hancock</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on the closing exercises of the Institute for the Deaf,
                    Dumb, and Blind. An organist, pianist, and orchestra made up of blind students
                    performed. The paper describes a variety of academic tests completed by the
                    students. Deaf mute students wrote answers on blackboards, and blind students
                    did math using wood blocks. Fractions, long division, geography, history,
                    natural philosophy, French, and geometry were among the subjects highlighted.
                    The paper prints the names of the students who won academic awards and performed
                    well in the tests. "Too much credit cannot be given to the energetic Directors
                    of the Institution, nor too much praise bestowed upon the well-ordered and able
                    corps of Instructors, who are doing, and have already done, so much towards the
                    amelioration of the sad fate of these poor unfortunates."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1866.07.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports an increase in travel. Last week, 301 people arrived at
                    Staunton's hotels: 178 at the American and 123 at the Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F. T.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>L. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>De W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following "Augusta boys sustained the reputation of the County by their
                    good conduct and proficiency at the University of Va." A. H. H. Stuart, Jr., F.
                    T. Stribling, Jr., L. T. Phillips, De W. C. Gallaher, and N. Van Lear.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Staunton S. S. Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>G. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Candler</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton S. S. Union held a meeting at the Baptist Church and agreed
                    upon permanent organization. The following officers were elected: William H.
                    Peyton, President; A. M. Simpson, 1st Vice President; G. T. Baker, 2d Vice
                    President; D. E. Strasburg, Secretary, and W. D. Candler, Treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Rebellious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors sarcastically suggest that Thad Stevens pass an amendment to
                    prevent McCormick Reapers from using a "reel" that could be mistaken for the
                    Confederate Battle Flag. "We and several other ex-rebels thought we saw the old
                    'battle flag' waving in a wheat field, but on a nearer view we discovered" that
                    it was one of the reapers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Fourth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To-day is the anniversary of the biggest "rebellion" on record, but it
                        differed from our little affair in being successful, which makes its
                        "treason" respectable and ours "odious." We hear of pic-nics, fishing
                        parties, &amp;c., and people generally are preparing to enjoy
                        themselves. The Grand Jury meets to-day, and some hundred witnesses have
                        been summoned to appear before it. Ain't it "treason" to hold Grand Juries
                        on the immortal Fourth? We understand that a number of persons desired to
                        read the "Declaration of Independence," but on examining it and consulting
                        very "loyal" authority, they concluded it was a treasonable document and
                        instead of doing so have, either determined to go a fishing or obey the
                        summons of the Grand Jury."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper discusses observations of the Fourth of July in the Valley. The
                    editors state that only failure distinguished the Confederate cause from the
                    American Revolution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Grand Concert By the Presbyterian Choir</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gives a good review of the Presbyterian Choir concert which
                    raised $200.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Masonic Procession</head>
                <origin>Old Commonwealth</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that Eureka Lodge, Bridgewater, celebrated the 23rd of
                    June with a procession, address, and dinner. It included all the lodges in the
                    area. Col. O'Ferrall, of Staunton, acted as Marshall. The group marched through
                    the streets to the M. E. Church where the choir performed and Dr. C. R. Harris,
                    of Mt. Solon, addressed the crowd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jamison</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>N. H. Anderson and Miss Maggie M. Jamison, both of Staunton, were married
                    on June 28th by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. A. Wilson and Miss Agnes A. Long were married on June 28th by the Rev.
                    Mr. Preston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bettie H. Miller died in Augusta County on May 7th. She was 12 years, 1
                    month, and 7 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1866.07.04.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Conquered Banner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>[Republished by Request]</p>
                    <p>Let that banner down, 'tis weary,<lb/> Round its staff 'tis drooping
                        dreary;<lb/> Furl it, fold it, let it rest,<lb/> For there is not a man to
                        wave it--<lb/> For there is not a sword to save it,<lb/> In the blood that
                        heroes gave it;<lb/> And its foes now scorn and brave it--<lb/> Furl it,
                        hide it, let it rest.</p>
                    <p>Take that banner down, 'tis tattered,<lb/> Broken is its staff and
                        shattered,<lb/> And the valiant hosts are scattered<lb/> Over whom it
                        floated high.<lb/> Oh, 'tis hard for us to fold it,<lb/> Hard to think
                        there's none to hold it--<lb/> Hard, that those who once unrolled it,<lb/>
                        Now must furl it with a sigh.</p>
                    <p>Furl that banner, furl it sadly;<lb/> Once, six millions hailed it
                        gladly,<lb/> And ten thousand, wildly, madly,<lb/> Swore it should forever
                        wave--<lb/> Swore that foreman's sword should never,<lb/> Hearts like theirs
                        entwined, dissever:<lb/> And the flag should float forever<lb/> O'er their
                        freedom, or their grave.</p>
                    <p>Furl it, for the hands that grasped it.<lb/> And the hearts that fondly
                        clasped it,<lb/> Cold and dead, are lying low;<lb/> And that banner, it is
                        trailing,<lb/> While around it sounds the wailing<lb/> Of its people in
                        their woe.<lb/> For though conquered, they adore it--<lb/> Love the cold
                        dead hands that bore it;<lb/> Weep for those who fell before it,<lb/> Pardon
                        those who trailed and tore it;<lb/> Oh, how wildly they deplore it,<lb/> Now
                        to furl and fold it so.</p>
                    <p>Furl that banner, true, 'tis gory,<lb/> But 'tis wreathed around with
                        glory,<lb/> And 'twill live in song and story,<lb/> Though its folds are in
                        the dust;<lb/> For its fame on bright pages,<lb/> Sang by poets, penned by
                        sages,<lb/> Shall go sounding down the ages--<lb/> Furl its folds, though
                        now we must.</p>
                    <p>Furl that banner, softly, slowly--<lb/> Furl it gently, it is holy,<lb/> For
                        it droops above the dead;<lb/> Touch it not, unfurl it never,<lb/> Let it
                        droop there, furled forever,<lb/> For its people's hopes are fled.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a poem honoring the Confederate flag.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Reply to the Conquered Banner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By An English Woman</p>
                    <p>Gallant nation foiled by numbers,<lb/> Say not that your hopes are fled;<lb/>
                        Keep that glorious flag that slumbers,<lb/> One day to avenge your
                        dead.<lb/> Keep it, widowed, sonless mothers,<lb/> Keep it, sisters,
                        mourning brothers;<lb/> Furl it with an iron will,<lb/> Furl it now, but
                        keep it still.<lb/> Think not that its work is done.<lb/> Keep it till your
                        children take it,<lb/> Once again to hail and make it<lb/> All your sons
                        have bled and fought for<lb/> All their noble hearts have sought for,<lb/>
                        Bled and fought for all alone.<lb/> All alone! aye, shame the story,<lb/>
                        Millions here deplore the stain,<lb/> Shame alas! for England's glory<lb/>
                        Freedom called and called in vain.<lb/> Furl that banner sadly, slowly,<lb/>
                        Furl it gently for 'tis holy,<lb/> Till that day, yes, furl it sadly,<lb/>
                        Then once more unfold it gladly--<lb/> Conquered Banner! keep it still.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a poem replying to the poem honoring the Confederate flag.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
