<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1865/va.au.ss.1865.12.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/06/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-12-19">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1865.12.19.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Bishop Glossbrenner's Reply</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. J. Glossbrenner</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glossbrenner</ln>
                        <fn>Bishop</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In the latest letter in a long running controversy, Bishop Glossbrenner
                    defends his claim that "the colored race" should be "protected in their persons
                    and property before the law as is the white man," but also rejects the notion
                    that he is "in favor of amalgamation and miscegenation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1865.12.19.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond Dispatch illustrating the short sighted policy of the "Richmond
                        Merchants" is virtuously indignant at the "startling propositions" of the
                        Baltimore and Ohio Railroad to build a branch from Winchester, along the
                        Valley, to Salem. The Dispatch says 'its effect would be divert from
                        Richmond much of the trade and traffic which our people have for years been
                        led to expect from Southwest Va., and the Valley. This simply means that
                        Baltimore would thus afford a market so much better than Richmond, that the
                        people of Southwest Va., and the Valley would trade with Baltimore because
                        it would be their private interest and resist this opportunity for the
                        Valley producers to seek better prices than Richmond merchants will give.</p>
                    <p>The Legislature is invoked to "consider" the matter. We trust it will do so
                        for the sake of the interest of the great producing portion of the people
                        which it equally represents with that of the "Commission Merchants" -- a
                        class useful enough, perhaps, but still which lives upon the profits arising
                        from this very want of facilities which requires a "middle-man" between
                        producer and consumer.</p>
                    <p>We admit the propriety of giving the preferences to our own State business
                        men, but calm that the "reciprocity" should not require our State producers
                        to make a sacrifice for the sake of increasing profits at the expense of
                        these very producers -- equally our own State citizens.--Just thirty years
                        ago, Baltimore proposed to build a railroad throughout the Valley, from
                        Harper's Ferry to the Tennessee line, and with a branch from Staunton to the
                        Ohio River, and not only not tax the people to build it, but actually
                        offered to pay a bonus forever into the State Treasury for the privilege.
                        But the Richmond merchants, naturally enough, defeated it by appeals to
                        "build up your own cities" -- and by promises that the Valley should have a
                        better market is not yet offered to counteract the greater expense of
                        getting to Baltimore. Meantime our producing community has been heavily
                        taxed to build roads, and all the while borne the tax upon their produce
                        consisting in the different of cost and time required to reach the beset
                        market amounting in thirty years to millions of dollars. This fact, alone
                        has discouraged thousands of our people, and sent them off to seek in mere
                        favored lands the just reward labor.</p>
                    <p>If our country had reached its maximum of production there night be some
                        excuse for controlling the disposition of its products to build up
                        particular cities. But when the capacity of production has been scarcely
                        tested, sound policy would seek to encourage the producer to his utmost, and
                        expect thus eventually, and more surely, to build up cities in which the
                        surplus production seeks its market.</p>
                    <p>In that very western country to which many of our farmers have in this last
                        thirty years been driven, the freest competition in choice of markets has
                        been granted, and, in consequence, all along these competing railroads the
                        "villages" of this thus developed region now exceed Richmond in wealth and
                        population.</p>
                    <p>The cost, and thus tax, upon the producer of getting his produce to market by
                        a railroad is increased by each additional mile of railroad -- the charge
                        being by the mile. Now a railroad from Staunton, for instance, to Baltimore,
                        would be something over 200 miles long, while to Richmond, by a short track
                        direct from Charlottesville, would be little over 100 miles, a difference of
                        100 <emph rend="italics">per cent</emph>. If Richmond fears competition with
                        Baltimore under the great difference, for the Augusta trade, it indicates
                        heavy charge upon this trade <emph rend="italics">to force</emph> it to go
                        to Richmond, notwithstanding. And to carry out the policy of requiring
                        Virginia to trade with Richmond, merely because it is in Virginia,
                        regardless of cost to the producer, would be to <emph rend="italics"
                        >compel</emph> the citizens all over the State, no matter how near to
                        Baltimore, and better prices for their products, to bring them to Richmond
                        that her merchants should make fortunes.</p>
                    <p>It is time such suicidal policy were abandoned. Let the Legislature now
                        "consider" how it can best develop the unlimited resources of the State's
                            <emph rend="italics">producing</emph> wealth, on which all other wealth
                        at last depends, and then it will follow, as the night does the day, that
                        "our own cities" will find their true prosperity, and be "built up"
                        permanently. Let her commission merchants and her local papers go to work,
                        like Baltimore, and build avenues that will induce trade there; let them
                        make, for instance, the "short track," so long <emph rend="italics"
                        >talked</emph> of, from the Valley to Richmond, thus bringing almost the
                        whole Valley nearer to Richmond than to Baltimore, and let them cease
                        whining because, without these facilities, people are left simply to sell
                        where they can sell highest and buy where they can buy cheapest. Hercules
                        helps those who put their own shoulders in the wheel.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Addresses the proposition of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad to build a
                    line from Staunton to Baltimore, decried by Richmond merchants as a measure that
                    would sap their commerce. The author claims that the Legislature should abandon
                    the "suicidal policy" of forcing producers to trade in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gen. Grant on Reconstruction</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Gen. Grant favors the immediate admission of the Southern
                    Congressmen-elect and suggests that with Grant and Johnson advocating "the cause
                    of forbearance, mercy, and justice, we may look forward with confidence to the
                    speedy reconstruction of the Union."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Southern Members</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "some of the more Radical presses are softening their tones
                    very much since they have scanned the President's firm language on the subject
                    of the relation of the Southern States to the Union" in his recent message,
                    published in an earlier issue of the Spectator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the National Valley Bank of Staunton was granted a charter on
                    Tuesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Strong Support</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that President Johnson's latest message, as well as his
                    Reconstruction policy, "seems to have won the approbation of the leading presses
                    of the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1865.12.19.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hengst</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ella Hite, of Augusta, and J. G. Riley were married on December 7 in
                    Baltimore by the Rev. Benjamin Hengst.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shields</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shields</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Shields and James Collins were married on November 9 by Rev.
                    George Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiner</ln>
                        <fn>Harman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Louisa Harrison, of Augusta, and Harman Hiner were married on December 13
                    by the Rev. J. C. Dice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Celmick</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lorentz</ln>
                        <fn>Lou.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lorentz</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Beard and Lou. Lorentz were married on October 20 by the Rev. Daniel
                    T. Celmick.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddy</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Lizzie Larew and Lieut. Joseph Waddy were married on December 12 by
                    the Rev. Francis McFarland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meredith</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ellen Price and Lewis Harman were married on December 13 by the Rev. W. C.
                    Meredith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sallie Ann Hawpe, 28, died on December 8th at the residence of her father.
                    Includes a poem in memory of Sallie.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
