<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1865/va.au.ss.1865.11.07">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/24/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-11-07">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>07</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>President Johnson's Opinions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An interview with the President, in which he argues that "to let the
                    negroes have universal suffrage now" would "breed a war of races."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Ottobine</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter castigates the resolutions of the General Conference of the
                    United Brethren Church for endorsing "that broad Black Republican doctrine," the
                    assertion "that the negro is the equal of the white man." The author suggests
                    that members of the Church throughout Virginia should "hold meetings and
                    denounce" the resolutions to demonstrate their disagreement with them, and
                    singles out an unnamed "prominent man of their denomination" who is formerly a
                    "citizen of Augusta."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.07.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mutterings of War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The signs indicate that there is a probability that the United States, may
                        soon be involved in war with England, France, or Maximillian in Mexico, and,
                        it may be, with all at the same time.</p>
                    <p>The United States' Government demands from the British Government
                        compensation for injuries done to American citizens by the Alabama and other
                        Confederate cruisers which sailed from British ports, which the latter
                        positively refuses to grant. In the language of a contemporary, Mr. Seward
                        demands indemnity, as a matter of justice, and Earl Russell refuses it as a
                        matter of honor. A "commission" is tendered on that side and rejected on
                        this, and there the matter stands. Now as to Mexico. In April 1864, when the
                        United States had its hands pretty full with attending to the Southern
                        Confederacy, <emph rend="italics">so-called</emph>, the U. S. House of
                        Representatives passed, by a unanimous vote, the following resolution:</p>
                    <p>"Resolved, &amp;c., That the Congress of the United States are unwilling,
                        by silence, to leave the nations of the world under the impression that they
                        are indifferent spectators of the deplorable events now occurring in the
                        republic of Mexico; and they, therefore, think fit to declare that it does
                        not accord with the policy of the United States to acknowledge a monarchical
                        government, erected on the ruins of any republican government in America
                        under the auspices of any European power."</p>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italics">Evening Post</emph> asks, "Does any one
                        believe that Congress will care less, now, about the French usurpation in
                        Mexico than it did at a time when our own perpetuity as a nation was
                        endangered?"</p>
                    <p>In a late speech of Mr. Seward delivered at Auburn, N. Y., he used the
                        following emphatic language.</p>
                    <p>"I expect that we shall see republican institutions, wherever they have been
                        heretofore established throughout the American continent, speedily
                        vindicated, renewed and re-invigorated."</p>
                    <p>In his connection the Richmond <emph rend="italics">Bulletin</emph> says: "Of
                        the temper in which such a warning and menace would be received by the Third
                        Napoleon, were presume there is no room for doubt; while Maximilian, of his
                        part, has already made his war speech, and vowed to shed, in defence of his
                        crown, every drop of that blood which is now "all Mexican."</p>
                    <p>The feeling which is to determine the course of this country, must be sought
                        among the people of the Northern States -- not here. The South wants war
                        with nobody, and upon no cause. She is too much engrossed with her own
                        sorrows, and has too much to do in repairing her desolations, to think
                        about, or care about, either Mexico or the Monroe doctrine, Maximilian or
                        Napoleon. She wants repose, and has no feelings to waste on the outside
                        world, whether on the other side of the gulf or the other side of the sea.
                        But the people and presses of the North are in a different mood; and it is
                        they who hold the power and have the votes that are to direct it."</p>
                    <p>Before the U. S. Government become involved in war with Foreign Nations it
                        should restore the people of the South to all their Constitutional rights.
                        It would not look well to go to war with Maximilian to secure the rights of
                        Mexicans, when constitutional rights were denied the citizens of the
                        Southern States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that "there is a probability that the United States may soon be
                    involved in war with England, France, or Maximillian in Mexico, and, it may be,
                    with all at the same time." But, the writer contends, before going to war "with
                    Foreign Nations" the government "should restore the people of the South to all
                    their Constitutional rights."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Negro Suffrage</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary>"The Richmond Enquirer says,"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond Enquirer says, "The <emph rend="italics">immediate</emph>
                        effects of negro suffrage would be felt in the Southern States; but the
                        white laboring men of the North would not escape its effects. The subject is
                        one to interest them and to influence their relation to parties, and upon
                        their votes, in their own States, will depend whether Abolitionism shall
                        further dictate to the country this humiliation of the white man. These
                        Southern States are powerless to protect themselves against fanaticism; --
                        their effort with arms failed -- their voices at the polls are unheeded --
                        the country must be saved from black crusade by the conservatism of the
                        North throwing itself between the fanatics and their victim. They have
                        determined not only to rule these States but to ruin them; to make them the
                        scenes of social experiment without regard to consequences. "To the victors
                        belong the spoils" is their motto, and having plundered us of rights and
                        property, they seek now to degrade us in social life. Our destiny and that
                        of the whole country is involved -- and whether this is the Government of
                        the white man will depend upon the defeat of the Republican abolition
                        fanatics."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "the effects of negro suffrage" would be felt not only in the
                    South, but also among "the white laboring men of the North." With the "Southern
                    States" now powerless to resist, it remained for the "conservatism of the North"
                    to determine "whether Abolitionism shall further dictate to the country this
                    humiliation of the white man."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mr. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Lynchburg Republican was the only other paper in the
                    state, besides the Spectator, to advocate electing candidates who were unable to
                    take the test-oath, and that the Lynchburg paper now expresses admiration for A.
                    H. H. Stuart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Vote for Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is the vote cast in this District for candidates for Congress:</p>
                    <p>It will be observed that Madison is the banner county. The small vote in
                        Craig county is accounted for in the fact that most of the citizens thought
                        they belonged to the Abingdon District, and voted, by mistake, for Hoge. The
                        Valley is the only portion of the State which had the manliness to vote for
                        candidates for Congress who would not agree to take the unconstitutional
                        Congressional test oath. Conrad in the Winchester District, and Stuart in
                        this, are the only Representatives from this State who will refuse to take
                        that obnoxious oath, and two better and abler Representatives could not have
                        been selected. The independent, conservative, Constitution-loving citizens
                        of the Valley feel ashamed of their fellow-citizens in Eastern Virginia who
                        were wont, before the war, to accuse them of a too submissive spirit.--When
                        the time arrived which "tried the <emph rend="italics">souls</emph> of men,"
                        the election test showed who possessed the most firmness and independence,
                        and the decision was in favor of the people of the Valley, and the counties
                        West of it. Madison is a glorious exception in the East.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the votes, by county, for Lewis and Stuart in the recent
                    Congressional election and praises the "firmness and independence" reflected in
                    the overwhelming majority for Stuart, pointing out that "the Valley is the only
                    portion of the State which had the manliness to vote for candidates for Congress
                    who would not agree to take the unconstitutional Congressional test oath."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Pardons for Virginians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Compton</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists residents of Augusta, Page, Rockingham, and Rockbridge counties who
                    recently received pardons from the Governor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>National Thanksgiving</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints Andrew Johnson's proclamation, recommending that the first
                    Thursday of December be set aside "as a day of national thanksgiving to the
                    Creator of the universe" for the "great deliverances and blessings" of the
                    previous year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local--Circuit Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Ralph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sketches the proceedings of the Circuit Court of Augusta, which has been
                    dealing exclusively with a heavy docket of criminal cases.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local--Painful Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Fisher, age 7 or 8, had his arm amputated after it was drawn into a
                    cane mill. William was assisting his father in grinding cane in a mill on Middle
                    River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pullen</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 2 Mary Pullen and Francis Huff were married by the Rev. J. C.
                    Dice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radener</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Sheets and Francis Radener were married on October 19 by the Rev. J.
                    C. Hensell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plecker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teaford</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Plecker and Mary Teaford were joined in marriage by the Rev. J. C.
                    Hensell on October 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1865.11.07.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
