<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.06.20">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/16</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-06-20">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.06.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>An Old Indictment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the Union State Convention of 1865 a resolution was adopted by
                        acclamation, declaring that the leaders and candidates of the Democratic
                            <emph rend="italic">alias</emph> Copperhead party stood arraigned before
                        the people of Pennsylvania for constantly obstructing the efforts of the
                        Constitutional authorities to maintain the life of the nation. We now repeat
                        the counts in the indictment then preferred by declaring that the Copperhead
                        leaders did this--</p>
                    <p>By inflaming the passion of their ignorant followers against the legally
                        elected officers of the Federal Government, and refraining from all reproach
                        against treason or armed traitors.</p>
                    <p>By procuring a decision from the Democratic judges of our Supreme Court,
                        denying the right of the Government to the services of the citizens of this
                        State for the defense of the imperiled country.</p>
                    <p>By discouraging men from volunteering into the armies of the Union; thus
                        rendering it necessary to succumb to treason, or to pay large bounties, and
                        so burdening every ward, township and borough in the State with debt to fill
                        the ranks of our armies.</p>
                    <p>By opposing the enlistment of negroes for our defense, although no white man
                        was required for every black one who could be enlisted, and this at the very
                        moment when the battle of Gettysburg was raging on the soil of Pennsylvania,
                        and that decisive battle was uncertain.</p>
                    <p>By denying to our soldiers the right to vote while fighting for the flag of
                        our fathers, on the plea that such rights were not allowed by our
                        Constitution, and by opposing an amendment which removed their objections
                        and relieved our brave soldiers from this disability.</p>
                    <p>By exaggerating the public indebtedness, decrying the public credit, and
                        teaching that the financial resources of the north were unequal to the
                        suppression of the rebellion.</p>
                    <p>By a shameful opposition to measures for extending relief to the families of
                        Union soldiers, and by a malignant effort by these means to secure the
                        success of the rebels in the field as such a protraction of the war as would
                        exhaust the nation in its effort to subdue their friends.</p>
                    <p>By <emph rend="italic">now</emph> heaping abuse upon the Government for
                        punishing assassins and their accomplices; by demanding the release of
                        leading traitors, by frowning down all attempts to bring to punishment the
                        fiends who starved our soldiers, and by assuring rebels that neither in
                        person nor property shall they be punished for their crimes.</p>
                    <p>And if anything were wanting to complete their infamy, we have it in their
                        determined opposition to free labor, and to a tariff which, while it would
                        make labor profitable by protecting the workingmen of Pennsylvania from
                        British competition, would largely increase the revenue essential to the
                        maintenance of the public faith and credit.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article recounts the resolutions adopted at the Union State Convention
                    of 1865, condemning Democrats for their stand on a range of topics, including
                    their opposition to the enlistment of black soldiers and their refusal to grant
                    soldiers the right to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.06.20.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Issue Made Up!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With Congress having agreed upon the terms to admit the former rebel states
                    back into the Union, the editors assert that the issue has been resolved. The
                    only remaining obstacle is the ratification of the amendment, which leaves the
                    onus upon white southerners themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. Seward at Auburn</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece castigates Secretary Seward for sympathizing with the plight of
                    the former rebels, whom, he asserts, are deserving of honor, both for their
                    bravery on the field of battle and for their willingness to abandon the
                    institution of slavery. His "strange madness" undermines the accomplishments of
                    his "long years of public service to the great principle of human equality" and
                    "mars the record of his own greatness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Clymer men are to have an preliminary meeting in Harrisburg on the 28th
                        inst., to call "a <emph rend="italic">real</emph> Soldier's
                        Convention"--that is of soldiers who will vote the Democratic ticket. We are
                        glad to hear that the enterprise has been undertaken, and it is all
                        important to have the call properly worded so as to make the Convention a
                        decided success. Knowing how seriously the committee will be embarrassed on
                        this point, we submit the following call for their consideration:<lb/> REAL
                        SOLDIERS CONVENTION!<lb/> BOUNTY JUMPERS TO THE RESCUE!<lb/> SKULKING
                        CONSCRIPTS COME FORTH!<lb/> DISCHARGED ERRING BRETHREN WELCOME!<lb/>
                        SOLDIERS OPPOSED TO SOLDIERS VOTING ATTEND!</p>
                    <p>A mass convention of the "real soldiers of Pennsylvania" will be held at the
                        head-quarters of the Molly Maguires in the coal regions, on the anniversary
                        of the New York Draft Riots of 1863--a period in the history of Democracy
                        and real soldiers to which we all point with emotions of profoundest
                        gratification and pride.</p>
                    <p>The Molly Maguires have organized a committee of heroic conscripts who
                        gallantly killed several conscription officers to preserve their own
                        liberties, and prevent the patriotic armies of Lee, M'Causland, Forrest and
                        other distinguished sons of the South from being overwhelmed. This committee
                        will have ample arrangements made for the entertainment and comfort of the
                        delegations in attendance, in the historic caves and mountain fastnesses so
                        sacred to every real soldier.</p>
                    <p>The grand procession will be formed with honorably discharged erring brethren
                        soldiers in the front, next bounty jumpers, taking precedence in the ranks
                        according to the number of times they served the government by enlisting;
                        next skulking conscripts who rendered the best service they could to the
                        Union army by staying out of it; next the gallant soldiers who believe with
                        Clymer that soldiers in the service would not be allowed to vote, and all to
                        have appropriate banners, with such strange devices as the patriotic efforts
                        of the different classes demand.</p>
                    <p>Distinguished speakers will be in attendance. Hon. Heister Clymer, the real
                        soldiers' candidate for Governor; Presidents Johnson and Davis are invited
                        and confidently expected; Col. Moseby, Gen. M'Causland, Gen. Forrest and
                        other distinguished soldiers of the United Republic will attend. By order of
                        the real soldiers' committee,<lb/> Wm. A. Wallace, Manager.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In response to the news that the "Clymer men" intend on holding "a real
                    Soldiers' Convention" on June 20th, the editors have issued a mock announcement
                    that denigrates the proposed proceedings as a meeting for "bounty jumpers" and
                    "skulking conscripts."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Information has come from a "Union resident" of Alabama that the state
                    legislature has passed an act referring to the Union army as the "'enemy,'"
                    which was signed by the newly-reconstructed governor, and intends "to crown the
                    Rebellion and all its originators and promoters with honor."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Female School</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of the letter calls for the creation of a female school in
                    Chambersburg, modeled after an academy near to Stuttgart, in the Kingdom of
                    Wuttemburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.06.20.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local News--The Grave of Captain Kerns</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerns</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The piece chronicles the last days of Capt. Kerns, who left his home in
                    Missouri at the outbreak of the war to return to his "Native State" and join the
                    Pennsylvania Reserves. Kerns died in the Second Battle of Bull Run, though the
                    location of his remains remained a mystery for quite some time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Robbery and Arrest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hatfield</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowdon</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diggs</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valkenburgh</ln>
                        <fn>O. Van</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two black men, Peter Hatfield and Joseph Plowdon, were arrested last
                    Tuesday after they tried to cash a stolen check at the National Bank of
                    Chambersburg. A third man, Charles Diggs was later implicated and arrested in
                    the affair. Prior to their arrest, Hatfield had tried to buy two suits of
                    clothing at a store in Chambersburg but the check was refused. The prisoners
                    assert that they did not steal the check but found it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Soldiers' Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritchey</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Local veterans of the Civil War who endorse the action of the Pittsburg
                    Soldiers' Convention will meet on June 27th to organize under the "National
                    Union of the Boys in Blue," as ordered by the last Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Grand Lodge of Good Templars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cramer</ln>
                        <fn>J. A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roney</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMurray</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following delegates from Franklin county attended the Pennsylvania
                    Grand Lodge of Good Templars meeting in Philadelphia last week: Rev. S. H. C.
                    Smith, W. W. Paxton, John M. Gilmore, W. F. Eyster, W. E. Tolbert, J. A. S.
                    Cramer, and W. S. Roney. Rev. J. S. McMurray and Rev. S. H. C. Smith were
                    elected officers for the ensuing year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Good Templars at St. Thomas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vautries</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodall</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Amelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>William H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parks</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sixas</ln>
                        <fn>T. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Lodge of the order of Good Templars was organized on the June 7th in St.
                    Thomas by W. C. T. John M. Gilmore. The following men were elected officers:
                    George Burkholder, John W. Coble, Benjamin K. Hassler, Margaret Miller, Jonathan
                    Coble, Kate Vautries, David Woodall, Amelia Weaver, William H. H. McCleary,
                    David Parks, E. Coble, Jennie Fohl, T. T. Sixas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Aggravated Assault and Battery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheetz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheetz</ln>
                        <fn>Paul</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An "old man named Sheetz" beat his son last Sunday while in a "frenzy of
                    intoxication," leaving him close to death. Though "quite young," the son, Paul,
                    served in the army in the late war and was "a gallant soldier." The father has
                    been committed to jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Soldier Gone</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Purviance</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that James Purviance, a member of the 77th Regt. Penna.
                    Vols., died near Waynesboro last Tuesday. He was buried with the "honors of war"
                    last Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Located</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. A. H. Strickler has relocated to Mercersburg to resume his practice.
                    Strickler is a graduate of Bellevue Hospital Medical College of New York City.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Returned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCausley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that I. H. McCausley has returned to Chambersburg after an absence
                    of two or three years, during which time he lived in several western states.
                    McCausley has indicated that he intends on making Chambersburg his home once
                    again where he will resume his law practice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nesbitt</ln>
                        <fn>Maria F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 12th, W. H. Hockenberry and Maria F. Nesbitt were married by Rev.
                    S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ulrick</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newroth</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 29th, Henry Ulrick and Ann Newroth were married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhl</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 26th, Adam Thomas and Mary Kuhl were married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Melbert</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kraemer</ln>
                        <fn>Philopena</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 14th, George Melbert and Philopena Kraemer were married by Rev. G.
                    Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoaff</ln>
                        <fn>I. James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rumler</ln>
                        <fn>Syvilla J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 12th, I. James Shoaff and Syvilla J. Rumler were married by Rev. J.
                    Dickson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carothers</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Symmes</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 14th, Andrew H. Witherspoon and Lizzie Carothers, of Sacramento,
                    Cal., were married by Rev. J. H. Symmes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Felker</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Felker</ln>
                        <fn>Lila</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Felker</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 2nd, Harry Beugene, infant son of David and Lila Felker, died near
                    Mount Morris, Ogle county, Ill. He was 17 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zarger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 14th, John Zarger, 16, died at the residence of his father in Antrim
                    township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mourer</ln>
                        <fn>Emma Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mourer</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mourer</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 27th, Emma Catharine, daughter of Peter and Elizabeth Mourer, died.
                    She was 15 months old. Two days later, Elizabeth Mourer, 25, died. Both were
                    interred in one grave on the May 30th at Brant's Church, near St. Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.06.20.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
