<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.09.12">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/21</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-09-12">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.09.12..01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Address of the Union State Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of the address given by F. Jordan before the Union State
                    Committee in Philadelphia on September 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>For What?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Mary Clemer Ames</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A story about the sacrifices made by a women whose sons went off to fight
                    in the war never to return home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.09.12..02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The President's Tour a National Disgrace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The past five years brought upon our nation frequent humiliations, and we
                        have many times bowed our heads to the dust in shame and sorrow. Treason,
                        with its attendant crimes, smote us to the breast with the bitter
                        consciousness that men who were of our own flesh and blood, who had been
                        inspired by the same glorious traditions and were sharers in the same grand
                        destiny, were capable of depravity and brutality which other races in darker
                        ages could not parallel.</p>
                    <p>Shame came upon us in a hundred forms throughout the weary war; when wrong so
                        often prevailed over right, when the arms of the wicked dominated, and the
                        lives and property of patriots were sacrificed in vain; when they whom we
                        honored and trusted proved false, and those whom we relied upon to rescue us
                        were found inefficient and imbecile, and success and glory turned from our
                        loyal hosts to brighten the banners of cruelty and treachery. And at length,
                        when behind the frowning Providence we beheld the smiling face, and triumph
                        after triumph gladdened us, and no mailed hand was uplifted against our
                        peace, and good men's lips moved in thanksgiving to God who gave us the
                        glory and the victory, and loving-kindness and forgiveness stirred all
                        bosoms even towards the authors of our woe and shame, the merciful ruler of
                        our rejoicing people was brutally murdered by the very criminals he was
                        compassionating. Then came the bitter blasting of our hopes by his infamous
                        successor, the man who never blushed that he--amid the most imposing and
                        august inauguration ceremonies, when his illustrious superior spake to the
                        awed multitude with the pathos and fervor and devotedness of inspiration
                        almost,--staggered and hiccuped as he poured his halting, incoherent
                        sentences of self-adulation into the reluctant ears of our highest
                        dignitaries, of the representatives of foreign powers, and of the decent men
                        and women of our land.</p>
                    <p>Rapidly followed the mortification of the President's abandoning the friends,
                        who with averted faces covered his obscenity with the mantle of charity, and
                        throwing himself into the hands of his harshest revilers--of his wholesale
                        pardoning of the most blood-guilty traitors, of his affiliation with them
                        and his rejection of the tried and true men who kept the government of the
                        people from destruction, and to whom this ungrateful betrayer owed his
                        change from an outlawed, branded fugitive, with a price upon his head, to
                        the most honorable position among men.</p>
                    <p>From the hour he felt the reigns of government secure in his grasp, he has
                        loaded us with shame. He has caused the Executive Mansion to be the haunt of
                        vileness; he has made its venerated retreats echo with low and brutal
                        vituperation and vulgarity; he has sought to corrupt the pure by bribery; he
                        has sullied his lips with falsehood, and had dyed his hands with blood, shed
                        without rebuke by the executors of his "policy."</p>
                    <p>The generous words he had spoken, he has cancelled with iniquitous deeds, the
                        kind promises he volunteered, he has redeemed by fierce cruelties; he stands
                        arrayed against his nobler self, an object of disgust and dread, flattered
                        by the bad men who once despised and hunted and would have slain him when he
                        was in the paths of duty, and shunned and feared by his honorable and
                        patriotic countrymen who protected and exalted him when he strove to walk
                        uprightly and loyally.</p>
                    <p>Such a man one should suppose would hide himself as much as might be from the
                        public gaze, and hedge himself with the dignity of his eminent position. Let
                        the pilgrimage to Chicago speak! Invited as President of the United States,
                        to participate in the consecration of a monument to the memory of the
                        lamented Douglas, he accepted the invitation for selfish and dishonest ends.
                        The invitation was not to Andrew Johnson, as an individual, but to him as
                        the Chief Magistrate. He should have gone humbled and contrite to the grave
                        of the illustrious dead. He should have remembered with what malignity he
                        assailed the honor and ability of Douglas, when he was supporting
                        Breckenridge in the mad effort to rend the Democratic party and effect the
                        dissolution of the Union; and it could only have been as the representative
                        of the American people, to whom the dead Statesman was dear, that Andrew
                        Johnson should have appeared on this solemn occasion at all. Truly, it was
                            <emph rend="italic">ex officio</emph> only that his presence at the base
                        of that monumental column could not affront the manes of the illustrious
                        patriot, in whose honor it is rising.</p>
                    <p>The "translated" and vicious Secretary of State, the handler and trainer of
                        the swaggering President, caught at the opportunity the trip would afford to
                        make an electioneering tour; and artfully hitched Gen. Grant and Admiral
                        Farragut to their car, to attract the grateful people and secure welcomes
                        from the crowds that would assemble to greet the heroes.</p>
                    <p>It does no credit to the taste of those distinguished men, as it detracts,
                        certainly, from their acuteness, to allow themselves to be used to get up
                        political meetings for the vagabondizing administration. Did they remember
                        in whose behalf the voices, now ringing out cheers and applauses, as, in
                        rebel language, "the rival of Caligula's horse" denounces the opponents of
                        his "policy," were raised, when they were struggling to open the
                        Mississippi? When the Congress that sustained them in their labors, and
                        covered them with honors, was scandalously vilified, were there no
                        compunctious visitings of conscience in their breasts? Did they not
                        sometimes feel as if they were cat's paws of the artful Secretary? We are
                        proud to believe that they had no part or sympathy with the political
                        gypsies, that inveigled them.</p>
                    <p>Our cheeks tingle with shame as we read the daily reports of the Presidential
                        progress.</p>
                    <p>The hospitality of cities is abused by venomous partisan harangues, the
                        people's sense of propriety is shocked at their President's ceaseless
                        boasting of his integrity, of his services, of the public positions he has
                        enjoyed, of his wonderful sacrifices for the common weal, of his inflexible
                        will, and at his parading his political wares like a greedy mountebank,
                        wherever two or three are gathered at a rail road station, and insulting the
                        crowds of citizens who come together to pay their respects to their Chief
                        Magistrate as such, or to do homage to the illustrious Soldier and Sailor
                        who attend him. With impotent anger, he denounces a co-ordinate branch of
                        government, the functions of which he arrogates; he rages at individual
                        statesmen, who differ from him in the plan of reconstruction; he clamors for
                        the hanging of private citizens, guiltless of the sin of rebellion, but
                        guilty of maintaining the rights of man; bandies billingsgate with unknown
                        interlocutors in his promiscuous audiences. Well might he say he cares not
                        for dignity! The twaddle, the ribaldry, the coarse jokes and harlequinry,
                        that this painfully extended tour has begotten is deplorable.</p>
                    <p>The rudest efforts of the rudest of frontier stump orators surpass in
                        elegance and force the diatribes of the President and the fallen Secretary
                        of State--the Buckeye Blacksmith in his instincts and oratory was a
                        Chesterfield in comparison with Andrew Johnson. He is the first of the
                        Presidents who has lowered the office in his personal habits: all his
                        predecessors preserved the dignity of the station. He alone is unimpressed
                        by its lofty character. We should expect nothing better from him. The
                        melancholy exhibitions on the 4th of March '65, and of 22d Feb. '66, were
                        enough to betray the stuff of which he is made. But we did expect the
                        Democratic party had respect enough for the highest office among us to keep
                        them from encouraging Andrew Johnson to defile it. He is theirs. We freely
                        relinquish him. They may reap the full reward of his defection, take the
                        patronage he commands, use him in all decent ways for their advancement. But
                        we implore them earnestly not to increase our humiliation by inducing, by
                        their plaudits and strategy, the President of the United States to expose
                        himself as a common blackguard and buffoon.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors issue a tirade against the President, who, since taking "the
                    reigns of government," has "loaded us with shame." In particular, they target
                    Johnson for the "venomous partisan harangues" he has repeatedly delivered over
                    the course of his most recent tour of the nation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Inevitable Results</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Should the Copperhead and rebel party lately formed at Philadelphia, at the
                        dictation of his accidency Andy Johnson, succeed in obtaining the control of
                        the Government, it would most assuredly adopt and carry out a <emph
                            rend="italic">Rebel</emph> policy. The great mass of its supporters
                        would be reconstructed rebels from the South, imbued with all the views and
                        opinions with which they commenced and fought their rebellion. The few
                        renegade Republicans and Johnsonites who may act with them will be of no
                        account whatever in shaping its policy--whilst the couple of score of
                        dirt-eating Northern Democrats who have been so very anxious for the
                        restoration of their "erring Southern brethren" to seats in Congress, will
                        not be able, even if desirous, to control the actions of the party to whom
                        they have sold themselves.</p>
                    <p>The House of Representatives of the United States, under the last
                        apportionment, consists of 242 members, 85 of which were apportioned to the
                        Slave States. A <emph rend="italic">majority</emph> of that body, if every
                        district were represented, would therefore be 122 members.</p>
                    <p>In the elections that have taken place in the late Slave States, since the
                        commencement of the rebellion, there were 18 <emph rend="italic"
                        >Union</emph> members elected, who were admitted to their seats, viz: 3 in
                        West Virginia, 3 in Maryland, 2 in Tennessee, 2 in Kentucky and 8 in
                        Missouri. The re-election of <emph rend="italic">Union</emph> men in some of
                        these districts is, to say the least, very doubtful. But suppose that they
                        should <emph rend="italic">all</emph> return good and true <emph
                            rend="italic">Union</emph> men, there would still be 67 re-constructed
                        Rebels returned by the other districts in the lately Slave States.</p>
                    <p>If to these be added the 35 Democratic votes from the Northern States, we
                        have a total of 102 votes which would be cast as a unit, according to the
                        dictation of the <emph rend="italic">Slave driving</emph> Southern majority
                        of the new party. And should this new party succeed in electing <emph
                            rend="italic">twenty</emph> new members of Congress in Northern
                        districts which are now represented by <emph rend="italic">Union
                        Republicans</emph>, they will have obtained a majority of the whole
                        body--and does any sane person doubt but that Andy Johnson would recognize
                        such a body as the <emph rend="italic">legal House of
                        Representatives</emph>?</p>
                    <p>Among the <emph rend="italic">inevitable results</emph> that would follow,
                        would be</p>
                    <p>1st. The REPUDIATION <emph rend="italic">of our National debt</emph>.</p>
                    <p>It is true that one of the resolutions adopted at Philadelphia by the new
                        party says the <emph rend="italic">National Debt of the United States shall
                            be paid</emph>. But we all know now that Convention was engineered. Its
                        members--especially the <emph rend="italic">unpardoned</emph> ones from the
                        South--were tongue-tied. They <emph rend="italic">dared not</emph> speak
                        their sentiments--and as soon as they learned the purport of the resolutions
                            <emph rend="italic">prepared</emph> for them, they left before even the
                        committee reported to the convention, so disgusted were they with the part
                        they had to play.</p>
                    <p>It is also well known that the Southern papers nearly unanimously repudiate
                        the action of the Convention, saying that their delegates had no power to
                        bind their people. How easy therefore will it be for the Southern members of
                        Congress to disregard the action of the Philadelphia Convention, once they
                        are safely restored to their places in Congress. They paid no regard to
                        their <emph rend="italic">oaths</emph>, in times past, and what regard will
                        they pay to <emph rend="italic">resolutions</emph> now? And that they will
                        either repudiate our National debt--and thus verify the predictions of their
                        orators by making "a <emph rend="italic">cord of greenbacks</emph> of no
                        more value than a cord of wood"--or saddle the free people of the North with
                        the payment of the <emph rend="italic">Rebel</emph> debt--a debt contracted
                        in the effort to break down our government--we have no doubt. If the people
                        of the country are so deluded as ever to put this new party into power they
                        must expect one or the other of these things to happen, for it is not likely
                        that the <emph rend="italic">meek and submissive</emph> rebels of the South
                        will ever pay any part of the debt created in thrashing them if they can get
                        rid of it.</p>
                    <p>2d. The REPEAL OF OUR PENSION AND BOUNTY LAWS, will then be certain.</p>
                    <p>Mark our prediction <emph rend="italic">Soldiers of the Union</emph>. Elevate
                        the Copperhead and Rebel party to power and they will either pension all
                        their rebel soldiers and widows and children upon the Treasury of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Union</emph>, and allow their dirty, greasy, gray-back
                        cut-throats, and their consorts and spawn, to fatten upon the money that
                        rightly belongs to you, and the widows and children of your comrades--or
                        they will repeal all the laws passed by your grateful country for your
                        support, and for the maintenance and support of the widows and families of
                        your comrades. This is no idle thought. It is the settled purpose of the
                            <emph rend="italic">rebels South</emph>, if ever they get into
                        power--and they are as much <emph rend="italic">rebels</emph> now as they
                        ever were, and hate you and your free government as much--nay more, as when
                        they were fighting you in the field.</p>
                    <p>Farmers, merchants, mechanics and laboring men of Franklin county, and of the
                        Union, are you prepared to see your national securities depreciated? Are you
                        prepared to see your <emph rend="italic">government bonds</emph>, in which
                        you have, perhaps, invested the hard earnings of past years of toil, brought
                        down and sacrificed? Are you prepared to see the pensions of our gallant
                        soldiers taken away from them? Are you prepared to see the widows and
                        orphans of those who fell fighting for the Union and the liberties you
                        enjoy, cast upon the cold charity of the world, deprived of the support a
                        grateful people has voted them, or worse even than this, are you prepared to
                        pay the <emph rend="italic">rebel debt</emph> of $3,000,000, in addition to
                        your own, and to saddle yourselves with bounties, pensions, annuities, and
                        pay due the rebel hordes who invaded your territory, burnt your towns and
                        villages, your houses, barns and shops, and slaughtered your husbands,
                        brothers and sons? If you are prepared to stand all this, then <emph
                            rend="italic">sneak</emph> out from your homes on the second Tuesday of
                        October next, and vote the Locofoco-Copperhead-Johnson ticket. But if you
                        are for LIBERTY AND UNION, <emph rend="italic">one and inseparable</emph>,
                        NOW AND FOREVER," march forth boldly as <emph rend="italic">freemen</emph>,
                        one and all of you, and vote the <emph rend="italic">Union Republican</emph>
                        ticket, with Gen. John W. Geary for Governor and Gen. Wm. H. Koontz for
                        Congress upon it, and the country will once more be saved from the
                        destroyers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Should the "Copperhead and Rebel party lately formed at Philadelphia" take
                    control of the government, cautions the article, it "would most assuredly adopt
                    and carry out a Rebel policy." Among the measures it asserts would be adopted
                    are the repudiation of the National Debt and the Repeal of the Pension and
                    Bounty Laws.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Congressional Contest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article offers a preliminary estimate of the outcome in the
                    congressional contest between Koontz and Sharpe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds readers that a huge Union party rally will take place in
                    Chambersburg on the following Monday. Among the distinguished speakers expected
                    to address the crowd are Mr. Stevens, Gen. Geary, Gen. Cameron, Gen. Negley,
                    William D. Kelly, and Col. F. S. Stumbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that a large meeting of Union men will take place in Waynesboro on
                    Sept. 18th. A number of delegations from the surrounding region, and as far away
                    as Maryland, are expected to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> is thrown into spasms by Mr. Deal's
                        card, and it belches forth a long article of abuse on Mr. Deal and the chief
                        editor of this journal. It is manifest from its article that Mr. Deal
                        learned too much of the purposes of the Democratic managers before he
                        exhibited his true colors, and they are vexed into all manner of follies to
                        prevent him from wounding the Copper-Johnson coalition. That Mr. Deal probed
                        this corruption to the bottom before he turned from its slimy embrace, is
                        evident, and the flutters of the wounded attest how effective is the blow of
                        his fidelity to his own convictions. Mr. Deal needs no vindication at our
                        hands, and the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> is welcome to writhe and
                        scold until it wearies of its impotent follies.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The piece defends Post Master Deal from the abuse levelled at him by the
                    Valley Spirit. Deal was nominated to attend the Philadelphia Convention by men
                    who evidently believed him to be sympathetic to the Democratic cause. Upon his
                    return from the political gathering, however, Deal voiced contempt for the
                    platform advanced at the convention and questioned the loyalty of its leaders.
                    As a consequence, Deal has been the target vitriolic and malicious criticism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A synopsis of the Union rallies held across Franklin county last week, each
                    of which the article categorizes as a success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> devotes a column to the article in this
                        journal of two weeks ago, on the right of deserters to vote, and with
                        characteristic disregard of the truth, charges us with inconsistency.</p>
                    <p>We hold precisely the same doctrine to-day we expressed in the remarks made
                        in the legislature. The proposition before the House was to disfranchise
                        deserters by legislation <emph rend="italic">after</emph> the crime had been
                        committed. It was unconstitutional, and was voted down. But the act of the
                        legislature in force now, is not <emph rend="italic">ex post facto</emph>,
                        but is designed to carry into effect an act of Congress.</p>
                    <p>One of the main grounds on which the act of Congress was objected to, was the
                        interference by Congress in the suffrage of a State; and what courts may
                        hold as to the validity of an act of the State, remains to be seen. One
                        point we have ever maintained--that no other tribunal than the Supreme Court
                        can determine that question.</p>
                    <p>That the decision of the Supreme Court in Huber vs. Reilly is in conflict
                        with the principle of the act of the legislature, we do not doubt; but it
                        may or may not be declared invalid when judicially decided. Until then no
                        election board can nullify it, and until then it must be obeyed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece denies a charge made by the Valley Spirit that the Repository
                    editors are guilty of "inconsistency" relative to their position on the right of
                    deserters to vote, maintaining that they "hold precisely the same doctrine
                    to-day" as earlier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reprimands the editors at the Valley Spirit for impugning A. K.
                    McClure's stand on the deserter question.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In response to a declaration issued by the Democratic County Committee
                    asserting that the Republicans insist on granting blacks the vote, the article
                    challenges the legitimacy of the claim and queries as to when such a
                    proclamation was ever articulated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Loyal Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of the Convention of Southern Loyalists, which met in
                    Philadelphia on September 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.09.12..03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Vote of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The list containing the voting returns for the past twelve years in
                    Franklin county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Copper-Johnson-Republican Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports that about five hundred people showed up to attend a
                    political rally in front of the Montgomery House last Thursday; The event was
                    organized by members of the Republican faction that supports Johnson. The piece
                    castigates Montgomery Blair, whose two hour speech was so "intolerably dull"
                    that a member of the audience tried to end it prematurely by sounding the fire
                    alarm "to relieve the audience" of its suffering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Death of J. Porter Brown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. Porter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ex-Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that J. Porter Brown, son of Ex-Sheriff Brown, died in a firefight
                    with Indians while en route to the Montana Territory. The incident occurred last
                    July. His remains were "buried by the side of the trail, and his companions,
                    after performing this last duty, proceeded with heavy hearts toward their
                    destination."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article informs soldiers that they must pay their assessments if they
                    hope to vote in the upcoming election, and urges them to do so if they have not
                    yet complied.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krome</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 10th, Lewis B. Krome and Annie E. Funk were married by Rev. Dr.
                    Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wile</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Sabina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 10th, William Wile and Sabina Smith were married by Rev. Dr.
                    Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 5th, Margaret Snively, 21, died in Fayetteville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 3rd, Mary Elizabeth, only daughter of Benjamin F. and Isabella E.
                    Lehman, died in Guilford township. She was 11 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 2nd, Margaret M., daughter of Patrick McDowell, dec'd, died in
                    Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.09.12..04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
