<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.03.07">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/15</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-03-07">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>07</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Rinderpest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports on the spread of rinderpest, a cattle disease that
                    threatens to wreak havoc in Franklin county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Pork Disease</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following article from the pen of one of the most intelligent and
                    well-known merchants of Philadelphia, will be read with interest:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of the piece tries to allay fears concerning the safety of
                    consuming meat in the wake of the spread of the rinderpest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Protection</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An extract from a speech delivered by William D. Kelly in Congress on the
                    question of "'Protection of American Industry.'" In his address, Kelly advocated
                    the enactment of a "just and equitable" tariff, which, he claims, "cheapens
                    goods, encourages healthy immigration, and builds up every branch of legitimate
                    business."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.07.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Georgia Senators</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Troubled by the election of Alex Stephens, the former Vice-President of the
                    Confederacy, to the U. S. Senate, the editors question whether Stephens, or
                    other rebel leaders, can be trusted to discharge their duties loyally and
                    properly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Political Status of the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President has recoiled from his own wrong, as if appalled at his crowning
                        treachery; but let no loyal man be deceived. It is as the recoil of the
                        viper after it has made one stroke at its victim, only to make another and
                        more deadly one if possible. Phrenzied by passion or the sad infirmity that
                        has heretofore made the Nation bow to humility and shame, he welcomed to his
                        embrace, by his speech of the 22d ult., a motley mass of malignant
                        copperheads and avowed rebels, and he exhausted the vocabulary of the Five
                        Points to denounce the Union majority in Congress. He was insolent, defiant,
                        vulgar and vituperative to a degree that would have degraded a ward
                        politician harrangueing at a corner grog-shop, and his utterances were
                        greeted by vociferous applause by every rebel within his hearing. Time,
                        reflection and sobriety brought back to him some appreciation of the fact
                        that he was the Chief Magistrate of thirty millions of people, and he found
                        that every true friend was alienated, and sorrow and mortification were as
                        wide-spread as loyalty itself.</p>
                    <p>He then sought to shield himself from his own madness. He had in an evil and
                        unguarded hour told the truth, proclaimed and boasted of his own treachery,
                        and it had gone with lightning wings to shadow a continent. He had thus
                        vindicated Congress and upon his voluntary record he could not stand. To
                        fall upon the Union column, now entrusted with the destiny of a Nation just
                        emerging from the terrible crucible of civil war, was to be broken into
                        fragments; and to have it fall upon him was to grind him to powder. He
                        therefore resolved by fresh treachery to renew his potency for evil. He
                        called about him several Union men--among them Gov. Cox of Ohio, and
                        attempted to explain that he was not at positive variance with Congress,
                        that he desired to retain his status in the Union party, and meant to deal
                        justly with the loyal sentiment of the country. This we regard as a graver
                        offence, if possible, than his incoherent but manifestly truthful offerings
                        on the altar of traitors. It but adds to his outrage upon justice and
                        freedom additional outrage upon truth. He may have wished at the time to
                        regain the jewel of consistency, fidelity and patriotism he had wantonly
                        cast from him; but the time is past when new wrongs can be inflicted upon
                        the great Union party of the Republic, by Andrew Johnson's perfidy. He has
                        filled its measure, completed its circle; and as he has cast his lot and
                        chosen his companionship, so he must abide.</p>
                    <p>We have not hastily handed over a President as hopelessly faithless. Many
                        months ago we felt well convinced that this dark day must come. We had seen
                        the shadows but too plainly which with fearful certainty betokened a
                        starless night of gloom. We had heard him defend treason, only treason, when
                        there was no Congress to give excuse for his ebullitions of passion. We had
                        seen him manifest unmingled satisfaction at the prospect of copperhead
                        victories in the North, when he hoped to turn them to account to complete
                        the triumph of traitors knocking at the doors of Congress. We had known of
                        his refusal to endorse the Union State tickets in New York and Pennsylvania
                        in 1865, or to deny the daily declarations of the foes of the Union party,
                        that he earnestly desired their success. We had not failed to observe that
                        beyond a few irresponsible hirelings of treason, who were without friends or
                        political power, he studiously shielded every rebel murderer, and even men
                        proclaimed by himself as the chief of assassins, from the demands of
                        justice. In common with many others who knew how carefully his follies were
                        cloaked and his wrongs concealed, we struggled on, and hoped that the silver
                        lining to the cloud, which now and again would brighten with the promise of
                        a noon-tide of fidelity, might yet be made to give ultimately some
                        measurable fruition of the heroism, the sacrifices and the bereavements of a
                        loyal people. But the last ray of hope has faded away, by his bold espousal
                        of the traitor's cause, and the official notice he has given Congress and
                        the Nation that there shall be no legislation for the rebellious States
                        until their Senators and Representatives aid in its enactment.</p>
                    <p>The veto of the Freedman's Bureau bill was the pretext for an irreconcilable
                        issue with Congress--not the cause. It was supported by nearly if not quite
                        every Union man in either branch. It was commended to Congress in his annual
                        message. It was advised by Gen. Grant in his report on the condition of the
                        South. It was prepared by the immediate supervision of Gen. Howard, the
                        President of the Bureau, and who has never encouraged what is termed
                        radicalism in politics or tolerated idleness on the part of the negroes.
                        Senators and Congressmen in daily consultation with the President supported
                        the measure, and no one doubted that he would promptly approve it. Indeed,
                        it cannot be questioned that he meant at first to sign it; that he intended
                        to postpone for some future occasion his issue with Congress, and expected
                        to be more potent to divide and destroy the Union party after approving the
                        bill than before; but the traitors of the South rebelled. They had carried
                        the outer works of the Executive and they would not delay their possession
                        of the very citadel of power. They demanded that there must be no restraint
                        upon their rebel proclivities in their States; no measure of justice or
                        protection to the freedmen, and pitiable ambition triumphed over right.
                        Since the issue was inevitable, we do not regret that it has come now and so
                        plainly that no Union man can err; and the spasmodic efforts of Mr. Johnson
                        to seduce the Union men from the loyal ranks must prove abortive. The Union
                        State Convention to meet to-day will likely not stop to antagonize or
                        denounce the President. It will have higher and holier duties to perform
                        than to descend to the modern style of Presidential denunciation; but it
                        will declare the principles of the Union party in letters of living light,
                        and in sentiments which will cheer every faithful man, and in thus
                        maintaining fidelity to a bleeding Nation and to the issues on which its
                        future peace and safety depend, it will simply consign to the rear a
                        President it would have delighted to honor, and leave him and his
                        camp-followers to the consuming scorn of an honest people and to the
                        retributive record of impartial history.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors assert that, despite his attempts to explain the circumstances
                    behind it, Johnson's February 22nd speech before "copperheads and avowed rebels"
                    was "insolent, defiant, vulgar and vituperative to a degree that would have
                    degraded a ward politician haranguing at a corner grog-shop." The veto of
                    Freedmen's Bureau was not a singular event, rather it was emblematic of his
                    efforts to "seduce the Union men" to support his reconstruction scheme.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner; Richmond Dispatch; Richmond Sentinel; Richmond Whig;
                    Norfolk Dominion; Charlottesville Chronicle; Wilmington Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that "rebel journals" throughout the South and their
                    copperhead counterparts in the North greeted news of the President's veto with
                    wild enthusiasm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With ex-Confederate Vice-President Stephens relieved of his parole by the
                    President, the piece sardonically asks why Jeff Davis remains incarcerated while
                    "his associates and cabinet officers in treason" are "deemed proper legislators
                    for the Union."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that copperheads in Gettysburg fired a salute over the
                    battlefield after it was announced that Johnson vetoed the Freedmen's bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Rinderpest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of the letter offers a variety of different theories regarding
                    the cause of and the cure for the Rinderpest, which he suggests is a strain of
                    small pox.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Speech of the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"A large meeting of copperheads,session sympathizers, returned rebel
                    soliders and refugees,--not a single Union man of note or character
                    participating in it--was held in Washington on the 22nd of February. It was
                    called under the auspices of the Democratic National Committee, and the
                    officers, speakers and managers were all of the same school. Most of the
                    copperhead leaders from Sunset Cox down to Coffroth were on hand and shouted
                    themselves hoarse over the perfidy of the President. After the meeting
                    adjourned, it proceeded to the White House, where the President delievered a
                    speech that would have disgraced any average township stumper, in which he
                    denounced everybody but rebels and copperheads, and said to them--"Come with me
                    and I will go with you!" The people of the Nation of all parties who would be
                    glad to repect the incumbent of the President office, will blush as they read
                    the disgraceful harrangue of the President. We subjoin the material portions of
                    it copied from the corrected report:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An extract of the controversial address given by President Johnson on Feb.
                    22nd, in which he railed against Congress, labeling its actions as
                    revolutionary, classified Sumner, Stevens, and Philips as traitors, and
                    proclaimed the denial of southern representation as reprehensible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Dry Run Coal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a rich coal vein was discovered in Dry Run. Samples extracted
                    thus far indicate that the coal is of high quality.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--County Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository's editors second the Valley Spirit's nomination of William
                    Hockenberry for County Superintendent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Fire at Greencastle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuss</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchler</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A fire destroyed the building containing Eli Fuss's confectionary store and
                    Joseph Buchler's saddlery shop last Sunday morning. Although Buchler lost his
                    entire stock, worth about $1,500, the extent of Fuss's loss is not yet known.
                    The blaze is suspected to be the work of an incendiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Guilford Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fetterhoff</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stadtler</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stickler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicklas</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sodenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Leander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cerver</ln>
                        <fn>George S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Leander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frederick</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the men nominated by the Union men of Guilford township for the
                    Spring election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Green Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Malton</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dale</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirk</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the men nominated for the Spring election by the Union men of
                    Green township on March 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Fire at Greenwood</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spoonhour</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wrist</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf>Mrs.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Spoonhour's house was destroyed by a fire last Sunday. The blaze
                    began in the chimney of the house and quickly engulfed the dwelling. The fire
                    spread to an adjoining log stable owned by Mrs. Wrist, before finally being
                    extinguished.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 28th, David Neff, of Scotland, and Susan, daughter of Jacob Wertz,
                    were married by Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>Bruce</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koonse</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coons</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 1st, Bruce Zeigler and Jennie M. Koonse were married at the
                    residence of the bride's grandfather, Martin Coons, by Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boggs</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 28th, Franklin T., youngest son of Mrs. H. M. Boggs, died of
                    typhoid fever. He was 8 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Clara Lidy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 24th, Clara Lidy, daughter of Daniel W. and Susan A. Miller, died.
                    She was 13 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coulter</ln>
                        <fn>Mathew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 17th, Margaret Blair, 88, died at the residence of her brother,
                    Mathew Coulter, near Doylesburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 28th, Franklin Gamble, 22, died at the residence of his
                    brother-in-law, Dr. Mackey, near Mt. Union. Gamble served in the army, both in
                    the six month service and later in the 21st Penn Cav.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.07.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
