<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; --><hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.03.14"><header><title>Franklin Repository</title><tagger><taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName><tagDate>03/19</tagDate><tagNote/></tagger><address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address><date n="1866-03-14"><year>1866</year><month norm="03">March</month><day>14</day><weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday></date><frequency>weekly</frequency><extent>04</extent><editionNote/></header><paperBody><page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.14.01"><pageNote/></page><page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.14.02"><div type="e"><column>1</column><head>Gen. John W. Geary</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript><p>We fling to the breeze to-day the Union banner for the struggle of 1866, with the honored name of Major General John W. Geary upon it as the unanimous choice of the great Union party for the Gubernatorial chair. Whatever differences of opinion may have been entertained as to the propriety of the choice, or whatever preferences may have been cherished for other able and distinguished Union leaders, all now unite cordially and make common cause, with a degree of earnestness unusual in our political conflicts, to give success to our standard-bearer. The present peculiar perils of the nation would, if there were no other considerations, impel every Union man to an exhaustive effort for Gen. Geary's success; but we are glad to know that the Union party will sustain him with a devotion and enthusiasm which could be accorded only to a favorite candidate.</p><p>We give elsewhere in this paper a full account of the life, character and services of the distinguished candidate of the Union party; and in this part of Pennsylvania, where Gen. Geary is not intimately known save as his achievements in the field have made his name a house-hold word, it will be read with interest. While all know how nobly he has struggled with our gallant armies to suppress the rebellion, his earlier history, it will be seen, is such as fitly comports with the brilliant laurels he has won in his complete circle of sanguinary battle-fields, from the Second Bull Run to Gettysburg, thence to the battle of the clouds on Missionary Ridge, thence to Atlanta, thence to Savannah, and finally to the surrender of Johnson in North Carolina. He owes his various positions of honor and responsible trust in life to no fortuitous circumstances, but has nobly won his way to the confidence and affections of his countrymen by his ability, fidelity and enlightened patriotism. He had earned distinction as a soldier in the bloody march from Vera Cruz to Mexico under Scott, and returned, when peace had been achieved, to his home in Westmoreland county; but he was soon assigned to an official position on the Pacific coast, where he remained several years in the discharge of most important public duties.</p><p>In July, 1856, President Pierce appointed Gen. Geary Governor of Kansas. Reeder and Shannon had been there before him and had been removed. Gen. Geary was then in good standing in the Democratic party of that day, and was doubtless expected by Mr. Pierce to promote the interests of the Slavery propagandists in that struggle; but he had mistaken Gen. Geary's fidelity to freedom and justice. When he reached that troubled country he carefully abstained from affording any sanction to the border-ruffianism that had assumed to control the territory, and the result was that the pro-slavery interest was soon arrayed against him. He struggled on for some time; but finding himself unsupported by the President he finally resigned and returned home. Since then, we believe, that Gen. Geary has affiliated with the free-soil element in the Democratic party, and in 1860 he supported Douglas for President--the last Democrat for whom he ever cast a vote. In 1861 he at once took position with the War Democrats who were compelled to sever themselves from their old party or be arrayed against their country, and he cordially supported Gov. Curtin in 1863, President Lincoln in 1864, and earnestly urged the success of the Union ticket in 1865. He manfully and emphatically endorsed the platform of the Union State Convention, and on all occasions, before the meeting of the Convention, he unhesitatingly declared himself to be in earnest sympathy with the Union majority of Congress in the pending struggle.</p><p>Such is the Union candidate for Governor,--one who is blameless in all the relations of private life and has maintained his devotion to principle in every struggle, and who returns to the people, after four years of terrible war, bronzed and battle scarred, and with a name of fame inseparably interwoven with the noblest achievements of our arms in the late fearful conflict. He has proven his fidelity to Freedom and Justice not only by words, but by deeds which give lustre to our thrilling history; and we have but to stand man to man, and heart to heart, and do our whole duty, and Gen. John W. Geary will be chosen to the Executive chair by the largest popular majority Pennsylvania has given since 1860.</p></transcript><trailer/><names/><summary>The editors cast their full-fledged support behind Gen. John W. Geary's gubernatorial candidacy.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="e"><column>1</column><head>Hon. Heister Clymer</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript><p>We congratulate the Democracy and the country on the nomination of Hon. Heister Clymer, of Berk, as the Democratic candidate for Governor. It was a manly act of his party, because he fitly and truly represents its principles; and with him as their candidate there can be no mistaking the issues involved in the contest. In 1864 the Democracy presented Gen. McClellan in front with Pendleton, Vallandigham and all their sympathizers in the back-ground, and in 1865, Col. Davis was pressed to the front to dim a soldier's fame and suffer the defeat his treachery to his country so richly merited. Not so now. Twice has fraud been tried by the Democracy, by presenting soldiers as candidates; but in 1866 they present Mr. Clymer who has, from the day the rebels fired upon Sumter until now, faithfully, ably and enthusiastically maintained the cause of those who nerved the arm of treason and cheered its heart in the bloody work.</p><p>We have too often tested the power of Mr. Clymer as a skilful and able disputant and leader; have too many pleasant recollections of his excellent social qualities, and of the high standard of manhood he ever maintains as a legislator and a gentleman, to assail him personally in the contest. He is deservedly beloved by his political friends and respected by his political foes; and we shall be mistaken if he does not conduct the struggle with a high measure of dignity and ability. He is an able and finished popular speaker, and will throw the highest measure of energy and enthusiasm into the fight; but he will be met at every step with his fatal record; confronted on every stand by those who fought the battles of his country while he fought the government and sought to defeat the measures essential to his very life; and the people of Pennsylvania cannot become such terrible suicides as to give them success.</p><p>Mr. Clymer was reared a Whig and so remained until 1856, when he went over to Buchanan. In 1860 he was chosen to the Senate to fill a vacancy, and at once took rank as a leader in his party. In 1861 he was re-elected, and again in 1864, and for five years past he has been confessedly the master spirit of the Democratic side in that body. In April, 1861, when dispatches were read from the clerk's desk announcing the bombardment of Sumter, he led his little party resolutely against a bill to put the Commonwealth in a state of defence. From thence until the overthrow of the rebellion, he acted consistently, earnestly, and with dangerous skill and ability, against every measure of the national administration designed to defeat treason and restore the government, and his last great effort in the Senate fitly demanded that blood-stained rebels should be admitted to representation in Congress. With the issues so clearly defined, no faithful man can err, and until Pennsylvania has ceased to be loyal, Mr. Clymer cannot be chosen her Chief Magistrate.</p></transcript><trailer/><names/><summary>The editorial applauds the Democrats' nomination of Heister Clymer for governor, contending that the decision ensures that there "can be no mistaking the issues involved in the contest."  In contrast to the previous two elections, when the Democrats tried to perpetrate a "fraud" by nominating soldiers, Clymer's candidacy indicates the Democrats will run on a platform that fully acknowledges the party's opposition to the late war.  Despite Clymer's position on the conflict, the piece notes, he is "deservedly beloved by his political friends and respected by his political foes."</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>2</column><head/><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>Although Gen. Meade has denied all suggestions that he consented to be nominated by Democrats as their gubernatorial candidate, the article intimates that the soldier has not been completely forthright in his response to the allegations.  According to the Repository's sources, Meade was solicited for the position by no other than President Johnson, who reportedly offered him a three year leave of absence "in case of his election," so that he could keep his rank in the army.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>2</column><head/><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>The article flatly denies the assertion made by the Harrisburg Telegraph that a resolution endorsing President Johnson was passed at Union State Convention, and calls on readers to inspect the party's platform approved at that meeting and judge for themselves the accuracy of the statement.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head/><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>Announces that Judge Pearson has appointed H. N. McAllister, of Bellafonte, and Col. Thomas J. Jordan and John Briggs, both of Harrisburg, as Appraisers to administer the program called for Relief Bill.  The piece praises the "high character of the board for business capacity, sound judgement and unswerving integrity" and contends that the appointees give "the best possible assurance not only that justice will be faithfully administered, but also that there will be a general and cordial acquiescence in their decisions because they will be accepted as just."</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head/><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>In its report on the possible presence of the rinderpest in Montgomery and Berks, a committee appointed by the Philadelphia Agricultural Society has determined that it is "unable to ascertain any authentic instance of the existence" of the cattle disease in either of the counties.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head>Gen. John W. Geary</head><origin>Pittsburg Dispatch</origin><commentary>"As most of our readers are not personally acquainted with Maj. Gen. Geary, and know but little of his early and private history, we give the following interesting article  from the Pittsburg Dispatch:"</commentary><excerpt/><transcript><p>As most of our readers are not personally acquainted with Maj. Gen. Geary, and know but little of his early and private history, we give the following interesting article from the Pittsburg <emph rend="italic">Dispatch:</emph></p><p>The Union State Convention have placed in nomination Gen. John W. Geary, of Westmoreland county. While our personal preference was for another candidate, we felt confident that, from the three more prominent gentlemen spoken of for the nomination, none could be chosen not eminently fit for the position. Now that a choice has been made, it is well to inform our readers who the individual is who has been chosen to bear the banner of the Union in the Fall Campaign.</p><p>Gen. John W. Geary was born in the neighboring county of Westmoreland, and is now about forty-seven years of age. His parents were of but small pecuniary means, and became involved in a debt, owing to the protracted illness of his father previous to his death, leaving our subject to support his widowed mother from the pittance in those days accorded to one who essayed to teach a country school, but he succeeded in cancelling the debts of his father, and, after acting for a time as a clerk in a wholesale house in our city, completed his education at Jefferson College, Canonsburg, Pa.</p><p>We next hear of him in the employ of the State authorities, and also of the Green River Improvement Company, as a civil engineer, in Kentucky, where he assisted in the survey of several public improvements--returning to his native State to become, after some service in subordinate positions, Superintendent of the Portage Railroad, at that time the connecting link between the canals on either side of the Alleghenies.</p><p>His taste for mathematics early gave him an inclination for military affairs, and he took such an interest in our volunteer militia, its proper organization and efficiency, that he was chosen to command the brigade comprising the counties of Somerset and Cambria.</p><p>Twenty years ago, on war arising with Mexico, he had an opportunity of bringing his military acquirements into play, and on the first call for troops marched to Pittsburg in command of the "American Highlanders," a company of mountaineers, composed of his neighbors, which joined Col. Robert's Second Pennsylvania Regiment, of which their youthful captain was almost unanimously chosen Lieutenant Colonel. Joining Scott at Vera Cruz, this regiment continued to serve under him throughout his brilliant campaign. In the battles of La Hoya, Chapultepec, Garita de Belen and the City of Mexico, the young soldier did noble service, and in that city was chosen, by vote of the regiment, to succeed Col. Roberts, on the death of the latter. His regiment did yeoman service in the enemy's land, gallantly, though unsuccessfully, storming the heights of Chapultepec, (where General G. was wounded,) and entering the Belen Gate under a terrific fire from the enemy. Their gallant service, and that of their commander, was at once acknowledged by placing him in command of the citadel. Although strict in discipline, he was kind of heart, and as quick to overlook the trifling faults which had their origin in ignorance and inexperience, as determined to punish such as persisted in evil-doing.</p><p>On the return of peace Col. Geary brought his regiment to this city from Mexico, (without the loss of a man by the way) where they mustered some four hundred of the eleven hundred who had gone to the war. Our citizens well remember the ovation given the soldiers of that war on their arrival at our wharves, and the speech of our venerable Wilkins, now no more, on their reception. It has not been excelled by anything of the kind in twenty years which have since elapsed.</p><p>For a year or two Col. Geary returned to private life, until called from retirement by President Polk, early in 1849, when he was sent to California as Postmaster of San Francisco, with authority to establish post-offices, mail routes, &amp;c., in that partially explored territory, just annexed to the Union, but, from the discovery of its golden treasures, increasing in importance with a rapidity never before exampled. Probably no better selection could have been made for the position, and the incumbent gave such general satisfaction that, on his removal from it on Gen. Taylor's accession, he was eight days after unanimously chosen Alcalde of the city, under the Spanish laws, an office comprising the position of alderman, mayor, coroner, public administrator, chairman of councils, register, recorder, and generally <emph rend="italic">all the county offices</emph>, the duties of which he executed with great ability, and a celebrity which better suited the vast Anglo-Saxon population flowing into the new State than the <emph rend="italic">poco tiempo</emph> habits of the <emph rend="italic">hourbres</emph> "to the manner born."</p><p>During the month which Col. Geary was, with his family, detained on the Isthmus, he succeeded in organizing the Masons and the Odd Fellows among the transient and resident Americans there, for the alleviation of the distress of the sick amongst the crowds of our countrymen continually subject to detention at Panama, through the paucity of shipping on the Pacific side. On his quarters being robbed by the guard in that city, he compelled the thieves to march back with their plunder, and deposit it in his room, after a struggle with the sergeant and his men, in which nothing but great coolness and determination saved his life.</p><p>General Bennet Riley, then Military Governor of California, also (on his election as Alcalde,) commissioned him as Judge of First Instance, which he subsequently resigned in favor of Judge Almond, of Missouri, since deceased. Re-elected Alcalde by a vote lacking but twelve of unanimity in a poll of four thousand, he held the position until the office was abolished, and the American system of city and county government established in May, 1850, when he was chosen Mayor. On the expiration of the term he acted as one of the Commissioners of the Funded Debt of the city until February, 1852, when he returned to "the States"--intending, like many others, to return to California, but was prevented by severe domestic afflictions, and pecuniary losses caused by the failure of others.</p><p>Having resided in San Francisco during a considerable portion of Gen. Geary's administration of its affairs, and having been for a part of the time placed in a position which gave us an opportunity of seeing his mode of conducting the city Government, we can say that it was as safe a city as a residence, so far as regards security for life and property, during that period, as the city of Pittsburg and Allegheny is to-day--that, notwithstanding its numerous drinking-houses and gambling-shops, and its heterogeneous population, much of it the offscouring of creation, and all thrown suddenly together, the robberies and murders were not more numerous than they are now in our own cities. Before he was Alcalde, the "hounds," (an exaggeration of our "mudlarks") roamed the streets and robbed in the open day, and after his mayorality a vigilance committee of a thousand armed men was deemed necessary to purify the city of its scoundrelism.</p><p>We all know that, although allowed to grant the city lands to whom he pleased, under a Mexican law, on condition of improvement, he sturdily refused to sacrifice her real estate when he could have realized many thousands of dollars for himself by such a lawful piece of rascality--and that, when a mere tool of some speculators was appointed Justice of the Peace to effect such a fraud, he sturdily opposed the notorious "Colton Grant" to the bitter end. His energy during the first great fire in the city, in December 1849, in checking flames by the free use of gunpowder, the only "fire extinguisher" available, and his courage in personally conveying much of it in buildings already in flames, saved property of vast value, but led to heavy judgments against himself, which, however, the city subsequently assumed. Taken altogether, his whole administration of the post office, municipal department and the sinking fund of that city, proved Gen. Geary no common man, but one possessed of executive ability of a high order.</p><p>In the Summer of 1856 he succeeded Wilson Shannon, of Ohio, as Territorial Governor of Kansas. Having always belonged to the Democratic party, which had acted with the South, it was supposed that Gen. Geary would be influenced to favor the pro-slavery men of the border in their desperate efforts to establish that institution in the new State just preparing for admission to the Union. The other Government officers there, however, soon discovered he could not be used as a mere tool of border ruffianism, and, with Atchison, Stringfellow and others, who were then raidieg the territory, joined in abuse of the Governor, who had issued orders to disarm the territorial militia, (principally Missourians,) called out by his predecessor, was endeavoring to bring peace out of anarchy-protected Lawrence against their threatened attack, and generally dealt with fairness toward all contending factions in the territory. Not receiving the support from President Buchanan which was promised him when he accepted the position, Gen. Geary, in March, 1857, resigned his office and returned home, greatly to the regret of the free-State population. His administration there, during a period of unexampled difficulty, will always be spoken of to his praise.</p><p>His more recent history, as a gallant General of the Union armies, during the Great Rebellion, is known to all, and needs no repetition here; as we had designed more to call attention to Geary as a civilian than as a military man, the duties of the position which he is next to occupy pertaining almost entirely to the former character, and requiring the executive ability so abundantly shown by him in the civil positions he has heretofore filled.</p><p>The Pittsburg <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph> gives the following brief but correct resume of Gen. Geary's military achievements during the late war:</p><p>From reports filed in the office of the Secretary of War, it appears that during his term of service Gen. Geary was engaged in over fifty hotly contested battles and important skirmishes, besides many others of lesser note. Among these engagements may be especially named that of Bolivar Heights, Cedar Mountain, the <emph rend="italic">three days'</emph> fight at Chancellorsville, the struggle at Gettysburg, which also lasted <emph rend="italic">three days</emph>, and resulted in driving back the enemy from the soil of Pennsylvania, Wauhatchie, Lookout Mountain, Mission Ridge, Ringgold, Triana, Mill Creek and Snake Creek Gaps, Resaca, (two days,) New Hope Church, (seven days,) Muddy Creek, Nose's Creek, Kolb's Farm, Kenesaw, Pine Hill, Marietta, Peach Tree Creek, siege and capture of Atlanta, (twenty days,) siege of Savannah, (ten days,) which was captured by his division ten hours before any other troops reached that city, as was also Fort Jackson, both of which places were surrendered in person to Gen Geary. In this capture three hundred and fifty prisoners, one hundred and fourteen pieces of artillery, thirty-eight thousand five hundred bales of cotton and five ocean steamers, with an immense variety of ammunition and other stores, fell into the hands of the victors.</p><p>Upon the capture of Savannah, Gen. Geary was appointed by Maj. Gen. Sherman, its <emph rend="italic">Military Governor</emph>, which position he filled with signal credit to himself until he was relieved, that he might accompany the triumphant army of Sherman in its further march through the Carolinas.</p><p>In the battle of Bolivar Heights he received a severe wound in the right knee, and at Cedar Mountain he was slightly wounded in the left ankle, and seriously through the elbow joint of the left arm. He was also struck in the right breast and severely injured by the fragment of a shell at Chancellorsville. His two sons accompanied him to the field, the eldest of whom, a young man of eighteen years, who had advanced himself by sterling ability to command a battery, with the rank of Captain, and gave promise of the utmost capacity and usefulness, was killed at the battle of Wauhatchie. "At the time that he fell," says an eloquent writer, "he was acting as Lieutenant of one section of Knapp's Battery. As an artillerist he had no superior in the army. His gun was his pride. He was always beside her, and his aim was unerring. At this battle, about twelve hundred and fifty men under command of Gen. Geary, were attacked from an eminence, by five thousand of the enemy, at twelve o'clock at night. The unequal fight was gallantly accepted, and though the command was at first thrown in some disorder, they speedily rallied, and not only repulsed, but drove from the field the vastly superior numbers of the enemy. In the hottest of the fight--in the act of sighting his gun, his forehead pierced with a bullet, young Geary fell, and instantly expired. His father coming to the spot, clasped in an agonizing embrace the lifeless form of his boy--then, mounting his horse, dashed wildly into the thickest ranks of the foe, and rode like an avenging spirit over that bloody field until the enemy were utterly routed and put to flight." This General Hooker pronounces the most gallant and successful charge that has come to his knowledge during the war.</p><p>In this official report of this battle Gen. Hooker says: "During these operations a heavy musketry fire, with rapid discharges of artillery, continued to reach us from Geary. It was evident that a formidable adversary had gathered around him and that he was battering him with all his might. For almost three hours, without assistance, he repelled the repeated attacks of vastly superior numbers, and, in the end, drove them ingloriously from the field. At one time they had enveloped him on three sides, under circumstances that would have dismayed any officer except one endowed with an iron will and the most exalted courage." SUCH IS THE CHARACTER OF GENERAL GEARY!</p></transcript><trailer/><names/><summary>A brief biography of the Republican party's gubernatorial candidate in the upcoming election, Gen. John W. Geary.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>5</column><head/><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>The piece relates the experiences of Col. Eli Parker, "an Indian, and one of the most trusted aids of Gen. Grant," who recently returned from a tour of the South where he was sent to gauge the level of anti-Union sentiments present there and to ascertain whether further reductions in the army were possible.  While wearing his uniform, Parker detected virtually no hostility directed toward the federal government.  Finding the southerners' sentiments slightly suspicious, Parker clothed himself as a Choctaw, one of the Southwest's most "intensely pro-slavery tribes."  "This disguise," says the article, "unloosed the latch-strings to their secret thoughts, and thereafter he heard not one loyal word, except when in the pursuance of his duty, he was with our own officers."</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>5</column><head/><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>According to the testimony of Major-General Thomas, secret organizations have sprung up throughout the South whose objective is "to obtain representation in Congress, then to impair or destroy the credit of the National Government, involve the country in a foreign war and then avail themselves of the opportunity thus created to effect a dissolution of the Union and the establishment of a separate Government."</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="l"><column>5</column><head>County Superintendent</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer>A School Director</trailer><names><name><ln>Youst</ln><fn>Jacob</fn><sf/><pf/></name></names><summary>The author of the letter seconds a motion offered in the last issue of the Repository, endorsing the nomination of Jacob Youst as a candidate for the office of Superintendent of Common Schools of Franklin county.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>7</column><head>Union State Convention!--Opening of the Great Struggle of 1866</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>A summary of the proceedings at the Union State Convention held last week and a copy of the party platform and resolutions adopted at the meeting.</summary><note/><look/></div><pageNote/></page><page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.14.03"><div type="a"><column>2</column><head>Local Items--Graduated</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Bard</ln><fn>Cephas L.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Burk</ln><fn>George</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Maxwell</ln><fn>James</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Gelwix</ln><fn>J. Montgomery</fn><sf/><pf/></name></names><summary>Commends Cephas L. Bard, James A. Maxwell, George W. Burk, and J. Montgomery Gelwix, all of whom graduated from Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia.  All of the graduates, the piece informs readers, had experience prior to attending school.  Bard, Burk, and Maxwell served in the army as medical assistants while Gelwix labored in a similar capacity in the practice of Richards &amp; Montgomery.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>2</column><head>Local Items--Borough Nominations</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Stoner</ln><fn>Henry S.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Rodes</ln><fn>Benjamin</fn><sf/><pf>Capt.</pf></name><name><ln>Hamilton</ln><fn>Adam B.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Shillito</ln><fn>S. Miller</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Snider</ln><fn>Jacob N.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Chamberlain</ln><fn>David</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Houser</ln><fn>Michael</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Huber</ln><fn>John</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Armstrong</ln><fn>Samuel M.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Henninger</ln><fn>Frederick</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Eyster</ln><fn>William C.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Pearce</ln><fn>William</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Forbes</ln><fn>John</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Balsley</ln><fn>George J.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Sieders</ln><fn>John</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>McClellan</ln><fn>Rufus K.</fn><sf/><pf/></name></names><summary>A list of the men nominated at the meeting of the North Ward, held at the Union Hotel, and the South Ward, held Indian Queen Hotel, to represent the Union Party in the upcoming election.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>2</column><head>Local Items--An Honor</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Richards</ln><fn>Jarrett T.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Richards</ln><fn>J. C.</fn><sf/><pf>Dr.</pf></name></names><summary>Proudly announces that Jarrett T. Richards, son of Dr. J. C. Richards, has been selected Alumni Orator of the Columbia College Law School by the class of 1866.  Richards will deliver the address at the commencement in May 1867.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head>Local Items--Thieves Arrested</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Houser</ln><fn/><sf/><pf>Officer</pf></name></names><summary>Three men were arraigned in Chambersburg last Thursday and charged with stealing forty dollars worth of jewelry from the daughter of Adam Wolff.  The men stole the jewelry while lodging at Wolff's boarding house near Cumberland Valley Depot and absconded the next morning.  They were arrested a short time later by Officer Houser who "started in immediate pursuit and overtook the thieves at Shippensburg, where he arrested them with the stolen property in their possession."  The men were placed in jail to await their trial in April.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head>Local Items--Shooting Affair At Mercersburg</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Mayhew</ln><fn>Harvey</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Hoeflich</ln><fn/><sf/><pf/></name></names><summary>Harvey Mayhew was wounded last Monday evening in an altercation that occurred at McAfee's Hotel in Mercersburg.  Evidently the incident started sometime earlier in the afternoon when Mayhew and another man named Hoeflich got into an argument while drinking.  Though the pair were separated after the melee, the two met again in the evening at McAfee's where the conflict was resumed.  According to witnesses, Mayhew struck Hoeflich with a severe blow that sent him to the floor.  When Hoeflich recovered, he pulled a gun and shot Mayhew in the groin.  Mayhew, it is reported, barely survived the shooting.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head>Local Items--Accident to Ex-Gov. Ritner</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>Reports that ex-Governor Ritner took a nasty spill last Thursday while visiting his daughter-in-law in Chambersburg.  Ritner "fell on the pavement, lacerating the back part of his head and was so stunned that he lay insensible for some time."</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head>Local Items</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Sellers</ln><fn>Jacob</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Miller</ln><fn>John</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Chambers</ln><fn>Benjamin</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>McCullogh</ln><fn>A. H.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Eyster</ln><fn>C. W.</fn><sf/><pf/></name></names><summary>Announces that Jacob Sellers, John Miller, Benjamin Chambers, A. H. McCulloch, and C. W. Eyster were appointed to serve on an advisory committee that will "act and advise" the appraisers sent to administer the relief bill against any fraudulent claims.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head>Local Items--The Hope</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>Announces that, after receiving their long-awaited new equipment, the Hope Fire Company paraded through the town's streets showing off the engine and hose carriage.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head>Local Items</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Caufman</ln><fn>A. D.</fn><sf/><pf/></name></names><summary>Reports that A. D. Caufman was placed on the Union State Committee for Franklin county.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="a"><column>3</column><head>Local Items--Religious</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names/><summary>The Presbyterian congregation will unite with the congregation of the German Reformed Church until further notice.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="s"><column>4</column><head>Married</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Ripple</ln><fn>James A.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Barkdoll</ln><fn>Sallie A.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Krebs</ln><fn>W. E.</fn><sf/><pf>Rev.</pf></name></names><summary>On March 8th, James A. Ripple nad Sallie A. Barkdoll were married by Rev. W.E. Krebs.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="s"><column>4</column><head>Married</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Winter</ln><fn>Samuel S.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Shockey</ln><fn>Eliza</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Shockey</ln><fn>Isaac</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Oller</ln><fn>J.  F.</fn><sf/><pf>Rev.</pf></name></names><summary>On Feb. 26th, Samuel S. Winter, of Marion, Kentucky, and Eliza Shockey, daughter of Isaac Shockey, were married by Rev. J. F. Oller.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="s"><column>4</column><head>Married</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Noll</ln><fn>Henry</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Brown</ln><fn>Fanny</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Eyster</ln><fn>W. F.</fn><sf/><pf>Rev.</pf></name></names><summary>On March 1st, Henry Noll and Fanny Brown were married by Rev. W. F. Eyster.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="s"><column>4</column><head>Married</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>McConnell</ln><fn>David</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Graul</ln><fn>Benjamin</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Graul</ln><fn>Lavania</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Akers</ln><fn>J. Benson</fn><sf/><pf>Rev.</pf></name></names><summary>On Feb. 28th, David McConnell and Lavania, daughter of Benjamin Graul, were married by Rev. J. Benson Akers.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="s"><column>4</column><head>Married</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>McCutchen</ln><fn>Robert</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Bowman</ln><fn>Mary E.</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Akers</ln><fn>J. Benson</fn><sf/><pf>Rev.</pf></name><name><ln>Adams</ln><fn>William</fn><sf/><pf/></name></names><summary>On March 1st, Robert McCutchen and Mary E. Bowman were married at the residence of William Adams by Rev. J. Benson Akers.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="s"><column>4</column><head>Married</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Skinner</ln><fn>Andrew</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Goshorn</ln><fn>Rosey</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>West</ln><fn>William</fn><sf/><pf>Rev.</pf></name></names><summary>On March 8th, Andrew Skinner and Rosey Goshorn were married by Rev. William West.</summary><note/><look/></div><div type="o"><column>4</column><head>Died</head><origin/><commentary/><excerpt/><transcript/><trailer/><names><name><ln>Grove</ln><fn>Frank Leachy</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Grove</ln><fn>Mary</fn><sf/><pf/></name><name><ln>Grove</ln><fn>Alexander</fn><sf/><pf/></name></names><summary>On March 1st, Frank Leachy, son of Mary and the late Alexander Grove, died in Chambersburg.  He was 14 years old.</summary><note/><look/></div><pageNote/></page><page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.14.04"><pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote></page></paperBody></hwp>