<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.10.03">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/25</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-10-03">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="10"/>
            <day>03</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.10.03.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>"My Policy" in 1864</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ANDREW JOHNSON ON RECONSTRUCTION.</p>
                    <p>"In calling a convention to restore the State, who shall restore and
                        re-establish it? Shall the man who gave his influence and his means to
                        destroy the Government? Is he to participate in the great work of
                        reorganization? Shall he who brought this misery upon the State be permitted
                        to control its destinies? If this be so, then all the precious blood of our
                        brave soldiers and officers so freely poured out will have been wantonly
                        spilled, all the glorious victories won by our noble armies will go for
                        naught, and all the battlefields which have been sown with dead heroes
                        during the rebellion will have been made memorable in vain. Why all this
                        carnage and devastation? It was that treason might be put down and traitors
                        punished. Therefore I say that traitors shall take a back seat in the work
                        of restoration."</p>
                    <p>ANDREW JOHNSON IN FAVOR OF DISFRANCHISING TRAITORS.</p>
                    <p>"I say that the traitor has ceased to be a citizen, and in joining the
                        rebellion has become a public enemy. He forfeited his right to vote with
                        loyal men when he renounced his citizenship and sought to destroy our
                        Government. We say to the most honest and industrious foreigner who comes
                        from England and Germany to dwell among us, and to add to the wealth of the
                        country, 'Before you can be a citizen you must stay here for five years.' If
                        we are so cautious about foreigners, who voluntarily renounce their homes to
                        live with us, what should we say to the traitor who, although born and
                        reared among us, has raised a parricidal hand against the Government which
                        always protected him? My judgement is that he should be subjected to a
                        severe ordeal before he is restored to citizenship."</p>
                    <p>ANDREW JOHNSON IN FAVOR OF EXECUTING TRAITORS.</p>
                    <p>"Show me who has been engaged in these conspiracies, who has fired upon our
                        flag, who has given instructions to take our forts, custom houses, arsenals,
                        and dock-yards, and I will show you a traitor. Were I President of the
                        United States, I would do as Thomas Jefferson did in 1806 with Aaron Burr. I
                        would have them arrested, and, if convicted, within the meaning and scope of
                        the Constitution, by the Eternal God I would execute them!"</p>
                    <p>ANDREW JOHNSON FAVORS CONFISCATION.</p>
                    <p>"Treason must be made odious and traitors must be punished and impoverished.
                        Their great plantations must be seized and divided into small farms, and
                        sold to honest, industrious men."</p>
                    <p>ANDREW JOHNSON JUDGED BY HIMSELF.</p>
                    <p>Whenever you find a man anywhere prating about the Constitution of the United
                        States, spot him: he's a traitor.--<emph rend="italic">Andrew Johnson's
                            Campaign Speech at Nashville, September, 1864.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since taking office, the article contends, Andrew Johnson has dramatically
                    altered his stand regarding the rebels. To illustrate the extent of his
                    reversal, it compares Johnson's pronouncements from 1864, when he advocated
                    disfranchising southern "traitors" and confiscating their property, with his
                    current, less adverserial policy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Facts For Bondholders</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>If Andrew Johnson succeeds in his attempts to usurp power from Congress,
                    the article cautions bondholders, his actions could have serious repercussions
                    on their investments. Indeed, should Johnson dismiss Congress, as it is rumored
                    he will do if northern Democrats and Johnson Republicans gain a sufficient
                    number of seats in the upcoming election, it will result in significant
                    reduction in the value of U. S. bonds, making "them as WORTHLESS AS REBEL
                    BONDS."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.10.03.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>What Of Pennsylvania?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors remind readers that the stakes in the upcoming election are
                    immense. They predict Gen. Geary will defeat Clymer, the Democratic nominee, by
                    20,000 or more votes in the gubernatorial contest, yet, they stress, it is
                    imperative that all Union men cast their ballots to insure such a result.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Coming Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This is the last number of the REPOSITORY that will be issued prior to the
                        election. We therefore take the opportunity to urge upon the Union men of
                        the various election Districts of our county to see to it that every Union
                        voter in their respective districts gets to the polls early on the day of
                        the election and casts his ticket for all the Republican nominees, from
                        Governor to County Auditor. A full vote will insure the election of your
                        county ticket by a good sound majority, and do much towards swelling the
                        majority which the people of the State have determined to give to Maj. Gen.
                        John W. Geary, as a reward for gallant services rendered them. <emph
                            rend="italic">Let there be no splitting of tickets</emph>, for any
                        cause. Should any individual have, or imagine he has, cause of grievance
                        against any candidate on the Union Republican ticket, let him forget the
                        individual grievance in the desire to advance the public good, and vote the
                        straight ticket. Bear in mind that every effort will be made by the Locofoco
                        Copperhead Johnsonites to defeat your nominees for the Legislature and for
                        Congress. They know full well that there is no hope for Clymer; and they
                        know also the importance of securing the Legislature so that they may be
                        able to elect a rebel-sympathizer to the United States Senate in place of
                        the renegade Cowan. And they are especially anxious to send Mr. Sharpe to
                        Congress in place of our true Union Representative, Gen. Wm. H. Koontz--as
                        they expect that Mr. Sharpe would support the President's policy and vote
                        for the immediate admission of unrepentant rebels to seats in Congress. Do
                        not therefore be surprised. Union men of Franklin County and of this
                        Congressional district, should Democrats, Copperheads and Johnsonites offer
                        to trade with you, and vote for Geary for Governor, if you will vote for
                        Sharpe for Congress, or for M'Allen or Adams for the Legislature. Spurn all
                        such offers with the contempt they merit. If you were to agree to them you
                        would be cheated--and would <emph rend="italic">deserve</emph> to be
                        cheated. They are the expedients of desperate, dishonest men--and fidelity
                        to your principles and your party demands that you should show them no
                        favor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors admonish Union men of the county "to see to it that every Union
                    voter in their respective districts gets to the polls." They also stress the
                    necessity of voting the straight ticket. Should the Democrats succeed at
                    electing one of their own either to Congress or the state legislature, they
                    warn, it will only strengthen the president's efforts to re-admit the southern
                    states to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Reconstruction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There are two competing visions of how Reconstruction should be carried
                    out, explains the article. The first calls for the immediate re-admission of the
                    former rebel states and is promulgated by President Johnson; the second seeks
                    guarantees, in the form of constitutional amendments, from the southern states
                    before they can be restored "to their old places of power and influence in the
                    nation" and is advocated by Congress. Should Johnson succeed at passing his
                    policy, it will "continue to disturb the peace of the nation for years to come."
                    If Congress prevails, however, peace "will be restored throughout the land" and
                    the country will begin a period of "prosperity unprecedented in the history of
                    the world."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gen. Wm. H. Koontz</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Koontz has been quite ill of late, explains the piece, as a
                    consequence he has been unable to visit the eastern sections of the district,
                    including Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Rebuke The Corruptionists!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Never before in the history of all the parties of the past or present did
                    an administration descend to the open and shameless purchase of votes by offices
                    and plunder."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article criticizes the Johnson administration for its corrupt tactics
                    and practices, which include blatant attempts at bribery and the bartering of
                    offices for votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Democratic Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article offers a negative appraisal of the Democratic meeting held in
                    Chambersburg last Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Democratic Electioneering</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>DEMOCRATIC ELECTIONEERING.--<emph rend="italic">Ten thousand dollars</emph>
                        we understand have been sent into this Congressional district to carry it
                        for Mr. Sharpe. It is confidently expected that from 500 to 1000 votes can
                        be <emph rend="italic">bought up</emph> for that sum. <emph rend="italic"
                            >Ten dollars</emph> a piece in cash have been offered to more than one
                            <emph rend="italic">needy</emph> Republican, if he would only agree to
                        drop Gen. Koontz and go for Mr. Sharpe. And <emph rend="italic">barrels of
                            flour</emph> have become quite plenty and easily obtainable. Only <emph
                            rend="italic">one</emph> Republican that we can hear of, has as yet
                        sacrificed his principles to his belly--and he, report says, could not live
                        upon <emph rend="italic">bread</emph> alone, but asked and obtained some
                            <emph rend="italic">mutton</emph> also. So well pleased is he said to be
                        with his bargain, that report says he has already hauled two other barrels
                        of flour to starving friends in St. Thomas township. Rumor says that a "big"
                        fish is acting as the Almoner in this distribution of bread and meat to the
                        hungry. It is not a very long time until the election, but we think it will
                        be plenty <emph rend="italic">long</emph> to <emph rend="italic">spot</emph>
                        this good Samaritan, and bring him and his needy friends to grief. Verily
                        the man who will sell his <emph rend="italic">birth-right</emph> for ten
                        dollars or a barrel of flour should be a Johnson man, for he is too mean to
                        belong to any respectable party.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Local Democrats have been given ten thousand dollars to "carry" the
                    election for William Sharpe. With that amount of money, the piece suggests,
                    Democrats hope to purchase 500 to 1,000 votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Colonizing Voters!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>COLONIZING VOTERS.--We are informed that the Copper-Johnsonites, despairing
                        of carrying this county by fair and honest means, are resorting to one of
                        their old tricks to effect the same end, viz: <emph rend="italic">colonizing
                            voters</emph>. It is said that from <emph rend="italic">eighty</emph> to
                            <emph rend="italic">one hundred</emph> persons have been brought into
                        the county, and put to work under the employ of certain Democratic <emph
                            rend="italic">Iron Masters</emph> in the lower end of Metal township to
                        see that no fraud is perpetrated upon them and the Union party of the State.
                        It is easy to tell in rural districts, such as theirs, who are, and who are
                        not entitled to vote, and in <emph rend="italic">all cases</emph> the votes
                        of these travelling electors should be challenged, and they be compelled to
                        establish their right to vote in the manner, <emph rend="italic">and under
                            the penalties</emph>, provided in the laws of the State.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Democrats in Metal township are "resorting to one of
                    their old tricks" in an effort to stave off their inevitable defeat in the
                    upcoming election. To accomplish this feat they have brought 80 to 100 men into
                    the county, and "put them to work under the employ of certain Democratic Iron
                    Masters" in the lower end of the township, "for the purpose of aiding by their
                    votes to elect Mr. Sharpe to Congress."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Bribery, Dark and Dirty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that local Democrats visited Wolfstown and offered to pay 36
                    young black girls--one for each state--to ride in the procession during the
                    political "mass meeting" last week, but were rebuffed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.10.03.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Change of Proprietors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Feldman</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>D. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Henry Feldman has taken over the Indian Queen Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Janeway</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Rev. Janeway, pastor of the Presbyterian Church, and Rev.
                    Dr. Conrad, pastor of the Lutheran Church, will both be leaving their positions
                    in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Andrews died "at the advanced age of 105" in Strasburg on Sept. 22nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Guillotine Still At Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoch</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that two more appointees have lost their positions as a result of
                    the changes initiated by the Johnson administration. B. Fohl, the Postmaster of
                    St. Thomas, and Miss Grove, Postmaster of Mercersburg, were replaced by Michael
                    Keyser and John Hogh respectively.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republicans will hold a meeting in Shippensburg next Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Union Republican Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swansy</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Light</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hemminger</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stove</ln>
                        <fn>Emmanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article offers an overview of the various Republican meetings held in
                    Franklin county last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Eliz'h</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 9th, Eliz'h Senseny, 64, died in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacoby</ln>
                        <fn>John Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacoby</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacoby</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 28th, John Jacob, only son of Jonathan and Susannah Jacoby, died
                    in Antrim township. He was 14 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.10.03.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
