
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.10.05">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/07/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-10-05">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>05</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.05.01" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Free Trade Record of B. F. Meyers, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a selection of articles from a number of papers attesting
                    to Meyers' support for free trade and opposition to the tariff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>A Comparison</head>
                <origin>N.Y. Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article showing that national expenditures and debt have declined under
                    Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>What Workingmen Should Consider</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article assering that the protective tariff defends the interests of labor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.05.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To the Voters of Franklin Co.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>We feel that we have discharged our duty to our constituents during the
                        campaign now closing, by maintaining the principles of our party, by
                        upholding the candidates set forth by its authorized conventions, and by
                        opposing the dangerous doctrines and disloyal standard bearers of an
                        organization not yet ashamed of the disgraceful part it played during the
                        rebellion, and which seeks to win the suffrages of the people by pandering
                        to unworthy prejudices and by misrepresentation and duplicity. Upon the
                        Republicans of the county now rests the responsibility of success or defeat
                        at the polls; and the endorsement or condemnation of measures which they
                        have hitherto honorably sustained. Once more they are called upon to uphold
                        the political polity they have again and again approved; and to meet an
                        unchanged enemy they have repeatedly repulsed. The Democracy muster their
                        forces under the same banner which they bore in the years of the war, when
                        they were the allies of traitors in arms, with the offensive addition of
                        free trade boldly superadded. They have abated not one jot or tittle of
                        their criminal creed. They have not even set forth less obnoxious
                        candidates. Their bold badness again challenges political chastisement. Is
                        there a Republican in our midst to whom the issues of the war are less dear
                        than they were two years ago; or, to whom the party and men who saved the
                        nation's life and honor seem less worthy of trust and gratitude? Who is he
                        that is careless whether the party which saved, or the party which sought to
                        ruin the republic, shall control its destinies? whether the vexed question
                        happily settled shall remain at rest, or be re-opened for distraction and
                        turmoil? whether the patriot party shall continue quietly to administer the
                        government, develop the country's resources, protect its industries, melt
                        away the mountains of debt heaped on it by the Democracy, and keep it
                        respected at home and abroad; or, whether the insurgent combinations shall
                        have the control, massing insolent rebels in the front, fomenting war of
                        races and religion, squandering the public revenues upon greedy speculators,
                        dishonoring the national credit and bringing reproach upon republican
                        institutions, at the very time when the whole world is rant in admiration of
                        this government of the people?</p>

                    <p>Personal prejudices have no place when such great public interests are at
                        stake. Men who permit petty personal dislikes, or fancied personal slights
                        to warp them to wrong actions, jeopardizing the common weal, have poor
                        conceptions of the duties of citizenship in a government where the people
                        rule. And we take it that such men will have trouble in maintaining their
                        self respect, when calmer moments come, and they weigh their conduct in the
                        scales of their conscience and judgment.</p>

                    <p>The question will come up in their own bosoms for arbitrament, whether or not
                        they should have declared for the right for its own righteous sake, or for
                        the wrong because they did not incline to some persons or views which were
                        benefited by the triumph of the right.</p>

                    <p>Among the influences which weaken the fidelity of a few Republicans is the
                        extension of the voting privilege to the Negro. It is gratifying to know
                        that this affects but few. The right to a vote the colored man has earned,
                        nobly earned. He will exercise his privilege loyally. He will support the
                        right. Is it not foolish for a white man to abandon a cause he believes
                        just, because it is supported by folks not quite up to his ideas? The
                        Democracy have no objection to the colored man voting their ticket, and if
                        the entire colored vote could go over to them, we would hardly expect a
                        copperheaded brother, however great his aversion to a darkey, to desert his
                        colors. Whenever there is a chance to win a "nigger" vote, you will find a
                        White Man's Party man niggling after it.</p>

                    <p>The Republicans of Franklin County never had a better set of candidates
                        before them more or worthy of support. The Hon. John Cessna is a tried and
                        faithful public servant, a man of varied experience and surpassing political
                        ability, active and indefatigable in his duties. Early in his first session,
                        he took a leading position in Congress, and is now the most influential
                        member of the Pennsylvania delegation. The party all over the county is
                        anxious for his return. This is an endorsement that should satisfy the most
                        exacting <orig reg="Republican">Rebublican</orig>; but he comes with an
                        endorsement equally satisfactory, in the mad, bitter hatred of the
                        Democracy. He is their pet aversion, their most insane antipathy. Whisper
                        his name in the ear of the most tranquil Democrat and his face distorts
                        electrically, and the gall rises in his gorge, and his mouth fills with
                        noxious epithets. Even our placid and equable District Attorney flashes off
                        as if he were surcharged with nitro-glycerin. They would sacrifice their
                        whole ticket to defeat him! We had almost said they would cheerfully vote
                        for Meyers, but his free trade, rebel serving sympathies reconcile them to
                        the unfitness of his candidacy. The Republicanism of the member of our party
                        who is unwilling to vote for Mr. Cessna lies very lightly on his conscience.</p>

                    <p>We all know Mahon--the gallant soldier, bearing the honorable wounds received
                        in his country's service; a man who has proved his ability and fidelity in a
                        former position of public trust, whose private character is without
                        reproach; no selfish politician willing to secure his own election by
                        sacrificing his associates on the ticket. Even his political enemies confess
                        that he will serve his constituents honorably and faithfully.</p>

                    <p>Our friends in Perry county have given us a gentleman who is a worthy
                        colleague of Mr. Mahon, for whom we earnestly invoke a hearty support.</p>

                    <p>And where can you find more excellent men than Judge Huber and Jacob
                        Strickler, known as the very best of our citizens, consenting to serve the
                        party only because they owe an allegiance to the party? In such hands the
                        interests of the county will be safe, and honesty and purity will be
                        assured. It is a privilege to vote for such men. Who dare arraign a party
                        with such candidates?</p>

                    <p>And Mackey and Cressler add to the moral strength of the ticket. We defy the
                        Democracy to give a reason against their election. To be sure such officers
                        will not help their case, excepting as they are citizens of the county,
                        interested with us in the honest, economical and judicious administration of
                        its affairs.</p>

                    <p>We ask the people of all parties whether they can select a better class of
                        candidates, and we will give them the whole 16th Congressional district to
                        chose from?</p>

                    <p>And now, fellow-citizens, we appeal to you to give them a fitting support.
                        Come out to the polls, one and all of you, Republicans of Franklin County;
                        and ye, worthy Democrats, who love honest men and honest principles, and
                        have mustered too long in the ranks of a party which cares for nothing but
                        spoils, and whose leaders have deceived you by specious falsehoods and
                        deluded you into false and shameful opposition to the welfare and glory of
                        your country, break the bonds that we know must gall you and give us the
                        vote, of which you will be proud hereafter.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Called on voters of the Franklin County to vote for the Republican ticket.
                    Listed all the virtues of the Republican candidates and denounced the Democratic
                    policies, especially free trade. Also defended black suffrage as a right and
                    necessary measure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper charges that Capt. G. W. Skinner took $9,500,000 in bonds out of
                    the sinking fund and gave them to "irresponsible railroad companies" in order to
                    win their support on the border damage bill. The border damage bill did not
                    pass, and, in the eyes of the editors, the incident only demonstrates Skinner's
                    incompetence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>SO, IT HAS COME TO THAT! The Democracy of Franklin county see defeat staring
                        them in the face, and, as during the rebellion, are determined to resist the
                        execution of the laws. Capt. Skinner stated in Harrisburg, last week, in the
                        State Capitol Hotel, that the Democracy intended to prevent negroes voting,
                        and that at one poll, seventy Irishmen intended to be present and intimidate
                        the colored voters and prevent them from casting their ballots. This shows
                        the desperation of the Democracy, as well as the fitness of Skinner for a
                        law maker. He asks to be sent to the Legislature to make our laws, and at
                        the same time boasts of the intention of the Democracy to override the laws.
                        Now we should like to see law abiding Republicans vote for him. This threat
                        was made in the presence of reliable men. It means trouble at Mercersburg
                        and Greencastle. We advise the citizens of those places to put on a strong
                        police force on election day strong enough and willing to protect all legal
                        voters in their rights, and strong enough and willing to prevent all
                        attempts at illegal voting, and all attempts to interfere with the exercise
                        of the right of suffrage by any citizen, be he white or black.</p>

                    <p>We are glad that the Democracy have a man among them who is indiscreet enough
                        to blab their riotous designs.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounced Democratic candidates, especially Capt. Skinner, who threatened
                    to prevent blacks from voting on election day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Two years ago William S. Stenger, almost the sole advocate of Benjamin F.
                        Meyers' election, made a speech in the Fair ground in which he is said to
                        have informed his audience that there were enough Democrats there to carry
                        Franklin county in spite of all the <emph rend="italic">Dunkers</emph> and
                            <emph rend="italic">Niggers</emph> that the Republican party could bring
                        to the polls; and said he hoped that they would have them all out on
                        election day just to show them how easily it could be done. The Fifteenth
                        Amendment had not then given the Democracy the first lesson in spelling as
                        it has since done, and it is only in a relatively insignificant portion of
                        the United States that they do not now spell the name of our African
                        citizens with as much correctness as the Republicans do. But he was
                        anticipating history a little when he made his boast. The fullness of time
                        had not yet come for the "nigger," and yet Mr. Stengers' party was defeated.
                        This fall he will be gratified. His "colored brethren" will all be at the
                        polls armed with the ballot just to show the Democracy how easily it can be
                        done, and if he will but watch he can see them do something which his party
                        friends have failed to do for many years, he will see them vote right.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridiculed past Democratic boasts of being able to carry Franklin county
                    easily regardless of black voters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>During the war, when the colored people of the South were fleeing from the
                        wrath to come, and making their way into the border free States by
                        thousands, a favorite cry of the Democracy was that they would overrun the
                        North and bring distress and suffering upon the white laborers. And in
                        January, 1863, in the Pennsylvania Legislature they attempted to pass a bill
                        to prevent the influx of negroes into the State, imposing imprisonment,
                        heavy penalties, etc. It did not become a law and disgrace the State, as it
                        would have done, because the Republicans defeated it. Now, however, they dig
                        their dirty job out of the Democratic cesspool, and on the authority of the
                        Harrisburg <emph rend="italic">Patriot</emph> ask the people to believe that
                        Hon. John Cessna prepared the bill. There is not of word of truth in it, but
                        it shows how desperate are their needs when they are driven to make use of
                        their own iniquity, to take advantage of their own wrong, in fighting the
                        battles of this campaign. The colored voters will not be deceived by any
                        such lies.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminded voters that Democrats championed a bill to prohibit blacks from
                    the state and are now trying to reverse their stand. Felt confident that black
                    voters would not look kindly on this about-face.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Meyers wants to bury the issues of the past, and he is now engaged in
                        traveling the district, begging that his infamous and disloyal conduct
                        during the bloody years of the rebellion be forgotten. How about this? Just
                        two years ago when Frank P. Blair was nominated by the national Democracy
                        for Vice President, because in his revolutionary letter he pledged himself
                        to forget nothing, and, if elected to power to turn back the wheels of time
                        and restore the old slave power, his faculty to remember seemed to be his
                        great merit. Meyers himself is only good at forgetting that which it suits
                        him best to have forgotten. The Fifteenth Amendment, for instance, which
                        does not suit him, he says must not be forgotten, and other amendments too,
                        which he promises shall be overthrown when the Democracy get back to the
                        places they only dream of now. This business of forgetting on the part of
                        Meyers, and all his political friends is a deliberate swindle. "Put not your
                        trust in them."</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridiculed the attempts by Democratic candidate Meyers to distance himself
                    from his past conduct.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper highlights the failure of Skinner and other Democratic
                    representatives of the border counties to pass a bill for payment of war damage
                    claims. The border counties are represented in the legislature by six Democrats
                    who had difficulty getting support for the bill. The editors argue that in a
                    Republican controlled legislature, the interests of the damage claimants would
                    be best served by electing Republican reps who could produce a majority in the
                    legislature favorable to the bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Protection is the true policy for the laborer, the mechanic and the farmer.
                        It means plenty of work and good wages; it means a home market for all our
                        raw materials, and a fair chance to compete with the pauper labor of Europe
                        in the production and sale of our manufactured commodities; it means
                        comfortable and happy homes, free schools, an intelligent and virtuous
                        population. Free Trade means more riches for the rich and greater poverty
                        for the poor. It means little work, and wages reduced to the standard of
                        Europe; it means the destruction of all diversified industry; it means that
                        we shall produce only raw materials for the workshops of England, Germany
                        and France, and receive in exchange the products of their own labor; it
                        means an idle, impoverished people, wretched hovels, ignorance, rage,
                        degradation and want.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argued against free trade as detrimental to the interests of workers and
                    farmers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges local Republicans to make nominations for candidates for
                    township offices that are in the interests of party unity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper argues that John Cessna should represent the 16th District
                    because it contains "the ashes of Chambersburg and the glories of Gettysburg."
                    Should the district, the editors ask, "be represented by Benjamin F. Meyers, who
                    rejoiced in our defeats and was sad when victory perched on the banners of the
                    Union armies?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper asserts that the increased expenses of the Poor House under
                    Democratic control attest to the "extravagant" nature of Democratic rule. The
                    editors urge voters to select Jacob Strickler of Guilford as an alternative to
                    the status quo.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thad M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fosselman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper asserts that voters should select Thad M. Mahon and Lt. Fosselman
                    because they were "gallant" soldiers that imperilled their lives "to defend the
                    government against traitors and rebels." The editors contrast their behavior to
                    that of Capt. Skinner who, "a gallant soldier during the war, he has united
                    himself with a ticket which has at its head the best convicted traitor to be
                    found in the Sixteenth Congressional district."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Republicans to vote the straight party ticket. "Do not
                    permit favor, friendship, anything to tempt you to cut a single name on our
                    ticket."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses Republican John Huber for election as county
                    commissioner. His "incorruptible integrity and business capacity" make him the
                    ideal candidate to restore a commission "disgraced and robbed by corrupt"
                    Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that the Democratic representatives of the border
                    counties have no influence with a Republican governor and a
                    Republican-controlled legislature. Only Republicans, the editors assert, have
                    the ability to pass war damage compensation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reminds "soldiers of the Sixteenth District" that Benjamin F.
                    Meyers, Democratic candidate for Congress, "was openly in favor of compromise
                    with the rebels, and discouraged and opposed the draft" during the war. "If his
                    counsels had prevailed there would not now be a Congress."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper charges that Meyers "is one of that class of despicable
                    Democratic politicians who filled the land with widows and orphans by inciting
                    the slaveholders to rebellion, and by fighting the Union armies in the rear
                    during the war." He should not be sent to Congress to make laws "for the
                    government which he sought to destroy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Look Out for Fraudulent Votes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that Democratic frauds, including one man who registered
                    sixty times under different names, have already been revealed in Philadelphia.
                    They are likely to be attempted in Chambersburg as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper charges that Benjamin F. Meyers' war record is a "reproach and
                    disgrace to the 16th district." The best way to "bury" the issue is to defeat
                    him for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meyers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper praises Democrats Kimmell, McLellan, and Sharpe for refusing to
                    support Meyers' or "make any speeches in behalf of a copperhead and traitor."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper instructs each member of the County Committee to be sure that all
                    Republicans in their respective towns get to the polls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that a full turnout and fraud-free election will
                    guarantee Republican victory. The editors attribute last years Democratic
                    victories to low turnout among Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses Jacob Strickler, "the model farmer of Guilford," for
                    director of the County Poor House and farm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thad M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fosselman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses Thad M. Mahon and Lt. William Fosselman for assembly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reminds voters that the next legislature will be responsible for
                    apportionment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper offers the monthly statement showing a large reduction in the
                    national debt as the best testimony to the benefits of Republican rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper endorses John Huber, "the experienced and upright merchant and
                    manufacturer of Chambersburg," for County Commissioner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.05.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Republican Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allison</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoun</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiestling</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>T. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>W. U.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Lew W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Elwaine</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Keehan</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pollock</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Chairman James G. Elder and Secretary John M. M'Dowell publish a schedule
                    of upcoming Republican meetings in Franklin County and append a list of expected
                    speakers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Republican Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Owing to the extremely inclement weather during several days of last week, a
                        number of the meetings announced could not be held. In most instances rooms
                        suited to public meetings could not be procured, and to stand in the wet and
                        rain for several hours was more than speakers and hearers had bargained for.
                        The meetings called for Mercersburg and Marion, on the 29th, and
                        Greencastle, on the 30th, were postponed. At Greenwood a small meeting was
                        held, and addressed by Messrs. Garver and Hays.</p>

                    <p>At Chambersburg, in the Court House, on the 27th, and at Fannettsburg and
                        Funkstown, on the 28th, large and enthusiastic meetings were held, excellent
                        addresses were made and profound and earnest attention was given to all that
                        was said.</p>

                    <p>The meeting held in the Court House was much the best that has been held here
                        for a long time. It was addressed by Judge Allison, Register of the
                        Treasury, and Hon. Mahlon Chance, of Fremont, Ohio. Judge Allison spoke for
                        an hour and a half, and gave the whole time to an impartial and earnest
                        review of the work done by the administration of Gen. Grant, and compared
                        its acts during the eighteen months of its existence with the pledges made
                        by the Republican party in its platform when Gen. Grant was nominated. His
                        position in the Treasury Department enabled him to present the case with
                        authority, and we are sure no impartial man went away from the meeting after
                        having listened to his cogent and loyal address without being convinced that
                        the pledges given to administer the affairs of the Government economically
                        and honestly, to reduce the taxes and to pay the debt had been strictly and
                        religiously kept by the administration. Before such a fair and candid
                        investigation Mr. Meyers' bungling sophistries melted away or were so fairly
                        exposed as to render their author ridiculous.</p>

                    <p>His keen and incisive exposition of the policy of the Democracy since the
                        election of Lincoln in 1860 was such as to carry conviction with it, and his
                        contempt for the party which, having opposed the suppression of the
                        rebellion, and after the war advocated repudiation of the public debt, now
                        has the unblushing effrontery to seek places of trust and honor in the
                        National Government, was withering.</p>

                    <p>His exposure of the inconsistency of the Democracy on the Tariff question was
                        happy, and impressed all who heard him. Accepting the position of the
                        Democracy that we should buy where we can buy cheapest, he charged upon them
                        that to be consistent they must accept the principle in all its meaning and
                        advocate buying labor where it is cheapest as well as the products of the
                        cheapest labor. In other words, if the Democracy favored admitting the
                        products of the pauper labor of Europe and Asia, they must also favor the
                        introduction of the pauper laborer as well. They must invite the Chinese
                        laborer to compete with our American laborer, though the former can work for
                        30 cents and live on a pinch of rice and a rat a day, while the <orig
                            reg="American">Amirican</orig> laborer requires good food, comfortable
                        clothes and dwellings, schools, churches, &amp;c. This is true. If they
                        demand the one they cannot go back on the other. How do American laborers
                        like voting with a party who are pledged with their free trade principles to
                        reduce them to the degraded condition of the half civilized Chinaman?</p>

                    <p>Mr. Chance spoke for three quarters of an hour and entertained his audience
                        by some capital hits and illustrations.</p>

                    <p>At Fannettsburg the meeting was held in the Town Hall, which was crowded, and
                        many could not find room inside. Hon. John Cessna, Hon. M. Chance, and H.E.
                        Shaffer, Esq., of M'Connellsburg, made addresses. We have received no
                        special report of the meeting.</p>

                    <p>The meeting at Funkstown was held at the lower tavern, and was large, quiet
                        and attentive. It was addressed by Col. Theodore M'Gowan, Col. F.S.
                        Stumbaugh, and C.W. M'Keehan. Good speeches were made and a good report is
                        promised and expected from Quincy township.</p>

                    <p>We may add that the people are fairly aroused throughout the county, and the
                        Republican voters are resolved to wipe out the defeat of last year. They
                        mean to settle the question of party supremacy for this county, this fall,
                        beyond the necessity for future caviling or controversy. They mean to show
                        the Democracy that the loyal party possesses the numerical strength here, as
                        it should do so long as it is true to its principles.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chance</ln>
                        <fn>Mahlon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>H. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Keehan</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reported on several Republican meetings and addresses at different towns
                    across the county. Also denounced Democratic free trade policies and felt
                    confident that Republicans would win control of Franklin county from the
                    Democrats in the next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meeting at Waynesboro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The meeting of Saturday evening at Waynesboro was a splendid success, utterly
                        sinking into insignificance the attempt of the Democracy a short time ago
                        when Meyers visited that place to address them. A large crowd was in
                        attendance and <orig reg="hastened">hstened</orig> with closest attention to
                        the well digested, thoughtful sentiments of Judge Allison who spoke at
                        considerable length. His argument covered the ground already reverted to in
                        noticing his speech earlier in the week at this place, and carried with them
                        conviction as they did here. Judge Allison was followed by W.U. Brewer, Esq.
                        who made a short and pungent address. Both were listened to with profound
                        attention and satisfaction.</p>

                    <p>The grand demonstration of the Democracy at Greencastle, on the same night,
                        did not meet with the same success. After preparing for a week, and
                        publishing extensively that the faithful should be in attendance on Saturday
                        night and hear some of the big guns go off, they succeeded in getting
                        together none of the requisites of a political meeting except a brass band.
                        Audience and speakers both were lacking, and what few of the former did
                        attend went away disgusted that they should have been so badly treated. It
                        was bad treatment, we admit, but there is some excuse for the speakers too.
                        The Democracy have but two speakers this fall, but two open friends of
                        Meyers, and as they had already announced a meeting at Mercersburg on
                        Saturday night, it was impossible for them to be at both places. We
                        sympathize with them, and hope the disappointed at Greencastle will not hold
                        them responsible for their disappointment. One thing is certain, Stenger and
                        Duncan can't be at two places at the same time.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praised the recent Republican meeting held at Waynesboro. At the same time,
                    ridiculed the poor attendance at the Democratic meeting held in Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Census Returns</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>We are indebted to Mr. W.K. Widner, Assistant Marshal, for the following
                        returns.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italic">Metal Township</emph>.--Whole population, 1,4919; white
                        males, 681; white females 719; colored males, 11; colored females, 8. Deaths
                        during the year ending June 1, 1870: white males, 10, females, 8--total, 18.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italic">Letterkenny Township</emph>.--Whole population, 2,178;
                        white males, 1,101; white females, 1,063; colored males, 9; colored females,
                        5. Deaths: white males, 8; white females, 13--total, 21.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italic">Green Township</emph>.--Whole population, 3,359; white
                        males, 1,580; white females, 1,634; black males, 73; black females 72.
                        Deaths; white males, 21; white females, 15; colored female, 1--total, 27.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Listed census data for 3 townships in Franklin county, divided between
                    whites and blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deceased</head>
                <origin>Mercersburg Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Connell</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Connell</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that "during the past year death has been unusually busy
                    among the aged residents" of Mercersburg. The article gives the three latest
                    obituaries. Mrs. Jane M'Connell, wife of Hugh M'Connell, died on Saturday after
                    a protracted illness. She was 60 years old. Hugh M'Connell passed away shortly
                    thereafter. He had been "prostrated by a billious attack for some time." "Mr. M.
                    has lonf been a resident of this place; being engaged in the manufacture of
                    earthenware, his business relations brought him many acquaintances throughout
                    this and adjoining counties, who will lwarn with pain of his death. He was 72
                    years old and a member of the M. E. Church. Frederick E. Smith, "another aged
                    and highly esteemed citizen," died on Tuesday. He had fallen from a ladder three
                    years ago, and never fully recovered. He was engaged in the book trade and a
                    member of the Reformed Church. He was 75 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>French's Circus and Caravan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>French's Circus and Caravan will visit Chambersburg. The paper prints an
                    excellent review of the show.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Olive Logan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Olive Logan, the gifted speaker, will deliver her lecture on "Girls" in
                    Repository Hall on the 15th. She is widely known throughout the country and "has
                    tried every vocation open to women and succeeded in all." "Let the Hall again
                    exhibit the beauty, the fashion, and the intelligence of our people as it has so
                    often before when no greater or hardly so great an attraction has been offered."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lanahan</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>L. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>President J. C. M'Lanahan and cashier L. H. Fletcher of the First National
                    Bank of Chambersburg issue resolutions of sympathy and respect adopted at the
                    last board meeting in honor of the late Capt. Samuel A. Bradley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Funkstown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Keehan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that the "telling blows" of prominent Republicans
                    delivered at a recent rally in Funkstown "had an excellent affect in that
                    Democratic stronghold." A number of Democrats allegedly came away determined to
                    "vote the loyal Republican ticket."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Shooting Gallery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilvery</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Gilvery has opened a shooting gallery in the basement of the Repository
                    Building. He invites "sporting gentlemen to examine his new patent gun."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Olive Logan's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A special train of cars will run from Shippensburg and Greencastle to
                    Chambersburg for Olive Logan's lecture on the 15th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thad M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A large number of ladies and gentlemen turned out for an "old fashioned"
                    Republican meeting in Greenvillage. The remarks of the speakers were met with
                    frequent rounds of applause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sleichter</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lloyd</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Sleichter and Miss Mary J. Forbes, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    at the M. E. Parsonage in Orrstown on September 29th by the Rev. John Lloyd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swisher</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karas</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles E. Swisher and Miss Mary Jane Karas, both of Carrick, were married
                    near Carrick on October 3rd at the house of Patrick Reilly by the Rev. J. Smith
                    Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraley</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Reed and Miss Sarah E. Fraley were married near Carrick on October
                    3rd at the house of Patrick Reilly by the Rev. J. Smith Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murphy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jemima</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Jemima Murphy died near Carrick on September 22nd. She was 1 year old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Carrie Emma Noonan died near Carrick on September 26th. She was 3 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Shillito died near Greencastle of typhoid fever on September 25th. He
                    was 22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.05.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
