
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.02.16">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/29/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-02-16">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.02.16.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.02.16.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Contested Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper identifies voter fraud as one of the gravest threats to American
                    democracy. The editors charge that the Democrats have benefited from it often in
                    recent elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The New Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>After a vigorous campaign on the part of the numerous applicants, the new
                        board of County Commissioners have made the following appointments: For
                        Clerk to the Commissioners, H. C. Koontz, of Chambersburg; Court House
                        Janitor, John Shinefield, Chambersburg; Mercantile Appraiser, A. Dehaven;
                        Physician to County Jail, Dr. John Montgomery.</p>

                    <p>The principal fight was made on the Clerkship, the most important as well as
                        the most remunerative office in the gift of the commissioners. For the first
                        time in a number of years the board of Commissioners is Democratic, and the
                        rush made for the few offices in its disposal was terrific. There were
                        eleven applicants for Clerk, eight of whom belong to Chambersburg. As is not
                        unusual, the least worthy of the number obtained the place. With a few
                        exceptions, the applicants from town, and all of those from the rest of the
                        county, would have filled the position with credit to themselves and to the
                        Commissioners. As for Mr. Koontz, we regard him as one of the exceptions,
                        with no qualifications except those belonging to the worst class of ward
                        politicians. He is disliked by the respectable men of his own party, and all
                        are busy conjecturing how it was possible for him to secure the place over
                        such men as Keyser and the other applicants. There are some who pretend to
                        know; we do not, nor do we wish to. But this we do know: the Commissioners
                        have done their party no good by the appointment.</p>

                    <p>Mr. Foreman, who is displaced by this appointment, has filled the position
                        for many years, to the entire satisfaction of both political parties, and
                        has performed the complex duties of his office with great accuracy,
                        systematic order and honesty. Those who are acquainted with him, and the
                        manner in which he did his work, will not deem it an idle boast if we say
                        that few could have done it as well. But for the change in the political
                        character of the board of Commissioners, such a thing as his removal would
                        not have been contemplated.</p>

                    <p>Mr. Samuel M'Gowan, whose place as Janitor to the Court House, was given to
                        J. W. Shinefield, has been invaluable, and everything in his charge was as
                        well cared for as if it had been his own property. Mr. Shinefield is also a
                        good man, and if the former had to be removed, we know no one whom we would
                        rather see take his place. We expect him to imitate Mr. M'Gowan in his care
                        of the property placed under his charge.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shinefield</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dehaven</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> discusses the new appointments
                    to county offices such as Court House Janitor and Mercantile Appraiser. Some
                    appointees are blasted, others supported.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that Gov. Geary survived Democratic "abuse," "slander,"
                    "falsehood," and "mockery" during the recent campaign. The editors charge that
                    the people grew so disgusted with it that they turned on the Democrats. Now the
                    Democrats, they maintain, are greeting Geary with hypocritical praise in order
                    to gain influence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Democrats on Protection</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that a recent vote in the legislature revealed the
                    Democrats true colors on protectionism. They voted against a tariff while
                    professing to support it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Rev. J. G. Schaff Corrected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italics">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository.</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>Rev. J. G. Schaff, in your last week's issue, attempts to give the reason for
                        the withdrawal of Rev. J. P. Bishop and himself from the Pennsylvania Annual
                        Conference of the church of the United Brethren Christ, in the following
                        language:</p>

                    <p>"After our views respecting the 'future everlasting punishment of the wicked'
                        had been overhauled by an inquisitorial committee, and the Conference had
                        passed a paper expressing its <emph rend="italics">'sense'</emph> in the
                        case, and most emphatically condemning our views, and demanding of us a
                        promise of entire silence in regard to them, after they themselves had <emph
                            rend="italics">published</emph> them, we felt we could no longer remain
                        in connection with the Conference and respect ourselves. We therefore
                        proposed to the Conference that, if they had any <emph rend="italics"
                        >law</emph> for their proceedings they should expel us. This, for good
                        reasons, no doubt, they declined to do. In order, therefore, to end the
                        matter, we proposed to withdraw on condition that we should receive a
                        certificate of good moral character, and that the withdrawal was occasioned
                        by our belief that 'the wicked would have no conscious living existence
                        after this life,' which proposition was promptly accepted by the
                        Conference."</p>

                    <p>The above requires correction in the following particulars: Revs. Bishop and
                        Schaff were known, by some members of the Conference, to have held erroneous
                        doctrine as above stated, for a number of years, and latterly they became so
                        outspoken that it was deemed time to call them to account. They were
                        arraigned before a committee, to whom they refused to answer the questions
                        proposed to them, as to what they <emph rend="italics">believed</emph>,
                        saying that any attempt to fathom their <emph rend="italics">mind</emph>
                        "was an inquisition on the mind." The Conference, unwilling that error
                        should shield itself behind such specious subterfuges, finally adopted the
                        recommendation of this committee, that "they be required to pledge
                        themselves to entire silence upon their peculiar views, that they carefully
                        and prayerfully review the whole question during the ensuing year, and that
                        in default to so pledge themselves, that they be left without appointments."
                        Ample time was given them for their defence. They were allowed to withdraw
                        written answers to some questions of the committee and substitute others in
                        their stead. In debate they were permitted the utmost latitude, even to
                        indulging in <emph rend="italics">coarse, offensive</emph> expressions and
                        personalities. When the report was finally adopted, they <emph
                            rend="italics">defiantly, indignantly,</emph> refused to give the
                        required pledge, saying "that they asked no mercy of the Conference," "that
                        they did not wish to die a lingering death," and dared the Conference to do
                        what it pleased with them.</p>

                    <p>At the close of that session, the presiding Bishop quietly designated two
                        brethren to prepare resolutions for their expulsion from Conference. During
                        the interval, before the next session, they were offered the privilege of
                        withdrawal upon the terms they afterwards accepted, which they refused,
                        saying "if we are to go out, you must put us out." When they entered the
                        Conference room again their minds had evidently undergone a change. They saw
                        that the Conference was about to expel them, and they called the committee
                        to one side and asked the privilege of withdrawal, which was mercifully
                        granted them. It was out of mere kindness that the Conference did not at
                        once expel them, but allowed them to withdraw. If they are incapable of
                        appreciating kindness, it is no fault of the Conference.</p>

                    <p>The stale rebel cry of <emph rend="italics">unconstitutionality</emph> and
                            <emph rend="italics">no law,</emph> is too trite and transparent to
                        require notice.</p>

                    <p>Does an intelligent community question the right and prerogative of a
                        religious body to drive error from concealment behind <emph rend="italics"
                            >quibbling technicalities,</emph> and to maintain the doctrinal purity
                        of its ministry? J. DICKSON.<lb/> CHAMBERSBURG, Feb. 11th, 1870.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter to the editors offers further corrections to the <emph
                        rend="italics">Repository</emph>'s previous reporting on the Pennsylvania
                    Annual Conference of the church of the United Brethren Christ. The author
                    disagrees with a previous account of events.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.02.16.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Notice--Internal Revenue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Jere Cook, assistant assessor for the 16th district, announces to Franklin
                    residents that income taxes and special taxes for licenses are due in his office
                    on March 1st. A 50% penalty will be applied to late payments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Distressing Occurrence</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Emmert</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. I. N. Snively, Dr. E. A. Herring, Dr. Frantz, Dr. Amberson, and J. M.
                    Emmert, a student, attempted an operation to remove a clay pipe stem that had
                    become lodged in the windpipe of Edward Metcalf, the five-year-old son of
                    Matthew Metcalf. The operation was successful, but Metcalf died six hours later.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Fifteen dollars and five cents were stolen from the Chambersburg Post
                    Office. A black man employed by the Repository was arrested and brought before
                    Justice Davison on suspicion of the crime.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appenzeller</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. K. Appenzeller has been admitted as a partner of the firm of J. Hoke and
                    Co. Appenzeller had been clerking for the firm, and "is a young man of excellent
                    business qualifications."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Arrangements are being made to establish a Horticultural School and Health
                    Institute on the West Franklin Fruit Farm near Mercersburg. The project needs
                    $50,000 to purchase the property. Shares of stock are being sold for $500 each,
                    and many capitalists from Philadelphia, Baltimore, and Washington have shown
                    interest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Church Re-Opening</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The First Methodist Church of Chambersburg has been remodeled and will be
                    opened for service on February 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Titus</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The new Lutheran Church in Waynesboro will be dedicated on February 20th.
                    Rev. Dr. Diehl of Hagerstown, Rev. Titus, and Rev. Owen will officiate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lower</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. W. S. Lower of the Virginia Conference has been appointed to take
                    charge of Chambersburg's United Brethren Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>T. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diller</ln>
                        <fn>A. Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheeleigh</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. Frank Garver of Chambersburg and Miss A. Mary Diller, daughter of John
                    Diller of Lebanon, Pa., were married in Lebanon on February 10th by the Rev. M.
                    Sheeleigh, assisted by Rev. M. Rhodes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clippinger</ln>
                        <fn>Henry R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry R. Clippinger and Miss Rebecca H. Gillan, daughter of John Gillan,
                    all of Franklin, were married in Pleasant Hall on February 10th at the residence
                    of the bride's father by the Rev. J. M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Highland</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George A. Mowers and Miss Jennie Highland, both from near Shippesnburg,
                    were married at the Pleasant Retreat Parsonage on February 11th by the Rev. J.
                    M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Wingert and Mrs. Barbara Hoffman, both from near Fayetteville,
                    were married on February 8th at the residence of Amos Rice by the Rev. John
                    Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Height</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Height and Mary J. Bitner, both of Guilford, were married at the
                    Parsonage on February 3rd by the Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burger</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George B. Unger of Maryland and Ann E. Burger of Chambersburg were married
                    at the Washington Hotel on February 8th by the Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Theodore Brandt and Miss Sarah E. Houck, both of Mercersburg, were married
                    on February 10th by the Rev. David Townsend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nissley</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John R. Nissley died in Green Township on January 26th. He was 50 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colbert</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Annie Colbert died in Carrick Furnace at the residence of her parents
                    on February 9th. She was 15 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.02.16.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
