
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.10.19">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/07/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-10-19">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.19.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.19.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Instead of the satisfaction which journalists always feel in the publication
                        of good news, we are forced to endure the pain which belongs to the
                        publication of that which is unfavorable. Our whole county ticket is
                        defeated, our candidates for Assembly are likewise defeated, and Meyers,
                        Democrat for Congress, has been elected, according to the returns which have
                        reached us, by a majority of 15 votes.</p>

                    <p>In addition to this we lose probably four members of Congress in the State,
                        and retain the control of the Legislation by a reduced majority on joint
                        ballot; our majority being not more than from 10 to 13.</p>

                    <p>The failure to elect our county and Legislative ticket cannot be claimed as a
                        Democratic victory since both these were in their control already.
                        Nevertheless it is in fact a Democratic victory because it was in the power
                        of Republicans to elect both; a very humiliating victory too, since we must
                        admit that it was secured by the votes of those who professed, and, so far
                        as we know, still profess to be Republicans.</p>

                    <p>The Democracy owe to the negro vote their triumph in this part of the State.
                        We do not mean, by any means, that the colored votes voted for the
                        Democratic candidates, they had far too much good sense for that. But we
                        mean that by reason of their exercising the right of suffrage, so many of
                        those who hitherto voted and acted with the Republican party, this time
                        voted with the Democracy, as to enable them to elect their ticket. There is
                        no concealing or denying this humiliating fact. It was not unexpected to
                        those who carefully watched the progress of the campaign, nor is it
                        particularly discouraging. It is but a temporary triumph of the Democracy,
                        and time will again, as in the past, make all things even. The men who voted
                        the Democratic ticket solely because the colored man had been justly dealt
                        with will not remain with that party any longer when they perceive that it
                        cares equally as much for the black man's vote is for their own. Nor will
                        they care that the negro has been endowed with the right of suffrage after
                        they come to examine the question fairly for themselves. A party may gain a
                        temporary triumph by a narrow minded illiberal policy, but it is only a
                        temporary triumph. The Democracy trimmed their sails to a popular prejudice,
                        and were carried into the port of victory. They may court it in vain when
                        next they need it. The very men who listened to their false speeches because
                        they flattered their prejudice will turn from them in disgust when they come
                        to weigh their conduct in the scales of Truth and Justice. We are not
                        discouraged at the result of last Tuesday's election, when reviewed in the
                        light of the past.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> admits defeat following the
                    election. The paper attributes the Democratic victory to displeased Republican
                    voters who disliked the fact that blacks were exercising their "right of
                    suffrage." The editorial predicts that this is but a "temporary triumph of the
                    Democracy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Death of General Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>On Wednesday of last week General Robert E. Lee died at Lexington, Virginia,
                        after a short illness, in the sixty-fifth year of his age. Of all the men
                        who participated in the rebellion none held so high a place in the esteem of
                        the people of the Confederacy as Gen. Lee. Whilst other civil and military
                        leaders <orig reg="failed">faild</orig> and disappeared under the turbulent
                        waves of the war, General Lee seemed to rise higher and <orig reg="higher"
                            >higer</orig>, until during at least the last year of the struggle the
                        only hope of the South was centered on him. The love and veneration which he
                        excited among the people of the Southern States seems to have been real and
                        permanent, if we may judge by the universal sorrow which responded to the
                        announcement of his death, and not the ephemeral growth of some brilliant
                        and unexpected military achievement. His military career is so recent and so
                        generally known that we need not more than refer to it. He did not forsake
                        the service of his government until some time after active rebellion, began,
                        and until he did desert his flag he continued to hold a position which
                        enabled him to get possession of the plans and secrets of the military
                        department. His desertion under such circumstances has often been denounced
                        as dishonorable, as he carried with him to the Confederacy valuable
                        information which he could only have received as a trusted officer of the
                        United States Army.</p>

                    <p>Whether he took advantage of what he learned at Washington before deserting
                        his flag or not we cannot say, but it is certain that his reputation for
                        honor was permanently damaged thereby. Another painful circumstance of the
                        war we believe he is directly responsible for, and it is one for which the
                        South as well as the North is not likely to forget him. His power over the
                            <orig reg="Confederacy">confederacy</orig> during the last year of the
                        war to which we have already referred, enabled him, if it had been his wish,
                        to stop the war, and thereby the bloodshed and the great sacrifice of life
                        long before he did and it was not possible that he failed to perceive for a
                        year at least, the utter hopelessness of the Confederate cause. Upon him,
                        far more than upon any person else does the responsibility of all the
                        sacrifices of the last year of the war lie.</p>

                    <p>After the rebellion was killed General Lee retired to Lexington and became
                        President of the University. He entirely withdrew from public life,
                        abstained from all intercourse with the public and gave no public expression
                        to his opinions. But while he scrupulously abstained from anything to foster
                        or encourage the feeling which had brought on the rebellion, he inst. as
                        scrupulously abstained from the expression of anything tending to heal up
                        the wounds, and to induce the people of the South to accept the generous
                        terms of the Government. He played the part of a defeated, but likewise a
                        discontented, dissatisfied old man, and while he was capable of doing more
                        for the permanent good and material prosperity of Virginia and the whole
                        South than any other man in the country, he refused to open his mouth. But
                        he is dead. Let his deeds be buried in the grave with his body.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This report announces the death of former Confederate general, Robert E.
                    Lee. The author notes the admiration that Southerners had for the general but
                    also criticizes him for not ending the war earlier. Furthermore, the article
                    blames Lee, "a discontented, dissatisfied old man," for not doing more to help
                    reunite the sections in the post-war world.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Election News. Franklin County--Official</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>FRANKLIN COUNTY - OFFICIAL<lb/> Governor, '69 - Congress and Assembly, '70</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1869 Governor</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1870 Congress</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Assembly</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Geary, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Packer, D.</cell>
                            <cell>Cessna, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Meyers, D.</cell>
                            <cell>Mahon, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Fosselman, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Skinner, D.</cell>
                            <cell>Milliken, D.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Antrim</cell>
                            <cell>507</cell>
                            <cell>485</cell>
                            <cell>544</cell>
                            <cell>529</cell>
                            <cell>555</cell>
                            <cell>555</cell>
                            <cell>528</cell>
                            <cell>524</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, NW</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>253</cell>
                            <cell>341</cell>
                            <cell>249</cell>
                            <cell>344</cell>
                            <cell>315</cell>
                            <cell>283</cell>
                            <cell>245</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g. SW</cell>
                            <cell>256</cell>
                            <cell>271</cell>
                            <cell>427</cell>
                            <cell>279</cell>
                            <cell>426</cell>
                            <cell>401</cell>
                            <cell>311</cell>
                            <cell>277</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Concord</cell>
                            <cell>28</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>25</cell>
                            <cell>94</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                            <cell>23</cell>
                            <cell>98</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dry Run</cell>
                            <cell>105</cell>
                            <cell>103</cell>
                            <cell>108</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                            <cell>108</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fayetteville</cell>
                            <cell>220</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>206</cell>
                            <cell>209</cell>
                            <cell>201</cell>
                            <cell>200</cell>
                            <cell>217</cell>
                            <cell>208</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenvillage</cell>
                            <cell>183</cell>
                            <cell>114</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>129</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>187</cell>
                            <cell>144</cell>
                            <cell>121</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Guilford</cell>
                            <cell>182</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>193</cell>
                            <cell>239</cell>
                            <cell>191</cell>
                            <cell>189</cell>
                            <cell>245</cell>
                            <cell>239</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hamilton</cell>
                            <cell>88</cell>
                            <cell>156</cell>
                            <cell>111</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                            <cell>106</cell>
                            <cell>110</cell>
                            <cell>170</cell>
                            <cell>165</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Letterkenny</cell>
                            <cell>149</cell>
                            <cell>223</cell>
                            <cell>117</cell>
                            <cell>209</cell>
                            <cell>118</cell>
                            <cell>119</cell>
                            <cell>209</cell>
                            <cell>206</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lurgan</cell>
                            <cell>89</cell>
                            <cell>153</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>77</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>143</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Loudon</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>119</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>125</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>125</cell>
                            <cell>125</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Metal</cell>
                            <cell>132</cell>
                            <cell>96</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>104</cell>
                            <cell>137</cell>
                            <cell>139</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>106</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery</cell>
                            <cell>205</cell>
                            <cell>172</cell>
                            <cell>255</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>251</cell>
                            <cell>245</cell>
                            <cell>204</cell>
                            <cell>200</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Orrstown</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>73</cell>
                            <cell>144</cell>
                            <cell>71</cell>
                            <cell>68</cell>
                            <cell>149</cell>
                            <cell>145</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peters</cell>
                            <cell>136</cell>
                            <cell>69</cell>
                            <cell>147</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>144</cell>
                            <cell>143</cell>
                            <cell>84</cell>
                            <cell>81</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Quincy</cell>
                            <cell>214</cell>
                            <cell>299</cell>
                            <cell>230</cell>
                            <cell>298</cell>
                            <cell>238</cell>
                            <cell>208</cell>
                            <cell>325</cell>
                            <cell>288</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Southampton</cell>
                            <cell>48</cell>
                            <cell>73</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                            <cell>82</cell>
                            <cell>66</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                            <cell>81</cell>
                            <cell>82</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sulph. Spring</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>46</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                            <cell>51</cell>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>51</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>St. Thomas</cell>
                            <cell>147</cell>
                            <cell>221</cell>
                            <cell>135</cell>
                            <cell>239</cell>
                            <cell>132</cell>
                            <cell>133</cell>
                            <cell>245</cell>
                            <cell>242</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Washington</cell>
                            <cell>330</cell>
                            <cell>297</cell>
                            <cell>320</cell>
                            <cell>309</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>319</cell>
                            <cell>315</cell>
                            <cell>307</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren</cell>
                            <cell>35</cell>
                            <cell>58</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Welsh Run</cell>
                            <cell>124</cell>
                            <cell>139</cell>
                            <cell>117</cell>
                            <cell>148</cell>
                            <cell>119</cell>
                            <cell>123</cell>
                            <cell>148</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>3698</cell>
                            <cell>4006</cell>
                            <cell>3981</cell>
                            <cell>4167</cell>
                            <cell>3978</cell>
                            <cell>3873</cell>
                            <cell>4346</cell>
                            <cell>4140</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Packer's majority, 1869</cell>
                            <cell>308</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Meyer's majority, 1870</cell>
                            <cell>186</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Skinner's majority over Mahon</cell>
                            <cell>368</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Skinner's majority over Fosselman</cell>
                            <cell>473</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Milliken's majority over Mahon</cell>
                            <cell>162</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Milliken's majority over Fosselman</cell>
                            <cell>267</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">Commissioner, Director of the Poor, Jury Commissioner and
                            Auditor.</emph>
                    </p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>County Commis'r</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Director Poor</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Jury Commis'r</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>County Auditor</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Huber, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Worley, D.</cell>
                            <cell>Strickler, R.</cell>
                            <cell>M'Ferren, D.</cell>
                            <cell>Mackey, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Patton, D.</cell>
                            <cell>Cressler, R.</cell>
                            <cell>Sellers, D.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Antrim</cell>
                            <cell>563</cell>
                            <cell>518</cell>
                            <cell>560</cell>
                            <cell>522</cell>
                            <cell>558</cell>
                            <cell>523</cell>
                            <cell>558</cell>
                            <cell>523</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, NW</cell>
                            <cell>350</cell>
                            <cell>242</cell>
                            <cell>335</cell>
                            <cell>262</cell>
                            <cell>344</cell>
                            <cell>249</cell>
                            <cell>345</cell>
                            <cell>250</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chamb'g, SW</cell>
                            <cell>425</cell>
                            <cell>287</cell>
                            <cell>414</cell>
                            <cell>298</cell>
                            <cell>425</cell>
                            <cell>285</cell>
                            <cell>426</cell>
                            <cell>285</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Concord</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                            <cell>97</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dry Run</cell>
                            <cell>110</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                            <cell>110</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                            <cell>115</cell>
                            <cell>96</cell>
                            <cell>110</cell>
                            <cell>101</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fayetteville</cell>
                            <cell>203</cell>
                            <cell>211</cell>
                            <cell>198</cell>
                            <cell>216</cell>
                            <cell>204</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                            <cell>204</cell>
                            <cell>210</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenvillage</cell>
                            <cell>197</cell>
                            <cell>129</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>129</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>129</cell>
                            <cell>195</cell>
                            <cell>130</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Guilford</cell>
                            <cell>196</cell>
                            <cell>235</cell>
                            <cell>198</cell>
                            <cell>234</cell>
                            <cell>192</cell>
                            <cell>240</cell>
                            <cell>192</cell>
                            <cell>240</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hamilton</cell>
                            <cell>114</cell>
                            <cell>164</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                            <cell>112</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Letterkenny</cell>
                            <cell>120</cell>
                            <cell>206</cell>
                            <cell>119</cell>
                            <cell>207</cell>
                            <cell>119</cell>
                            <cell>207</cell>
                            <cell>119</cell>
                            <cell>207</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lurgen</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Loudon</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>125</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>125</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>125</cell>
                            <cell>86</cell>
                            <cell>125</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Metal</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>107</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>107</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>106</cell>
                            <cell>140</cell>
                            <cell>107</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery</cell>
                            <cell>251</cell>
                            <cell>200</cell>
                            <cell>250</cell>
                            <cell>201</cell>
                            <cell>250</cell>
                            <cell>201</cell>
                            <cell>250</cell>
                            <cell>201</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Orrstown</cell>
                            <cell>71</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                            <cell>71</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                            <cell>72</cell>
                            <cell>145</cell>
                            <cell>70</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peters</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                            <cell>146</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                            <cell>145</cell>
                            <cell>81</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Quincy</cell>
                            <cell>240</cell>
                            <cell>293</cell>
                            <cell>235</cell>
                            <cell>298</cell>
                            <cell>235</cell>
                            <cell>298</cell>
                            <cell>235</cell>
                            <cell>298</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Southampton</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                            <cell>82</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                            <cell>82</cell>
                            <cell>65</cell>
                            <cell>82</cell>
                            <cell>68</cell>
                            <cell>79</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sulph. Spring</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>49</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>St. Thomas</cell>
                            <cell>136</cell>
                            <cell>240</cell>
                            <cell>135</cell>
                            <cell>241</cell>
                            <cell>135</cell>
                            <cell>241</cell>
                            <cell>134</cell>
                            <cell>240</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Washington</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>309</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>309</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>309</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell>309</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                            <cell>33</cell>
                            <cell>47</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Welsh Run</cell>
                            <cell>124</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>124</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>124</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                            <cell>124</cell>
                            <cell>142</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>4028</cell>
                            <cell>4153</cell>
                            <cell>3985</cell>
                            <cell>4202</cell>
                            <cell>4009</cell>
                            <cell>4169</cell>
                            <cell>4004</cell>
                            <cell>4176</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Worley's majority</cell>
                            <cell>125</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>M'Ferren's majority</cell>
                            <cell>217</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Patton's majority</cell>
                            <cell>160</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Seller's majority</cell>
                            <cell>172</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">Official Majorities for Congress.</emph>
                    </p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Adams</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>325</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bedford</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>32</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Franklin</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>186</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fulton</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>420</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Somerset</cell>
                            <cell>948</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>948</cell>
                            <cell>963</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>Meyer's majority, 15.</p>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">Assembly - Official.</emph>
                    </p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Republicans</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Democrats</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Mahon.</cell>
                            <cell>Fosselman.</cell>
                            <cell>Skinner.</cell>
                            <cell>Milliken.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Franklin</cell>
                            <cell>3978</cell>
                            <cell>3873</cell>
                            <cell>4346</cell>
                            <cell>4140</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Perry</cell>
                            <cell>2223</cell>
                            <cell>2306</cell>
                            <cell>2455</cell>
                            <cell>2439</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>6201</cell>
                            <cell>6179</cell>
                            <cell>6801</cell>
                            <cell>6579</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">Borough of Chambersburg.</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>BURGESS.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Republican.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Citizens.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>James G. Elder,</cell>
                            <cell>563</cell>
                            <cell>Wm M'Lellan, D.</cell>
                            <cell>470</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>TOWN COUNCIL</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>F. S. Gillespie</cell>
                            <cell>544</cell>
                            <cell>Geo Ludwig, D.</cell>
                            <cell>483</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>S F Greenawalt</cell>
                            <cell>547</cell>
                            <cell>R E Tolbert, R.</cell>
                            <cell>452</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>J L Suesserott</cell>
                            <cell>517</cell>
                            <cell>William Forbes, R.</cell>
                            <cell>420</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peter Kreighbaum</cell>
                            <cell>526</cell>
                            <cell>David Croft, R.</cell>
                            <cell>426</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Thomas Henneberger</cell>
                            <cell>559</cell>
                            <cell>D M Leisher, R.</cell>
                            <cell>412</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>SCHOOL DIRECTORS.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lyman S Clarke</cell>
                            <cell>535</cell>
                            <cell>B S Schneck, D.</cell>
                            <cell>470</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>James Hamilton</cell>
                            <cell>554</cell>
                            <cell>Geo R Mersersmith, R.</cell>
                            <cell>438</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>ASSESSOR.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Robert P Hazelet</cell>
                            <cell>556</cell>
                            <cell>Charles H Smith, D.</cell>
                            <cell>473</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>ASSISTANT ASSESSORS.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>A H Newman</cell>
                            <cell>973</cell>
                            <cell>Mr Newman on both tickets</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>D A Wertz</cell>
                            <cell>541</cell>
                            <cell>Charles Evans, D.</cell>
                            <cell>475</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>AUDITOR.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Andrew M'Elwaine</cell>
                            <cell>554</cell>
                            <cell>No opposition</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">North Ward.</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>JUDGE.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Republicans.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Democrat.</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>A D Canfman</cell>
                            <cell>308</cell>
                            <cell>P H Peiffer</cell>
                            <cell>231</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>INSPECTORS.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>S Wilson Hays</cell>
                            <cell>310</cell>
                            <cell>J W Douglas</cell>
                            <cell>229</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>JUSTICE OF THE PEACE.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Philip Hamman</cell>
                            <cell>166</cell>
                            <cell>D S Reishor, I D</cell>
                            <cell>36</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>S M Armstrong, I R</cell>
                            <cell>323</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>CONSTABLE.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rufus K M'Lellan</cell>
                            <cell>297</cell>
                            <cell>No opposition</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="bold">South Ward.</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>JUDGE:</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>B L Maurer</cell>
                            <cell>383</cell>
                            <cell>William D Guthrie</cell>
                            <cell>233</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>INSPECTORS.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>D F Leisher</cell>
                            <cell>386</cell>
                            <cell>Jacob B Holtzworth</cell>
                            <cell>231</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>JUSTICE OF THE PEACE.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>David Piper, I.</cell>
                            <cell>99</cell>
                            <cell>Samuel Reisher, I.</cell>
                            <cell>215</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                    <p>CONSTABLE.</p>

                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Frank Zarman, Jr.</cell>
                            <cell>371</cell>
                            <cell>Jacob Speidle</cell>
                            <cell>230</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This report presents the results of the recent election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.19.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Election Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Last Tuesday gave another opportunity to the citizens of the Commonwealth of
                        Pennsylvania to exercise their boasted right, the right of suffrage. It has
                        been remarked before, we believe, that rain on election days is no unusual
                        occurrence, and though Republicans were disappointed on Tuesday morning to
                        find an unwonted degree of humidity they were by no means surprised. It was
                        a nasty day from morning until night, and the sun struggled in vain to show
                        his face. His best efforts were "<orig reg="circumvented"
                        >circumwented</orig>," as were those of the Republican voters.</p>

                    <p>The marked feature of the election was the depositing of their ballots by the
                        colored voters, and here let us do them full justice and say, as we have no
                        doubt their political opponents will confirm, that they acquitted themselves
                        like good law abiding law respecting citizens. Over two hundred colored men
                        voted in Chambersburg, most of them depositing their ballots in the morning,
                        and not a single difficulty of any kind arose. When they had voted they
                        departed from the polls, many of them returning to their work again, and but
                        a few were seen in the vicinity during the rest of the day. Their efforts to
                        vote were not impeded or interrupted by the Democracy in a single instance,
                        to our knowledge, except when objections were made, and when these were
                        settled, as in the case of white voters, that was the end of it.</p>

                    <p>So far as the policy of extending the suffrage to negroes can be justified or
                        vindicated by the conduct of the negroes themselves we claim that this has
                        been fully done. We wish we could add that the conduct of the white voters
                        had been as unexceptionable as that of the black. Henceforth we hope to hear
                        no more objections made on this ground. The conduct of the colored voters on
                        election day is an example well worthy of imitation, and some white voters
                        whom we could mention would do themselves credit by learning a lesson from
                        their colored brethren, and striving to reach the standard of good
                        citizenship which they exhibited.</p>

                    <p>The result of the election, in the county, is not what we hoped it would be,
                        though it is no worse than we feared it might be. A <orig reg="prejudice"
                            >predjudice</orig>, the growth of two centuries, cannot be eradicated in
                        a day or a year, and <orig reg="prejudice">predjudice</orig> defeated the
                        Republican party. The accession of five hundred colored voters to the
                        Republican strength was more than counterbalanced by disaffected men, not
                        merely men who stayed away from the polls, but men who representing
                        themselves to be Republicans, quietly voted the Democratic ticket. Though
                        acting a coward's part, they are ashamed to have their cowardice known, and
                        even now, do not dare to say how they voted. These are the victims of a
                            <orig reg="prejudice">predjudice</orig>. They have been Republicans, and
                        would be still, but they feared the negro, and voted with the democracy in
                        favor of a Copperhead for Congress, who was less worthy of their suffrage
                        than the rebel General Lee, by as much as he is less able, less frank, and
                        less brave; and not because his devotion to the cause of the Confederacy was
                        any less sincere, or his grief at its downfall a whit less bitter. We cannot
                        comfort them with the assurance that their fear of the superiority of the
                        colored voter is groundless. They must be presumed, at least, to be better
                        judges of this question than ourselves; and a comparison of their conduct
                        and that of the colored voters on election day, would seem to imply that
                        their conviction is well founded. Unfortunately, their fear of the negro,
                        whom they so love to call ignorant and degraded, and whose superiority they
                        so fully admitted by voting with their political enemies, against him, at
                        the polls on last Tuesday, has only increased their troubles. The Democracy
                        were a "white man's party" for the sole purpose of catching fools, and
                        having caught them they did not the less strive to get negro votes. They
                        worked quietly during the campaign to induce colored men to vote the
                        Democratic ticket, and <orig reg="employed">exployed</orig> all the tricks
                        they use with white voters. They offered them money for their votes and gave
                        them whisky freely and liberally, and on election day openly contested with
                        Republicans for their votes, as they had a perfect right to do. They even
                        succeeded in voting a few of them, and though we must admit that such as
                        they did vote were by far the meanest negroes in town it proves that they
                        are not insensible to the value of a ballot even when deposited by black
                        fingers, and it further proves that the Republicans whom prejudice drove to
                        the Democratic ticket to escape the negro were sold a Democratic trick.</p>

                    <p>The true Republicans of the county, though defeated, have much to encourage
                        them. They have struggled for years along with the best men of the party
                        everywhere to have our government made a government of the people, by the
                        people and for the people; and their efforts have not been in vain. They do
                        not now for the first time behold the temporary triumph of prejudice over
                        principle, but they find encouragement in the fact that Truth and Right ever
                        prove stronger and prejudice weaker, and that this last crowning act of
                        justice to the colored and white race will be fully vindicated and approved
                        by the American people, as have been those which preceded.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This report discusses the events of election day, praising the conduct of
                    black voters. The author blames racial prejudice for the Republican party's
                    defeat at the polls. Many Republicans, the article observes, protested black
                    suffrage by not voting or by casting their ballots for the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>We are indebted to the Local of the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> for
                        the following notice of the opening of Wilson College: A large and brilliant
                        assemblage was gathered together in the Wilson College buildings, on
                        Thursday last, to witness the formal opening ceremonies at that Institution.
                        At eleven o'clock the ceremonies began with an Invocation by Rev. I. N.
                        Hays, Pastor of the Central Presbyterian Church. The Coronation hymn - "All
                        hail the power of <orig reg="Jesus">Jusus</orig>' name" was sung. An earnest
                        and fervent prayer was offered by Rev. Thomas Creigh, D. D. This was
                        followed by the singing of the 100th Psalm. The President of the College,
                        Rev. Tryon Edwards, D. D., was then introduced and delivered an appropriate
                        address of great beauty and force. He contrasted the interest which has
                        hitherto been manifested in the education of boys and that which has been
                        exhibited in the education of girls. He spoke of the large sums of money
                        that have been appropriated all over the country for the endowment of
                        institutions of learning for males whilst the daughters of the lands have
                        been sadly neglected. As one who had risen above this narrow-mindedness he
                        instanced the founder of Vassar College. He eulogized his life and services
                        in the work of education, in the highest terms, and dwelt upon the system of
                        education which has been adopted in that celebrated institution.</p>

                    <p>Dr. Edwards then briefly sketched the trial and dangers through which Wilson
                        College has passed, referred in most touching language to the magnificent
                        bequest of Miss Sarah Wilson and the generosity manifested by other persons
                        in the neighborhood. He dwelt upon the importance of educating the women of
                        the land so as to fit them for the duties of home and social life, and also
                        to prepare them for a home beyond the skies. It is impossible to do justice
                        to the Dr's. address in the synopsis to which we are obliged to confine
                        ourselves. Suffice it to say that it was received with infinite satisfaction
                        and delight.</p>

                    <p>A prayer was then offered by Rev. I. N. Hays.</p>

                    <p>Dr. Robinson, of Harrisburg, had been chosen to deliver an address but he was
                        unable to be present, and Rev. J. Agnew Crawford was substituted in his
                        stead. He spoke as follows:</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italics">Ladies and Gentlemen and Friends of this
                        Institution:</emph> We may exchange <orig reg="congratulations"
                        >gratulations</orig> this morning, and at the same time give thanks to God
                        for the auspicious circumstances in which we meet. Few of you know anything
                        of the anxieties and sinkings of the heart, of the labor and sacrifice which
                        have been inseparable from the efforts that have placed the College where it
                        is <orig reg="today">to-day</orig>. Unfortunately, an impression not early
                        abroad, that because the gifts of Miss Wilson were so generous, we needed
                        but little more. Whereas had it not been for the earnest efforts of some
                        gentlemen in the Board of Trustees, our opening must have been deferred a
                        year or two. They are entitled to our gratitude. Not only has their large
                        business experience been brought into requisition, but their private means
                        have been freely used. So that <orig reg="today">to-day</orig> we present
                        you with an Institution which we think will be found worthy of your
                        confidence and support. I congratulate you that you have, at home, the
                        chance of educating your daughters equal to that which you would have were
                        they sent to some other place. It is not for us to multiply promises - but
                        we may be allowed to say that this shall be made a first-class Institution.
                        The Trustees are resolved to spare nothing which will tend to make it the
                        peer of any Seminary of learning in the land. Although the College has been
                        founded with Presbyterian capital, and is mainly supported by it, we do not
                        propose to make it sectarian in any offensive sense. It must be <emph
                            rend="italics">Christian</emph>. And you may rely upon it that the
                        central object here - the central influence here - the great central thought
                        here will be the <emph rend="italics">Lord Jesus Christ</emph>. Your
                        daughters will be rallied round the cross. I bespeak, therefore, for the
                        Institution your hearty support and a place in your prayers.</p>

                    <p>Rev. J. W. Wightman, Vice President of the Institution, was then introduced
                        to the assemblage and made a brief address. He said that this was to be a
                            <emph rend="italics">first class</emph> institution. A large number of
                        so-called Colleges are not worthy of the title. It is the intention of the
                        founders of this institution, to redeem the name of College, if possible,
                        from the contempt which has fallen upon female institutions. The effort will
                        not be to cram the minds of pupils with facts, but to spend time in
                        development of thought so that the pupils will learn to think for
                        themselves, and thus be enabled in after life to become leaders, instead of
                        followers, in society. It is not to be a Woman's Rights Institution in the
                        popular sense. But woman has rights which must be protected. She must be
                        prepared for the responsibilities which she must meet. She must have all the
                        personal culture that can be given. She must be educated for Christ. He
                        closed by asking the prayers of those present as well as those of all
                        friends of education so that the College may be a tree planted by the rivers
                        of water whose blossoming and fruitage shall be above the clouds.</p>

                    <p>Rev. I. N. Hays, then returned the thanks of the Board of Trustees to the
                        Workmen, many of whom were present, for their earnest and energetic labors
                        in pushing the work of completing the building.</p>

                    <p>The Doxology, "Praise God from whom all blessings flow" was sung, after which
                        the benediction was pronounced by the Rev. J. F. Kennedy, and the audience
                        dispersed. We passed through the buildings and were delighted with the
                        arrangements that have been made for the comfort and convenience of the
                        pupils. The furniture is of the best quality. Each bed has two <orig
                            reg="mattresses">mattrasses</orig>, one husk and the other hair. The
                        rooms look cheerful and cozy. There is an air of comfort about them which
                        will do much towards banishing <orig reg="homesickness"
                        >home-sickness</orig>.</p>

                    <p>Any one who contemplates sending his daughter to an institution of this
                        character should visit Wilson College, and he will certainly be struck with
                        the manner in which the wants of its pupils are provided for.</p>

                    <p>The Institution opens under happy auspices. Let our people foster and care
                        for it as it deserves to be fostered and cared for.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edward</ln>
                        <fn>Tryon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. Agnew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This reprinted article notes the opening of Wilson College. A few
                    individuals addressed the crowd and spoke about the importance of female
                    education.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>"Girls"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A large audience heard Olive Logan deliver her lecture on "Girls" on
                    Saturday in Repository Hall. "The intention of the lecturer seemed to prove the
                    fitness of women for the avocations from which they are excluded by the force of
                    society, and that there was no quality in woman's nature harmed or outraged by
                    her so engaging in them. She claimed for her sex the right to vote and hold
                    office, and to compete with the sterner sex in all honorable professions and all
                    departments of labor and industry." In the opinion of the editors, she did not
                    succeed. The paper gave her talk a disappointing review, finding her lacking
                    "depth of feeling" and "earnestness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>I.O.G.T.--Preamble</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazelet</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A committee of Good Templars issue a call for a district convention of the
                    order to meet in Franklin to promote the cause of temperance. The event will
                    include a children's mass meeting. The Cumberland Valley Railroad is issuing
                    tickets.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Base Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ginrich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peightal</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pawling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robeson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breitch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coulter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreichbaum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keil</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Upton N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A baseball match was played at the Chambersburg Fairgrounds on October 8th
                    between the Grecian Bend Club of Mercersburg College and a picked nine from
                    Chambersburg. Grecian Bend won the match. Jacob Heyser hosted a supper for the
                    teams after the game.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Shippensburg News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Richard Baker, the only African American in Shippensburg to have cast a
                    ballot before the state restricted voting by race, voted again for the firt time
                    in one third of a century last week. He "again cast his ballot with that party
                    who believes that governments instituted among men derive their just powers from
                    the consent of the governed."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Teachers' County Institute of Franklin will meet in Chambersburg on
                    November 21st. Prof. Kidd, "the great elocutionist," will be present.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Travelers may purchase through tickets to all points west from W. B.
                    Gilmore, Ticket Agent of the Cumberland Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fortney</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinsal</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel P. Fortney and Miss Mary E. Kinsal, both from near Quincy, were
                    married on October 13th by the Rev. John Fohl at his residence in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susan Reed died on October 6th at the residence of her son-in-law, L.
                    B. Kurtz. She was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.10.19.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
