<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.01.26">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/28/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-01-26">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.01.26.01" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Inaugural Address of Gov. John W. Geary, Delivered at Harrisburg, Tuesday,
                    January 18, 1870</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints Gov. Geary's inaugural address. He promises to bring
                    honesty to government, expresses support for protectionism, and reflects on the
                    outcome of the war. "The settlement of the vexed questions growing out of the
                    armed conflict with treason, devolves a mighty responsibility on the loyal men
                    of the land. Armed rebellion was signally crushed by the force of armed loyalty,
                    and the Government has triumphantly established its ability successfully to
                    suppress domestic insurrection, however gigantic. The war itself has served to
                    stimulate our people to fresh energies, and to the development of new
                    enterprises. Our manufactories have multipled, plenty has smiled upon our
                    fields, and blessed the labors of the husbandman. Peace has restored our people
                    to their homes, and cheered our firesides. The rates of taxation have been
                    reduced, and are entirely abolished upon real estate for the use of the
                    Commonwealth. Our State debt is being steadily and surely liquidated. Immense
                    sums have been paid for pensions and other charities. The cause of education has
                    advanced, and the institutions for the support and tuition of the soldiers'
                    orphans have been liberally supplied. Railroads have been constructed, and new
                    material resources developed. And thus our State and nation are rapidly
                    progressing in the attainment of those elements of greatness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.01.26.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Poor House Farm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper supports the sale of the poor house farm except for the 40 acres
                    surrounding the house since the land has never been productive or profitable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Slave Law-Givers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"A. K. M." reports on a trip to South Carolina. He pays particular
                    attention to the actions of African Americans in the state legislature. He
                    stresses that the ex-slaves are now the masters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.01.26.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The following cases were disposed of last week:</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Franklin Kurtz and John Sites. - Assault and Battery. Verdict
                        guilty, and each sentenced to two months imprisoned in county jail.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Nick Keefer. - Assault and Battery. Verdict guilty. Sentenced to pay
                        a fine of ten dollars and costs of prosecution.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Scott Wolfe. - Assault and Battery - two cases - to each of which he
                        plead guilty and was sentenced, in one to pay a fine of one dollar and costs
                        of prosecution and in the other a fine of ten dollars and costs of
                        prosecution.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Benjamin Jackson. - Assault and Battery. Verdict guilty. Sentenced
                        to pay a fine of one dollar and costs of prosecution and to six weeks in
                        county jail.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. George Shough, Martin Ruthrauff, Samuel Gorman. - Riot. Martin
                        Ruthrauff was not arrested. The two others were tried and found "not
                        guilty," and the prosecutor, Gilbert B. Valentine, to pay one-third of the
                        costs of prosecution and Shough and Gorman each one-third.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. John Sites. - Disturbing religious meeting. Verdict guilty.
                        Sentenced to pay a fine of one cent and undergo imprisonment in county jail
                        for two months.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Charles Myers. - Larceny. Verdict guilty. Sentence deferred.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Calvin Plowden. - Assault and Battery. Verdict guilty. Sentence
                        deferred.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Peter Pote. - Malicious Mischief. Verdict not guilty, and defendant
                        to pay three-fifths and prosecutrix, Margaret Vellis, two-fifths of costs of
                        prosecution.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Walters and Edward Jordan. - Assault and Battery. Verdict
                        guilty. Sentenced to pay a fine of one cent and costs of prosecution.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. John Sites. - Misdemeanor. Verdict guilty. Sentenced to be
                        imprisoned four months in county jail.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Ferdinand Evans. - Highway Robbery. The facts in the case were
                        these: As Mr. Samuel Garner was walking home from Greencastle he met
                        defendant on the public road, just as he passed by him defendant knocked him
                        down with a club and robbed him of every thing in his possession, amounting
                        almost to one hundred dollars. Defendant plead guilty and said he was drunk
                        at the time. Sentenced to nine years and nine months in the Penitentiary.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Franklin Kurtz. - Disturbing Religious Meeting. Defendant plead
                        guilty and was sentenced to pay a fine of one cent, costs of prosecution and
                        to two months in county jail.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Alice Gray. - Burglary. Verdict not guilty.</p>

                    <p>The following bills were ignored by Grand Jury: Com. vs. Wm. Keyser, Com. vs.
                        David Harper, Com. vs. Wm. A. Kogler, Com. vs. Alice Gray, Com. vs. David
                        Harper, Com. vs. S. G. Hays, Com. vs. Idelia Martin.</p>

                    <p>The following tavern licenses were granted by the court last week: Wm. Krome,
                        Funkstown; Hezekiah Keefer, Chambersburg; Daniel Miller, Chambersburg;
                        Michael G. Minter, Quincy; David Guyer, Letterkenny; George H. Myers, St.
                        Thomas; Wm. Bratten, st. Thomas township; Henry Kurtz, Roxbury; Samuel
                        Staver, Roxbury; Jacob L. Deatrick, Greencastle; Lewis Etter, Marion.</p>

                    <p>Philip Fendrick was granted a license to keep a restaurant in Mercersburg.</p>

                    <p>A. B. Siebert, of Concord, and E. P. Brumbaugh, Dry Run, were refused
                        licenses.</p>

                    <p>Report of the Grand Jury in relation to our County Institutions:</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italics">To the Honorable the Judges of the several Courts of
                            Franklin County:</emph> We, the Grand Jurors of the January session of
                        1870, would respectfully report that after acting on all the bills handed us
                        by the District Attorney, we visited the Alms House, and that we found
                        everything in good order; the buildings being neat and clean. We believe the
                        paupers are well cared for. We would, however, recommend that some change be
                        made in the hospital with regard to ventilation. We would also report that
                        we believe that it would be to the interest of the county, to sell all the
                        land belonging to the Alms House farm, except from thirty to forty acres of
                        that lying nearest to the buildings. We would also recommend to the
                        Directors of the Poor to allow nothing to out-door paupers, unless well
                        satisfied that they are worthy subjects. We would further report that we
                        visited the Prison, and that everything is neat and clean, and we well
                        arranged as can be in the present building. We would recommend that
                        arrangements be made to put all prisoners therein confined at labor of some
                        kind, for the benefit of the county. P. M. SHOEMAKER, Foreman.</p>

                    <p>SECOND WEEK. - W. S. Fletcher. vs. Peter Brough, Daniel Trostle and C. C.
                        Foltz. - Summons in Assumpsit. Defendants abandon their case and confess
                        judgment in favor of plaintiff for $632,72.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sites</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Nick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>Scott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shough</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valentine</ln>
                        <fn>Gilbert B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pote</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Ferdinand</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garner</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kogler</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Idelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krome</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minter</ln>
                        <fn>Michael G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrick</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fendrick</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Siebert</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trostle</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This weekly article lists court proceedings, including the verdicts, people
                    involved, and punishments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Alex W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Tobias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Horticultural Society met on the 11th. Twenty-one members and several
                    ladies attended. A variety of fruit and produce was displayed. Officials were
                    elected for the coming year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Blind Tom the Pianist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A very large and appreciative audience was assembled on Thursday evening
                        last, in Repository Hall, to listen to this wonderful prodigy. If any still
                        doubted that he really was what has been claimed for him, they could
                        scarcely be in doubt after hearing him on the evening referred to. What
                        seeming contradictions meet us in this homliest specimen of the pure African
                        race. An <emph rend="italic">idiot</emph> and yet a musical genius of a high
                        order, possessing a mastery over the piano truly wonderful. No matter how
                        difficult the piece of music, or how long, <emph rend="italic">one
                        hearing</emph> is sufficient for him to re-produce it note for note, chords
                        and discords, without a slur, false register, or omission. The writer has
                        heard him elsewhere, where an expert performer <emph rend="italic"
                            >improvised</emph> a long and difficult piece, which Tom reproduced
                        perfectly. Also, eight bars of Mendelsohn's "Song without Words," (very
                        peculiar and difficult), and a part of Back's Fugue, No. 17, the theme of
                        which, as well as parts of the answer, he imitated correctly. When waiting
                        for some one else to play, and while listening to a performance which is to
                        be re-produced, he throws himself into all sorts of clownish
                        positions--poising himself on one leg, sawing the air with his arms,
                        whistling through his teeth, &amp;c., but as soon as he is led to the
                        piano he appears "all right," and with a half maniac laugh will sometimes
                        ejaculate: "that's just's easy es nothin'!" His manager will perhaps call on
                        some one in the audience to hold up anything they please, and if there is,
                        for instance, a fan raised, the manager will strike a few notes, and Tom,
                        with his back turned to the audience, will spell out the right word. Or he
                        will analyze any number of notes--chords or discords--struck at random on
                        the piano, and will with wonderful celerity name every note. Or he will play
                        one piece with his right hand, another with his left hand, and will sing a
                        third piece on another key!</p>
                    <p>Then as to his <emph rend="italic">style</emph> and <emph rend="italic"
                            >manner</emph> of playing no one who heard him render such a piece as
                        Gottschalk's "Last Hope," or the "Fantasia" by Liszt, or his "Imitation of a
                        Musical Box" or his own "Battle of Manassas," if he has any musical
                        apprehensions at all, but must have been thrilled with delight or solemnized
                        as if in an act of devotion.</p>
                    <p>Indeed the sweetness and delicacy of touch, or, when he choses the brilliancy
                        and overpowering grandeur with which he seems to inspire the dumb
                        instrument, may well constrain, as it did, the great Moschelles--the
                        instructor of Thalburg and Mendelsohn--to say, that Tom's gifts were
                        "marvellous," beyond his comprehension entirely.</p>
                    <p>Whence has this demented son of Africa this gift--this wonderful attainment?
                        How can such skill--artistic skill of the highest order--dwell in such a
                        being? Or put in another form. How can art and scientific knowledge proceed
                        from what seems the very embodiment of ignorance and stupidity? Our
                        philosophies are here at fault. It is a deep question for the psychologist
                        to unravel. Man can only wonder, adore and feel, that a higher power is at
                        work here. Does not God here also "move in a mysterious way?" bringing light
                        out of darkness--yea, the bright corruscations of light in thick, Egyptian
                        darkness? How others were impressed, I do not know, but to me the
                        performance of that evening was more than gratification of the taste or
                        sense--and the morality of even that innocent gratification has its limits
                        at some point--to me it seemed designed to raise our thoughts and
                        contemplations upward, even to <emph rend="italic">him</emph> the primal
                        source and fountain of all art and science, of all good and ennabling gifts
                        and blessings. It is a theme worthy to think of--worthy of calm thought and
                        reflection.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reviews the performance of "Blind Tom" the pianist, expressing
                    wonder at the musical talent of this "homliest specimen of the pure African
                    race."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyner</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>Enos B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper celebrates the fact that the committee sent by the Franklin
                    County Horticultural Society to the meeting of the Pennsylvania Fruit Growers
                    Society have secured Chambersburg as the site of the group's next meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Chambersburg in Darkness</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Allen C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A stoppage in the gas pipes left the town without light on Monday. Allen C.
                    McGrath, superintendent of the gas works, was able to remove the obstruction and
                    restore gas to the town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearse</ln>
                        <fn>Nathaniel P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nathaniel P. Pearse, a well-known citizen of Chambersburg, died on
                    Saturday. He was 54 years old. He had served at the post office and once held
                    the post of Assistant Revenue Assessor. He eventually lost his post due to his
                    fealty to the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Prof. Bowman of Dickinson College will preach at the First Methodist
                    Church on Sunday. He will also appear with Prof. Shumaker to address the
                    Chambersburg Academy upon their Missionary Anniversary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pentz</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel R. Pentz of Scotland, Franklin County, has been appointed Assistant
                    Bookkeeper in the National Bank of Chambersburg. Pentz had been a long-time
                    clerk at Curriden's book store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. J. L. Suesserott of Chambersburg was elected Vice President of the
                    State Horticultural Society at Lancaster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>D. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Ellie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pardoe</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. Smith Fahnestock and Miss Ellie M. Brandt, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on January 12th by the Rev. H. C. Pardoe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorden</ln>
                        <fn>D. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Demoyer</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. R. Gorden of Chambersburg and Miss Mary M. Nevin of Waynesboro were
                    married on January 19th by the Rev. J. A. Demoyer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quickel</ln>
                        <fn>Leah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew H. Rice of Mowersville, Franklin County, and Miss Leah J. Quickel of
                    Cumberland County were married near Newburg on January 11th by the Rev. J. M.
                    Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Hannah S. Wilhelm died near Fannettsburg on January 17th. She was 26
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Henry L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry L. Hege died at Dry Run, Peters township, on January 4th. He was 59
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James King died in Chambersburg on January 6th. He was 65 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bricker</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Bricker died in Chambersburg on January 17th. He was 15 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.01.26.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
