
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.09.07">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/06/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-09-07">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>07</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.09.07.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.09.07.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>A. M'L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowermaster</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The conferees of Adams, Franklin, and Fulton counties announce that the
                    Republican County Conventions in the 16th District have all expressed a
                    preference for the renomination of John Cessna, the present representative, as
                    Republican candidate for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Democratic Lie</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The world over to take advantage of ones own wrong is regarded as about the
                        most dastardly and cowardly trick that any one can be guilty of. To do a
                        wrong act and to try and lie out of it is mean, but it bears no comparison
                        to doing a wrong act and then attempting to give notoriety and publicity to
                        the wrong by charging it upon an innocent party. The latter is just what the
                        Democratic newspapers of Pennsylvania have been doing. First the <emph
                            rend="italics">Age</emph> did it, then the <emph rend="italics"
                        >Patriot</emph> did it and then all the others, generally, did the same
                        thing. What they did do was this: the administration of Gen. Grant has shown
                        such extraordinary energy and ability in collecting the revenues and paying
                        off the public debt that the Democracy found they must do something if
                        possible to counteract the influence this had upon the people. They found as
                        long as it was allowed to go on unhindered the Republican party must grow
                        stronger and more popular among the people. They could not deny the monthly
                        statement of the large <del/> of <del/>
                        <del/>
                        <del/> but they remembered that during Johnson's administration large
                        numbers of Democratic revenue collectors had proved defaulters and defrauded
                        the Government out of millions of dollars, and they resolved to use this
                        knowledge against the Republican party. A statement of Secretary of the
                        Treasury Boutwell to Congress, in reply to a resolution, showed that about
                        six millions of dollars had been stolen by Internal Revenue officers in
                        different parts of the country. The <emph rend="italics">Age</emph> at once
                        alleged that this had been done since the advent of Gen. Grant's
                        administration, and that none of the defaulters had been arrested and
                        brought to justice. From the statement it argued that the administration had
                        utterly failed to <orig reg="fulfill">fulfil</orig> its promises to conduct
                        the affairs of the Government honestly and economically.</p>

                    <p>Now the statement of the <emph rend="italics">Age</emph>, and the argument
                        drawn from it were lies, lies which the <emph rend="italics">Age</emph> knew
                        to be such when they were made, and which the other Democratic papers that
                        have since published them knew to be false. When the Secretary of the
                        Treasury furnished a detailed statement of balances due the government by
                        Collectors of Internal Revenue it was accompanied by a letter from the First
                        Comptroller of the Treasury, containing the following extract:</p>

                    <p>The balances and payments as shown by the statement are those which appear by
                        accounts adjusted, but in many of them I have no doubt the balances will
                        wholly or in part disappear when further reports and vouchers shall have
                        been transmitted to the Auditor and been acted upon.</p>

                    <p>In a large proportion of the cases, the balances against collectors consist
                        of tax lists charged to them, but turned over to their successors in office.
                        Under the existing law the accounting officer cannot credit an outgoing
                        collector with lists so turned over unless the Commissioner of Internal
                        Revenue shall certify that such outgoing collector has used due diligence.
                        Hitherto the practice of the Internal Revenue Office has been to withhold
                        such certificates, and to await the collection of such taxes by the
                        successor, and allowances for such of them as may appear to be <orig
                            reg="uncollectible">uncollectable</orig>.</p>

                    <p>It is evident that this practice delays the settlement of accounts, is
                        vexatious and annoying to collectors, and puts them upon the record as
                        apparently defaulters for an indefinite period of time. I am pleased to know
                        that the present Commissioner is disposed to change the practice, and to
                        remedy as far as practicable the evils which exist under it.</p>

                    <p>From this extract, to make the story short, there is not a tithe of the six
                        millions still due to the Government, and in saying so we are dealing more
                        fair and honorable with the Democracy than they have been striving to do
                        with the Republican administration, for these balances are charged against
                        the Revenue Collectors appointed by Andrew Johnson, who were Democrats, and
                        not their successors appointed by Grant. These Democratic papers ought to be
                        ashamed to take advantage of their own wrong.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>When Democratic newspapers blame President Grant's administration for
                    failing to deal with corrupt tax collectors, the Repository points out that the
                    individuals at fault were Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Must Have Better Authority</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Last week's <emph rend="italics">Valley Spirit</emph> said this:</p>

                    <p>$100,000 IN THE FIELD - It will be a source of great satisfaction to the
                        fellows who "feed" on the candidates for office, to know that Hon. John
                        Cessna is about to throw into the Congressional District <emph
                            rend="italics">one hundred thousand dollars to secure his
                        election</emph>. He knows that there is no possible chance of election
                        unless by the lavish expenditure of money. The people must be debauched in
                        order to send him back to Congress. Now is the time for the harpies to sink
                        their long claws into the Hon. John's purse.</p>

                    <p>But the queries among the people are, where does the money come from? Who
                        furnishes this large amount of greenbacks?</p>

                    <p>Not by any manner of means. There is only one query among the people, and
                        that is, who is willing to believe such a prodigious story on the faith of
                        the <emph rend="italics">Valley Spirit</emph> alone? See, there is no <emph
                            rend="italics">authority</emph> given for the silly assertions. "It will
                        be a source of great satisfaction to the fellows who 'feed' on the
                        candidates for offices to know that Hon. John Cessna is about to throw into
                        this Congressional District <emph rend="italics">one hundred thousand
                            dollars to secure his election</emph>." We have no doubt it would be.
                        But how are they to <emph rend="italics">know</emph> it? On the faith of the
                            <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>? We can't ask any one to strain his
                        credulity to that extent. We sincerely advise the purchasable element of the
                        Democracy not to put any faith in the statement, for if they rely on it to
                        get their "feed" they will be disappointed.</p>

                    <p>Again we must assure the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>, as we had
                        occasion to do two years ago, that it must not expect to claim the credit of
                        the Hon. John Cessna's election. Its Munchausen stories then disgusted many
                        of its own party, and drove some Republicans, dissatisfied with the
                        nomination their party had made, to accept the candidate. Though there are
                        no dissatisfied Republicans now, it is adopting the same course again. If it
                        is shaping its policy to secure a part of the <emph rend="italics">hundred
                            thousand dollars</emph> let it be warned in time that it is wholly in
                        error. We know how powerfully its pocket nerve pulsates at the mere
                        suggestion of campaign funds, and we know too how joyfully it would accept
                        such an inducement to give Meyers a lukewarm support. But fate is against
                        it. Cessna has no need to buy its support, and if he had, neither the party
                        nor the candidate would accept victory at such a price. The <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph> is doomed to carry the load of Meyers and
                        his infamy sorrowfully through the campaign, and dare not lay it down until
                        the end. Bear it meekly and patiently if you can, brother Stenger, though
                        your fragile frame and slender limbs are poorly suited to the burden. It is
                        hard to support a renegade, harder still when that renegade became a traitor
                        and aided and encouraged the rebellion, and advised resistance to the draft,
                        and still harder when that renegade became a free trader and devoted his
                        time and talents to the overthrow of the industrial interests of his
                        district, and to the reduction of the wages of the laboring man to the low
                        standard of the wages in England.</p>

                    <p>But you have the sublime consolation afforded by the fact that it was not
                        your fault. If the Democratic party blindly and <orig reg="willfully"
                            >wilfully</orig> chose Meyers, it was not because you did not cry out
                        against it, and warn them that the task was Herculean, and that nature had
                        not shaped and <orig reg="molded">moulded</orig> you to perform Herculean
                        work.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>When the <emph rend="italics">Valley Spirit</emph> accuses incumbent
                    Republican representative, John Cessna, of attempting to purchase his reelection
                    with $100,000, the <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> defends the
                    congressman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Still Another Argument in Favor of Republican Rule</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper celebrates the large reductions shown in the public debt
                    statement for September as proof of the excellence of a Republican controlled
                    government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>This Renegade and That One</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>"It never rains but it pours," says the proverb, and a very expressive
                        proverb it is. But it fails to express the full meaning of the situation in
                        which the Franklin county Democracy are plunged by the nomination of Meyers
                        for Congress, Stenger, and Kimmell, and Duncan, and Brewer, and a number of
                        others of our Democrats have frequently howled themselves into spasms, like
                        spoiled children, whenever the thought entered their minds that Cessna had
                        once been a Democrat and is now a Republican. At the sight of him the cry
                        would go up, "Oh the renegade, the howling renegade, the nasty little
                        renegade; take him away, take him away," and off they would go into fits at
                        the very idea.</p>

                    <p>And yet Cessna is no patching to <orig reg="Meyers">Myers</orig> as a
                        renegade. First a Democrat, then a Republican; that is Cessna's record.</p>

                    <p>"First a Whig, then a Know Nothing, then an ultra pro slavery Secession
                        tinctured, and now an exceedingly 'White man's anti-protective tariff
                        Democrat," that is Meyers' record, written of him by Ed Scull, Esq. of the
                        Somerset <emph rend="italics">Herald</emph>, with whom he was raised and who
                        has known him intimately all his life.</p>

                    <p>Great Heavens! what a load for our Democrats? First a Whig, and there never
                        was a Whig who was not a Protective Tariff man, he is now the notorious
                        advocate of Free Trade. "oh, the renegade." Then a Know Nothing, denouncing
                        Germans and Irish, unwilling to give them citizenship much less the ballot
                        or a participation in the administration of public affairs, and now ready to
                        crawl on his belly to secure their votes. Nothing half so sweet in life as
                        the "sweet German accent, or the rich Irish brogue." "Oh the renegade." And
                        now a white man's anti-protective tariff Democrat. "Oh the renegade." Now
                        gentlemen, when Hon. John Cessna <unclear>crosses</unclear> your path, as we
                        have no doubt he will this fall, we don't expect you to hold your tongues,
                        because it would be so hard to explain to the rank and file of your party if
                        you did, but we do expect you to reflect that every time you howl "renegade"
                        at him you prove yourselves arrant demagogues; and we know that it secret
                        you will pull your hair and curse your unlucky fate in having Meyers, the
                        quadruple renegade, foisted upon you as your candidate for Congress.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After the Democratic press denounces Republican congressman, John Cessna,
                    as a "renegade," the <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> points out that the
                    Democrat's own nominee has switched his party allegiance and ideology numerous
                    times.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>County Chairman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Republican County Committee met on Saturday the 3d inst., and organized
                        by electing Col. J. G. Elder, Chairman. We regard this as a very excellent
                        selection, and the Republicans of the county may rest assured that the
                        campaign carried on under his management will be thorough and active. The
                        time until election day is too brief to be spent in inaction, nor can the
                        campaign be made too lively. We want a thorough stirring up of the dry bones
                        of the party. The issues are too important to allow a quiet campaign. The
                        Republican party have nothing to conceal. They want discussion and
                        ventilation both of the acts and doings of their own party and those of the
                        Democracy. We say emphatically, give us an active campaign.</p>

                    <p>There will be another meeting of the Committee on Saturday next, the 10th
                        inst. at 1 o'clock, when the meetings for the county will be arranged, and
                        other important business transacted. It is important that every member of
                        the Committee be in attendance, and if any cannot be present some one should
                        be sent instead.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> reports that Col. J. G. Elder
                    will be in charge of managing the Republican election campaign and calls for an
                    "active" contest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Campaign Repository</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports it is making arrangements to expand circulation during
                    the campiagn. One thousand copies have been taken so far, and the editors hope
                    to hit two thousand.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.09.07.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Van Amburg and Co.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Van Amburg's menagerie visited Chambersburg on Wednesday. Large crowds
                    attended the exhibition and saw the "long train of beautiful wagons" pass
                    through the streets. The displays of wild animals were tasteful and appropriate
                    for "all classes of our citizens." The paper calls it the best exhibition to
                    have visited Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. M. Richards of Shippensburg died suddenly on August 31st. He had lived
                    in Chambersburg for six years before recently moving to Shippensburg where he
                    taught in one of the public schools. "He was a man of quiet demeanor and retired
                    habits" but well-known and "highly respected for his many excellencies of
                    character." He was ill for only two days. He leaves a wife and family of small
                    children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elsrode</ln>
                        <fn>O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Printers and the Scrub Nine of Shippensburg played a game
                    of baseball in Shippensburg resulting in a victory for the Printers. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Deceased</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Judge Orr, "a well known and influential citizen of this county," died at
                    his residence in Orrstown on Sunday. A number of Masonic brethren attended the
                    funeral.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>In Luck</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper thanks the Ladies' Committee of the German Reformed Church
                    festival of St. Thomas for a beautiful cake. The ladies raised $150 at the
                    event.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potts</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Potts and Miss Margaret Robinson, both of Franklin County, were
                    married in Mercersburg on August 30th by the Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Katie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis </ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George A. Wood and Miss Katie Spangler, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    in the First Reformed Church in Chambersburg on September 1st by the Rev. P. S.
                    Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meade</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Josiah Meade died in Chambersburg on August 26th. He was 67 years old. "He
                    was an old citizen of this place and an honored and respected member of the M.
                    E. Church. After an illness of several years, he died without a struggle,
                    passing peacefully and calmly into the life to come."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>Amelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Miller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Amelia Carlisle, daughter of Thomas and Anna Miller Carlisle of Pittsburgh,
                    died in Chambersburg on August 26th. She was 7 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Craig of Welsh Run died on August 26th. He was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>James Dunlap</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Dunlap McDowell, son of A. B. McDowell of Peters, died on August
                    30th. He was 9 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>S. Doyle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jesse M. Jones, son of S. Doyle and Emma Jones, died at Carrick Furnace on
                    August 28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. M. Richards died in Shippensburg on August 31st after suffering an
                    illness of two days. He was 51 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>Gertrude</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gertrude Hewitt, daughter of William and Susan Hewitt, died at Carrick
                    Furnace on July 29th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallagher</ln>
                        <fn>James McGinley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James McGinley Gallagher died at Carrick Furnace on August 29th. He was 5
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.09.07.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
