
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.03.16">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/29/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-03-16">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.16.01" exists="no">



            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.16.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Inquirer and the Border Damage Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends the border war-damage claimants against charges from
                    Philadelphia papers that they are nothing but a special-interest lobby. The
                    editors assert that the broder counties suffered during the war and deserve
                    compensation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Too Frequent Changes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Republicans in the legislature helped pass a law banning spring elections,
                    and providing for election of all local posts in the fall. Democrats resisted
                    the measure because, according to the editors, the spring elections often
                    favored Democrats. The Democratic machine brings voters out at all electtion,
                    while Republicans are traditionally more difficult to entice to the polls at odd
                    times of year when large issues are not at stake. The paper believes the change
                    in the election schedule, however, is fair and will not harm either party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>More Taxes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes a measure before the legislature that calls for a $150
                    increase in the salary of Franklin County's associate judges. The editors hold
                    that only a few interested persons pushed the measure on the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes the Philadelphia Press for failing to print the
                    letters of "gentlemen in the border counties" refuting charges that war damage
                    claimants are "thieves," "plunderers," and "corruptionists."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Gen. Butler has appointed a colored boy to West Point. He is said to be well
                        qualified, and his father was killed fighting in the Union army against the
                        rebellion. These are good reasons for the appointment, and if suitable in
                        other respects the fact of race should not be against him. There are strong
                        prejudices to fight at West Point, but we hope these will not be allowed to
                        come between the boy and his merits. If he is able to take a creditable
                        place in his class his race should not bar him from it, and if he is a dunce
                        he should stand in the dunce's place where many white boys have stood before
                        him. We hope the Democratic journals which felt the injustice of keeping the
                        negro out of West Point so keenly and talked about it so feelingly will
                        express themselves delighted over this just act of Gen. Butler.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This short article announces that General Butler has appointed a black man
                    to West Point and encourages the institution to treat him fairly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.16.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>On last Thursday evening the colored men of this place held a meeting at the
                        Bethel church, for the purpose of making arrangements to celebrate the
                        adoption of the Fifteenth Amendment soon after the President shall issue his
                        proclamation in relation to the same. At an early hour the sable sons of
                        Africa began to gather, and in a short time the church was crowded to
                        excess. Here and there in the audience was to be seen a pale face, looking
                        on with deep interest. Many of them were there as friends of the colored
                        people, and were present to encourage them in the good cause, whilst a few
                        were their old enemies, and were there from sinister motives. Among the
                        latter was a prominent Democratic politician, who occupied a seat in the
                        "amen corner," and looked as innocent as a lamb, his eyes plainly speaking
                        the following words: "All men are born free and equal: peace, good will to
                        all, men," etc. Near him sat a half dozen of his faithful mourners. The
                        disgusting smell which used to offend their delicate nostrils now seemed, as
                        if by magic, to be converted into a sweet odor, that made everything about
                        them agreeable. They smiled and felt that it was good to enjoy sweet
                        fellowship with the darkies around them, and would be delightful to receive
                        their hearty support next October. No doubt they thought that their presence
                        and smiles would have a salutary effect upon the colored voters. If so, they
                        were badly disappointed, because several of the colored men addressed their
                        brethren, and in their remarks denounced the course the Democratic party has
                        pursued towards their race in bitter terms. They pronounced the treatment
                        they had received at their hands cruel and unjust, so much so that they
                        never could forget or forgive them, or vote with them. This was enough for
                        the Democratic wolves in sheeps' clothing. The old smell was apparent at
                        once, they struck their tents, bade farewell to the old South Ward, once the
                        joy of the Democracy, and left with the assurance that the men whom they had
                        honored with their presence intended, one and all, to vote the Radical
                        ticket. The meeting was a success, all the speeches had the true ring, and
                        from their actions the colored men seem determined to stand by the party
                        that has stood by and rescued them from the hands of their oppressors. The
                        beat of order prevailed, and the meeting was harmonious in all its
                        proceedings.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> reports on a recent meeting of
                    black men in the Bethel church to celebrate the passage of the Fifteenth
                    Amendment. It mentions that white citizens, both friendly and antagonistic to
                    the cause, were also in attendance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meeting of Border Claimants</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>In accordance with previous notice, a mass meeting of the Border Claimants of
                        Franklin County was held in the Court House, in the Borough of Chambersburg,
                        on Wednesday, the 9th inst. Maj. J. C. Austin was called to the Chair; Jacob
                        Hoke, Hon. John Huber, John Cree, Hon. J. L. Black. J. W. Fletcher and Dr.
                        E. Culbertson appointed Vice Presidents; Dr. Wm. H. Boyle, J. S. Brand and
                        J. N. Flinder, chosen as Secretaries.</p>

                    <p>The object of the meeting being stated, A. H. M'Culloh, Esq., offered the
                        following resolutions, which were unanimously adopted:</p>

                    <p>WHEREAS, It has been frequently asserted in certain newspapers of this State,
                        that the claims of the citizens have been assigned by them to third parties
                        for a small consideration, and that such parties, for the purpose of
                        speculation, are endeavoring to procure the passage of an Act of Assembly
                        for the payment of said claims. And Whereas, such assertions, published in
                        respectable newspapers, are well calculated to excite undue prejudice and
                        prevent a <orig reg="fair">far</orig> and candid consideration of the bill
                        now before the Legislature for the relief of the citizens of the Border
                        Counties; therefore be it</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italics">Resolved,</emph> By the claimants of Franklin county, in
                        mass meeting assembled, That such allegations are entirely without
                        foundation, and utterly devoid of truth; and so far as this county is
                        concerned, that not a single claim has been assigned, nor has there been at
                        any time any effort made to assign such claims.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italics">2d.</emph> That the citizens of the Border Counties
                        having born the usual calamities of war in common with all the other
                        counties of the Commonwealth, deem it but an act of simple justice and
                        right, that having been a break water for the hosts of the rebellion, they
                        should be compensated for their losses to which their exposed situation
                        subjected them.</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italics">3d.</emph> That in order that the bill now before the
                        Legislature may be considered in a spirit of candor and justice, and be
                        disposed of upon its merits, we respectfully request the newspapers that
                        have published these injurious and incorrect statements to recall the same.</p>

                    <p>On motion the meeting adjourned.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cree</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flinder</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Culloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article reprints the proclamation adopted by a mass meeting of the
                    Border Claimants of Franklin County. The participants refuted claims made by
                    newspapers that oppose reparations for border communities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keger</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegerreis</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Fannettsburg Lyceum met on Monday and discussed the question, "Is Love
                    a Stronger Passion than Anger."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Graduates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Edgar N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merklein</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merklein</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edgar N. Senseny, son of Dr. A. H. Senseny, graduated from Jefferson
                    Medical College with a degree as Doctor of Medicine. Charles H. Merklein and
                    George H. Merklein graduated from the University of Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tickets for Mr. Gough's lecture in Chambersburg are selling rapidly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mlle. Zoe and a company of artists will perform in Repository Hall this
                    week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeder</ln>
                        <fn>Cynthia Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Everett and Miss Cynthia Ann Reeder, both of Metal, were married on
                    February 17th by the Rev. J. Smith Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Julia C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Julia C. Grove died in Chambersburg on February 22nd. She was 79 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Fanny Witherow, wife of James Witherow, died near Carrick on March
                    7th. She was 49 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine Thomas died on March 2nd at the residence of her son-in-law,
                    Rev. James M. Bishop. She was 76 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.16.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
