
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.03.09">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/29/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-03-09">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>09</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.09.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.09.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The transition of an unwilling subject from even a lower condition to a
                        higher one, is often marked with strange <orig reg="ebullitions"
                        >ebulitions</orig> of temper which to the eye of the beholder are seen in
                        their true character, weakness, absurdity and pitiable childishness. Take
                        for example a modern Democrat, one who through all the vicissitudes of our
                        country's struggle to free itself of the incubus of slavery, has held fast
                        to his political "Diana," whom he supposed "all Asia and the world
                        worshipped." Every effort of our glorious country to rise to a level with
                        the Declaration of Independence, is still viewed by our modern Democrat as a
                        thrust at his political faith. He has had a tear of sympathy to shed for
                        every pang which his idol felt, a deep drawn sigh to swell his bosom for
                        every symptom of dissolution which indicated the death of the "beast," at
                        whose shrine he knelt. The final triumph of the government over the enemy
                        that was grappling it by the throat, is still viewed by the fogy Democrat as
                        a calamity. The "Fifteenth Amendment" is alike odious to their vision as the
                        "Declaration of Independence." Now, like the rebellious Israelites after
                        their emancipation from Egyptian bondage, they are wont to look back to the
                        "leeks and onions" which they left in Egypt; they manifest their discontent
                        by grumbling at the beneficent changes which have followed in the wake of
                        our country's march to its higher destiny. A down trodden people whose
                        loyalty and devotion to our government have been demonstrated by their
                        patience under the most flagrant wrongs, and their enthusiastic efforts to
                        assimilate themselves with those who were their oppressors, in the grand
                        march to national greatness and national glory. Revels, now a U.S. Senator,
                        is a "thorn in their flesh." The modern Democrat is grieved to the heart
                        that Jefferson Davis, J. C. Calhoun and other dignitaries who were men
                        "after his own heart," have been succeeded by one of the hated colored race.
                        What an infraction of the Constitution to have Saulsbury and Garrett Davis
                        disgraced by the presence of Revels of Mississippi?</p>

                    <p>Our neighbor of the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> is a fair specimen of
                        one of these transition unfortunates. The character and dignity of the
                        Senate of the United States, has sadly deteriorated in his eyes. He looks
                        back with a <orig reg="mournful">mourful</orig> interest to the glorious
                        past when Democracy in the person of Brooks was engaged in the dignified
                        duty of purifying the Senate from the contaminating influence of a Sumner; a
                        Keit and Barksdale were endeavoring to give dignity to the House in their
                        courteous encounter with Grow of Pennsylvania, or a Pryor was wont to
                        admonish Potter that the free discussion of public measures must not be
                        tolerated, by sending his a challenge to mortal combat. Oh, how unlike the
                        good old times, to him, is the heresy of the "equality of citizens before
                        the law," compared with that glorious period when an anti-slavery lecturer
                        was pelted with rotten eggs, or even that <emph rend="italics"
                            >constitutional era</emph>, when a Northern citizen could be tarred and
                        feathered or hanged by the neck till he was dead on suspicion of being an
                        abolitionist if caught in a Southern State. Nay, it must needs make our
                        modern Democrat draw a sigh of relief, in his retrospect of our country, to
                        know that there was a period in our country's history when the Constitution
                        guaranteed the right to a mob to murder Lovejoy and destroy his printing
                        press. And the <orig reg="bloodhounds">blood-hounds</orig> of the South in
                        full communion with the biped <orig reg="bloodhounds">blood-hounds</orig> of
                        the North could chase the trembling slave, fleeing from bondage, within
                        sight of the proud banners of his native land. But we must have patience
                        with the Democrat in his transition state. He has had severe trials. He has
                        seen his proud, dominant party disintegrate, large numbers of which went to
                        swell the columns of the hated Republican party. He too from force of
                        circumstances will soon find it convenient to turn his eyes on the future;
                        his last look on these pleasant visions of the past will be an epoch to be
                        remembered as the "last sigh of the Moor."</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> mocks Democrats who are upset to
                    see black politicians taking office in areas of the country in place of men like
                    John C. Calhoun and Jefferson Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.09.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Special Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jere Cook, assistant assessor for the 16th District, will meet the citizens
                    of Antrim on March 8th-10th at Greencastle's Hays House to collect income and
                    special license taxes. A 50% penalty will be added to late payments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Town Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Culloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Nulty</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkhart</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>E. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heefner</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The border war damage claimants will meet tomorrow in the Court House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Franklin County Horticultural Society was held in Mr.
                    Reed's building on the corner of Front and King Streets. Thirty members
                    attended. The spring exhibition will be held on June 11th. Several members read
                    papers on various aspects of horticulture.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Franklin County Bank</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKibben</ln>
                        <fn>Chambers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. H. Taylor, popular long-time teller at the First National Bank, and Col.
                    Chambers McKibben of Philadelphia, purchased the banking house of Austin, Elder,
                    and Fletcher to be hereafter named the Franklin County Bank. The paper endorses
                    the partners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Linn, son of John Linn, died suddenly on Tuesday. He was 13 years
                    old. He suddenly became sick after spending the day at school. He was buried in
                    Falling Spring Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The concert in Repository Hall for the benefit of the poor raised $129.00.
                    An additional subscription purse of $34.00 was also raised, and contributions
                    made of meat, flour, and potatoes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atwell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel M. Atwell and Miss Mattie E. Jarrett, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married in the Methodist Parsonage on March 1st by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>James T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerrin</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James T. Wood and Miss Maggie A. McFerrin, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on January 20th at the Methodist Parsonage by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vondersmith</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rebecca Vondersmith died near Church Hill on February 12th. She was 74
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.03.09.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
