<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.05.04">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/30/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-05-04">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>04</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.04.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.04.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Celebration on Tuesday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The exercise held throughout the State on Tuesday of last week by the colored
                        citizens, to celebrate the adoption of the Fifteenth Amendment, were too
                        important and too instructive to be passed over without comment. In almost
                        every town in the Commonwealth, in every important town and city, these
                        exercises were held, and to the great honor of the colored citizens the
                        newspapers have not one single instance of disorderly or riotous conduct to
                        chronicle.</p>

                    <p>It is no trifling matter that in the midst of such unusual joy and rejoicing
                        as pervaded the enfranchised class on that day, they were never unmindful
                        that with the right of citizenship came also the duties of citizens. The
                        order, decorum and propriety which marked their conduct at other places were
                        also observed here. The procession of the various societies and companies
                        was dignified and becoming in all its appointments. The banners with their
                        inscriptions and mottoes were appropriate and right. There was nothing done
                        for the purpose of giving offense, and if any offense was taken by any white
                        person he must have taken special pains to be hurt. Altogether our colored
                        citizens are entitled to the highest praise for this, and for this reason;
                        Our experience does not furnish us a single instance in Chambersburg where
                        white persons, either Democratic or Republican, assembled in large numbers,
                        that the day passed off so peacefully and orderly as did this one. There is
                        no doubt that the inducements to behave well on this occasion were strong,
                        but at the same time the temptation to yield to the feeling of unrestrained
                        joy and rejoicing which they met to celebrate was great. They are entitled
                        to commendation for their good conduct, and we at least shall not withhold
                        it.</p>

                    <p>In the afternoon speeches were made in front of the Court House by both white
                        and colored speakers, and also in Repository Hall in the evening. The
                        attendance was large, both classes being well represented. Of the remarks
                        made by the white speakers we need say nothing. What the colored orators had
                        to say is of more importance as an expression of their views, sentiments and
                        feelings. What was made memorable during the long enslavement of the colored
                        race, and particularly during the war of the rebellion, was also apparent in
                        their remarks. They cherish no feeling of revenge or resentment towards
                        those who stole their labor and their liberty, who made them ignorant and
                        degraded, but they have a keen and just appreciation of all their wrongs and
                        cannot be deceived as to who were their friends and who their enemies. Those
                        were the dominant ideas pervading the remarks of each of the speakers and we
                        heard three or four. They were all Republicans, and Republican from the
                        purest and highest motives. They reasoned clearly and unerringly that their
                        interest and their duty both allied them with the Republican party. They
                        foresaw and predicted that the Democratic party were bound to make an effort
                        to secure their suffrages, but they warned them that the record they had
                        made in the past would forever destroy the confidence of the colored voters
                        in their promises in the future. We fear the Democracy derived but little
                        comfort or encouragement from what they heard.</p>

                    <p>We were pleased to see that the colored citizens provided most of the
                        speakers for this occasion from their own color. They were right in so
                        doing. We urge them to persevere in this rule. If many of them are ignorant,
                        it is because they could not be intelligent and be slaves. The whites were
                        the stronger and they chose rather to have them ignorant and slaves than
                        free and intelligent. With the natural ability they have, and the
                        earnestness and zeal to learn which they display, they need not long be
                        behind their more favored brethren since learning and paid labor are as open
                        to them as to others.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> reports that the recent
                    celebration of the passage of the Fifteenth Amendment was marked by orderly,
                    appropriate behavior from the 'colored citizens' of the county and Republican
                    allies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The Democratic leaders have persistently dinned into the ears of the ignorant
                        of their party that if slavery were allowed to vote they would soon occupy
                        all the places or trade and labor held by the white Democrats, and thus they
                        would be left without employment and without the means of living. These
                        leaders did not then believe that their own places were endangered by the
                        encroachments of the negro, but it seems they were. In Philadelphia the
                        headquarters of the Democracy, hallowed by the memory of years devoted to
                        the enslavement and degradation of the negro race, has been converted into a
                        negro minstrel concert room.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports mockingly that the previous headquarters of the
                    Democratic party in Philadelphia has become a 'negro minstrel concert room,' an
                    unexpected fulfillment of the prophecy of black men taking over white places.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns that Democrats plan to "alienate the foreign vote" from the
                    Republican Party at all costs. The 15th Amendment brought such a large number of
                    new voters into Republican ranks that it is imperative for Democrats to make up
                    the numbers elsewhere.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.04.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Day of Jubilee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Tuesday of last week was a day that will long be remembered by the colored
                        people of Chambersburg. It was a day for which they had been preparing since
                        the 30th of March. Nothing was left undone to make the occasion a grand one.
                        The weather was exceedingly pleasant.</p>

                    <p>The procession formed about 1 o'clock P. M., and marched through the various
                        streets of the town in charge of the following officers:</p>

                    <p>Chief Marshal - Albert Jones.<lb/> Aids - Henson Turner, James D. Lewis and
                        George Williams.<lb/> Commander of Military - Capt. Thomas L. White.<lb/>
                        Adjutant - Alexander Lewis.</p>

                    <p>ORDER OF PROCESSION:</p>

                    <p>Marshal and Aids,<lb/> Band.<lb/> Rough and Ready Boys, Capt. Elijah
                        Hammett.<lb/> Stevens Union Star Club, Capt. Geo. Miller.<lb/> Drum
                        Corps.<lb/> Independent Blues, Capt. Alfred Bradford.<lb/> Lincoln Cadets,
                        Capt. John Downey.<lb/> Wagon containing thirty ladies, representing the
                        thirty States who ratified the Fifteenth Amendment, in charge of Jesse
                        Holmes, mounted.<lb/> Delegation from Mount Alto, Capt. Campbell.<lb/>
                        Civilians, in charge of Henry Stuart.</p>

                    <p>The procession halted in front of the Court House, when speaking began at 2
                        P.M. Speeches appropriated to the occasion were made by the following
                        gentlemen: Joseph R. Winters, Wm. S. Hall, Rev. Dr. A. R. Green, of
                        Washington, D. C., and John Stewart, Esq. The speaking over, the procession
                        counter-marched to Water street, where it was disbanded.</p>

                    <p>In the evening there was a grand festival and ball in Repository Hall, which
                        was largely attended. The audience was addressed by I. H. McCauley, Esq., L.
                        S. Clarke, Esq., Mr. H. G. Mendenhall, Gen. F. S. Stumbaugh, W. S. Hall,
                        Ashford F. Collins, Rev. McKeehan and J. R. Winters. Much of the success
                        attending the celebration is due to the energy of Henry Monks, Chairman of
                        the Executive committee, and Wm. H. Middleton, Secretary.</p>

                    <p>The colored men have every reason to feel gratified that their day of
                        rejoicing passed off as pleasantly as it did. Their <orig reg="program"
                            >programme</orig> was carried out with excellent order. Their friends
                        were pleased with the manner in which they conducted themselves, and their
                        enemies were compelled to acknowledge that there never was a public day in
                        this place attended with so little disturbance.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Henson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammett</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradford</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holmes</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mendenhall</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Ashford F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKeehan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monks</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middleton</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article contains a details account of the recent celebration of the
                    passage of the Fifteenth Amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Anniversary Exercises</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noftsker</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Odd Fellows of America celebrated their fifty-first anniversary, and
                    the Chambersburg ladges observed the occasion with music and addresses. The
                    Silver Cornet Band played, Prof. George W. Noftsker led the choir, and Rev. D.
                    Townsend and Rev. E. W. Kirby led prayers and addressed the crowd. Past Grand
                    Master I. H. McCauley also spoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Last Tuesday at Greencastle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The colored citizens of the Southern portion of Franklin county celebrated
                        the final passage of the Fifteenth Amendment, near Greencastle, on Tuesday
                        last. Mercersburg, Greencastle, and Waynesboro were all represented. The
                        procession, after marching through the principal streets, proceeded to Moss
                        Spring. His honor Judge Rowe, being compelled to come to Chambersburg to
                        preside at court, made a short speech shortly after arriving on the grounds.
                        He made no reference to politics. His remarks were eloquent and were greeted
                        with rounds of applause. After the Judge had concluded the crowd was
                        dismissed until 1.30 p. m. An elegant dinner had been prepared and as one of
                        the guests we must say we enjoyed it.</p>

                    <p>In the afternoon addresses were delivered by S. W. Hays, Esq., Geo. W.
                        Zeigler, Esq., and Rev. Whiteman. Mr. Hays spoke for about an hour. He was
                        then followed by Mr. Zeigler, who addressed the audience in an earnest and
                        effective manner. Rev. Whiteman's remarks were peculiarly appropriate. He
                        advised the colored people not only to educate their minds, but to see it
                        that their hearts were also purified. His speech was of such a character as
                        one would be sure to hear from a Christian minister. Mr. Anderson's remarks
                        were full of good advice to his colored brethren, and were well received.</p>

                    <p>The audience dispersed about 4 p. m., and retired quietly to their homes. The
                        order on the grounds could not have been better. The colored Band of
                        Greencastle furnished good music for the occasion.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whiteman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper here discusses two speakers' remarks at the recent celebration of
                    the passage of the Fifteenth Amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>One Eye but Two Ears</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>A Democratic politician was engaged in earnest conversation with a one-eyed
                        colored man on Wallace's corner, one day last week, and seeing a lady pass
                        remarked to her that he was making a convert to the Democratic faith.</p>

                    <p>"It is well you try the one-eyed darkies first," she remarked, "for you can
                        never find one with two eyes that couldn't see through your miserable
                        blarney."</p>

                    <p>"Lord, missus," said the newly enfranchised, "if this darkey is got only one
                        eye, he has two ears, and he lets the copperheads talk in at one, and out it
                        goes at the other."</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This short account contains a 'humorous' snippet of conversation overheard
                    between a Democrat, a one-eyed black man, and a Republican woman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Old Fashioned Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>G. G. Grady's Old Fashioned American Circus will exhibit in Chambersburg on
                    May 13th. It will feature riders, leapers, vaulters, tumblers, gymnasts,
                    contortionists, and clowns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Horticultural Soicety held their regular meeting on April 19th. Six or
                    eight ladies were present. Prof. Shumaker, Judge King, and Mr. Jenkins plan to
                    list the prizes for the upcoming exhibition on June 11th and 12th. The group
                    discussed various aspects of vegetable cultivation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>I.O.O.F.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Olive Branch Encampment No. 13, I.O.O.F., will meet on May 6th. Members of
                    Shippensburg Encampment will also attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Cumberland Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Auditor General for Pennsylvania published the following statistics on
                    the Cumberland Valley Railroad: length, 73 miles; engine houses and shops, 5;
                    engines, 16; first class passenger cars, 14; baggage, mail, and express cars, 6;
                    freight, 232; iron bridges, 17; wooden bridges, 2; railroads crossed, 1; ticket
                    stations on road, 8; flag stations on road, 14; wood and water stations, 6;
                    total passengers carried, 308,213; gross tonnage, 244,532.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Bible Society will hold an anniversary meeting in the
                    Lutheran English Church on the second Sunday in May.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hullenberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Silver Cornet Band refused to play for the celebration by
                    African American citizens last week. The paper has the "pleasure" of stating
                    that Prof. Keller, Mr. Snider, and Mr. Hullenberger were in favor of playing.
                    "The Fayetteville Band behaved like men, although they charged mighty well for
                    their services."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The African American residents of Chambersburg were refused the use of the
                    grounds of the Franklin County Agricultural Society through the intransigence of
                    one member. He wished to charge them $20 for an hour and a half, which they
                    refused to pay.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. McHenry, former pastor of the Grindstone Hill Lutheran
                    congregation, preached his farewell sermon on April 24th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>President C. M. Duncan and Secretary C. Gilbert announce that the Franklin
                    County Agricultural Fair Company will hold its annual meeting on May 5th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Sentenced</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swingler</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William F. Swingler, and African American man formerly of Chambersburg, was
                    found guilty of stealing a coat in Adams County and was sentenced to one year's
                    imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Officer</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shrup</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flora</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keltner</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Officer Houser arrested Lewis Shrup, William Flora, and Lewis Keltner on
                    Saturday for drunkenness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Brotherton, formery of Franklin, died in New Orleans on January 27th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keagey</ln>
                        <fn>William Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keagey</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keagey</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Leonard Keagey, oldest son of Henry and Maggie Keagey, died in
                    Chambersburg on April 30th. He was 6 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>Harry Strock</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>B. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harry Strock Cormany, son of B. A. and Elizabeth Cormany, died on May 2nd.
                    He was 2 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.04.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
