
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.11.02">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/07/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-11-02">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>02</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.11.02.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.11.02.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Meyers Whistles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>THIS whistling to keep up one's courage is one of the oldest tricks in the
                        world, and it is amusing to see how Meyers keeps whistling in the columns of
                        his "two papers," one daily. No person has said that Hon. John Cessna means
                        to contest Meyers' seat in the next Congress. Cessna has made no such
                        announcement in the papers, he has given no person authority to say so for
                        him, he has not given Meyers notice, either official or otherwise, that he
                        intends to contest, and yet not an issue of the <emph rend="italics"
                        >Patriot</emph> or the Bedford <emph rend="italics">Gazette</emph> appears
                        that is not full of it. Meyers' unexpected success seems to have upset his
                        equanimity. He didn't expect to succeed, and now, that he seems to have a
                        small majority, doubtless knowing how fraudulently it was obtained, sleeping
                        or waking, he sees visions of a contest. In every issue of his papers he
                        babbles about the contest, and <orig reg="makes">make</orig> ridiculous
                        threats, and tells stupendous stories, until even his friends are
                        apprehensive that his Congressional campaign has produced a little crack
                        somewhere in his organism.</p>

                    <p>We beg him, purely in charity, to preserve his soul in peace, and if possible
                        suppress his anxiety for a few days. If Cessna means to contest he can't
                        possibly do it without letting him know all about it, and giving him
                        abundant time to get up all sorts of dreadful things. But if Meyers thinks
                        to deter him from entering upon a contest by constantly publishing his silly
                        stories, he is a bigger fool than we took him for, and is making a case to
                        prove that he isn't fit for a seat in Congress, whether the people elected
                        him to the position or not.</p>

                    <p>We can assure Mr. Meyers now, that if Mr. Cessna has reason to believe that
                        the former secured his election by fraudulent votes he will be sure to
                        contest the seat, and Mr. Meyers may as well save his strength and temper
                        for the occasion.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> denies that defeated Republican
                    congressional representative, John Cessna, has plans to contest Democrat B. F.
                    Meyers's victory. The paper suggests that Meyers's fears are a sign of weakness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.11.02.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the Convention of I.O.G.T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sloan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlosser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chase</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roney</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donahue</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Townsend</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The lodges of the I.O.G.T. in Franklin and Cumberland Counties met in the
                    Temperance Hall in Chambersburg on October 25th for a grand convention. The
                    group discussed the relationship between temperance reform and the christian
                    church, the expediency of pushing for prohibition and outlawing drink, and the
                    best means of promoting membership and the cause. Many non-members also attended
                    the proceedings. A children's meeting and a public mass meeting accompanied the
                    event.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Chapter of Horse Thefts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebbert</ln>
                        <fn>Jerry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A man named S. Smee registered at the Washington House and is thought to be
                    one of a gang of horse thieves. He has not been seen since he has been
                    identified. A horse was recently stolen from the stable of Jerry Ebbert near
                    Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The criminal business was disposed of by Wednesday evening, and the grand
                        jury discharged on Thursday morning. The following cases were disposed of,
                        and those convicted of crimes sentenced on Thursday morning:</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Leonard Nave. - Fornication and Bastardy, on oath of Sarah Ann
                        Porter. Verdict guilty. The usual sentence imposed by the court.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. George Keil, Sr. - Surety of the Peace, on oath of Francis Myers.
                        Case heard and court sentenced Myers to pay the costs of suit.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Myers - Surety of the Peace, on oath of John C. Gilbert. Case
                        heard and court sentenced defendant to pay costs of suit.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. David Bergenstock. - Surety of the Peace, on oath of John C.
                        Gilbert. Case heard, and defendant sentenced by the court to pay costs of
                        suit.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Henry Bergenstock. - Surety of the Peace, on oath of John C.
                        Gilbert. Case heard by the court and defendant sentenced to pay costs of
                        suit.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. George Keil and Joseph Keil. - Assault and Battery, on oath of
                        Francis Myers, George Keil plead guilty, and was sentenced by the court to
                        pay a fine of $5 and costs.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. George Goettman. - Larceny of Scotch Ale, Wine and "Checks," from
                        the restaurant of Lautz &amp; Unger. Verdict guilty and defendant
                        sentenced to pay a fine of one cent, costs of prosecution, and undergo an
                        imprisonment in the County Jail for a period of two months.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Francis Leasure. - Assault and Battery, on oath of Catharine E.
                        Ganes. Verdict not guilty, but that the defendant pay two thirds and the
                        prosecutrix one-third of the costs.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Francis Leasure. - Case heard by the Court and defendant sentenced
                        to pay the costs of suit.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Daniel Rowe. - Assault and Battery on oath of Abram R. Saylor.
                        Verdict guilty and defendant sentenced to pay a fine of five dollars and
                        costs of suit.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Jane Gilbert - Surety of the Peace, on oath of Mary Myers. Case
                        heard and prosecutrix sentenced to pay the costs.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. John Thomas and Wm. Thomas - Larceny. The defendants were the
                        parties who stole Mr. Hunsecker's horse. They were found guilty and were
                        each sentenced to six years in the Penitentiary. For stealing the buggy from
                        the residence of Mr. Palmer, they were each sentenced to undergo an
                        imprisonment of two years in the Eastern Penitentiary.</p>

                    <p>By leave of the Court the District Attorney entered a <emph rend="italics"
                            >nolle prosequi</emph> in each of the following cases: Com vs. John
                        Pannell and James Martin; Com vs. James Pannell; Com vs. Frederick Myers;
                        Com. vs. Henry Kershner; Com. vs. John w. Kuhn; Com. vs. Michael Gable; Com.
                        vs. David Little, et al.</p>

                    <p>The following bills were ignored: Com vs J. U. Hannan; Com vs Susan Scott;
                        Com vs Wm. Sly; Com vs Byers Wingert and Frank Shively; Com vs Alfred
                        Nelson; Com vs George Long (two bills); Com vs Margaret Wolfe; Com vs Jacob
                        R Kreps; Com vs Samuel Brooks; Com vs Andrew Meads, et al; Com vs David
                        Henderson, et al; Com vs Abraham Saylor.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nave</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porter</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keil</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bergenstock</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bergenstock</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keil</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goettman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leasure</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ganes</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saylor</ln>
                        <fn>Abram R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert </ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunsecker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pannell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pannell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Furgeson</ln>
                        <fn>Jerome</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meade</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kershner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gable</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hannan</ln>
                        <fn>J. U.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sly</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Byers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreps</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saylor</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> notes recent court cases, naming
                    the parties involved and noting the verdicts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Odd Fellows Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The members of Columbus Lodge No. 75, I.O.O.F., of Chambersburg took the
                    trains on the Cumberland Valley Railroad to visit a brother-lodge in Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>New Hardware Establishment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George A. Miller has opened a new hardware store in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Reunion of the 126th Penna. Vols.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The soldiers of the 126th Pa will hold a reunion in Chambersburg's
                    Repository Hall on December 13th. "The regiment was made up chiefly from
                    Franklin, Fulton, and Juniata counties, much the largest being from Franklin.
                    Chambersburg has therefore been selected as the place for holding the next
                    meeting." The committee of arrangements is attempting to send an invitation to
                    every survivor of the regiment but lacks reliable information for those who have
                    moved. Any soldier that does not receive an invitation, but hears of the event
                    should consider themselves invited.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Methodists of St. Thomas made $127 at their recent festival.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>Beckie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. T. J. McLanahan and Miss Beckie A. Austin, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on October 27th at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. I. N.
                    Hays, assisted by the Rev. James F. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiffer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rothe</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Peiffer and Miss Sophia Hassler, both of Franklin, were married on
                    October 27th by the Rev. G. Rothe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vink</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter Vink, formerly of Chambersburg, died in Adams County on September
                    21st. He was 54 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyer</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Jennie A. Cormany died in Ohio on October 19th at the residence of her
                    brother-in-law, A. J. Boyer, after suffering a long and severe case of pulmonary
                    consumption. She was 35 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Washington Vanderaw, son of Jacob and Rebecca Vanderaw, died in
                    Mississippi on July 22nd. He was 33 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.11.02.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
