
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.06.29">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/03/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-06-29">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.29.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.29.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Democratic Conundrum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>A CONUNDRUM the Democracy never weary of asking is, "What will be the
                        political complexion of the next Congress?" It shows the increasing
                        restlessness and anxiety of the Democratic mind that the party should for
                        ten years back have biennially sought information upon this subject in
                        advance of the elections. That the answers which they framed to this
                        oft-repeated interrogatory were always wrong does not seem to deter them
                        from making the same inquiry now, and of answering it again to suit their
                        desires. In the same breath they ask the question and give a reply. As oft
                        before, they say, this time, at least, Congress will be Democratic.</p>

                    <p>We feel like encouraging this search into the secrets of the future. It gives
                        innocent entertainment to those who but for this might be occupied in
                        something less harmless. It affords a temporary enjoyment to the Democracy
                        only less satisfying, this belief in their triumph, than the actual triumph
                        itself. Indeed it is claimed by many wise philosophers that the pursuit of
                        an end or object gives men greater satisfaction than its attainment. We wish
                        to think so, because we wish to see our Democratic brethren happy. They
                        shall have all the enjoyment the chase affords; the Republican party will
                        bag the game.</p>

                    <p>Why should the Democratic party triumph in the next election? Not because as
                        a party, they were opposed to the abolition of slavery. The people have
                        decided against them on this question, and do not wish to reverse their
                        decision. Not because, as a party, they were in sympathy with the rebellion
                        during the war. The people said the rebellion must be put down, and they did
                        it. Not <orig reg="because">bebause</orig>, as a party, they were opposed to
                        making suffrage in the United States universal. The people declared by their
                        Legislatures that the constitution must be so amended, and it was so
                        amended. Not because the rebellious States were compelled to recognize the
                        changed condition wrought in the country by the overthrow of the rebellion,
                        and to bring their State governments into harmony with these conditions
                        before they could enter into the relation of States to the Union. The people
                        demanded this as a guaranty for the future, and it was done. These things
                        have all been fixed, and irrevocably fixed. They cannot now be changed. If
                        it were possible the people would contemplate with horror a single step
                        backwards. The principles of the Declaration of Independence and the
                        principles of slavery were arrayed against each other, and the wisdom of the
                        fathers was confirmed by the acts of their sons, in that the former were
                        placed on an enduring foundation and the latter were destroyed.</p>

                    <p>None of these things can be in issue again whatever politicians may do. They
                        are <emph rend="italics">functus officio</emph>. When the Democracy claim
                        that they will control the next Congress, they must calculate to get this
                        control by means of some other question than any of these. They must bury
                        out of sight and recollection of the people the catalogue of their crimes
                        and iniquities, and arraign the Republican party for having in something
                        betrayed the trust and confidence of the people. The election of Grant over
                        Seymour must be accepted as a complete endorsement of the Republican party
                        up to that time. If it is unworthy of the place it now holds the cause of
                        this unworthiness has originated since his election. What are the prominent
                        features of his administration? His watchwords were Peace, the economical
                        administration of the government, the extinguishment of the public debt, the
                        reduction of the taxes and the enforcement of the laws. On these he was
                        elected and the lease of the Republican party extended. Have his promises
                        been idle words or have they been strictly lived up to? Almost every man
                        woman and child is prepared to answer these questions for him or herself. He
                        has maintained the rights and dignity of the United States, in their
                        relations with foreign powers in a particularly critical period; and while
                        all may not agree as to the details of his foreign policy he has won the
                        respect of every nation and preserved peace without any humiliating
                        concessions. The government has been administered with rare economy and
                        skill. Except the extraordinary expenses entailed by the war, and that
                        caused by the rapid settlement of the Indian country, the necessary expenses
                        of the government would be no greater than before the war. The public debt
                        has been extinguished at the rate of a hundred millions a year, and while
                        this has been done the taxes have been taken off of many <orig
                            reg="commodities">commodoties</orig> and articles of manufacture. Before
                        Congress adjourns still further reduction of taxes will be made. The laws
                        have been justly and rigidly enforced. The passage of the Fifteenth
                        Amendment has been secured, and those whom it has made citizens are
                        protected in their rights.</p>

                    <p>Is it for any of these things that the Democracy can hope to secure the
                        control of the next Congress. A majority of all the voters are Republicans.
                        Can they or any part of them be purchased to join the ranks of their
                        enemies? We fail to see any reason to think that they can. Do the Democracy;
                        and whence their hope?</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial defends President Grant's administration and states that the
                    upcoming elections will be favorable for the Republicans despite what their
                    Democratic counterparts suggest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Will Free Negroes Work?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>It used to be incumbent on every good Democrat to proclaim that they would
                        not; that they were an idle, lazy, shiftless, thriftless lot, and if slavery
                        was abolished productive labor would be at an end in the South. What is the
                        fact? Last cotton crop is larger by a million bales than that of the year
                        before. It numbers over three millions bales and is worth more than
                        $300,000,000. It was produced by free negro labor, and these figures do not
                        represent more than half the productive labor of the South last year. It
                        does not include the tobacco, corn wheat rye and oats, the fruits and
                        vegetables of the South, nearly all the growth of voluntary negro labor. In
                        addition to this the former slaves have since the war deposited of their
                        earnings some millions of money, we do not now know how many, in Saving
                        Banks, and have built churches, school-houses, and many of them have bought
                        land and made themselves permanent homes. Altogether, we doubt if history
                        furnishes another example where the wisdom of those who freed and
                        enfranchised an enslaved race has been so wonderly vindicated by the results
                        as in the case of the colored people of the United States.</p>

                    <p>By means of the negro labor the South has actually rebounded from the
                        condition of abject and deplorable poverty into which it was plunged by the
                        rebellion, and our Democratic friends who are howling about the negroes now
                        should recollect that to them their dear Southern brethren owe their
                        prosperity <orig reg="today">to-day</orig>. No thinking mind familiar with
                        the facts will undertake to deny that the ex slaveholders have done far less
                        than the ex slaves to bring about the present prosperous condition of the
                        South. But for the presence of their former slaves after the war they would
                        scarcely have escaped starvation. How well it becomes them and the Democracy
                        of the North to denounce their benefactors we leave for the sober judgment
                        of the unprejudiced everywhere to say.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> argues that the freedmen have
                    done well for themselves and have helped the South to recover from the war. The
                    article cites increased agricultural output and proclaims that free black labor
                    is a success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Income Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Senate passed a bill striking out the income tax. "There is no doubt
                    that the sentiment of the country is against the Income Tax, and within the last
                    month that sentiment has received such general expression that the House when
                    called to act on the amended bill will hearken to it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.29.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Case</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bozzaris</ln>
                        <fn>Marco</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loose</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bloyer</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>J. Harper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>G. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>N. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lanahan</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mendenhall</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderbilt</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russel</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>J. Harper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>L. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Academy exhibition, held on Friday in Repository Hall,
                    received excellent reviews. Prof. Shumaker's students performed music and
                    delivered literary addresses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Public Bath House Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Public response has supported the Repository's call for a public bath house
                    in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paddock</ln>
                        <fn>Wilbur F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamberton</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clerc</ln>
                        <fn>Francis J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marsden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hare</ln>
                        <fn>William Hobart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heaton</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglass</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orrick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kellogg</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Corner-stone laying services will take place in Trinity Church,
                    Chambersburg, on July 6th. A schedule of services is included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Shippensburg Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelso</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagner</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffey</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Shippensburg is installing a town clock. Fines are being instituted in town
                    for unmuzzled dogs allowed to roam freely. A chapter of the Improved Order of
                    Red Men was recently founded. A vote was taken on a location for the proposed
                    Cumberland Valley State Normal School.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article chastizes the slow pace of work on the pavements on North Front
                    Street.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deputy U.S. Marshals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Widner</ln>
                        <fn>W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackens</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Study</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prather</ln>
                        <fn>Henry P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following were appointed Deputy US Marshals in Franklin County: Jacob
                    Kendig, Lurgan, Fannett, and Metal; W. K. Widner, Southampton, Letterkenny, and
                    Green; D. F. Leisher, North Ward of Chambersburg and Hamilton; W. T. Graham, St.
                    Thomas and Peters; W. Lackens, Montgomery and Warren; E. D. Reid, South Ward of
                    Chambersburg; J. P. Study, Guilford and Quincy; Henry P. Prather, Greencastle
                    and Antrim; J. F. Kurtz, Waynesboro and Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yingling</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Monterey Springs, four miles from Waynesboro, will be open for visitors on
                    July 4th. Harry Yingling is proprietor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn>O. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A large bell was elevated to the top of the Central Presbyterian Church.
                    Col. O. N. Lull of Chambersburg was among those presenting the bell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Medical Society will meet in Chambersburg on July 6th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAfee</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Wolf and Miss Mary E. McAfee, both of Mercersburg, were married on
                    June 4th at the M. E. Parsonage in Chambersburg by the Rev. E. W. Kirby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sechrist</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Maria Sechrist died in Warren on June 22nd. She was 64 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Williams died in Warren on June 20th. He was 58 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Thomas died in Warren on May 1st. He was 35 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeakle</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eliza Yeakle died on April 30th in Warren. She was 30 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Edward Shriver</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Emeline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>William </fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Shriver Miller, son of G. A. and Mary Emeline Miller of
                    Chambersburg, died in Baltimore at the residence of his uncle, Dr. William
                    Riley, after returning from Florida. He was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John C. Anderson, adopted son of Mr. John C. Anderson, died in Chambersburg
                    on June 22nd of cholera infantum. He was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.29.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
