
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.05.25">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-05-25">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.25.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.25.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Theodore McGowan, Chairman of the Republican County Committee,
                    announces that the committee will meet in Chambersburg on June 4th to set a date
                    for the county convention. Although the local posts up for election in the fall
                    are not those most highly sought after, the paper urges enthusiasm and support.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Protection Versus Free Trade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the House has postponed a vote on the tariff bill,
                    but fierce conflict is expected in the future. The editors assert that the issue
                    is not partisan or sectional in nature, but regional and should produce odd
                    combinations of support and opposition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Fated Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>It is somewhat interesting to observe the efforts of the Democracy to adjust
                        itself to the new order of things. Without any principles to guide its
                        movements, it seems quite at a loss to know what expedients will avail to
                        make it appear in harmony with the popular sentiment. Having committed
                        itself against the negro and in favor of human slavery during the terrible
                        struggle which our country endured in its throes to get rid of the foul blot
                        that made it a reproach and a byword in the eyes of Liberty and Christianity
                        and having suffered defeat after defeat in the interest of the foul monster,
                        now that slavery is dead and the emancipated race have been enfranchised,
                        the Democracy is sorely tried by the dilemma that presents itself to their
                        choice. The Democratic press and Democratic leaders have educated the rank
                        and file in bigotry and prejudice to such an extent that they now find
                        themselves totally unable to undo their own work or to bring the mass of
                        their voters to see that equal rights to all men, irrespective of race,
                        color, or previous condition of servitude, is a settled fact, and that
                        acquiescence is the duty and policy of all parties. No doubt, then, with
                        this condition of things the Democracy has found itself sorely puzzled to
                        know what to do in the premises. Finding, however, that the colored voters
                        have determined to vote with the party that followed principle rather than
                        prejudice, and that the only chance of success to the Democracy, was in
                        swearing that the "horse was sixteen feet high," because in their mistake,
                        they had at first said so - they concluded:</p>

                    <p>"Stept in so far that should they wade no more,<lb/> Returning were as
                        tedious as go o'er."<lb/> 'Twas a sad necessity, but the horn of the dilemma
                        they have chosen is to be "consistent," not "simply to be true," so they
                        again launch the boat bigotry <emph rend="italics">alias</emph> prejudice,
                        and strike for the port of success, forgetting that they have been stranded
                        again and again in that same fated vessel. Always measuring popular
                        sentiment by their own narrow views, they have hoped to draw from the masses
                        enough to give them the majority, the power, and especially the spoils;
                        instead, however, of making converts and gaining strength, they have
                        generally succeeded in driving from the remnant of what was once the great
                        Democratic party, the honest and intelligent who had still clung to their
                        sinking fortunes. The leaders will find popular sentiment still far in
                        advance of their "white man's party" theory, and the most unaccountable
                        feature of their whole scheme is that while laughing in their own sleeves at
                        the <orig reg="maneuver">manoeuvre</orig>, they should suppose that the
                        weakest in the Republican ranks should be caught with their twaddle about
                        the necessity for a white man's party. The fortunes of the Democracy have
                        been untoward, and if experience has failed to teach them the utter folly of
                        staking their fortunes in the lap of bigotry in its conflict with truth, we
                        suppose they are fated to exemplify the old adage, that "whome the gods
                        intend to destroy the first make mad."</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial suggests that the Democrats are stuck in a political bind
                    for, having positioned themselves against emancipation and black
                    enfranchisement, they cannot alter their stance and, as a result, are losing
                    supporters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.25.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowen</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Theodore M'Gowen announces that the Republican County Committee will meet
                    in the office of Thomas J. Grimison on June 4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Decoration Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>At a meeting, on Monday evening last, of the Committee appointed by the
                        soldiers to make arrangements for the ceremonies attending the decoration of
                        the soldiers graves in this place, on Monday next, the following committees
                        were appointed:</p>

                    <p>Committee to mark the graves of soldiers and place flags over the same - Jno.
                        A. Seiders, T. M. Mahon, Harry Strickler, Geo. Wampler.</p>

                    <p>Committee on Invitations and Music - S. W. Hays, D. F. Leisher J. L. P.
                        Deitrich, Dr. G. F. Platte.</p>

                    <p>Committee to see to the tolling of the bells - Daniel Glass, M. W. Houser,
                        Solomon Swert, Jere. Donavin, Jno. <unclear>Shinafield</unclear>.</p>

                    <p>Committee to secure an Orator for the occasion - Dr. S. G. Lane, G. W. Welsh,
                        W. Clugston, S. G. Barnes.</p>

                    <p>The different secret societies and the citizens generally are cordially
                        invited to appear in the procession, and to take part in the ceremonies of
                        the day.</p>

                    <p>The following circular has been addressed especially to the ladies:<lb/>
                        "Strew Garlands of Flowers around each sleeping Hero's Grave."</p>

                    <p>IN MEMORIAM</p>

                    <p><emph rend="italics">To the Ladies of Chambersburg:</emph> At a meeting of
                        the soldiers of the Borough of Chambersburg, held on Monday evening, May
                        16th, the undersigned were appointed a committee to invite the ladies to
                        join with them in procuring flowers for the purpose of strewing the graves
                        of those of our soldiers who sleep in our midst. The committee remember with
                        gratitude and pleasure your noble response on former occasions, and take the
                        method of reminding you at the return of the annual decoration day,
                        believing that this alone will be necessary to insure a liberal donation of
                        choice flowers and <orig reg="bouquets">boquets</orig>. The living comrades
                        of our gallant dead desire to make the coming occasion one of peculiar
                        interest. They realize that one after another the years are settling down
                        over their passionless mounds and over the events which called so many of
                        them from life to death - hence they believe that on each successive
                        occasion redoubled efforts should be made to keep alive the memory of their
                        invaluable services.</p>

                    <p>"A debt of gratitude we own<lb/> To them is justly due,<lb/> And till our
                        nation's latest day,<lb/> Our children's children still shall say,<lb/> They
                        died for me and you."</p>

                    <p>T. J. Grimason,<lb/> Geo. W. Skinner, Com.<lb/> T. M. Mahon.</p>

                    <p>Contributions of flowers may be left at Repository Hall, between the hours of
                        8 and 12 A.M., on Monday, May 30.</p>

                    <p>Col. Theodore M'Gowan, chief Marshal, has appointed as his side Capt. G. W.
                        Skinner, Sergt. John A. Seiders, Lieut. G. F. Platt, Lieut. Geo. W. Welsh.</p>

                    <p>The procession will form in front of the Court House, at 3 o'clock, on Monday
                        afternoon next, and move off in two detachments, one to decorate all graves
                        south of Market street and the other all North of Market street, when they
                        will join in the Diamond and proceed to the cemetery, where the oration will
                        be delivered.</p>

                    <p>The procession will then countermarch to the Court House and be dismissed.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampler</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platte</ln>
                        <fn>G. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swert</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donavin</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shinafield</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimason</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>G. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article reports the formation of committees for the upcoming
                    Decoration Day celebrations and invites the ladies of Chambersburg to join in
                    decorating the graves of the fallen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Base Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Case</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hastings</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shook</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreps</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robeson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreichbaum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A baseball match was played between the Osceola Nine and Academy Nine of
                    Chambersburg, resulting in a victory for the academy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob S. Brown died at his residence in Chambersburg after suffering a
                    lingering illness. Brown served as sheriff and deputy sheriff before resigning
                    due to ill health. He was burried in Cedar Grove Cemetery. The Order of Odd
                    Fellows, of which he was a member, led the ceremonies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Elwain</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. M'Elwain is offering teacher preparation courses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper notes that many veterans are clerks and mechanics, and asks that
                    employers excuse them to participate in Memorial Day ceremonies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The soldiers and citizens of Greenvillage are invited to attend the
                    Decoration of Soldiers' Graves on May 30th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.05.25.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
