
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.06.08">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-06-08">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>08</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.08.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.08.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Antrim All Right</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>From Antrim township our neighbor, the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>,
                        last week received the first public endorsement of his "white man's party"
                        policy. The endorsement was full and hearty, so emphatically so that it even
                        transcended the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>'s demands, and called
                        from that journal a mild and gentle qualification as to some of its
                        sentiments. We regret that the entirely of its approval to this
                        communication should have been marred by its conservatism on this question,
                        because we were pleased to believe that in behalf of those Democrats who are
                        just now seeking political offices by deceiving the people the <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph> was prepared to go the whole hog. But our
                        admiration and praise must not be <orig reg="withheld">witheld</orig> from
                        the writer, who takes care to guard his readers from any error they might
                        fall into as to the kind of animal he might be taken for, by subscribing
                        himself WHITE MAN. It is settled on his own authority that he is a white
                        man, and if the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> did not go the whole hog,
                        the same objection does not hold against him. He not only went the whole hog
                        and a pig or two better, but a whole herd of whole hogs. In the extremity of
                        his great concern for the white race it is true he inadvertently disclosed
                        the cause which nerved him to resist the progress of the negro, and though
                        it seems to us that we have seen the same thing before, it does not render
                        as indifferent to his appeal. No man has a right to dispute it when this
                        writer tells us that he fears the advancement of the negro. It may be
                        humiliating, nevertheless true. We are pained to hear it yet we believe him.
                        He feels that in the race for supremacy, since all shackles are broken, and
                        manhood and intellect in a black casket count for as much as these qualities
                        do when bound up in a white epidermis, he is bound to be hopefully
                        distanced; and this is what is the matter. Hence he calls upon all white men
                        to come to his rescue. We entreat them to come.</p>

                    <p>Though he still has faith in Providence that He will not suffer him to be
                        surpassed by the hated and despised African, it is not that faith which
                        removes mountains. He believes that "the distinction which God and nature
                        have irrevocably fixed between us and them will not so soon give way to the
                        accursed doctrine of training us and our offspring up for the companionship
                        of the sooty African." But if the great God has made it irrevocable, why
                        should it, or how could it, give way at all? Evidently he has not the
                        confidence in the "irrevocable distinction" himself which a true believer
                        ought to have. But from metaphysics he turns to sentiment, and here is he
                        strong, he is in his true sphere. He don't trust Providence, but he knows,
                        what he wants. Says he "we want him below us, or above us, but not with us."
                        How about the irrevocable distinction now? After all, this "want" is not so
                        very unreasonable. It has two tails, either one of which will suit "the
                        subscriber," and if he is just willing to have a little patience natural
                        causes will soon bring it about. In his individual case we have no doubt the
                        negro will be obliging enough to go above him, if he is not already there.
                        There is no danger, my dear, distressed friend, that he will be "with you"
                        very long. "Giving him the ballot," says our <emph rend="italics">white
                        man</emph> "is a heavy trend on a tender spot in our body politic." How
                        sweetly and yet with what an injured innocence this is put. It was a regular
                        elephant's tread upon the sorest of Democratic corns, and Oh! how it made
                        the animal howl, and how, he continues to howl in his impotent rage. Though
                        this exquisitely illogical <emph rend="italics">white man</emph> had just
                        agreed that the negro might be above him, he now advises the <emph
                            rend="italics">Spirit</emph> to pull him down. Says he "we must lend no
                        assistance to radicalism under any guise, <emph rend="italics">by
                            contributing to the education of the freedmen, so called. We must make
                            no clubs to break our own heads with</emph>."</p>

                    <p>Why here is a man to be admired. He feels that the negro is his superior and
                        he is ingenuous enough to say so. He wants to keep the negro below himself,
                        and knowing that it cannot be done by fair means he advises that it be done
                        by foul. He is not any worse than the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> to
                        which he writes, but he has less cunning and deception. How simple his plan,
                        if it could not be carried out. "We must not contribute to the education of
                        the negro. We will keep him in ignorance and then we will be able to keep
                        him under us. <emph rend="italics">We must make no clubs to break our own
                            heads with</emph>." And this Democracy in the year of our Lord 1870. We
                        send men and money to Europe, Asia and Africa, and to all the islands of the
                        oceans to educate and Christianize the inhabitants thereof, and we are
                        Americans: we live in the land of the free, the home of the brave. But we
                        must not educate the negro, him whom we enslaved for two centuries, and for
                        which sin the God whom this writer dares to charge with having made the
                        negro to be his slaves, has punished us with an awful punishment. And yet we
                        boast of our civilization, we boast of our liberty, and many of us do not
                        forget to pray that they may be extended over the whole world.</p>

                    <p>But we can pursue this no further. It is true, as put in the polished terms
                        of the writer, that "a learned nigger will be a learned enemy in the hands
                        of radicalism." He will perforce be the enemy of ignorance and bigotry, and
                        so long as the class of which the writer is a fair specimen exists, he is
                        bound to be a club powerful for breaking it in pieces. Alas for the
                        political party which must build its house upon such a foundation as that
                        laid down in the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>'s communication.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial assails the arguments of a man who published his thoughts in
                    the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph> and advocated resistance to freedmen's
                    education.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper scoffs at Democratic attempts to woo white Republican voters.
                    "The more hostile Democrats become to the colored voters the more marked is
                    their affection for white Republicans." Still, they never offer them any
                    decision-making power within the party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper condemns Democrats for withholding education from African
                    Americans in an attempt "to keep the negro down." "If all other marks of
                    distinction fail, Democrats might adopt the wearing of badges marked WHITE MAN.
                    That would always distinguish them from negroes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper mocks Democrats for asserting racial inequality while fearing
                    black citizens might "get above them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Appointment of Assessor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morganthal</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sowers</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Max</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter asserts that the Democratic board of commissioners followed
                    precedent in appointing Republican George Foreman to take the place of departing
                    Republican Capt. John Doebler. Republican controlled bodies did the same in
                    Montgomery, Waynesboro, Guilford, and Southampton when appointing James B.
                    Robison, John M'Laughlin, George Morganthal, H. C. Sowers, and Max Kennedy to
                    replace Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.08.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Interesting Masonic Dedication Ceremonies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brawor</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. G. W. Brawor attended ceremonies in Carlisle for dedicating a new
                    Masonic Lodge in that town. He was appointed Grand Steward of the event.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Memorial Day in Greenvillage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>A correspondent furnishes the following:</p>

                    <p>The afternoon of the 30th of May was spent by our ladies in making wreaths of
                        evergreen and gathering flowers to decorate the graves of our noble dead,
                        who sleep in the old Methodist <orig reg="graveyard">grave yard</orig> in
                        this place. The hour of meeting, 6 o'clock, P.M., was announced by the
                        ringing of the bell, when the citizens repaired to the <orig reg="graveyard"
                            >grave yard</orig>. A requiem.</p>

                    <p>"Toll the bell, the brave are sleeping."<lb/> was sung in very fine style by
                        Misses Sue Maner, Sallie Embich, Sallie Howe and Lizzie Wallace assisted by
                        Messrs Ditzler, Miller and Wallace. During the singing, beautiful wreaths of
                        evergreen wild flowers, and laurel, were hung upon the tombstone of each
                        soldier's grave, and a small flag fastened to the wreath, there to wave and
                        keep a lonely vigil over the sleeping warrior, as he lies "taking his rest."
                        After these solemnities were ended, for they required some time, some of the
                        graves being literally covered with bouquets and flowers, Prof. J. A. Miller
                        delivered a very fine and appropriate address. After which the spectators
                        slowly retired.</p>

                    <p>Left to our own meditation, we thought of the dear ones who took part with us
                        in like solemnities just one year ago, whose hands planted some of those
                        little flags that still wave above the grass. We turned to see them once
                        again, and we heard the mournful echoes say, "passed away!" "passed away!"
                        The tuneful voice of our dear old Preacher is no longer heard in the closing
                        benediction, while among the tombs we dropped a tear to the memory of Lieut.
                        Abram G. Over, Sergt. Lewis Rinehart, Foster and Immell, whose forms are
                            <orig reg="moldering">mouldering</orig> into dust in some unknown spot,
                        where no friend, can scatter flowers, or drop a tear of sympathy over their
                        lonely graves.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maner</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyer</ln>
                        <fn>Abram G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A correspondent reports on the Memorial (Decoration) Day ceremonies in
                    Greenvillage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Chambersburg was teeming with street performers last week, including a
                    remarkable mathematician, two organ grinders, and a man dispensing candy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreichbaum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuckman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiffer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heefner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grier</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wetzel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A game of baseball was played on May 30th between the Athletic and
                    Printer's Nines of Chambersburg. Athletic won, and also defeated a team from
                    Guilford in a second match.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>J. H. Cruzen of the American Tract Society is visiting the towns along the
                    Cumberland Valley Railroad to furnish Sunday Schools with books and
                    publications. The society offers publications to students, pastors, and schools
                    at a 10% discount. The paper provides a schedule of his appearances throughout
                    Franklin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lt. Col. Henry C. Hodges, Quartermaster of the U.S. Army, is soliciting
                    information relative to the graves of Union officers and soldiers burried
                    throughout Pennsylvania. Franklin County citizens are urged to help.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An agent of the Franklin County Bible Society visited Chambersburg during
                    May. He met with 481 families and found 47 destitute of bibles. One hotel needed
                    15 bibles for its rooms. He found 67 families not connected with any church, and
                    their names were forwarded to ministers in the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. P. S. Davis will read an essay on flowers at the Horticultural
                    Festival in Repository Hall on Friday. The lecture has received high praise in
                    the past.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Ladies' Improvement Society of the First M. E. Church held a successful
                    festival in Repository Hall on Friday. The event raised $227.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Meeting of the County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Republican County Committee met on Saturday. The date of the county
                    convention was set for the first Tuesday in August.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Internal Revenue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George J. Balsley, Deputy Collector of Internal Revenue for Franklin, will
                    receive taxes on annual income and special taxes on business and professions in
                    Chambersburg between June 14th and 18th. All licenses must be paid at this time
                    as well. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Merrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward and Merrick Stoner, two young boys whose father died during the war,
                    led the procession as part of decoration ceremonies in M'Connellsburg. One
                    played the fife and the other the drum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Anniversary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Kearney Lodge No. 159, Knights of Pythias, will celebrate their first
                    anniversary on Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. J. T. Wright has returned to Chambersburg and will be offering
                    classes in vocal and instrumental music. He is staying at the residence of Rev.
                    W. G. Hawkins.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbery</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbery</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elias Rosenbery and Miss Lizzie Carter, both of Horse Valley, were married
                    on May 26th at the residence of Benjamin Rosenbery by the Rev. A. E. Fulton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.08.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
