
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.08.03">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/05/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-08-03">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>03</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.08.03.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.08.03.02" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>We place at the head of the editorial page of this issue the ticket put in
                        nomination at the County Convention yesterday. As the paper really goes to
                        press on Tuesday evening, immediately after the adjournment of the
                        convention, though dated on Wednesday, there is no time to make any comments
                        upon the candidates put in nomination. This must be deferred to our next
                        issue, when each one will receive a due share of our attention. The only
                        important county offices to be filled this fall, to which we referred at
                        some length when speaking of the County Convention, are County Commissioner
                        and Director of the Poor. For each of these a good and unexceptionable man
                        has been chosen, and it only remains for the Republicans of Franklin county
                        to say whether they shall be elected, and <orig reg="inaugurate"
                        >inaugerate</orig> a reign of economy and honesty where the Democratic party
                        by the election of unworthy men have introduced profligacy and dishonesty.
                        The Democracy have done all in their power to render their management of the
                        affairs of the county odious, and to bring reproach and shame upon
                        themselves. Let us take advantage of this condition of things, and by a
                        strong and united effort hurl them from the places they have disgraced. Look
                        at the rapidly accumulating expenses of the Poor House. See the jobs of the
                        Commissioners. The Democracy have elected men to these places who use them
                        for themselves and their party, not for the people. They must be removed,
                        and better, worthier, <orig reg="more honest">honester</orig> men put in
                        their places. Such men the the Republican Convention has nominated. See that
                        they are not defeated. The choice of Franklin County for Assembly will be
                        accepted by Perry as one of the two Republican candidates to be voted for in
                        the District. Perry will nominate the other. We will give due consideration
                        to the merits of our candidate in the next issue.</p>

                    <p>For Congress it has not ever been questioned that Hon. John Cessna would
                        receive a unanimous <orig reg="renomination">re-nomination</orig>. He has
                        served his constituency with such zeal and industry for their interests, and
                        has taken such an honorable place among the leaders of the party in the
                        House that many of those who were averse to his nomination two years ago are
                        earnest advocates for it now. He is without doubt stronger in his district
                        now than he was then, and has besides won a national reputation as an
                        advanced Republican and an able parliamentarian. He is keenly alive to the
                        interests of Pennsylvania, and can do more to protect her mining and
                        manufacturing interests from the assaults of the free traders than any other
                        man in the district. His reelection is believed to be beyond peradventure.</p>

                    <p>As the Republicans of Somerset, Bedford and Fulton counties had <orig
                            reg="instructed">instruced</orig> their conferees to vote for his
                        renomination previous to our county convention, thus giving him a majority
                        of the counties of the district, it will hardly be deemed necessary for the
                        conferees to meet in convention. A telegraphic <orig reg="dispatch"
                        >despatch</orig> from the conferees of each county would be sufficient to
                        settle the whole matter.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article encourages Franklin County citizens to vote for the Republican
                    nominees for local office and also praises Congressional representative, John
                    Cessna.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.08.03.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Visit to Rocky Spring Church--A Historical Spot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"J.P.W." writes the paper to deliver an account of an excursion by a number
                    of young ladies and gentlemen from Greenvillage to Rocky Spring "beneath the
                    shadows of the old church." The author notes that a number of the excursionists
                    were descendents of the original members of the church congregation. This
                    prompts a nostalgic account of area history.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>On Saturday last two lads, about fourteen years of age, the one white and the
                        other colored, became involved in a quarrel near the corner of Front and
                        Washington streets, which came near resulting seriously to one of the
                        parties. The white boy is a son of Mr. Jacob Huber, of the Union Hotel, and
                        the colored boy is named Stevenson. From what we can learn the quarrel was
                        caused by the white lad calling the other names, and expressing a desire to
                        whip him. The colored boy, who pursues the humble occupation of a boot
                        black, was not unwilling to gratify so becoming a desire, but claiming the
                        privilege of the challenged party chose a neighboring alley as the place for
                        the <orig reg="reencounter">rencounter</orig>. To this the white boy
                        objected, and after considerable talk on both sides the other took up the
                        tools of his trade to depart. While in the act of doing this the white boy
                        struck him a blow on the head, but whether with his fist or with something
                        else seems to be disputed. This was the signal for a free fight. The boys
                        went for each other, and after fighting for a minute or so separated and
                        each seized stones. The colored boy was first to get a stone, and struck his
                        opponent on the temple inflicting a severe wound, and knocking him
                        senseless. It was half an hour or more before he became conscious, and
                        considerable fear was expressed that the blow might prove fatal.</p>

                    <p>It is unfortunate that such disgraceful scenes should ever happen on our
                        streets, but they do sometimes occur, and sometimes when those who have had
                        the better training and advantages are in the wrong. It seems to have been
                        so here. The white boy we fear was the aggressor, and apparently for no
                        better reason than that the other was a "nigger." Some other disturbances
                        grew out of this quarrel which did not reflect much credit on the white
                        persons engaged in it, but it seems when the races come in conflict white
                        people are hardly expected to act calmly and <orig reg="dispassionately"
                            >dispasisonately</orig>.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article reports that a fight broke out between two teenagers - one
                    black, one white - and notes that some "other disturbances grew out of this
                    quarrel which did not reflect much credit on the white persons engaged in it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagner</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagner</ln>
                        <fn>I. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Camp Meeting of the Carlisle District began today at Red Barn station.
                    Participants have erected 250 tents on the grounds. Religious exercises will
                    begin at 3:00 and continue to the close of the camp. Rev. Dr. Mitchell,
                    presiding elder of the district, is in charge. Postmaster Seiders of
                    Chambersburg will establish a post office at the camp and mail trains will visit
                    each day. D.K. and I.C. Wagner of the Shippensburg News will publish a daily
                    paper at the camp entitled Camp Journal. Subscriptions are 25 cents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Improvements in Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William McClintock has begun work on a vacant lot between Paxton's Hat and
                    Shoe Store and A. J. Miller's Drug Store on the Diamond. D. S. Fahnestock has
                    removed the old building from the lot opposite W. L. Chambers and is beginning
                    construction on the same site. Col. Elder is repairing and beautifying his
                    residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Interesting Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwaine</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A lecture on capital punishment will be delivered in the Court House on
                    Thursday by A. McElwaine. Admission is 25 cents, and the proceeds will go to
                    liquidate the debt of the Bethel Church of God.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mercersburg Post Office has been made a money order office by the
                    Postal Department. This will greatly convenience the citizens of Mercersburg who
                    do not now have a bank.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Balloon Ascension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Light</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Light will ascend from a balloon before crowds in Shippensburg on
                    August 4th. A special excursion train will run from Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gov. Geary has reappointed and commissioned Thomas Carlisle as a Notary
                    Public.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William Paxton, an "eminent clergyman of the Presbyterian Church,"
                    visited Greencastle last week. He began his career as a minister in that town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Longnecker</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah A. Longnecker of Cumberland County and Miss Rebecca Burkholder of
                    Guilford were married in July 21st in the parsonage in Upper Strasburg by the
                    Rev. A. H. Sheets.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latus</ln>
                        <fn>Julia Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latus</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latus</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Julia Kate Latus, daughter of Michael and Catharine Latus, died in
                    Chambersburg of cholera infantum on August 1st. She was 7 1/2 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.08.03.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
