
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1870/pa.fr.fr.1870.06.22">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/03/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1870-06-22">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.22.01" exists="no">



            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.22.02" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.22.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sales of the Wilson College Property Last Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The property remaining unsold at the close of the sale of the previous week
                        was mainly disposed of during last week at private sale, so that when
                        Friday, the day fixed for the adjourned sale, arrived there were only a few
                        lots left unsold. Among the purchasers at private sale are Dr. Senseny who
                        bought Numbers 11 and 12 along the turnpike for $900. Rev. Roth, lot No. 46
                        about an acre and a half, at $200 per acre. The two tracks along the
                        turnpike, about 15 acres, including the Grapery and other improvements were
                        purchased by Jacob Zook for $4500. Lots No. 13 and 14 on the turnpike and
                        running back to the C. V. R. R., containing between 19 and 20 acres, were
                        sold to John Weaver for $4500.</p>

                    <p>There still remain two lots in front and one in the rear unsold, but offers
                        have been made for them which will very likely be taken. this is in all
                        respects a very satisfactory sale of ground, and its success is greatly
                        owing to the skill and judgment of those who had it in charge. About 67
                        acres were disposed of, realizing in the aggregate $18,000. The three lots
                        still to sell will bring it above $19,000. This transaction solves the
                        question of the Wilson College. The trustees intend to begin the erection of
                        an additional building for the use of pupils at once, and propose to open
                        the college for pupils the 1st of October next. This is a matter of great
                        importance to Chambersburg, and her citizens should give all the
                        encouragement and assistance in their power. This section of the State needs
                        a first class college for young ladies, our citizens need it for their
                        children, and the town needs it for its own prosperity and for the
                        improvement it will bring in general intelligence and morals. Let us all
                        strive to make it a success.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This report notes the success of recent land sales and encourages people to
                    support Wilson College.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Public Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The public schools of Chambersburg have completed their term for the year
                    1869. Mr. Hockenberry examined the Male High School and Mr. Gaff examined the
                    Female High School. The schools impressed the examiners. Miss Sarah E. Reynolds
                    led the opening exercises that included a song of welcome sung by a class of
                    young ladies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Judge James O. Carson died on Wednesday at his residence in Mercersburg. He
                    suffered a long illness and had been confined to his chamber for one year. He
                    was 76 years old. The Franklin County native was a well-known and respected
                    citizen. "Intelligent and earnest in his own convictions, he was liberal to
                    those of others, so that those who differed most widely from him in their views
                    never denied him their respect. His strict integrity, excellent judgement and
                    kind disposition made him a trusted friend and counsellor of many."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Organs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curriden</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>E. W. Curriden is Chambersburg agent for the renowned Mason and Hamlin
                    Organ Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The annual assessment of internal revenue taxes for the 16th district has
                    been published. The total amounted to $41,649.72 including $27,570.00 on
                    licenses, $13,104.62 on incomes, and $634.40 on watches, carriages, and silver
                    plate. The 16th district includes Adams, Franklin, Fulton, Bedford, and Somerset
                    Counties. Franklin payed nearly half the entire assessment, a total of
                    $19,604.87.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Young Folk's Singing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Young Folk's Singing Class of Scotland, directed by Prof. T. L. Budd,
                    gave a concert recently. The editors praise the group made up of children
                    between the ages of ten and fourteen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Interesting Occasion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The annual exhibition of the Chambersburg Academy will be held in
                    Repository Hall on Friday. Students will deliver orations and perform music, all
                    under the direction of Prof. Shumaker. The editors promise the work will equal
                    the quality of many colleges.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls attention to Chambersburg's need of a good bath house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn>Johnny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seidenstricker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Lantz and Mr. Unger purchased the Franklin Club Rooms from Mr. A.
                    Seidenstricker. Johnny Lantz runs the popular restaurant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rev. Joseph A. Seiss of Philadelphia will preach in the Lutheran Church on
                    Sunday. Rev. J. Donahue will preach in the M. E. Church on the Resurrection.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Schofield and Miss Catharine Kohler, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on May 9th by the Rev. I. N. Hays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>Katie May</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>P. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>Annie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Katie May Jacobs, infant daughter of P. W. and Annie M. Jacobs, died on
                    June 14th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heart</ln>
                        <fn>J. Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Milton Heart died in Chambersburg on June 17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1870.06.22.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
