<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.08.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/2/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-08-11">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="11">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.08.11.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>What It Takes to Make A Lady?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When Beau Brummel was asked what it took to make gentlemen, his quick reply
                        was, "Starch, Starch, my lord!" This may be true; but it takes a great deal
                        more to make a lady; and though it may seem singular, I am ready to maintain
                        that no conceivable quantity of muslin, silk or satin, edging, trilling,
                        hooping, flouncing or furbelowing, can <emph rend="italic">per se</emph> or
                        per dress maker, constitute a real lady. Was not Mrs. Abbott Lawrence just
                        as much a lady when attired in twelve-cent calico, in Boston, as when
                        arrayed in full court dress at St. James' London? "As Mrs. Washington was
                        said to be so grand a lady," says a celebrated English visitor (Mrs Thorpe,)
                        "we thought we must put on our best bids and bands; so we dressed ourselves
                        in our most elegant ruffles and silks, and were introduced to her ladyship:
                        and don't you think we found her knitting, and with her check apron on! She
                        received us very graciously and easily; but after the compliments were over
                        she resumed her knitting. There we were, without a stitch of work, and
                        sitting in state; but General Washington's lady, with her own hands was
                        knitting stockings for her husband!" Does not that sweet republican
                        simplicity command your admiration?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that expensive or fashionable clothing does not
                    necessarily "make a lady" in a republican society.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.08.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We notice, in preambulating the streets of Staunton, a considerable awakening
                        among the business portion of our community. Some of our Dry Goods, Grocery
                        and Hardware Merchants are receiving stocks of new goods, others are
                        brushing up preparatory to receiving their new assortments. The Tobacconists
                        have fine stocks and boast that they are old ones. The Confectioners are
                        exhibiting a tempting lot of fresh candies, fruits, &amp;c. The
                        Druggists have on hand, or are ready to prepare, at short notice, any
                        compound needful to kill or cure. Physicians, Surgeons and Dentists are in
                        readiness at all times to prescribe for a patient, amputate a limb or
                        extract a tooth. Lawyers are as abundant as necessary, but fortunately there
                        are no courts to practice in. The Mechanics have brushed off the dust of
                        four year's idleness and are ready to split a match or peg, "steel" their
                        patrons work, build or repair a house or carriage, mend a coat or make you a
                        sole or coffin. And last but not least, the millinery establishments abound
                        with--we don't know whether it is fine, elegant, exquisite, or what sort
                        of--"what do you call 'ems!", but the fabrics are there in all their
                        gorgeous, crimped and crumpled brilliancy, with such a lot of customers!
                        Well if we don't know what to call the fabrics we know the customers are
                        beautiful. We wish we were not a bachelor, we could then drop in, with some
                        sort of show, to look at the--no not the "what do you call 'ems"--but the
                        "stray angels."</p>
                    <p>We thought we had a good thing of it the other day--we had a bill against one
                        of these establishments and dropped in to collect the amount--no, that
                        wasn't it, but to see the throng of beauties, but the lady proprietress was
                        too polite to detain us and paid us instanter. We expected her to ask us to
                        wait awhile and then invite us to call again and she would settle, but she
                        wouldn't. Wonder if she treats married gentlemen as she treated us. We
                        wouldn't be a bachelor a day longer if we could help it. Won't somebody give
                        us the agency of a sewing machine?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial discusses a perceived "awakening" of business in Staunton.
                    The shops are stocked with merchandise, and doctors, lawyers and artisans are
                    ready to return to work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that the Adam's Express Company can be used to ship
                    "freight, monies and parcels to any portion of the Country" at "liberal rates."
                    Interested persons should contact the company's Staunton agent, Mr. R. Hawkins.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that H. H. Peck, "our enterprising fellow-citizen" has
                    "leased the Gas Works and will shortly supply the people of Staunton with more
                    light."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>To the Justices of the County Court of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter, signed "One Who Knows," recommends that G. A. Bruce, Esq., of
                    Waynesboro be elected Presiding Justice. The author declares that Bruce "is a
                    gentleman of sound practical sense, possesses a discriminating mind, quick
                    perception, and whose character for honesty, morality and integrity is without
                    spot or blemish," and will "discharge the duties of the office with strict
                    fidelity and impartiality."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Chapman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hudson</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces the results of the Staunton municipal elections. They
                    were as follows: N. K. Trout, Mayor; James F. Patterson, Clerk; Chapman Johnson,
                    Commonwealth's Attorney; George H. Hudson, Commissioner of the Revenue; Jacob F.
                    Parent, Sergeant; W. B. Kayser, B. F. Points, D. C. McGuffin, W. L. Balthis, J.
                    B. Scherer, J. M. Hardy, W. H. Wilson, J. W. Crawford, R. J. Hope, A. M. Bruce,
                    and J. B. Evans, Councilmen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
