<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.10.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/11/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-10-06">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="06">06</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.10.06.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.10.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In this, our last issue before the election, which takes place on the 12th
                        inst., we cannot refrain from calling the attention of our readers to its
                        importance. The members of the Legislature to be elected will go there,
                        either clothed with conventional powers (by the voice of the people,) to
                        change the present proscriptive clause of the Constitution, so as to allow
                        all former citizens to be elected and to hold office, or merely to sit as a
                        Legislative body, without the authority to relieve a number of good and
                        reliable men from a burdensome proscription. We do not hesitate to assert
                        our belief that the vast majority of the people of Virginia will vote wisely
                        and confer the authority upon the Legislature to repeal the proscriptive
                        clause.</p>
                    <p>While this is of importance, the question involved in the Congressional
                        election is of more momentous consequence to us at present. We know the
                        people of the South to be loyal and desirous of so acting as to secure the
                        best interests of the States and the Union. They desire earnestly a speedy
                        restoration of the Union. The great obstacle to the attainment of this end,
                        to some, seems to be the "Test Oath" which is required to be taken by all
                        the members elect to Congress before taking their seats. We do not conceive
                        that the probability of this oath's being required to be taken, or the
                        question of its unconstitutionality, has much to do with the coming
                        election.</p>
                    <p>Some of our Northern exchanges say, that, whether our Representatives can or
                        cannot take the oath prescribed, it is the settled policy of the Radicals,
                        who had a majority in the last Congress, to prevent, if possible, any
                        Southern State from being represented in the next Congress, and that it is
                        likely that the moderate Republicans will act with the conservatives on this
                        issue, and thus throw the majority in favor of the Conservatives, which will
                        result in an early repeal of the "Test Oath." Others say, while the
                        Republican Conventions of some of the Northern States have endorsed the
                        policy of President Johnson, that it was done in order not to break with him
                        at once, that they are now waiting and arming for the great fight in
                        Congress, and that the "Test Oath" required will be finally adhered to.</p>
                    <p>We give the above views to the one or the other of which most of our Northern
                        exchanges lean, with the desire that our readers may know the sentiments of
                        the Conservative Northern press on this subject.</p>
                    <p>From all we can gather we incline to the belief that the action of the
                        Radicals will not turn on the "Test Oath," but with the fear of losing the
                        preponderance in Congress, by the admission of Conservatives from the South,
                        they will endeavor by all possible means, to prevent the South's admission
                        to the Union by a representation in the next Congress, and especially on the
                        ground that the South is conquered territory and should be ruled as such.</p>
                    <p>Whether it would be better to have the door of Congress slapped in the face
                        of representatives who can take the oath or those who cannot take it, we
                        opine, is in reality the question for our people to determine. We know that
                        they will endeavor to act for the best interest of the State and Republic
                        and we trust that they, by their votes, will aid in strengthening the
                        President and the Conservatives, who are the only real Union men in the
                        country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reminds Augusta citizens of the importance of the upcoming
                    elections. It hopes that in the elections for Congress the voters "will aid in
                    strengthening the President and the Conservatives, who are the only real Union
                    men in the country" despite threats from radicals that no southern
                    representatives will be seated. The editors urge that in the state elections,
                    the voters send representatives authorized to "change the present proscriptive
                    clause of the Constitution, so as to allow all former citizens to be elected and
                    to hold office."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tournament at New Hope</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Friday last, Sept. 20th, the quiet village of New Hope was the scene of an
                        animated and brilliant Tournament. A large number of spectators, of all
                        ages, sexes and conditions, assembled together from various quarters of the
                        county, and manifested, during the day, the liveliest interest in the
                        performances. At 10 o'clock A. M., about forty Knights, composed of the
                        flower of our youth, elegantly mounted and handsomely decorated in trimmings
                        and colors, were drawn up in line-of-battle by the Marshall, and on
                        invitation extended by committee, Howe Y. Peyton, Esq., of Staunton, came
                        forward and spoke as follows:</p>
                    <p>Sir Knights:--The manly sports, with which you are about to celebrate this
                        day, are associated with some of the most stirring reminiscences of the
                        Twelfth century and are beginning to excite in the minds of our own people
                        an absorbing and romantic interest, which may well justify their being
                        conducted, in the future, upon a larger and more splendid scale. The
                        memorable wars of the Crusades, which engrossed the attention of all Europe
                        for two centuries, and which resulted in the disenthrallment of the human
                        mind from the bondage of a long dark night of a thousand years, gave birth
                        to the sacred order of Knighthood, from whence sprang that spirit of
                        chivalry which has filled the world with stories of wild adventure; produced
                        examples of heroic self-sacrificing devotion, never before surpassed, and
                        furnished to the Historian, the Novelist and the Bard an exhaustless theme
                        for immortal labors. If it be your purpose to establish in West Augusta the
                        ancient order of Knighthood, my warmest sympathies are with you and whatever
                        counsel or assistance, I can give, shall be cheerfully placed at your
                        command. There is nothing in such an Institution at all hostile to the
                        spirit of the age, nor inconsistent with the character of a christian and a
                        gentleman; but much to kindle in your breasts a generous emulation to rival
                        the simple virtues of your ancestors and to attain the excellence of
                        conforming to all that is sublime in religion and beautiful in morality. The
                        idea of a true Knight is inseparably connected with that of a high-toned
                        gentleman; and this term, in its modern signification, implies all that is
                        noble, generous and chivalric in man. Truth, justice, honor, patriotism,
                        sympathy for the bereaved, charity for the poor, respect and tenderness for
                        women, admiration for the true, the beautiful and the good are the noble
                        characteristics of Knighthood and the crowning glory of its votaries.</p>
                    <p>It is needless, Sir Knights, to prolong these remarks to stimulate your ardor
                        on this [unclear] an eloquence in the scene around you which words can never
                        describe. The gray haired sires and the noble matrons of Augusta have
                        assembled from far and near to behold your feats of horsemanship--the bright
                        eyes of Virginia's loveliest daughters are watching you with eager interest
                        and some fond heart is surely throbbing for every lance within the lists.
                        The memory of the trials and hardships you have endured and the magnificent
                        deeds of daring which signalized your conduct during the mighty revolution,
                        which has just swept over the land, will be vividly recalled by this day's
                        exercises and as you may spur your steeds forward, with the confident
                        assurance, that the sympathies of this great audience are with you and that
                        every honor will be gladly extended to your victorious Knights.</p>
                    <p>Thanking you for the attention with which you have listened to these crude
                        remarks, I may, in conclusion, express the hope that it may be vouchsafed to
                        him, whose heart glows fiercest with the immortal fires of love, to reap the
                        first honors of this day's labors and crown, with his own hands, the "Queen
                        of Love and Beauty."</p>
                    <p>After the conclusion of Mr. Peyton's remarks, the equestrian exercises of the
                        day commenced. The very difficult feat of carrying off upon the point of a
                        spear, three separate rings hanging from different scaffoldings, about
                        thirty feet apart, was required and in consequence, thereof, it was late in
                        the evening before it could be determined who were the successful
                        contestants. Indeed, all of the Knights seemed to be perfectly at home in
                        the saddle and most of them were partially successful, but Mr. Crawford
                        Miller, was adjudged worthy of the highest honor and entitled to crown the
                        Queen of Love and Beauty. This he did in a modest and becoming manner,
                        selecting Miss Sally Crawford, as the recipient of his justly earned trophy
                        and crowning her Queen of the occasion, in the presence of the assembled
                        neighborhood. The second prize was awarded to Mr. DeWitt Turk, who selected
                        and crowned as the first Maid of Honor Miss M. E. Mowry. The remaining
                        honors were awarded to Messrs. Courtney Roler, Sandy Crawford, Asher Harman
                        and Frank Bell. Mr. Harman, crowning Miss Miller, Mr. Crawford, Miss M.
                        Miller, and Mr. Bell, Miss Sarah Crawford. After the ceremonies of the
                        coronation were concluded, the Queen, Knights, Lords, Ladies and attendants,
                        were ushered into a magnificent dining-room, formed by the hand of Nature
                        and partook of a simple but elegant feast, which had been hastily prepared
                        for the occasion. May there be many returns of such glorious holidays in our
                        midst.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Howe Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Crawford</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Sally</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>DeWitt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>M. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roler</ln>
                        <fn>Courtney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Sandy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Asher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports on a medieval tournament held at New Hope. Howe Y. Peyton
                    of Staunton delivered the opening remarks on the virtues of knighthood in the
                    modern age and the post-war era, which the paper reprints. Among other things,
                    he asserted that "the memory of the trials and hardships you have endured and
                    the magnificent deeds of daring which signalized your conduct during the mighty
                    revolution, which has just swept over the land, will be vividly recalled by this
                    day's exercises."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1865.10.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>National Bank in Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>Claiborne R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>Briscoe B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that since "the amount of stock necessary to the
                    establishment of a National Bank, in our town, having been taken, by a portion
                    of the citizens of Augusta" the stockholders met in the rooms of the late
                    Central Bank on September 23rd to elect bank directors. The following men were
                    chosen: Alexander H. H. Stuart, Charles T. Cochran, Hugh W. Sheffey, Claiborne
                    R. Mason, Briscoe B. Donaghe, William Allan, William H. Tams, James W. Crawford,
                    and M. G. Harman. Of those, Stuart was chosen President, Sheffey Vice President,
                    and Allan cashier. The paper praised the men as follows: "The gentlemen thus
                    selected as guardians of this institution are men of prominence and distinction
                    in this community, closely identified with the interests of our county, and
                    understand, fully, the wants and necessities of our people. We trust and believe
                    they will so manage the affairs of the Bank, as to satisfy the stockholders and
                    at the same time merit the approbation of the public generally.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Tournaments seem to be exceedingly popular in these peaceful times, quite an
                        interesting one came off at Madisonian Academy in this County, on Friday
                        evening last. The Knights were the pupils of the Academy, and unlike many of
                        the Knights of this season, did not ride but ran for the honors.</p>
                    <p>The Knight of the "Rebel Girl" Master O. Wellington Koiner, took the 1st
                        Honor having taken the ring five times, and crowned Miss Celestine Caldwell,
                        Queen of Love and Beauty.</p>
                    <p>The Knight of the "Bonnie Blue Flag" Master Harry M. Dold, took the 2nd Honor
                        and chose Miss Sallie M. Koiner 1st Maid of Honor.</p>
                    <p>The Knight of the "Southern Cross" Master John M. Koiner, took the 3d Honor
                        and chose Miss Sallie C. Reives 2d Maid of Honor.</p>
                    <p>The Knight of the "Flying Cloud," Master Arthur Z. Koiner took the 4th Honor
                        and chose Miss Emma C. McComb 3d Maid of Honor.</p>
                    <p>As a finale to the Tournament was a nicely gotten up Pic-nic, if we can judge
                        by the nice present of nick-nacks sent the Editor, which we enjoyed hugely.
                        We wish that the successful Knights may run the race of life as
                        successfully, taking honors in the broad fields of knowledge and literature
                        and be blessed in their swift career by the smiles of some chosen and
                        treasured fair one.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>O. Wellington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caldwell</ln>
                        <fn>Celestine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dold</ln>
                        <fn>Harry M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Sally M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reives</ln>
                        <fn>Sally C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Arthur Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McComb</ln>
                        <fn>Emma C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces the results of a tournament at the Madisonian Academy.
                    Such events "seem to be exceedingly popular in these peaceful times" the editors
                    remark. Many of the "Knights" competed under titles reminiscent of the
                    ex-Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perry</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summerson</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>G. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>O. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>J. I. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Jeff</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper lists the Augusta County residents recently pardoned by President
                    Johnson: J. C. Cochran, R. H. Dudley, Dr. B. B. Donaghe, W. C. Perry, N. K.
                    Trout, J. Wayt Bell, R. Summerson, W. W. Donaghe, G. M. Cochran, J. B. Evans, C.
                    R. Mason, O. C. Morris, John Newton, R. G. Bickle, A. H. Taylor, Hugh Guthrie,
                    Henry Eidson, C. C. Francisco, Thomas Johnston, J. I. A. Trotter, J. Trimble,
                    Jeff. Kinney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper thanks Mrs. Capt. C. G. Miller, from near Waynesboro, for a gift
                    of a 17 1/2 pound cabbage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hallman</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints a letter, signed by Justitia, supporting Justice of the
                    Peace B. F. Hallman as a candidate for the legislature. The author argues that
                    his election would be fair since "there has not been a representative from the
                    upper end of the county for many years." Justitia went on: "We are all nearly
                    ruined, and should have as representatives honest, sensible, practical, working
                    men, such as know the wants of the people in this our time of need."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1865.10.06.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
