<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1865/va.au.rv.1865.09.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/9/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1865-09-29">
            <year>1865</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="29">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.29.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Negro Suffrage</head>
                <origin>Logan Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The "local" of the Logan <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph> occasionally gets
                        off some good things. The following is one of his latest productions:</p>
                    <p>"Chalk and ivory! Heels and shins!"<lb/> Sambo's glory now begins!<lb/> Go
                        'way white man! You don't know<lb/> How to vote right--dat is so.<lb/> Yaw,
                        yaw, yaw!--Yaw, yaw, yaw!<lb/> De happiest day I eber saw!</p>
                    <p>"War's de tickets?--Fetch em straight!"<lb/> I votes early--I votes
                        late--<lb/> I votes often--I votes right--<lb/> I's no ignoramus
                        white--<lb/> Man and brudder--equal born--<lb/> De Maker's image (in a
                        horn!)<lb/> De glory ob de rising day;<lb/> De culled cuss from Africa!<lb/>
                        Oh, kinkey, minkey, stinky, oh!<lb/> If dis ain't glory, tell me so!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reprints a poem ridiculing the idea of voting rights for blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The condition of the freedmen of the Southern States has excited the sympathy
                        and interest of their former masters in no ordinary degree. They feel that,
                        unless some inducement to labor and to remain steadfast to their engagements
                        can be offered them, there must necessarily be great suffering among them
                        during the winter seasons. It is a problem how this anticipated unpleasant
                        condition of the freedmen can be avoided or averted. They do not seem to
                        believe themselves free until they have left their old masters to live with
                        new employers, without contracts, or, if made, to break them at pleasure,
                        and swallow with avidity the councils of strangers, while the healthy advice
                        of their old friends, to keep their faith inviolable and to fulfill their
                        contracts, even if not seemingly so advantageous as some new and luring
                        offer, in order to promote their future prosperity, is almost unheeded. We
                        believe that nothing can prevent suffering among them this winter, caused by
                        erroneous impressions received from new and professed friends. Experience,
                        however, will teach some that they must follow the example of the bee and
                        the ant to be either comfortable or happy in their new condition. Next to
                        experience, comes the improvement of the negro's mental and moral condition,
                        to render freedom any thing of a boon to him. The various churches of the
                        South, Methodist, Baptist, Presbyterian and Episcopalian, especially, are
                        turning their attention to this subject and exhibit, in their desire to
                        ameliorate the condition of the negro, by rendering him more fit to enjoy
                        the freedom thrust upon him, real philanthropy, which is in direct contrast
                        with the shallow pretences and heartless schemes of the abolitionists, whose
                        every step but adds to his embarrassment by bringing him in conflict with
                        his real friends, with whom there should be no conflict. They do not care so
                        their own plans for self aggrandizement are accomplished. To show the spirit
                        of the Southern people, as expressed by their churches, we give the report
                        adopted by the Episcopal convention which lately assembled in Richmond,
                        merely premising that late Presbyterian, Baptist and Methodist convenings
                        have taken somewhat similar action on the same subject.</p>
                    <p>"Recognizing the change in the social condition of the colored race, the
                        Church of Virginia desires to express her continued interest in the
                        welfare--both spiritual and temporal--of the freedmen scattered throughout
                        the Diocese; therefore</p>
                    <p>1. "<emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the clergy of the Diocese of
                        Va. pledge themselves to renewed efforts in the work of their religious
                        instruction by preaching, Sunday school efforts, and every other available
                        means that may contribute to their moral and religious well-being.</p>
                    <p>2. "<emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the laity of the Diocese will
                        co-operate with their pastors, and as far as practicable, both in the Sunday
                        school and at home, give particular attention to their mental as well as
                        religious instruction.</p>
                    <p>3. "<emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That, as one of the means for the
                        accomplishment of the above purpose, the establishment of parochial schools
                        be recommended."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper expresses concern that the freedmen will suffer from poverty and
                    exposure over the winter. The editors posit that this condition stems from the
                    freedmen's willingness to listen to "false friends" and leave the plantations
                    and homes of their former masters in search of better work. The paper urges them
                    to remain faithful to their old masters, and applauds the initiatives southern
                    churches have taken in providing them with religious instruction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Slowly but surely has President Johnson pursued his policy for the
                        restoration of the Union, nor, whether attempted to be cajoled by sickly
                        adulation, or dragooned by menaces, does he deviate from the path marked
                        out. He is to-day fighting the battle of a Republic of United and Co-equal
                        States against a consolidated despotism. Guided by the light of the
                        Constitution, he is pursuing the only course which will restore a permanent
                        Union. His conservatism surprises, as well as delights the people of the
                        Southern States, who had been led to expect a stern and bitter fate, and
                        will make them firm friends of permanent Union, while his conciliatory
                        measures must and will redound to the everlasting praise of Republican
                        Governments. Not only does his conservatism and conciliation meet with the
                        cordial approbation of the people of the South, but the Democracy of the
                        North have commended and endorsed his policy, and the conservative
                        Republicans of the States of New York, Ohio and Pennsylvania, recognizing
                        the fact that, the question of slavery being removed from the political
                        arena, there only remain a wise, conservative and conciliatory policy to be
                        pursued to reunite the old Republic on a firm and lasting basis, have also
                        endorsed his policy of restoration.</p>
                    <p>While the President is receiving the assistance of the conservatives of the
                        North, the South must add her voice in sustaining him, by sending, as her
                        representatives, men who have not been leaders in the Secession movement, or
                        in any way identified with its extreme measures. By such a course, the
                        Northern radicals, whose ranks are daily dwindling away, will find but a
                        meagre morsel, in the newly elected representatives of the South, upon which
                        to feed their fanatical followers. In fact we believe they will, as a matter
                        of self preservation, go over "horse, foot and dragoons" to the
                        conservatives.</p>
                    <p>The people of the South must look well to their interests in the selection of
                        their representatives, and if they be but true to themselves, their section
                        and the whole country, in the coming elections, a far brighter day will dawn
                        upon us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper celebrates the battle President Johnson is fighting of "united
                    and co-equal states against a consolidated despotism." The editors state that
                    southerners, northern Democrats, and conservative Republicans have been
                    pleasantly surprised by Johnson's conciliatory approach to reconstruction and
                    are supporting him as a result. The paper urges southerners to elect to office
                    men who did not support secession in order to deprive radicals of an issue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cason</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>George C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyde</ln>
                        <fn>Davis B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blouth</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Orlando</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Robert M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irvin</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper lists the proceedings of the latest meeting of the County Court:
                    Jacob Cason was acquitted of shooting James P. Brown "with intent to kill;"
                    Augustus Fisher was charged with stealing a horse; Jno. W. Kuhn, J. F. Huffman
                    and freedwoman Mary Bell were severally charged with felony; George C. Crouse
                    and Davis B. Hyde were denied liquor licenses; Augustus Blouth was granted a
                    license to keep a house of public entertainment in Greenville; William Chapman
                    and Jno. B. Smith were granted licenses to keep houses of private entertainment
                    in Waynesboro; General John Echols and Capt. Orlando Smith were qualified as
                    Attorneys; Robert G. Bickle, William Chapman, and James Henderson were appointed
                    proxies to represent the County Stock in the Va. Central Railroad in the next
                    annual meeting of stockholders; Robert M. White, William F. Smith, S. B. Finley,
                    James M. Lilley, and Jno. M. Irvin were appointed Augusta County road
                    commissioners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One day last week, a friend of ours, residing in our neighboring town of
                        Greenville, was asked by an elderly gentleman, on horseback, to be so kind
                        as to direct him to the hotel of the town, which our amiable friend did in
                        as kind terms as the request had been made, and after the departure of the
                        gentleman, turned to pursue his business, little thinking that the
                        occurrence would again be brought to his mind. An old negro man, coming down
                        the street, passed the solitary horseman, and politely lifted his hat to
                        him, and upon approaching our friend asked him if he knew the gentleman.
                        Upon receiving a negative reply, said "why that's our great old General.
                        That's Massa Robt E. Lee." If a thousand Mortars had suddenly let loose upon
                        the town a greater excitement could scarcely have been created. The news
                        spread like wild-fire, crowds from town and country rushed in to get a sight
                        of the great and good man whom, not only the Southern people, but those
                        throughout the world, who appreciate true greatness, love to admire.</p>
                    <p>He was on his way to assume the duties of President of Washington College, to
                        which position, without solicitation, he had been lately elected, and, in
                        his unostentatious way, would have passed by unknown, but for being
                        recognized by the old negro, who had followed his campaigns. As it was his
                        advent into Greenville was an era in her history and long will she remember
                        the day.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports on Robert E. Lee's brief stay in Greenville. He caused an
                    immediate sensation after being recognized by "an old negro man."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that the office of the Adam's Express Company has been
                    refurbished under direction of its "enterprising" owner, F. Scheffer Esq. The
                    company agent, Richard Hawkins, has again taken up business in the old quarters,
                    and "under the late schedule of low rates, with increased facilities for
                    dispatch, is prepared to forward all goods, moneys, letters, &amp;c., to any
                    point within sound of the rattle of a Stage coach, or the whistle of an Engine."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that Charles W. Turner, of Staunton, is doing business
                    for the Baltimore firm, Chaney, Randall, and Co. The firm has been praised by
                    local merchants, and "from the established reputation of our young Townsman as a
                    business man, we predict for the firm, and trust they will receive, a large
                    share of the Valley trade."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that many Virginia post offices are re-opening by order
                    of the Postmaster General, including the following from Augusta County: Swope's
                    Depot, Mrs. Bettie A. Dull, Postmistress; Mt. Sidney, A. H. Ross, Postmaster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Committed to Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Ralph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces that a youth named Ralph Marshall was committed to
                    County Jail for stealing a horse belonging to Augusta County resident John
                    Switzer on August 31st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaw</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bean</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Robert Gaw, of Woodstock, and Miss Margaret E. Bean of Staunton, were
                    married in Staunton at the residence of Job Turner on September 22. The Reverend
                    George B. Taylor presided. According to the paper, "both bride and bridegroom"
                    were "Deaf Mutes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Benjamin G. Patterson, of Harrisonburg, married Miss Fannie Koiner,
                    daughter of Augusta County resident Martin Koiner, on South River on September
                    21st. The Rev. J. Killian presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radford</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gladwell</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William J. Radford and Miss Sarah Gladwell, both of Augusta County,
                    were married on September 21st by the Rev. J. W. Kiracofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ensor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. George B. Ensor, of Davisville, Baltimore County, Md., married Miss
                    Jennie H. Beard at the home of the bride's father, John Beard, near Mint Spring,
                    Augusta County, on September 14th. The Rev. J. C. Dice presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>Mary W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPhail</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary W. Imboden, wife of General John D. Imboden, died of consumption
                    on September 21st at Mulberry Hill, Charlotte County, Va., the home of her
                    father, John B. McPhail. She was 32 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>R. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. N. H. Hamilton, wife of Dr. R. L. Hamilton and daughter of the late
                    Henry Sterrett, died in Churchville after a brief illness on the evening of
                    September 8th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1865.09.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
