<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-05-25">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25.01">
            <pageNote>Columns 1-3 list and review current books and periodicals, including the
                Atlantic Monthly, Blackwoods Edinburgh Magazine, Love Me Little, Love Me
            Long</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25.03">
            <pageNote>Bottom illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Judge Taney</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial about slavery in the Territories and Americans' opinions of the
                    Supreme Court.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Lots about Black Republicans.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Growing Evil</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>The number of peddling imposters, and itinerant quacks, perambulating the
                    county in every direction, and imposing upon the people, are becoming a nuisance
                    to every neighborhood, and demand some denunciatory notice from the press
                    generally.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The number of peddling imposters, and itinerant quacks, perambulating the
                        county in every direction, and imposing upon the people, are becoming a
                        nuisance to every neighborhood, and demand some denunciatory notice from the
                        press generally. There is not a town, village or farm house any longer free
                        from their intrusion.--They will thrust themselves into your presence
                        anywhere and everywhere and insist in palming upon you their notions, and
                        should you refuse to purchase, you are expected to put up with whatever
                        quantity of bluster and abuse they may think proper to bestow on you for
                        daring to assert that you are not disposed to be humbugged. In your dealings
                        with such characters, in nine cases out of ten, you are sure to be cheated,
                        if not in the quality of the article, in the price demanded for it. Your own
                        dealers, you will find, can always supply your wants, at fair prices,
                        without requiring you to patronize such "birds of passage." No class of men
                        better understand the value of a favorable newspaper notice than these
                        vagrants, and they make a bold push in every town they visit to secure
                        something of the kind. For such characters we have no affinity--no
                        liking--and if any of them reckon on our services to aid them in fleeing the
                        community they will most assuredly "reckon without their host." Honest
                        praise we admire; and wherever we can say a word in commendation of the
                        handiwork of our own mechanics, or of our merchants, or professional
                        gentlemen, "anything in their line," we will do it most cordially; but
                        strolling mountebanks must <emph rend="italic">excuse us</emph> from
                        perpetrating any notice of them calculated to "tickle their fancy," and they
                        may too, make up their minds that their bluster in relation to us is the
                        very worst means possible, to which they can resort, to secure our silence.
                        We would regret to wound the feelings of any worthy man, if there is any
                        such to be found among this class, but so far as our notices of them may be
                        a drawback to their illegitimate traffic we have no regrets to express past,
                        present or future.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses concern about the number of quacks and impostors setting up shop
                    in the county. Provides advice on how to avoid them and how not to be cheated.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/may59.html#5.25a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Theatre</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>George Gile's theatre company is coming from Philadelphia to perform in
                    Franklin Hall.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Fine Boat</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Solenburger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Smith and Solenburger are having a boat built for pleasure trips on the
                    stream. Available for hire.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Drowned</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Johnston's five-year-old daughter drowned in their spring.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Splendid Monument</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>--Among the many works of art and skill which adorn the burial grounds
                    attached to the Presbyterian Church, the Monument just erected over the grave of
                    the former wife of our late esteemed townsman, George S. Eyster, is not only an
                    appropriate tribute of affectionate regard from her children, but stands
                    unrivalled for beautiful workmanship, excellence of design and massive
                    proportions.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Among the many works of art and skill which adorn the burial grounds
                        attached to the Presbyterian Church, the Monument just erected over the
                        grave of the former wife of our late esteemed townsman, George S. Eyster, is
                        not only an appropriate tribute of affectionate regard from her children,
                        but stands unrivalled for beautiful workmanship, excellence of design and
                        massive proportions. This splendid work of art was executed by Mr. McFadden,
                        of this place, and will add much to his already high reputation as a
                        skillful worker in marble.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Compliments the monument to Eyster's wife just erected in the Presbyterian
                    burial grounds.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/may59.html#5.25b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the Franklin County Educational Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cobble</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Omwake</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoler</ln>
                        <fn>A.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guff</ln>
                        <fn>J.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Meeting of Educational Association at German Reformed Church, St. Thomas on
                    May 5-6.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page is difficult to read. Markets in column 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.25.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
