<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/21/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-03-16">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Remarks of Mr. Nill of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nill's remarks in the legislature on erecting a monument to commemorate
                    those who died in the Mexican war. He opposes it as an unnecessary
                expenditure</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16.03">
            <pageNote>Humorous column.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16.04">
            <pageNote>Markets in column 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The workmen have commenced operations on the first section of the road,
                    and along the entire line the timber is being delivered as fast as it can be
                    produced."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--During the latter part of last, and the beginning of the present week, some
                        eighteen cars passed over the Cumberland Valley Railroad, and arrived at the
                        Depot in this place, loaded with the iron for relaying the track of the
                        Franklin Railroad. This iron is o the very best quality being first class T
                        rail. The workmen have commenced operations on the first section of the
                        road, and along the entire line the timber is being delivered as fast as it
                        can be produced. Mr. Sam'l Seibert, our esteemed fellow townsman, has been
                        very successful in his contracts for lumber to construct the road, and has
                        pushed forward the business entrusted to him with commendable energy. We are
                        gratified to learn that the road is to be constructed under the
                        Superintendency of Col. O. N. Lull. No better man could have been selected
                        for the purpose. He is thoroughly conversant with railroad matters, and
                        understands how to make as well as manage a road, equal to any other man in
                        the country. We have no doubt whatever that this road will be completed and
                        put in running order in a very few months. Its president A. J. Jones, Esq,
                        of Harrisburg, deserves much credit for the successful manner in which he
                        has surmounted all difficulties, and carried forward this enterprize to its
                        present and gratifying prosperous condition. We are well satisfied in our
                        mind that he will find it a safe and good investment, and one from which he
                        will realize a handsome remuneration.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn>O.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details of the construction of the new railroad</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march59.html#3.16a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Public Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Mr. Shoemaker has labored faithfully to perfect our system of common
                    schools, and advance the cause of education in our county.--He has ridden by day
                    and night nearly a thousand miles over our highways and byways; examining over
                    two hundred schools; and nearly a thousand pupils since the 3d of October last."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--During the past week the County Superintendent, Mr. P. M. Shoemaker has
                        been engaged in examining the scholars in the Public Schools of this
                        borough. These examinations were conducted in a very systematic and thorough
                        manner, and exhibited a degree of care and proficiency on the part of the
                        Superintendent which cannot fail to make himself and his office popular with
                        the people. Our schools, one and all, are in a most excellent condition
                        which speaks loudly in praise of the teachers, reflects much credit on the
                        scholars, and the system of instruction which has been inaugurated.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Shoemaker has labored faithfully to perfect our system of common schools,
                        and advance the cause of education in our county.--He has ridden by day and
                        night nearly a thousand miles over our highways and byways; examining over
                        two hundred schools; and nearly a thousand pupils since the 3d of October
                        last. Through his instrumentality our schools have attained a standard of
                        excellence to which those who take an interest in the progress of education
                        may refer with feelings of pleasure and pride.</p>
                    <p>We understand it is the intention of our Directors to have a public
                        examination of the pupils in the Public Schools, at the close of the present
                        session in the last week in June, at which the State and County
                        Superintendents are expected to be present.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Shoemaker, the Superintendent, has been examining all the county's schools
                    in an effort to improve them.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march59.html#3.16b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Attention Battalion!</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keckler</ln>
                        <fn>Valentine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detwiler</ln>
                        <fn>???</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hippert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>???</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightcap</ln>
                        <fn>???</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appenseller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spindle</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Durboraw</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of the privates in the Poor House Battalion. Officers listed in 03/09
                    edition. The Spirit satirizes the rush for patronage positions.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Legislation</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brower</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of actions taken and petitions read by local legislators.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Valley Spirit; County Superintendent in Southampton Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Southampton</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of meeting of "Friends of Education" in Orrstown. They want to start
                    their own school district and Superintendency.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Poor House</head>
                <origin>The Independent</origin>
                <commentary>Notes the Independent's praise of the new Poor House officers.</commentary>
                <excerpt>"The House and Farm have been kept in excellent order by Mr. Shinefield,
                    the intelligent and competent Steward, who has discharged his trust with
                    fidelity to the County and to the unfortunates under his care."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The time for which the present Steward, Mr. Shinifield, was appointed does
                        not expire until the 1st of next October. The Physician and Clerk go out of
                        office on the 1st of April. The <emph rend="italic">Independent</emph> gives
                        the following very flattering notice of the present incumbents:</p>
                    <p>"It is due to the gentlemen who have had the management for the past few
                        years, to declare that they have performed their duties with great ability
                        and integrity; and that any improvement upon their administration need
                        hardly be expected. The House and Farm have been kept in excellent order by
                        Mr. Shinefield, the intelligent and competent Steward, who has discharged
                        his trust with fidelity to the County and to the unfortunates under his
                        care. The medical supeintendence has been highly creditable to the
                        professional character of Dr. Boyle, whose place his successor will find it
                        no sinecure to supply. The well-known reputation of J. Wyeth Douglas, Esq.,
                        is sufficient voucher for his competency as Attorney and Clerk. The
                        gentlemen who have been lately appointed will doubtless give satisfaction;
                        and we look to them for a continuance of the good management now
                    obtaining."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shininfeld</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J.Wyeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praise of Poor House officers.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/march59.html#3.16c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>An Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>W.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easten</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Election of Directors of Chambersburg and Bedford Turnpike Company. From
                    Franklin and Bedford.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodrock</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knepper</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 10 at Mrs. Fisher's Hotel.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robaugh</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollingsworth</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 2 in Greencastle.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Camp</ln>
                        <fn>J.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 8.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morary</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goshert</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 16.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom too blurry to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16.06">
            <pageNote>Youths' Department, col.1</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16.07">
            <pageNote>Serious Reading, col. 1--seems religious</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.03.16.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
