<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/29/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-01-19">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A White Heiress Elopes With a Negro</head>
                <origin>Detroit Free Press</origin>
                <excerpt>"A young girl named Sarah Judson, whose father lives on a fine property a
                    mile or two from Pontiac, eloped on Saturday and came to Detroit. The partner of
                    her flight was a black man, who has been in the employment of her father for
                    some time in the capacity of farm hand."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Detroit <emph rend="italic">Free Press</emph> of Thursday tells of a
                        singular elopement in that vicinity on Saturday:</p>
                    <p>A young girl named Sarah Judson, whose father lives on a fine property a mile
                        or two from Pontiac, eloped on Saturday and came to Detroit. The partner of
                        her flight was a black man, who has been in the employment of her father for
                        some time in the capacity of farm hand. the first intimation that the father
                        had of the intention of the parties was conveyed by the fact of their
                        flight. They immediately crossed over to Windsor, upon reaching the city,
                        fully sensible that they could not accomplish their unnatural designs on
                        this side, as no official or clergyman could have been found who would have
                        so far transgressed the bounds of decency as to unite the couple, the
                        appearance of the girl being such as would forbid the union in the mind of
                        any sensible man, to say nothing of the law in the case. Some individual was
                        found in Canada who performed the ceremony, however, and the two were made
                        one. They are now in Windsor, enjoying the sweets of the honeymoon.</p>
                    <p>The brother of the girl came on the next day arriving here on Sunday, and
                        ascertaining there whereabouts, went to her and implored her to return. She
                        was contented, however--loved her ebony half--was happy in his arms, and
                        couldn't think of going back. The emotions of a brother at such a sight can
                        better be imagined than described. Some men would have blotted out their
                        disgrace with a single blow, but he had been taught that it was no sin
                        against God or man that his young sister should repose in the embrace of a
                        negro, and at the same time calmly look [word missing] to the face and say
                        that she was contented. He went home as he had come, alone.</p>
                    <p>The girl is about eighteen years old.--The family are said to have occupied a
                        position in society which was first class, and the blow is, consequently a
                        terrible one. The father is rich, and the girl and heiress, which makes it
                        very nice for the African of her choice. The matter has caused an intense
                        excitement in the neighborhood where the parties are well known, the girl
                        having been born and brought up where her parents reside. It is difficult to
                        imagine any train of circumstances by which a young and intelligent girl
                        could be brought to form a connexion so repugnant to all the senses; yet the
                        fact exists. A more complete retribution for the crime of fanaticism we
                        never heard of. The least we can wish is, that the father, undoubtedly well
                        cured of his belief by this time, may be able to save his young daughter
                        from the terrible future that now opens to her.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article about a white girl who eloped with black farm hand.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/jan59.html#1.19a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19.04">
            <pageNote>Congressional report. List of standing committees for the Pennsylvania
                legislature.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lady in Black</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mysterious female gardener, dressed in black, has been patronizing local
                    merchants.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>At a Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Spangler</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of meeting of Friendship Fire Company on January 12.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>McCauley's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>McCauley's lecture before the Gibson Literary society was well
                received.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Funeral</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Adams funeral attended by members of Hope and Friendship Fire
                companies.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Shocking Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbons</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frank</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gibbons, blacksmith's assistant, fell into the fire and was badly
                burned.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Thief</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>African-American man named Ramsey was accused of stealing clover from
                    Chambers mill.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hannaberry</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGovern</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 26, 1858</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hannaberry</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kempton</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 4, 1859</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Adams died of consumption on January 11, 1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Letter from Washington. Markets in col. 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.01.19.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
