<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/29/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-02-09">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="09">9</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09.01">
            <pageNote>Weekly Letter from Washington in col. 1.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Education</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In presenting for the inspection of our readers the annual report of the
                        County Superintendent of Common Schools it gives us a peculiar pleasure to
                        bestow a word of just praise on the gentleman who fills that important
                        position. For many years the cause of education in Franklin County has been
                        in a languishing condition, and the Common School System was fast sinking
                        into disrepute with the people. Propositions were openly made to abolish the
                        office of County Superintendent, and a decided feeling of hostility was
                        apparent, in almost every district in the County, against the whole system
                        of public education. At this juncture, Mr. P. M. Shoemaker was elected
                        County Superintendent. He entered upon his duties with a formidable array of
                        difficulties staring him in the face. His office was unpopular-- the whole
                        system in disrepute--teachers incompetent--schools at a low ebb, and no
                        interest taken in the cause of education. It was a gloomy picture to
                        contemplate, and any one of less sagacity and energy, than he possessed
                        would have shrunk from the Herculean labors before them. Not so with Mr.
                        Shoemaker; with hand, heart and brain, he engaged in the work. In a quiet
                        but determined manner has he, by his example and exertions, reformed,
                        remodelled, and improved our schools until they now fully and fairly
                        realized the sanguine expectations of the friends of the Common School
                        System of Education. We are aware that there is still much to accomplish
                        before we can pronounce our schools perfect, but Mr. Shoemaker is fully
                        equal to the task, and under his supervision, the day is not far distant,
                        when the public schools of Franklin will take rank with those of any other
                        county in the State. <lb/>Franklin County. <lb/>SCHOOL HOUSES.--1st class,
                        good, 1; 2d class, improvable, 154; 3d class, unfit, 35.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Material of School Houses</emph>.--Brick, 135; stone, 17;
                        log, 24; frame, 14.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">School Furniture</emph>.--1st class, good, none; 2d
                        class, medium, 136; 3d class, unfit, 54.</p>
                    <p>SCHOOLS.--1st class, graded, 24; 2d class, classified, 84; 3d class, neither
                        graded nor classified, 94.</p>
                    <p>TEACHERS.--<emph rend="italic">Ages of Teachers</emph>.--Under seventeen, 3;
                        between seventeen and twenty one, 52; between twenty one and twenty five,
                        57; between twenty five and thirty, 26; between thirty and forty, 36;
                        between forty and fifty, 17; over fifty, 11.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Birthplace of Teachers</emph>.--Born in Pennsylvania,
                        182; born out of Pennsylvania, 20.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Experience in Teaching</emph>.--Taught less than one
                        year, 66; from one to three years, 47; from three to six years, 32; from six
                        to ten years, 22; from ten to twenty years, 20; over twenty years, 15.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Professional Reading</emph>.--Number who have read books
                        or periodicals on teaching, 89; number who have not, 118.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Permanent Teachers</emph>.--Number who intend to make
                        teaching a permanent business, 132; those who do not, 70.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Grade of Teachers</emph>.--1st class, qualified, 50; 2d
                        class, medium; 3d class, unfit, 38.</p>
                    <p>GENERAL REMARKS.--In the first class I have placed the Washington street
                        house, Chambersburg. In the second class there are some very good houses,
                        but not so constructed, in all particulars, as to entitle them to be classed
                        in the first division, but might be made such with very little expense. Two
                        of this class, and the best, are in Hamilton; the one was described by my
                        predecessor; the other is called Webster's school house, was built last
                        summer, and is in every respect similar to the first.</p>
                    <p>I will here state that the efficient and energetic board of directors of
                        Chambersburg have in process of erection a very fine school building; one
                        that will be an ornament to the town as well as a great advantage in grading
                        the schools, and will reflect great credit upon the worthy board of
                        directors. It is much needed, for some of the present houses are illy
                        calculated for their uses.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Examinations and Certificates</emph>.--In some of the
                        districts a majority of the directors, and many of the citizens, were
                        present to witness the public examination of teachers, and appeared to be
                        pleased with the manner of conducting them, as well as interested in them.
                        In other districts but few directors or citizens were present, and in some
                        none.</p>
                    <p>My predecessors granted one hundred and thirteen professional certificates
                        during the first three years of the superintendency, but most of the holders
                        of them have either abandoned the profession or left the country.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">County Association</emph>.--We have a county association
                        of teachers and friends of education. It was organized in November, 1854. It
                        holds two meetings each year in Chambersburg; generally in May and November.
                        The last meeting convened May 6th, 1858; the proceedings were quite
                        interesting and instructive. It was attended by about fifty teachers, and
                        many of the friends of education. Although the association has not been as
                        numerously attended as we could wish, yet it has been productive of much
                        good in awakening teachers, and impressing upon their minds the dignity and
                        value of their profession. There never was as efficient and energetic a band
                        of teachers in the county as there is at the present time. It has also had
                        its influence on public opinion, enlisting it to a great extent on the side
                        of education. It has also been instrumental in removing some of the
                        objections urged against the school system. I believe our people need only
                        to understand it properly to approve it. No considerable portion of the
                        citizens of this county are opposed to the present school system; on the
                        contrary, I believe that a majority are favorable to it, especially of the
                        thinking and more intelligent part of the community. It is true there are
                        still many objections urged against certain features of it, but I think a
                        few years more will remove most of them.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">District Institutes</emph>.--There had been teachers'
                        institutes organized in two or three districts prior to my election. Since
                        that time they have been organized in a majority of the districts in the
                        county. But in none have they been so successfully carried on as in St.
                        Thomas, Antrim and Letterkenny. In the first named the meetings were held
                        semi monthly in the evening, and were productive of much good, not only in
                        improving and awakening the teachers, but also in informing the public of
                        the workings of the school system, and in removing much of the opposition to
                        it. In the second the meetings were held every alternate Saturday, and
                        considerable interest was manifested in them by teachers, directors and
                        citizens. In the last mentioned the meetings were held the same as in the
                        first, but not productive of quite so much good, although of great benefit
                        to the teachers of the district.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Visitations</emph>.--I commenced my visitations about the
                        first of October, visiting those schools which commenced earliest first. In
                        some of the districts I visited three schools per day; in others but two. Of
                        the two hundred and two schools in the county, I visited one hundred and
                        ninety eight; four I failed to visit. I visited forty schools twice.</p>
                    <p>I generally remained long enough in the school room to hear all the classes
                        recite. Sometimes the teacher conducted the recitations, and I observed the
                        manner of imparting instruction; at other times I heard the recitations
                        myself. I frequently gave the classes a short examination. In cases where I
                        thought the teacher was not properly discharging his duty, I privately and
                        kindly pointed out his errors, and urged him to correct them. Before leaving
                        a school I generally occupied a few moments in talking to the scholars in
                        plain language, such as they could easily understand, urging them to be
                        studious; showing them the advantages of a good education, and trying to
                        impress upon their youthful minds that an education of the head and not of
                        the heart may prove to them no better than a curse.</p>
                    <p>I was accompanied to many of the schools by the directors, and sometimes by
                        teachers and citizens, who manifested a lively interest in the recitations
                        and examinations. The <emph rend="italic">directors</emph> of some of the
                        districts are entitled to <emph rend="italic">much credit</emph>, as a
                        majority of each board left their work and went along to the schools of
                        their respective districts; in some few cases spending three and four days
                        with me, and rendering me valuable assistance. The districts alluded to are
                        St. Thomas, Metal, Antrim, Montgomery, Waynesboro', Chambersburg and
                        Hamilton. In a majority of the other districts I was accompanied by a few of
                        the directors to some of the schools; but the same interest was not
                        manifested as in the above. I met many schools, in my visitations, which are
                        commendable in almost every respect.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Public Meetings</emph>.--During the winter upwards of
                        thirty public meetings were held in different parts of the county, in which
                        the nature and duties of my office were explained, the necessity of regular
                        attendance of pupils, of proper classification, and uniformity of text
                        books, as well as the duties and responsibilities of parents and teachers;
                        and in all cases the necessity of improvement was urged upon teachers, and
                        as a means of such improvement, tried to induce them to attend the Normal
                        school. I also urged upon directors and citizens the necessity of improving
                        school houses and school grounds, and other things that benefit our schools.
                        The meetings were generally well attended.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Text Books</emph>.--A majority of the districts have
                        complied with the requisitions of the law in adopting a regular series of
                        text books. But in the requisition that "these shall be used and no others,"
                        has not been fully complied with in more than two or three districts. In
                        some of the schools I found copies of nearly all the school books published
                        since the days of Pythagoras. This want of uniformity in text books is
                        seriously felt, and is a great barrier to classification. We hope, however,
                        to have this hindrance obviated, or nearly so, during the coming year.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Directors' Visits</emph>.--In some of the districts
                        directors and citizens visit the schools regularly; in others they neglect
                        it almost entirely.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Teachers' Salaries</emph>.--In a majority of the
                        districts teachers are paid according to qualifications and skill in the art
                        of teaching. The provisional certificates are divided into two grades;
                        making in all three grades. First grade, professional; second grade, good
                        provisional; third grade, medium. The first grade gets from two to four
                        dollars more per month than the second; and the second from two to four more
                        than the third. But the salaries are entirely inadequate to the labor
                        performed in the school room.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Improvement</emph>.--The improvement in this county has
                        not been such as could be desired; but no thinking man can compare the
                        present with fours years ago and justly say there has been no improvement
                        made. I think it is stamped on a majority of the schools of the county.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Normal School</emph>.--We have a Normal school in
                        connection with the Chambersburg Academy, under the control of John K.
                        Shryock, in whose hands no enterprise can fail, as he is a gifted, efficient
                        and successful teacher. There are about forty students in the Normal
                        department. It commenced on the 19th of April and is to continue ten weeks.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Acknowledgments</emph>.--In almost every part of the
                        county I received the kindest attention from directors, citizens and
                        teachers, and their hospitality was generously extended to me. For this they
                        have my grateful thanks.</p>
                    <p>In conclusion, I hope the day is not far distant when the <emph rend="italic"
                            >free schools</emph> of Franklin county shall be her proudest boast.
                        <lb/>PHILIP M. SHOEMAKER. <lb/><emph rend="italic">County
                        Superintendent</emph>.</p>
                    <p>UPPER STRASBURG, June 17, 1858.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editorial concerning the Annual Report of County Superintendent for Common
                    Schools. Editors praise the work of P. M. Shoemaker.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.9a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Railroad to Gettysburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The great advantages that a connection with the Gettysburg road would open
                    up to our farmers, and the business community, are so obvious that self interest
                    must sooner or later determine its completion."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The importance of a connection with the Railroad at Gettysburg is
                        attracting the attention of the businessmen of this neighborhood. We have
                        heard considerable talk, within a few days past, of having a survey made in
                        order to show the practicability of constructing a road, over a route of an
                        easy grade, and free from any unusual expense in building. Such a route we
                        are assured exists and that a survey of it will be made at an early day. The
                        great advantages that a connection with the Gettysburg road would open up to
                        our farmers, and the business community, are so obvious that self interest
                        must sooner or later determine its completion. By the route proposed which
                        would only require about twenty four miles of road to be built, we would
                        obtain a direct railroad communication with the Baltimore market, at a
                        saving of forty three miles in distance and at least twenty five per cent on
                        freight over the roundabout road we are now obliged to travel to get to that
                        market. The Merchants of Baltimore see the necessity of this road, in order
                        to secure the trade and produce of the great Cumberland Valley, and express
                        themselves as ready to invest their money in it whenever the demand is made
                        upon them. From the well known energetic character of the men who are
                        agitating this subject in our community, we have no doubt whatever that this
                        road will be built at no very distant day.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial stresses the importance of and need for a rail connection to
                    Gettysburg. Claims the line would be good for farmers and merchants, as a direct
                    connection to Baltimore</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.9b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Grand Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"It affords us much gratification to record the fact that a "Young Men's
                    Christian Association" has been organized in this place. These societies are
                    rapidly springing up in all our principal towns, and are found to be productive
                    of much good."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--It affords us much gratification to record the fact that a "Young Men's
                        Christian Association" has been organized in this place. These societies are
                        rapidly springing up in all our principal towns, and are found to be
                        productive of much good. It is the object of the members of these
                        associations to seek out young men and bring them under Christian
                        influences; surround them with moral associates, and use every religious
                        instrumentality to effect a change in their thoughts and habits. Such
                        societies are the visible embodiment of Christian philanthropy, and are
                        calculated to confer great blessings upon the minds and morals of the young
                        men of the present day. It is the duty of every Christian citizen to aid by
                        his best efforts in arraying on the side of these associations whatever of
                        intelligence, patriotism and Christian philanthropy may exist in the
                        community. The interests of religion--of humanity--of our country--of the
                        world--of unborn generations--demand it at their hands. It is a high and
                        holy vocation our Young Men have assumed and not without its
                        responsibilities. We trust it may be sustained by an energy commensurate
                        with its real and vast importance, and with a full sense of accountability
                        to God for the right use of the means they have assumed for doing good.</p>
                    <p>The Society in this place has been permanently organized, a Constitution and
                        By-Laws adopted, and the following named gentlemen elected as officers:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">President.</emph>--Wm. G. Reed <lb/><emph rend="italic"
                            >Vice Presidents.</emph>--Jacob Brand, A. N. Rankin, B. Y. Hamsher, W.
                        H. R. Detrich, Jacob Hoke, J. S. Nixon, B. B. Henchy, J. R. Smith.
                            <lb/><emph rend="italic">Recording Secretary.</emph>--J. J. Rehman.
                            <lb/><emph rend="italic">Corresponding Secretary.</emph>--J. W. Deal.
                            <lb/><emph rend="italic">Treasurer.</emph>--Wm. Adams. <lb/><emph
                            rend="italic">Librarian.</emph>--Geo. H. Mengel.</p>
                    <p>At a stated meeting held on Monday evening, the following Board of Managers
                        were elected, vix:--L. H. McCauley, S. H. Shillito, Anthony Holler, W. H.
                        Sullenburger, M. Gillan, J. K. Shryock. The Board of Managers are notified
                        to meet on Monday Evening, February 14th, at the office of Wm. Adams,
                    Esq.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunsher</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dietrich</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henchy</ln>
                        <fn>B.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebman</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mengel</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>L.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shilto</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holler</ln>
                        <fn>Anthony</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullenberger</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillam</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>J.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praising the establishment of a local Young Men's Christian Association.
                    Includes list of officers.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.9c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Receipts and Expenditures of the Poor House</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinstry</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wrants</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shin</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Annual report of County Poor House</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Lawlin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushstone</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 1 at Montgomery Hotel.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodrock</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Abrahm</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beans</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 13 at Indian Queen Hotel.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Large table showing Aggregate Amount of Assessments and Valuation of the
                several towns in the county. Across cols. 3-5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09.06">
            <pageNote>all ads</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.09.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
