<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04">
     <header>
          <title>Valley Spirit</title>
          <tagger>
               <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
               <tagDate>12/21/95</tagDate>
               <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
          </tagger>
          <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
          <date n="1859-05-04">
               <year>1859</year>
               <month norm="05">May</month>
               <day norm="04">4</day>
               <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
          </date>
          <frequency>weekly</frequency>
          <extent>08</extent>
          <editionNote/>
     </header>
     <paperBody>
          <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04.01">
               <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04.02">
               <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04.03">
               <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04.04">
               <div type="a">
                    <column>2</column>
                    <head>German Americans</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <excerpt> The Germans are very generally hostile to slavery. The Republican
                         falsehood that the Democracy are "slavery propogandists" was yelled into
                         their ears till they believed it. They gave their support to the Republican
                         party, believing that in so doing they were aiding to strike off the
                         shackle of the slave; but they have discovered that they were only forging
                         shackles for themselves. Their Republican <emph rend="italic"
                         >friends</emph> have turned out to be enemies in disguise, and the
                         naturalized Germans have been taught by a bitter lesson that partisan
                         "Republicanism" is simply proscriptive "Know Nothingism" under another
                         name. </excerpt>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>A new danger threatens the opposition party, and invites them to talk
                              less about Democratic dissensions and look more to the disruption
                              occurring among themselves. For several years past the Republican
                              party has carried off a large share of the naturalized German vote.
                              This has been especially the case in the extreme Eastern and Northern
                              States, and it accounts in great part for the heavy majorities the
                              Republicans have obtained in that quarter of the country. The Germans
                              are very generally hostile to slavery. The Republican falsehood that
                              the Democracy are "slavery propogandists" was yelled into their ears
                              till they believed it. They gave their support to the Republican
                              party, believing that in so doing they were aiding to strike off the
                              shackle of the slave; but they have discovered that they were only
                              forging shackles for themselves. Their Republican <emph rend="italic"
                                   >friends</emph> have turned out to be enemies in disguise, and
                              the naturalized Germans have been taught by a bitter lesson that
                              partisan "Republicanism" is simply proscriptive "Know Nothingism"
                              under another name.</p>
                         <p>Flushed with their repeated victories, and believing themselves strong
                              enough to retain power without the aid of their German allies, the
                              Republicans of the Eastern and Northern States have reaffirmed the
                              Know Nothing doctrines they pretended to have discarded, and placed a
                              mark of degredation on the brow of every man whose Maker saw fit to
                              bring him into existence in another country than our own. The action
                              of the Republican Legislature of Massachusetts, in passing laws
                              placing dishonorable disabilities upon persons born in other countries
                              of the world, and the registry bill adopted by the Republican
                              legislature of New York, which is intended as a blow at naturalized
                              citizens, has opened the eyes of the Germans. They are not disposed to
                              submit tamely to such outrages from the party to whose success they
                              have contributed so much. The German Republicans of Massachusetts have
                              issued an address to the people of the United States, commenting upon
                              the action of the Republican party, and making the following emphatic
                              declaration of their intentions for the future:</p>
                         <p>"<emph rend="italic">We, citizens of German descent, will have nothing
                                   more to do with the Republican party. We will never more lend our
                                   help to elevate a party to power which tramples us under
                              foot</emph>."</p>
                         <p>The wonder is that any naturalized citizens ever did help the Republican
                              party, for it at least ought to have been plain to every man who had
                              eyes to see, that the Republican party was in the main just the same
                              as the Know Nothing party. The same men who belonged to the one
                              belonged to the other. If they were honest when they avowed Know
                              Nothing sentiments, they must hold those sentiments still, however
                              they might conceal them; and if they were not honest as Know Nothings,
                              how could they be honest in anything else? The Germans would do well
                              to attach themselves as one man to the Democratic party, for it is the
                              only party now in existence that does equal and exact justice to all
                              classes of citizens and all sections of the country.</p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names/>
                    <summary>Republicans have been relying on the votes of German immigrants, who
                         are largely opposed to slavery. But now the Know-Nothings have taken over
                         the party and have rejected the Germans. These immigrants are now turning
                         to the Democrats.</summary>
                    <note>frbrowser/may59.html#5.4b</note>
               </div>
               <pageNote/>
          </page>
          <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04.05">
               <div type="a">
                    <column>1</column>
                    <head>Odd Fellows Celebration</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <excerpt>The principles of Odd Fellowship are taught chiefly by symbols. This
                         constitutes a universal language and enables us to hold "converse sweet"
                         with "all nations, tongues and kindreds of the earth." The language of
                         signs by which Odd Fellows recognise each other, is a beautiful feature in
                         the order, and one that should never be urged against it by way of
                         reproach.</excerpt>
                    <transcript>
                         <p>At the Annual Communication of the Right Worthy Grand Lodge of the
                              United States, held in the month of September last, it was resolved to
                              set apart the 26th day of April, 1859, to be observed by the entire
                              membership under its jurisdiction as a day of Thanksgiving to Divine
                              Providence for the unexampled prosperity which has attended the order
                              since its organization on the American continent. Acting in accordance
                              with this recommendation, the R. W. Grand Lodge of Pennsylvania, at
                              its session in November, granted permission to all subordinate Lodges,
                              in the State, to celebrate the day named with such becoming ceremonies
                              as may be deemed suitable to the occasion. On the 20th of January
                              last, "Chambersburg Lodge," No. 175 paid a fraternal visit to
                              "Columbus Lodge," No. 75, when propositions were made to celebrate the
                              Fortieth Anniversary of the establishment of the Order, in the United
                              States, by a grand demonstration, in this place, on the 26th of April.
                              Committees were appointed by the respective Lodges to carry out
                              conjointly the necessary arrangements for the contemplated
                              celebration. The Committee on behalf of "Columbus Lodge" were I. H.
                              McCauley, J. N. Snider, and J. G. Scheible; from "Chambersburg Lodge"
                              D. A. Wertz, D. H. Hutchinson and H. Bishop. The Committees decided
                              that the prominent exercises of the day should consist of a
                              Procession, Oration and Banquet, and that all neighboring Lodges be
                              invited to participate in the celebration. <lb/>The Day. In conformity
                              with previous arrangements the members of "Columbus" and
                              "Chambersburg" Lodges met at their respective Halls, at 1 o'clock, and
                              were joined by the visiting brethren of the neighboring Lodges. The
                              weather proving rather unpropitious the attendance of the members of
                              the order was not as large as had been anticipated. The number of
                              people attracted to town to witness the novelty of the Procession were
                              numerous; they seemed highly delighted with the proceedings, and
                              conducted themselves in an orderly and commendable manner throughout
                              the day. <lb/>The Procession. <lb/>The Procession was formed under the
                              direction of the Chief Marshal, <lb/>COL. F. S. STUMBAUGH; <lb/>Aids,
                              <lb/>P. B. HOUSEM and C. M. DUNCAN, Esqs. <lb/>It was arranged in the
                              following order: <lb/>Chambersburg Mechanics' <lb/>Brass Band;
                              <lb/>Bradley's Saxe Band of Mercersburg, <lb/>Cumberland county;
                              <lb/>Delegation from "Gettys Lodge" <lb/>No. 124, <lb/>of Gettysburg,
                              Adams county; <lb/>Delegation from "Path Valley Lodge" No. 419,
                              <lb/>Boxbury, Franklin county; <lb/>Delegation <lb/>from "Marshall
                              Lodge" No. 233, of Mercersb'g, <lb/>Franklin county; <lb/>Visiting
                              Brothers generally; <lb/>Members of <lb/>Chambersburg Lodge" No. 175,
                              <lb/>With Banner; <lb/>Members of "Columbus Lodge" No. 75. <lb/>The
                              Procession presented a grand and imposing appearance, and,
                              notwithstanding the rain, passed over the route designated, enlivened
                              by the very excellent music of the respective Bands.</p>
                         <p>Oration.</p>
                         <p><lb/>The Procession having paraded through the principal streets,
                              returned to the "FRANKLIN HALL," where the following were the order of
                              exercise:</p>
                         <p><emph rend="italic">Prayer</emph>--By the Rev. D. A. Laverty.</p>
                         <p><emph rend="italic">Thanksgiving Ode</emph>--Sung by the brothers
                              present:</p>
                         <p>"O Lord, our God, Omnipotent!</p>
                         <p><lb/>Throughout the land be mercies sent: <lb/>On <emph rend="italic"
                                   >all</emph> thy bounty be. <lb/>O'ershadow with thy saving grace,
                              <lb/>Our brotherhood in every place; <lb/>O turn their hearts to thee.</p>
                         <p>Our Order owes its thanks to thee! <lb/>And humbly thus upon the knee,
                              <lb/>Acknowledges thy love. <lb/>Accept our praise, O Lord, most High!
                              <lb/>And in thy gracious majesty <lb/>Add blessings from above!</p>
                         <p>Kept by thy care for forty years! <lb/>Thy love sustained--removed our
                              fears <lb/>And gave us lasting fame. <lb/>Be with us Lord, in every
                              clime <lb/>And aid us now, and in all time <lb/>To glorify thy name!</p>
                         <p>Thee shall, O Lord, Jehovah great! <lb/>Earth's son's of high and low
                              estate, <lb/>Thy holiness adore. <lb/>And millions hallelujah's sing--
                              <lb/>Their voices make the welkin ring <lb/>With praises evermore!</p>
                         <p><emph rend="italic">Oration</emph>--By Past Grand, I. H. McCauley.</p>
                         <p>The subject of the address was "The Spirit of the Age." About an hour
                              was occupied in its delivery, and was listened to with marked
                              attention by all present. It was truly and able production and will
                              add much to the intellectual reputation of its author, as well as
                              impress all who heard it with the correct notions of the usefulness
                              and nobleness of Odd Fellowship.</p>
                         <p>After the Address the following ode was sung:</p>
                         <p>"Brothers! let your voices raise-- <lb/>Fill this house with sweetest
                              praise; <lb/>Make it echo with the lays, <lb/>Which we sing to day.</p>
                         <p>Forty years have passed and gone, <lb/>Since our Order first was known,
                              <lb/>By WILDEY'S care, in "Washington"-- <lb/>Of Lodges--Number one!</p>
                         <p>Our ancient "Emblems" be combined, <lb/>Our "motto's" with them
                              intertwined-- <lb/>They make the "links" that ever bind <lb/>Our souls
                              in unity!</p>
                         <p>Our's the "<emph rend="italic">Friendship</emph>" ne'er betrays--
                              <lb/>Our's the "<emph rend="italic">Love</emph>" that ne'er decays--
                              <lb/>Our's the "<emph rend="italic">Truth</emph>", whose purest rays,
                              <lb/>Ever brilliant shine!</p>
                         <p>Brothers! then your vows revere-- <lb/>They they Widow's heart will
                              cheer-- <lb/>They will dry the Orphan's tear-- <lb/>And show your
                              fealty!</p>
                         <p>By our ancient COVENANT tie-- <lb/>By that FAITH that ne'er can die--
                              <lb/>Under God's all seeing eye, <lb/>Let us reverent be!</p>
                         <p>By the HOPE that we all have, <lb/>Of a life beyond the grave,
                              <lb/>Freely give of what you save, <lb/>In sweet CHARITY!</p>
                         <p>Sacred is each mystic rite-- <lb/>Great the numbers they unite--
                              <lb/>Fairest in our Chaplet bright <lb/>Is our harmony!</p>
                         <p>They who have our conduct scann'd, <lb/>Find in us no rev'ling band--
                              <lb/>But united here we stand, <lb/>In Fraternity!</p>
                         <p>Come then Brothers! join the lays-- <lb/>Bring your offerings of
                              praise-- <lb/>Hail this first of natal days, <lb/>With festivity!</p>
                         <p>At the conclusion of the ode a Benediction was pronounced by Rev.
                              Laverty, and the assemblage dismissed to prepare the Hall for the
                              evening entertainment.</p>
                         <p><lb/>The Banquet. <lb/>At 9 o'clock the members of the Order reassembled
                              at the Hall and partook of a sumptuous supper, prepared in magnificent
                              style, by Mr. Abel Mishler, of the "Franklin Hotel," under the
                              supervision of D. H. Hutchinson, the gentlemanly assistant in that
                              establishment. The feast was spread on three tables each extending the
                              entire length of the Exhibition Room in Franklin Hall. They were
                              provided with all the substantials and delicacies the market affords,
                              and the <emph rend="italic">gusto</emph> with which they were
                              dispatched told how well they were served up.</p>
                         <p>After supper, the following Ode termed "The Triple Chain" was sung:</p>
                         <p>"Here around this festal table <lb/>Let thine influence, <emph
                                   rend="italic">Fellowship</emph>, fall, <lb/>Binding, by a union
                              stable, <lb/>Each to each, and all to all: <lb/>Nor alone, 'mid hours
                              of gladness, <lb/>O'er us be thy wings outspread. <lb/>Guide us, be
                              our source of sadness, <lb/>By the sick, the grieved, the dead.</p>
                         <p>Here, too, <emph rend="italic">Love</emph>, at this our meeting.
                              <lb/>Come, and warm each Brother's breast; <lb/>Here let quickened
                              pulses beating <lb/>Show thy power, o'er all confessed; <lb/>Seldom
                              have so many brothers <lb/>Met around one board before; <lb/>Draw each
                              heart to all the others, <lb/>Ere they part to meet no more.</p>
                         <p><emph rend="italic">Truth!</emph> may'st thou, too, hover o'er us!
                              <lb/>Touch each lip, and touch each heart; <lb/>Never, with thy light
                              before us, <lb/>Can we from our vows depart. <lb/>By this triple bond
                              united, <lb/>Brothers we may stand secure; <lb/>May it ne'er be
                              scorned or slighted, <lb/>But stay firm, and bright, and pure!"</p>
                         <p>The following Regular and Volunteer toasts were then proposed:--
                              <lb/>Regular Toasts. <lb/>I. <emph rend="italic">The day we
                              celebrate:</emph> Hallowed as the birth day of an Institution which
                              has done more than any other of the age, to establish and maintain
                              that <emph rend="italic">Universal Fraternity</emph>, which God and
                              Nature designed should exist among men.</p>
                         <p>The Rev. D. A. Laverty responded to this sentiment in a most felicitous
                              style. Odd Fellowship was a chain in which every link was a human
                              heart, riveted together by the noblest feelings of our nature. It was
                              in nowise inimical to religion and sound morality. It did not aspire
                              to take the place of religion--it was but a man made institution--it
                              was satisfied, nay, it gloried in placing the Religion of Christ far
                              above all earthly institutions. It asked only to be permitted to take
                              its seat humbly at the footstool of the Christian Church and the honor
                              of acting as its handmaid in the good work of Charity and Brotherly
                              Love.</p>
                         <p>2. <emph rend="italic">The orator of the day, I. H. McCauley, Esq.
                              :</emph> It is an honor to do honor to such a noble specimen of an Odd
                              Fellow.</p>
                         <p>In reply to this sentiment, Mr. McCauley briefly remarked, that, for
                              himself he claimed no "honors." If his ardent feelings for the good of
                              the Order, and his exertions in its behalf, were in any way calculated
                              to promote its usefulness, among his fellow men, his highest
                              aspirations were satisfied. Mr. McCauley concluded his remarks by
                              submitting the following toast:</p>
                         <p><lb/><emph rend="italic">The wives of Odd Fellows:</emph> May they ever
                              be <emph rend="italic">sweet</emph> fellows- -linked to <emph
                                   rend="italic">good</emph> fellows, by triple chains of <emph
                                   rend="italic">young</emph> fellows.</p>
                         <p>3. <emph rend="italic">Past Grand Sire. Thos. Wildey:</emph> The founder
                              of American Odd Fellowship. The Institution which he established, like
                              the Bread Tree of India, shelters thousands beneath its branches,
                              whilst it supports them with its fruits.</p>
                         <p>The following letter and sentiment received from P. G. S. Wildey were
                              then read: <lb/>BALTIMORE, April 23, 1859. <lb/>Yours, as Chairman of
                              the Committee of Invitation for the contemplated celebration of the
                              40th Anniversary of Odd Fellowship at Chambersburg, has reached me. Be
                              pleased to accept my sincere thanks for this mark of the esteem and
                              respect of my Brethren of Chambersburg. Having previously accepted the
                              invitation of the Brotherhood of Southern New York, to be present at
                              the National Celebration on that day, it will be out of my power to be
                              with you. I enclose you a sentiment. <lb/>Yours Fraternally,
                              <lb/>THOMAS WILDEY. <lb/><emph rend="italic">Odd Fellowship:</emph>
                              God speed its onward march.</p>
                         <p>4. <emph rend="italic">P. G. M. James B. Nicholson, Representative Elect
                                   to the G. L. U. S.:</emph> An able and eloquent expounder of the
                              Principles of our Order. May he ever be found on the side of "Liberty,
                              Fraternity and Equality."</p>
                         <p>P. G. Nicholson addressed a letter to the Committee of Invitation and
                              enclosed the following sentiment which was then offered: <lb/><emph
                                   rend="italic">Odd Fellowship:</emph> May it be turned by no
                              influence whatever, from its simple, but sublime efforts for the good
                              of our race, until misfortune has no want to relieve and sympathy no
                              tear to dry; then will its mission be accomplished, its destiny be
                              happily fulfilled.</p>
                         <p>5. <emph rend="italic">P. G. M. R. A. Lamberton:</emph> We honor him for
                              his virtues; we thank him for his devotion to the best interests of
                              our Order; we regret his absence.</p>
                         <p>In reply to this sentiment a letter from P. G. Master Lamberton was read
                              in which he says:"When supper has been disposed of and like Marius you
                              are sitting amid the ruins, then offer for me the following
                              sentiment:" <lb/><emph rend="italic">Odd Fellowship:</emph> Pure in
                              its precepts, noiseless in its benefactions, it is religion's humble
                              keeper in the promotion of peace and good will upon earth.</p>
                         <p>6. <emph rend="italic">R. W. G. Warden, J. Alex. Simpson:</emph> A true
                              Odd Fellow and gentleman. The interests of our Brotherhood could not
                              be committed to more worthy hands.</p>
                         <p>The following sentiment from R. W. G. Warden Simpson was then read:
                                   <lb/><emph rend="italic">Friendship, Love, and Truth:</emph> The
                              three links of an expanding chain that binds more willing captives
                              that any material chain ever welded by mortal hands--may they continue
                              to expand until sorrow shall have no want to relieve and no tear to
                              dry.</p>
                         <p>7. <emph rend="italic">R. W. G. See'y, Wm. Curtis:</emph> For 19 years
                              the historian of the doings of our Order in Pennsylvania. His long
                              experience, great knowledge and undenied capacity peculiarly qualify
                              him for the position he holds.</p>
                         <p>The annexed sentiment was furnished by R. W. G. See'y Curtis: <lb/><emph
                                   rend="italic">The Order of Odd Fellows in the United
                              States:</emph> Humble and lowly in its origin its mission has been
                              that of Love and Duty, following the precepts of our Great Master to
                              do good on earth and to bring peace and good will to all men.</p>
                         <p>8. <emph rend="italic">R. W. G. Treasurer, W. Richards Muckle:</emph>
                              His Integrity, Vigilance and Financial skill render it certain that so
                              long as he guards the "Strong Box" of our Order, nothing will get our
                              of it but by authority of law. </p>
                         <p>The following sentiment recived from R. W. G. Treasurer Muckle was
                              offered after this toast: <lb/><emph rend="italic">Odd
                              Fellowship:</emph>Its principles properly adhered to and practised,
                              bring man one step nearer perfection.</p>
                         <p>9. <emph rend="italic">Our Lodge:</emph> Altars at which all religious
                              persuasions may worship; retreats where the stranger will always find
                              a home; the distressed a brother's hand and welcome, and the children
                              of distant climes a language in which to make their wants known.</p>
                         <p>F. S. Stumbaugh replied to this sentiment in a very eloquent and
                              forcible manner. He alluded with apparent feeling to his own case,
                              when prostrated on a bed of sickness, he had found his brother Odd
                              Fellows' hands ever ready to relieve his wants and their hearts to
                              bear the burthen of his woes. He concluded by offering the following
                              sentiment: <lb/><emph rend="italic">The Brothers of our Order:</emph>
                              May they never falter in the discharge of their duty and may their
                              means never fail to relieve the distressed, comfort the widow and
                              educate the orphan.</p>
                         <p>10. <emph rend="italic">The Odd Fellow's Breast Plate:</emph>
                              "Friendship, Love and Truth;" "Faith, Hope and Charity;" "Liberty,
                              Equality and Fraternity;" "Industry, Integrity, Sobriety."</p>
                         <p>To this sentiment Mr. J. George Ripper responded. He remarked that he
                              had faith in Odd Fellowship. He believed that it infused into the
                              hearts of its votaries a principle of patriotism. Made him glory in
                              the national greatness of his country and feel the importance of
                              preserving her honor unsullied. He exhorted the Brethren to do nothing
                              of which they might be ashamed--nothing that would blot or tarnish
                              their personal or fraternal escutheon, and an unceasing light will
                              ever beam on them and their Order like that which shines from the
                              "glorious orb of day." He offered the following: <lb/><emph
                                   rend="italic">Our Country:</emph> The land of the free and the
                              home of the brave! May the Odd Fellow's heart ever cherish the
                              precious liberties of our common Country: and may they ever defend and
                              protect this happy Union with the bonds of "<emph rend="italic"
                                   >Friendship, Love and Truth.</emph>"</p>
                         <p>11. <emph rend="italic">The Lodge and the Fireside:</emph> "Friendship,
                              Love and Truth," the principles of the <emph rend="italic"
                              >first</emph>, are the sweetest virtues cherished at the <emph
                                   rend="italic">latter</emph>.--There should be no jealously
                              between them, for the best Odd Fellows are the best fathers, sons,
                              brothers and lovers.</p>
                         <p>W. S. Everett, Esq., replied to the sentiment. Odd Fellowship, he
                              remarked, was eminently a social institution in all its practical
                              bearings. It had none of the selfishness of asceticism in its
                              composition. Every principle in it was warm with sympathy, and alive
                              for the welfare of those we hold near and dear. Mr. Everett concluded
                              his very eloquent and appropriate remarks by proposing the following
                              sentiment: <lb/><emph rend="italic">Young Ladies and Old Maids:</emph>
                              They need not despair whilst there are 200, 000 <emph rend="italic"
                                   >Odd</emph> Fellows in the land, willing to give them <emph
                                   rend="italic">new</emph> names.</p>
                         <p><emph rend="italic">Our Symbols and Mysteries:</emph> Beautiful and
                              instructive to those who understand them.--"Ask and ye shall
                              receive--Seek and ye shall find- -Knock and it shall be opened to
                              you."</p>
                         <p>Dr. W. H. Boyle was called on for a response to this sentiment. He
                              observed that objections have been urged against the mystic language
                              of our order by those who do not understand its symbolic significance.
                              The principles of Odd Fellowship are taught chiefly by symbols. This
                              constitutes a universal language and enables us to hold "converse
                              sweet" with "all nations, tongues and kindreds of the earth." The
                              language of signs by which Odd Fellows recognise each other, is a
                              beautiful feature in the order, and one that should never be urged
                              against it by way of reproach. It is to a considerable extent the
                              language of us all. It has ever existed in all nations, and among all
                              classes of people. It is the first language of infancy, and is seen in
                              the farewell "grip" which old age gives as the last <emph
                                   rend="italic">token</emph> of affectionate regard. In the
                              salutatory waveing of the hand--in the nod of recognition--in the
                              gestures of the orator--in our motions in animated conversation, we
                              have examples of the language of signs.--Among the aborigines of this
                              continent the silent, but significent language of signs is much in
                              use. By drawing the hand crosswise across the eyebrows they indicate a
                              white, or civilized man, signifying he wears a hat. A spaniard the
                              designate by taking hold of the chin with the fore finger and thumb
                              which indicates he wears a beard. A storm is described by holding the
                              right hand over the head and moving it up and down to show the fall of
                              snow or rain. To tell the truth the sign is--the fore fingers of right
                              hand are held over the mouth. to like--the forefinger of the right
                              hand is passed over the mouth to the left shoulder, in which doubtless
                              originated the saying "<emph rend="italic">over the left</emph>." A
                              volume has been written on these, Indian signs which would afford a
                                   <emph rend="italic">curious</emph> subject of study to the Odd
                              Fellow, who professes to have improved and perfected this natural
                              language and reduced it to the beauty and order of a complete system.
                              He concluded by submitting the following sentiment:--</p>
                         <p>May the Odd Fellow who "throws a sign" unnecessarily never fail to
                              recieve a rebuke in having the "answer" withheld.</p>
                         <p><emph rend="italic">Our Visiting Brethren:</emph> We greet them
                              cordially and welcome them fraternally to our festal board. We bid
                              them "God Speed" in the good work of benevolence and love, and tho' we
                              cannot hold daily companionship with them on Earth--we trust to meet
                              them all in the <emph rend="italic">Grand Lodge</emph> above.</p>
                         <p><emph rend="italic">The Chief Marshal of the Day:</emph> Col: F. S.
                              Stumbaugh. The right man for the right place. May he ever shine a
                              "bright particular star" in our noble fraternity.</p>
                         <p><emph rend="italic">Our Host and Hostess:</emph> Mr. Abel Mishler and
                              Lady. The good taste they have displayed in getting up this Supper is
                              holy excelled by our <emph rend="italic">taste</emph> in getting it
                              down. <lb/>Volunteer Toasts. <lb/>By I. H. McCauley.--<emph
                                   rend="italic">Aaron Nicholls:</emph> A name identified with the
                              history of Odd Fellowship in Penna.--known wherever its branches have
                              been established--and honored wherever known as the first presiding
                              Officer of its Grand Lodge. <lb/>In offering this sentiment Mr.
                              McCauley gave a short biographical sketch of Aaron Nicholls and
                              exhibited the "Card" he obtained from his Lodge when he left his
                              mother country to seek a home in the Western world, and find an <emph
                                   rend="italic">unmarked grave</emph> in a church yard in this
                              borough. The following is a copy of the Card which is printed on thick
                              paper about six inches long and four wide:--It has a very ancient
                              appearance and is considered by the Odd Fellows a valuable relic.
                              <lb/>GRAND LODGE OF ODD FELLOWS, <lb/><emph rend="italic"
                              >Sheffield.</emph><lb/>I hereby certify that Mr. Aaron Nicholls was
                              registered as a Member of this Lodge, being a Past Grand of Lodge No.
                              2, this 21st day of March, 1806. As witness my hand and seal. <lb/>{
                              SEAL }no. 170.] SAMUEL BENNETT, <lb/>Grand Sec'y.</p>
                         <p>ON THE REVERSE.</p>
                         <p>The Sun, Moon and Stars. A dove with the Olive Branch. The Emblems of
                              the Order, with the British Lion, all inclosed in a wreath--Two
                              Brethren in full regalia--and below all, <lb/>"<emph rend="italic"
                                   >Amicitia, Amor et Veritas</emph>" <lb/>Friendship, Love and
                              Truth."</p>
                         <p>By W. H. Boyle--<emph rend="italic">The N. G. of Columbus Lodge,
                                   Speckmen Hicks:</emph> May he continue to pay his QUARTERS
                              regularly, in his subordinate Lodge below, until he obtains <emph
                                   rend="italic">quarters</emph> in the Grand Lodge above.</p>
                         <p>by A. R. Hurst--<emph rend="italic">Adam:</emph> The first Odd Fellow.
                              God was the priest, and Angels the witnesses at his wedding.</p>
                         <p>By B. F. Frey--<emph rend="italic">Past Grand Wm. Blankney:</emph> The
                              oldest Odd Fellow in our County. May he continue to live long--very
                              long--to cheer us with his presence and may his <emph rend="italic"
                                   >gray hairs</emph> never go down in sorrow to the grave.</p>
                         <p>By Committee of Arrangement--<emph rend="italic">Bro. Laverty:</emph>
                              The Chaplain of the day. We are deeply indebted to him for his
                              ministrations. May his days, like those of the Patriarchs of old, be
                              long in the land, and his passage into the Grand Lodge above, calm and
                              peaceful.</p>
                         <p>In reply to this sentiment the Reverend gentleman made some interesting
                              remarks as to his motive in joining the order--the good he had seen
                              resulting from its noble deeds of charity, and its adaptation to the
                              promotion of a spirit of fraternal fellowship among mankind.</p>
                         <p>By I. H. McCauley--<emph rend="italic">American Old Fellowship</emph>:
                              The offspring of "The Spirit of the Age." Its grand principle, the
                              practical recognition of <emph rend="italic">human brotherhood</emph>,
                              finds its appropriate home in a Republic whose foundation is <emph
                                   rend="italic">ploitical equality</emph>.</p>
                         <p><lb/>By Rev. Daniel Washburn, of Pottsville--<emph rend="italic">Our
                                   Benevolent Order:</emph> May peace, prosperity and brotherly
                              affection pervade its membership, caring for the sick and relieving
                              the distressed; and may integrity, fidelity and honor ever crown its
                              official station.</p>
                         <p>By a Guest--<emph rend="italic">The only correct</emph> EXPOSE <emph
                                   rend="italic">of Odd Fellowship:</emph> It is to be found in the
                                   <emph rend="italic">good deeds</emph> of the Order, and the <emph
                                   rend="italic">good conduct</emph> of its members.</p>
                         <p>By District Deputy, P. B. Housum--<emph rend="italic">The Odd Fellows of
                                   Pennsylvania:</emph> An army near fifty thousand strong. A host
                              with brave hearts and firm purposes, engaged in a "holy war" against
                              vice in all its forms. "<emph rend="italic">Friendship</emph> towards
                              man prompts the contest. <emph rend="italic">Love</emph> supplies the
                              weapons. <emph rend="italic">Truth</emph> consecrates the effort and
                              leads to victory."</p>
                         <p>By Col. F. S. Stumbaugh--<emph rend="italic">The Committee of
                                   Arrangements:</emph> Just the men we took them to be. They have
                              our thanks for the efficient manner in which they have discharged
                              their duties.</p>
                         <p><lb/>Conclusion. <lb/>The festivities were kept up until about 11
                              o'clock when the assemblage dispersed in an orderly and quiet manner
                              all present expressing themselves highly delighted with the enjoyments
                              of the day. </p>
                    </transcript>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                              <fn>F.S.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Housem</ln>
                              <fn>P.B.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Duncan</ln>
                              <fn>C.M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Laverty</ln>
                              <fn>D.A.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Rev.</pf>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>McCauley</ln>
                              <fn>I.H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Mishler</ln>
                              <fn>Abel</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hutchison</ln>
                              <fn>D.M.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Nicholson</ln>
                              <fn>James</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Lamberton</ln>
                              <fn>R.A.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Simpson</ln>
                              <fn>J. Alex</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Ripper</ln>
                              <fn>J. George</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Boyle</ln>
                              <fn>W.H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Hurst</ln>
                              <fn>A.R.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Frey</ln>
                              <fn>B.F.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Everett</ln>
                              <fn>W.S.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Boyle</ln>
                              <fn>W.H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf>Dr.</pf>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Details of the Odd Fellows 40th Anniversary celebration, held on April
                         26. Very long article that describes the procession, orations, and toasts
                         of the celebration. Bands and lodges from Shippensburg, Gettysburg,
                         Roxbury, and Mercersburg attended.</summary>
                    <note>frbrowser/may59.html#5.4a</note>
                    <look/>
               </div>
               <div type="a">
                    <column>4</column>
                    <head>Borough Election</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>McCauley</ln>
                              <fn>I.H.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Caufman</ln>
                              <fn>A.D.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Flack</ln>
                              <fn>George</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Banker</ln>
                              <fn>Andrew</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                              <fn>B.E.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Rensher</ln>
                              <fn>Samuel</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                              <fn>Emanuuel</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                              <fn>John</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Wright</ln>
                              <fn>J.B.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Henninger</ln>
                              <fn>Jacob</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Wood</ln>
                              <fn>T.B.</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Gross</ln>
                              <fn>George</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Results of the Borough of Chambersburg elections: Burgess--I. H.
                         McCauley; Town Council--A. D. Caufman, George Flack, Andrew Banker, B. E.
                         Tolbert, Samuel Rensher; Borough Auditors--Emanuuel Kuhn, John Rhodes, J.
                         B. Wright; School Directors--Jacob Henninger, T. B. Wood; High
                         Constable--George Gross.</summary>
               </div>
               <div type="s">
                    <column>5</column>
                    <head>Married</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                              <fn>John</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                              <fn>Levi</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Johnston</ln>
                              <fn>Sarah</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>Married on April 26.</summary>
               </div>
               <div type="o">
                    <column>5</column>
                    <head>Deaths</head>
                    <origin/>
                    <excerpt/>
                    <transcript/>
                    <trailer/>
                    <names>
                         <name>
                              <ln>Harrison</ln>
                              <fn>James</fn>
                              <sf/>
                              <pf/>
                         </name>
                    </names>
                    <summary>James Harrison, of Fayetteville, died on April 19. He was a member of
                         the Lutheran church.</summary>
               </div>
               <pageNote>Markets in column 5.</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04.06">
               <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04.07">
               <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
          </page>
          <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.04.08">
               <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
          </page>
     </paperBody>
</hwp>
