<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-08-24">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24.01">
            <div type="j">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Candidates</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sechrist</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morganthall</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcements of candidacy for local political offices. County treasurer:
                    Samuel Fisher, J. C. Snyder; Sheriffalty: A. J. Brand, Jacob C. Sechrist,
                    William Rebert, Jacob Sellers, James Piper, George Morganthall; District
                    Attorneyship: D. Watson Rowe, William S. Everett, John R. Orr, George Eyster,
                    George Welsh, James P. McClintock. Also appeared the week before.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>More Amalgamation; A Mysterious Disappearance Accounted For--Rich Developments
                    Among the British Abolitionists</head>
                <origin>Detroit Free Press</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story about the wife of a Canadian abolitionist running off with a black
                    farmer who had been living with them. She was found in a house that is owned by
                    a black and supposedly used for immoral activities.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Forney's Press on Personalities</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Valley Spirit is now fighting with the Philadelphia Press, because of the
                    Press's "outburst of virtuous indignation at the personalities of the Valley
                    Spirit." All stems from Spirit's attacks on McClure. Spirit calls the Press a
                    "Black Republican dung-spreader" and a "reeking pest-house of personal
                    defamation-a filthy sewer of stinking slander."</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A New Song</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>Dedicated to McClure's Menagerie, to be howled through the present
                    Senatorial Campaign.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Song mocking McClure, especially for his libel suit against the
                Spirit.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fred. Douglas [sic]</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"He would appear to forget altogether that the Creator Himself has made a
                    distinction when he established the great and immovable barrier of color between
                    the races."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p> This gentleman of color paid our town a visit, on Saturday last, to brighten
                        the prospects of his Republican friends which are now so hopelessly in the
                            <emph rend="italic">dark.</emph> There is no calling in question the
                        extraordinary ability of Mr. Douglass as an Orator. He is an elegant and
                        powerful speaker, and possesses a clear well modulated voice, and a style of
                        elocution unaffected and impressive. His discourse was well received by a
                        large and attentive auditory, and with occasional demonstrations of applause
                        from those who seemed disposed to favor his peculiar doctrine. His aim is to
                        place the negro on an equality with the white man--to have him eat at the
                        same table, sit in the same pew, and vote at the same ballot box. He would
                        appear to forget altogether that the Creator Himself has made a distinction
                        when he established the great and immovable barrier of color between the
                        races. Mr. Douglas certainly does not benefit his cause by opening his vials
                        of wrath on religion, or by representing our leading divines as monsters of
                        inhumanity. They certainly are as capable of knowing what is right and what
                        is wrong as he is, and may be supposed to be as honest in their views. We
                        are constrained to say that that portion of his discourse deserved the
                        pointed rebuke of the whole community.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglass</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports Douglass's visit to Chambersburg, but does not mention his meeting
                    with John Brown. Compliments him on his oratory, but not his message.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug59.html#8.24a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>McClure's Slander Suit</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Spirit is mad that McClure is suing them for libel.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.24.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
