<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-06-29">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote>This is a new volume: Number 13. Announcement on page 5.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29.01">
            <pageNote>Literature and book notices, European news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Transcript of June 8th</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>More of the Spirit's fight with the Transcript over Taney and Dred Scott.
                    Spirit argues that Transcript is taking Taney's most damning remarks out of
                    context. The Spirit wonders why it is not getting its copies of the
                Transcript.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Slavery in the Territories--The Position of the National Democracy</head>
                <origin>New Orleans Courier</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article from New Orleans Courier expresses Louisiana Democratic Party
                    opinion: Congress should not interfere with slavery in territories.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29.05">
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of Mr. Robinson</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robinson, a former Whig member of Congress, died on June 24. He was a
                    native of Antrim. He had suffered from a mysterious illness for 2
                years.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>McClure to the Rescue</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article dealing with local politics. Using oblique language, the article
                    pokes fun at the Transcript and the Opposition. Refers to a letter that appeared
                    in the Transcript from "Heavy Peg" that was critical of the Spirit.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>School Examination</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"There is no cause so deserving of our attention as that of education, and
                    no opportunity of a character like this should be permitted to pass by without
                    our bestowing on it by our presence that encouragement its importance demands."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--A public examination of the pupils of the Chambersburg Academy, Mr. J. K.
                        Shryock, Principal, commenced on Monday last, in the Academy Buildings, and
                        will continue until Wednesday. The friends of education and the public
                        generally have been invited to attend. There is no cause so deserving of our
                        attention as that of education, and no opportunity, of a character like
                        this, should be permitted to pass by without our bestowing on it by our
                        presence that encouragement its importance demands. We trust that this
                        examination may be well attended, and that our "future generation of citizen
                        kings" may feel that some persons, other than their teachers, take an
                        interest in their studies and progress in learning. We need hardly reiterate
                        a truth, so well know, that the school taught by Mr. Shryock, and his
                        talented associates, is about as perfect in every department as it is
                        possible to attain. A visit to this school, at this time, will not only be
                        an agreeable but a profitable spent hour, and will give us a better idea of
                        the advancement education is making among us than we could obtain in any
                        other way.</p>
                    <p>The Exhibition of the Music Class, in Franklin Hall, on Thursday evening,
                        will, we are assured, be a most delightful entertainment.--It is sufficient
                        to know that it is under the management of Mr. Shryock to predict for it a
                        complete success, both as regards the proficiency of the scholars and the
                        gratification their performance will afford the audience. The exhibition
                        will be gratuitous, but we hope some means will be adopted to prevent the
                        house from being filled with rowdy boys, who seem to attend such exhibitions
                        for no other purpose than to interrupt the performance with their unmannerly
                        clamor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>J.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of open examinations of pupils at Chambersburg Academy.
                    Praises quality of Academy education.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/june59.html#6.29a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Man as is a Man</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steake</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Amazement that Steake, at age 71, is still plowing his fields all day and
                    keeping up with much younger men.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Resolutions of Condolence</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Snively</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Resolutions honoring David Robinson, passed by the Franklin County
                Bar.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 4. Ads for many publications, including Scientific American,
                Godey's Ladies Book and Water Cure Journal.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.29.08">
            <pageNote>Column 3 has list of grand and traverse jurors for August court. Print is very
                small.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
