<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-06-08">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08.01">
            <pageNote>Literature and Book Notices include books about slavery and the slave trade,
                including one, "God Against Slavery," about how awful abolitionists have been to
                African progress.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Monument to the Founder of Our Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>Polished marble is very beautiful, but it is unsuited to the perpetuation
                    of the stern and rugged virtues of the early settlers of this valley. If ever we
                    erect a Monument to their memory, let us make it of stone quarried from the soil
                    their courage and industry won from the savage and subdued for our use.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--That interesting event, the presentation of a Flag to the Chambers
                        Artillery by the Hon. GEORGE CHAMBERS, which was duly chronicled in the
                        local columns of our last issue, has suggested to some one of our citizens
                        the propriety of erecting a Monument to the memory of BENJAMIN CHAMBERS, the
                        founder of our beautiful town. The citizen to whom this tribute to the
                        founder of Chambersburg has thus been suggested, has given the public his
                        views through the medium of a communication in the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Transcript</emph>. He pays a proper tribute to the stern virtues and
                        high courage of the men of the Revolutionary Age of the Republic, and does
                        some injustice to the present generation by attributing to them a want of
                        appreciation of the glorious deeds of their immortal ancestors.</p>
                    <p>We intend to endorse the proposition of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Transcript's</emph> correspondent to erect a monument to the memory of the
                        founder of our town, but we wish first to record our protest against his
                        repetition of the standing slander upon the men of the present day, that
                        they are insensible to the blessings they enjoy and ungrateful to the memory
                        of those who achieved their country's independence. That this is a slander
                        upon the present generation, is a fact of which any one can satisfy himself
                        very easily. Let him go upon our street and ask the first gray-haired sire
                        who totters along in life's decline, to name the greatest man that ever
                        walked the earth, and he will answer--GEORGE WASHINGTON. Let him put the
                        same question to the youngest schoolboy, and he will get the same answer.
                        Let him put it to all he meets--old and young , male and female--and the
                        answer of each and all will be the same. This feeling of admiration and
                        veneration for the Father of his Country is so universal, that it really
                        seems as if every American was <emph rend="italic">born</emph> with the
                        image of WASHINGTON impressed upon his heart.</p>
                    <p>Nor is the name of WASHINGTON alone held in admiring remembrance by those who
                        live and move and have their being in what are slightingly and unjustly
                        termed "these degenerate days." When the mind of an American of <emph
                            rend="italic">to day</emph> reverts to the trying times of our country's
                        struggle for independence, other venerated forms rise up beside that of the
                        Great Chief, and the names of ADAMS, JEFFERSON, FRANKLIN, HANCOCK, HENRY,
                        LAFAYETTE, GREENE, MERCKER, Once a resident of our county, we believe,)
                        MARION, PUTNAM, WARREN, and a host of others, burst from lips that name them
                        but to praise them. Why have these departed patriots, statesmen and warriors
                        such a deep hold on the affections of the present generation? Why is it
                        that, from youth through manhood to old age, the story we all read with the
                        greatest interest is the story of the Revolution? Unquestionably it is
                        because we cherish in our heart of hearts the liveliest gratitude to the
                        noble and self-sacrificing spirits who achieved the liberties we enjoy.</p>
                    <p>But let us recur to the proposed Monument. It would be an interesting feature
                        of our town and an appropriate tribute to the brave pioneer who planted the
                        flag of civilization on the banks of the Conococheague and and defended it
                        against the savages who swarmed around. The Academy . . . [text missing] . .
                        . proposes to locate it would not be the site we should select. If ever the
                        Monument is to be erected, it should be put on a <emph rend="italic">Public
                            Square</emph>, a place always open to citizens and strangers.
                        Unfortunately at this late day it is almost impossible to get an unimproved
                        piece of ground of sufficient extent for a Public Square within convenient
                        reach of the centre of town. The most suitable point, perhaps, would be the
                        lot owned by the Misses DENNY, and separated from the Academy grounds only
                        by an alley. This lot would make a very handsome little square. It has all
                        the advantages claimed for the Academy grounds, with others that those
                        grounds do not possess; and we have very little doubt that its amiable,
                        intelligent, and we may say <emph rend="italic">patriotic</emph> owners
                        would part with it for <emph rend="italic">this</emph> purpose, however
                        reluctant they might be to yield their title to it under other
                        circumstances.</p>
                    <p>In regard to the material of which the proposed Monument should be
                        constructed, we will say a word. Polished marble is very beautiful, but it
                        is unsuited to the perpetuation of the stern and rugged virtues of the early
                        settlers of this valley. If ever we erect a Monument to their memory, let us
                        make it of stone quarried from the soil their courage and industry won from
                        the savage and subdued for our use.</p>
                    <p>The name of the <emph rend="italic">Transcript's</emph> correspondent is
                        unknown to us. We have objected to certain parts of his article, but the
                        main point we have cordially endorsed. His proposal is one that must meet
                        general approbation, and we trust he will keep it before our people till the
                        morning sun and the evening stars shall greet a CHAMBERS MONUMENT in DENNY
                        SQUARE.</p>
                    <p>If the immediate accomplishment of this object on a scale worthy of an
                        enlightened community like ours be considered impracticable, might not
                        measures now be initiated which would ensure its fulfilment on the
                        Centennial Anniversary of the laying out of the town? The ground might be
                        secured and gradually embellished in the course of the next two or three
                        years, as means would justify, and in 1864 the design could be finally
                        carried out by the erection of the Monument, which might receive an
                        appropriate dedication on the Fourth of July.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Denny</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A local citizen has suggested in the Transcript that the town erect a
                    monument to B. Chambers, town founder. The Spirit endorses the proposal, but
                    protests the citizen's "slander upon the present generation."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/june59.html#6.8a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Transcript's Taney Slander</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains about the Transcript's unfair treatment of Justice
                Taney.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Ladies Attention</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>The Court House is often the place where the attendance of their fathers,
                    husbands, brothers and perhaps, "a dearer one still, and a nearer one" is
                    required, and something to please the eye, and glad the heart, may create a
                    happy thought and make them feel that "a thing of beauty is a joy forever."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--We would most respectfully, and earnestly, direct your attention to a
                        matter which we conceive would be a pleasant duty for you to perform. It is
                        this- -our County Commissioners have laid off the yard in tear of the Court
                        House in a most beautiful and ornamental manner, and desire to have it
                        further adorned by planting Flowers and Shrubery. This they think the ladies
                        of our county would gladly undertake, and will, therefore, leave it to be
                        adorned by them in whatever manner their good taste may suggest, always
                        ready to give whatever assistance may be needed. We must commend our
                        Commissioners for the view they have taken of this matter--it is right and
                        considerate, and we hope our ladies will not be backward in coming forward
                        with whatever offering they have to bestow; no matter how trifling the donor
                        may consider it, it will gratefully receive a place. The Court House is
                        often the place where the attendance of their fathers, husbands, brothers
                        and perhaps, "a dearer one still, and a nearer one" is required, and
                        something to please the eye, and glad the heart, may create a happy thought
                        and make them feel that "a thing of beauty is a joy forever."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the ladies of the town help out the county commissioners by
                    planting flowers and shrubs around the Court House. Article also suggests that
                    the planting would make the Court House nicer for their fathers, husbands, and
                    brothers.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/june59.html#6.8b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Military Encampment</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>The companies in attendance presented a handsome appearance and are not
                    surpassed by any in the State for correct discipline, and the accuracy with
                    which they perform all military evolutions.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Military Encampment held at this place, and which commenced on Tuesday
                        week last, continued until Friday forenoon, when it was broken up and the
                        soldiery assembled returned to their homes, and our town once more resumed
                        its wanted quiet. The companies in attendance presented a handsome
                        appearance and are not surpassed by any in the State for correct discipline,
                        and the accuracy with which they perform all military evolutions. The
                        encampment throughout was well conducted and all its arrangements were in
                        strict conformity with the laws and regulations prescribed for camp duty. We
                        saw much that we would like to praise but it might seem invidious in us to
                        draw distinctions where all looked well, behaved well, and performed their
                        duty well. The companies present, we have no doubt, profited much by their
                        instructions and experience in the duties of camp life, while they socially
                        enjoyed themselves in a delightful manner, and contributed greatly to the
                        gratification of the immense crowds assembled to witness the display.</p>
                    <p>The following officers and companies were in attendance:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Brigadier General:</emph> DAVID DETRICH.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Brigade Inspector:</emph> J. McCURDY.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Colonel:</emph> F. S. STUMBAUGH.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Major:</emph> R. W. McALLEN.</p>
                    <p>COMPANIES.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">St. Thomas Artillery</emph>.--From St. Thomas. Captain,
                        James G. Elder; 1st Lieutenant, Jacob West; 1st Lieutenant, junior, D. W.
                        Dixon; 2d Lieutenant, A. H. Stump. Numbers 40 men.</p>
                    <p>[text missing]. . . Numbers 40 men.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Washington Blues</emph>.--From Harrisonville, Fulton
                        County. Captain, James C. Austin; 1st Lieutenant, D. H. Betz; 2d Lieutenant,
                        David L. Michaels; 3d Lieutenant, Michael Miller. The company numbers 57
                        men, and was the largest on the ground.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Light Infantry</emph>.--From Greencastle, Capt., Joseph
                        Stickle; 1st Lieutenant, Edgar Washabaugh; 2nd Lieutenant, A. Kreitzer.
                        Numbers 30 men.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Washington Blues</emph>.--From Fannetsburg.--Captain,
                        Samuel Walker; 1st Lieutenant, John Walker; 2d Lieutenant, Jno. H.
                        Witherow.--Numbers 40 men.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Wayne Rifles</emph>.--From Waynesboro'. Capt., J. H.
                        Clayton; 1st Lieutenant, George J. Balsley; 2d Lieutenant, Emanuel
                        Defendaffer.--Numbers 30 men.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Union Guards</emph>.--From Mercersburg, Capt. F. Winger;
                        1st Lieutenant, Thomas McAfee; 2d Lieutenant, E. Hammill. Numbers 40 men.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Light Dragoons</emph>.--Chambersburg. Captain, C. T.
                        Campbell; 1st Lieutenant, K. S. Taylor; 2d Lieutenant, C. C. Folts. Numbers
                        40 men.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chambers Artillery</emph>.--Chambersburg. Capt., F. S.
                        Stumbaugh; 1st Lieutenant, P. B. Housum; 1st Lieutenant, junior, Matthew
                        Gillan; 2d Lieutenant, Calvin Duncan. Number 50 men.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCurdy</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>B.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stump</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sansom</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Betz</ln>
                        <fn>D.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michaels</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stickles</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Edgar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreiser</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witheron</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balley</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Defendaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Emmanual</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAfee</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammill</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>C.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>K.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>C.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>2d Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant, junior</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>2d Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Description of a four-day local military encampment, which lasted from May
                    31 to June 3. Praises companies and officers present and lists them: St. Thomas
                    Artillery, National Guards (McConnelsburg); Washington Blues (Harrisonville);
                    Wayne Rifles (Waynesboro); Union Guards; Light Dragoons; Chambers Artillery.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/june59.html#6.8c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sharp Shooting</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitemask</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn>A.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contest between two local dealers in reapers.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>Latrobe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Solmon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Siebert</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Barnet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>H. Bard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perry</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lutz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunce</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kearny</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duke</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Boyd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Election of officers for Friendship Fire Company.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.06.08.08">
            <pageNote>Agricultural advice.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
