<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-08-31">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>YE SKEETERS HEV CUM.</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Well yer a tricky varmint after all; Ye put me in mind of lawyers, and yer
                    bout as tricky. Yer always found inside a bar, reddy to Run up a bill, and it
                    keeps a feller sparrin To keep yer off, he gits no sleap, Ye make the nite
                    mornin, and the mornin, Nite, fines."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>YE SKEETERS HEV CUM.</p>
                    <p>August--and yer here, skeeters. <lb/>I hev been a lookin for ye sum time
                        since, <lb/>An a hopin that ye woodnt cum <lb/>At all, but yer bein here
                        <lb/>Wont keep me from speakin out mi mind, <lb/>Fur ive got no respect fur
                        yer presents ye tarnal <lb/>Pests, wurs than the frogs that plagued old
                        Noar, <lb/>And made him let the gyptians all go free; <lb/>But that's an ole
                        subjec.</p>
                    <p>e needn't be buzzin roun an makin so much ado, <lb/>For yer nothin but a
                        skeeter no how, <lb/>A cussed little thing, and a littler yit <lb/>When ye
                        was a wiggle tail, <lb/>Spose ye don't remember whar ye cum frum, <lb/>Folks
                        ginerally do it when they git up a notch, <lb/>But I can't think what ye was
                        made fur, no how, <lb/>Cept it was to keep the perlice awake; well, I spect
                        that was it.</p>
                    <p>Sum say ye sing, so does a hoss, <lb/>The durndest singin ever I hearn, if
                        yer call it singin, <lb/>Ye can quit, or else ile own ive get no year
                        <lb/>For musick; if other poits can find virtues in ye, <lb/>Skeeters, its
                        morn I kin, I don't think yer <lb/>Performans'll ever raise an angel to the
                        skies, <lb/>Specially if I'm the angel.</p>
                    <p>Well yer a tricky varmint after all; <lb/>Ye put me in mind of lawyers, and
                        yer bout as tricky. <lb/>Yer always found inside a bar, reddy to <lb/>Run up
                        a bill, and it keeps a feller sparrin <lb/>To keep yer off, he gits no
                        sleap, <lb/>Ye make the nite mornin, and the mornin, <lb/>Nite, fines.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A political poem talking against Skeeters (mosquitoes)--that is a reference
                    to Republicans.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug59.html#8.31a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Stories on this page all have moral lessons, especially for women on how to be
                a good wife (undemanding, quiet, good housekeeper etc).</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Split Lion</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story is about McClure, but first few paragraphs are about a lion in a
                    circus being split in two and reattached. Draws an analogy to McClure--he has
                    two contradictory sides.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Blondin Coming</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Mons. Blondin's success in carrying a man over the yawning chasm of
                    Niagara below the falls, has, we understand, obtained for him a brilliant
                    engagement here. The Executive Committee of the People's Politician's Party have
                    engaged him to carry Col. McClure over this district, on a rope stretched from
                    Scrub Ridge to McSherrystown. A summerset will be turned at every election
                    district if required, the signal for which will be 'Simon says-up!'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>More satire aimed at McClure.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Valley Spirit; Our Country as it is</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The Opposition not only attack every Democratic measure, but they heap the
                    foulest calumny upon its men. What is it to them to abuse our honored Buchanan,
                    the man who holds the highest office in the gift of a free people? What is it to
                    the Opposition party to hurl their malice upon the venerable Cass, or the high
                    minded, talented Black?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR:--There is no nation upon the globe that enjoys greater blessings,
                        both religious and political, than the people of the United States, bound
                        together, as it were, by the strong chain of "Virtue, Liberty and
                        Independence." For nearly one century has the "Star Spangled Banner" been
                        waving "over this land of the free and the home of the brave," and
                        prosperity and happiness have crowned the toil and labor of its citizens.</p>
                    <p>But what has been the cause of all this greatness? What else, but the liberal
                        principles embodied in that great Chart, the American Constitution, framed
                        and handed down to us by that noble band of Patriots, whose memory is
                        cherished with veneration by every true hearted American? That Constitution
                        with "Equal Rights and Equal Laws" as its motto, stands without a parallel
                        in the history of nations, and will ever be cherished with admiration by a
                        grateful people. Under that Constitution our Country has been extending its
                        bounds with unparalleled rapidity. State after State has been added to the
                        Union, and the cry is "still they come."</p>
                    <p>The Democratic party, under whose rule for the last fifty years--with but few
                        exceptions--we have grown with such giant steps, has ever aimed to carry out
                        the provisions as they are laid down by this great National Chart. It is the
                        Democratic party whose aim has always been to promote the prosperity of our
                        people. She has been the protector of our country's rights both at home and
                        abroad. She has vindicated the unsullied honor of our Union. The Democratic
                        party, sir, has given her aid to protect the oppressed of all nations who
                        seek this country as an asylum. History itself testifies to these facts, and
                        no party on earth can rob her of these laurels.</p>
                    <p>Notwithstanding all these facts, however, there is still a faction of
                        unprincipled men, who would vain make one believe, that our country is
                        ruined, that we are on the verge of bankruptcy, and that another course of
                        policy must be pursued if we are to continue an independent people! There
                        hatred to any and all measures which are advocated by the great Democratic
                        party, is notorious. No matter how salutary a measure may be, if the
                        Democracy support it, the Opposition are down to it, "like a thousand
                        brick." The fact is the Opposition cannot boast of one great measure which
                        they ever advocated that stood the test; hence their opposition to anything
                        that has its origin in the Democratic party. The Opposition not only attack
                        every Democratic measure, but they heap the foulest calumny upon its men.
                        What is it to them to abuse our honored Buchanan, the man who holds the
                        highest office in the gift of a free people? What is it to the Opposition
                        party to hurl their malice upon the venerable Cass, or the high minded,
                        talented Black? men, whose whole life has been faithfully devoted to the
                        welfare of our common country; men, who are an honor to any nation, and
                        whose services are and will ever be appreciated by the generous hearts of
                        our people.</p>
                    <p>But there is a time coming when the sovereign people of the United States
                        will hurl back with contempt the calumny which the Opposition party heap
                        upon our great men, and be more firmly united as freemen, belonging to the
                        great National Democratic party. More anon.</p>
                    <p>FRANKLIN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Franklin</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Partisan letter, addressed to "Mr. Editor," about how wonderful America is.
                    Its greatness can only be protected by the Democratic party.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug59.html#8.31b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Slave Trade and Sensation Manufacturers</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussion of measures that the government has used to curb the African
                    trade. Argues that these measures do not favor the South or slave traders.
                    Believes that Republicans are just trying to stir up trouble.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democratic County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>D.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>E.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillipy</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>Woodrow</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheary</ln>
                        <fn>Aug.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pike</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacoby</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hearty</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>D.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>J.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clagston</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stockbridge</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowell</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>R.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>N.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sechrist</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morganthall</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harburg</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McD</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushwan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowar</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliot</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>L.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of Democratic County Convention. List of Officers and delegates
                    (print is very small and very faint). Elections for County Ticket.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>High Treason!</head>
                <origin>Transcript</origin>
                <excerpt> "The above is a pretty fair sample of the quality of mental food dished up
                        <emph rend="italic">Weakly [sic]</emph> to the readers of the <emph
                        rend="italic">Transcript</emph>. The concern was at low ebb enough before
                    the libellous pen of McClure resumed its willing work of defamation but his bad
                    example has sunk it so low that contempt can hardly reach it at a nine days
                    tumble. Let us see how a plain tale will knock the music out of the above <emph
                        rend="italic">niggerism</emph>." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Nigger Democracy, in a rage at their loss of influence and power in the
                        South, are beginning to turn their backs upon their former friends and
                        allies.-- Last Saturday night their leader Fred. Douglass, the notorious
                        Negro Orator from the State of New York, delivered a <emph rend="italic"
                            >flaming</emph> address to <emph rend="italic">his friends and
                        admirers</emph>, in the Public Hall in this place. We noticed one of the
                        editors of the Valley Spirit sitting in a front seat--evidently as the
                        "right supporter" of the sable speaker. What is Democracy coming to? What
                        expedients will not that party resort to in order to rescue their sinking
                        political ship? They have brought this man here for political effect. They
                        became in 1844, the most ardent friends of the Tariff of '42, and succeeded
                        in carrying the election, under that banner. Are they now about to don the
                        garb of <emph rend="italic">abolitionism</emph>? Do they foolishly think
                        this will enable them to carry the North? If they are after this game, why
                        not pursue it openly? All underhanded work is despicable. How did it <emph
                            rend="italic">happen</emph> that the principal [sic] editor of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph>--that is when there is any editorial in that
                        barren sheet--John M Cooper, a clerk in Attorney General Black's Office, at
                        Washington, and this wooly headed son of Africa, Fred. Douglass, both
                        dropped so suddenly and unexpectedly into our midst, about the same time?</p>
                    <p>The above is a pretty fair sample of the quality of mental food dished up
                            <emph rend="italic">Weakly [sic]</emph> to the readers of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Transcript</emph>. The concern was at low ebb enough
                        before the libellous pen of McClure resumed its willing work of defamation
                        but his bad example has sunk it so low that contempt can hardly reach it at
                        a nine days tumble. Let us see how a plain tale will knock the music out of
                        the above <emph rend="italic">niggerism</emph>. The nigger Douglass visited
                        this place as a well known ally of the Republican party. His bills for his
                        meeting were printed at the <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> office.
                        The editor of that paper honored him with a call at the negro house he
                        stopped at, somewhere on the suburbs of the town, under pretence of getting
                        his hair oiled. The same editor held the "second post of honor," with two
                        other niggers, on the evening of the lecture, acting as usherer behind the
                        scenes, and taking upon himself the dignified business of introducing
                        prominent members of his party to the Darkey. On Sunday while Douglass
                        remained in town he sent an Ambassador of State, in the person of Frank
                        Myers, a colored individual, to the residence of the editor of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Transcript</emph> to know if he required his services any
                        longer in this locality. The little editor was cheek by jowl with the nigger
                        in all his movements, but <emph rend="italic">his</emph> piety seems to have
                        received a shock from the infidel sentiments, and treasonable doctrines of
                        his wooly-headed companion. It would be advisable for him to visit the negro
                        hovel frequently, and have his hair well oiled, or there is danger of it
                        becoming as wooly as that of his Republican ally. We have some hope for the
                            <emph rend="italic">Transcript</emph> editor after all.-- For once in
                        his life he appears ashamed of his <emph rend="italic">niggerism</emph> and
                        would gladly rid himself, and his party, of the disgrace brought upon both
                        by his overweening love for the nigger. We have no fault to find with such a
                        praise-worthy effort on his part, but he must not attempt to palm his
                        infidel negro friends on the Democratic party. It won't stand the
                    stench.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglass</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Spirit includes Transcript's article about Frederick Douglass's visit,
                    which basically accuses the Spirit and the Democrats of being abolitionists and
                    cozying up to Douglass. According to the Spirit, McClure and the Transcript are
                    being hypocrites, since Douglass is a Republican and had his advertisements
                    printed at the Transcript office, and the Transcript's editor called on
                    Douglass.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug59.html#8.31d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Balloon Ascension</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of another local balloon ascension, attended by thousands of
                    visitors. Includes descriptive letter from John Light, the
                ascensionist.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.31.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
