<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-08-17">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>17</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17.01">
            <pageNote>Page is very faint. Small article about Mississippi in column 1 was also in
                Spectator. Report from Burton and Speke in Africa. Kentucky, Alabama, and Texas
                elections in column 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gov. Wise's Confession</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains article from Richmond Enquirer all about Wise and the letter he
                    sent to the New York Democrats. Given a lot of space in the Spectator also.
                    Contains full exchange of letters.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Effects of Emancipation on the African Race</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>\This article claims that West Indian blacks express no gratitude to the
                    English workingmen who secured their freedom. The article gives a negative
                    characterization of free blacks.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Operations of the Under-Ground Railroad.</head>
                <origin>New Bedford Mercury</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Philadelphian gave a speech in Massachusetts detailing operations of the
                    underground railroad--hiding out, etc.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Print is very faint.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Dismal</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Highly partisan report of the "Peoples Party" meeting at the
                courthouse.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockson</ln>
                        <fn>J.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunshod</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of local Democratic meeting.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Public Library</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"--The managers of the Public Library and Reading Room expect to open to
                    the Public on the First of September."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The managers of the Public Library and Reading Room expect to open to the
                        Public on the First of September. They have a convenient room in the Mansion
                        House, and have selected a large and valuable library. It is to be hoped
                        that this Enterprise will be sustained by our citizens. So far it has been
                        the work of but a few enterprising persons. There are many in our midst
                        perfectly able to help, who have yet shown no interest in it. Come,
                        Gentlemen, lend your aid.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Library to open on September 1. The Spirit is still trying to drum up more
                    support for it.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug59.html#8.17a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Pavements</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"--We have not said any thing about the state of the pavements lately; our
                    town Fathers are doing very well on the streets, and we trust the side walks
                    will next claim their attention."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--We have not said any thing about the state of the pavements lately; our
                        town Fathers are doing very well on the streets, and we trust the side walks
                        will next claim their attention. In the mean time, we would call their
                        attention to a board walk that is considered a public nuisance, and calls
                        loudly for removal.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Compliments Town Fathers on upkeep of pavements. Calls for removal of
                    boardwalk, which is "a public nuisance."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/aug59.html#8.17b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Admitted</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Admitted to county bar.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Potter</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolnist</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgh</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rensler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>R.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cassidy</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stricky</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glenn</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>August Court term proceedings. Same cases as always: Assault, larceny,
                    mischief.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Casselman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sipe</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at Camp Hill on August 3.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>C.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eliza Anna, age 10 months, died on July 29th.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page is very faint, especially columns 3-4. Markets in columns
            4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.08.17.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Paris Fashions for August</head>
                <origin>Galignani's Messenger</origin>
                <excerpt>"Fashion in bonnets is nearly at a stand still, and our artists, for the
                    time being, have ceased racking their brains for novelties."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Light summer toilets engross all the attention, and there is a great run of
                        white, by far the prettiest wear for this melting period of the year. What,
                        for instance, is cooler or more harmonious than a white robe.</p>
                    <p>A fashionable costume consists of three distinct parts--dress, fichu, and
                        mantle-- all of which can be worn together or separately. The skirt is of
                        white muslin, and there are two flounces and two large bouillons, and two
                        flounces and two bouillons again. In the hem of the flounces is a blue,
                        pink, or green rib and and a much wider one is run underneath the bouillons.
                        The corsage is low, lined with silk the color of the riband, and a petticoat
                        of the same silk is worn with the skirt. The sleeves, reaching to the middle
                        of the arm, have two flounces and four bouillons, carried nearly up to the
                        shoulder. At the waist is also a riband, fastening either in front or
                        behind, and, if the dress is preferred high, the shoulders can be covered
                        with a fichu composed of flounces and bouillons, and drawn at the throat
                        with riband. For outdoors this toilet is completed by a mantle trimmed to
                        match the skirt and . . . [text missing] . . . length and voluminousness of
                        this mantle that distinguishes it from all that have been worn hitherto, and
                        it is patronised by those ladies who are always on the watch for new and
                        striking changes.</p>
                    <p>For morning wear there is nothing equal to clear muslin, colored or figured,
                        made with loose jacket or full bodice; either the body or jacket is fastened
                        in front by bows of muslin, the edges of which are rounded and edged with a
                        guipure.</p>
                    <p>Fashion in bonnets is nearly at a stand still, and our artists, for the time
                        being, have ceased racking their brains for novelties. The newest thing we
                        can mention is a bonnet made of fine black hair, embroidered with buttercups
                        in silken straw. The riband used in trimming has a black ground, and the
                        flowers at the side entirely black with jet centres. The effect of the
                        combination is very original, and it has the advantage of defying dust.</p>
                    <p>The heat is too great for caps to be worn in the house, and their place is
                        prettily supplied by resilles of silk lace. A wide riband goes all round and
                        terminates in a bow on one side; but, in order to render this coiffure
                        perfectly graceful it should have something like a light hood at the back.
                        If the resille is made of gold or silver thread, it can be worn in the ball
                        room by young girls, and Spanish acorns, finely worked, serve to complete
                        it. Fair women can wear the hood of the black lace, which keeps its
                        freshness and is not oppressively hot. Elderly ladies can line them with
                        thin silk, and those who have plenty of hair have only to put a flower on
                        one side, and they are at once in possession of a charming coiffure.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A discussion of the latest fashions from France.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
