<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0139"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0139">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: P.H. Powers to his Wife, December
                    17, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to his wife, december 17 1862</title>
        <author>Powers, P. H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>David Samuel Freed </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0139</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1998 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501798</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: P.H. Powers to his Wife, December 17 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to his wife, december 17 1862</title>
            <author>P. H. Powers</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Photocopy from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-17">1862-12-17 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Family </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 1st Va. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: none </term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A0139T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Powers writes to his wife about his cavalry's participation in the battle of
                    Fredericksburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Partial address containing Winchester, Virginia and date. 
                    <name type="recipient">Wife</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-17">Dec 17 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Fredericksburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dearest Wife. </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I wrote you very hurriedly last Saturday and took this letter by Major Browns who
                    was going directly to the Valley. I hope you received it. At the time I wrote
                    the battle was raging. And as soon as it was finished I rode along the lines to
                    ascertain how this day was going. The firing was incessant and grand. By the
                    time I reached our left where Jackson was engaged, the enemy were repulsed and
                    driven with great loss into Fredericksburg and under cover of his heavy
                    batteries over the opposite side of the river. I spent the night with Bud James.
                    The next day we confidently expected a reversal of this fight. And I again rode
                    along the line of battle. The enemy were drawn up in large forces and in sight;
                    but the severe punishment he had reseived the day before deterred him from
                    pursuing the attack. Thus the two armies remained all day Sunday and Monday.
                    Monday Afternoon the enemy asked permission to bury his dead, which was granted.
                    Monday night he hurriedly and quickly withdrew the slain army across the
                    Rappahannock leaving some 200 or 300 of his dead unburied. Yesterday morning I
                    rode over the battle field and counted in our place fifty five dead bodies,
                    lying dark and cold. And almost naked. A most ghastly experience. They had been
                    carried to some spot for burial, but their inhumane friends had left that duty
                    unperformed and under cover of the truce flag vacated their position - So ends
                    the Battle of Fredericksburg which I suppose Burnside will claim as a great
                    victory. Prisoners said that he ordered a renewal of the attack on Sunday
                    Morning, but could not get his men to come up to the scratch. His Generals
                    remonstrated with him that it was impossible to carry our position. And then the
                    On to Richmond is again delayed. Last evening Jackson's Corps moved towards Port
                    Royal. And one now believes that place and Fredericksburg shows what the enemy
                    are about. I have not heard. -- Changing his base I suppose. </p>
                <p>It is bitter cold to night, but very comfortable in our tent. A little stove
                    keeping it warm, but not as comfortable as by your side. No other place can be.
                    I cannot lay down much. I miss you. how I long to be with you again. but alas I
                    fear we can not be much together again until this war closes. And when will that
                    be? God only knows -- Could you see Mrs. Hall soon <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> may send
                    word to Mr. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> that his brother is well. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>Mr
                    Ratliff reached camp safely -- Give love to All. Kiss <unclear>my</unclear>
                    little ones for me. And for my <unclear>sake</unclear> endure the
                        <unclear>privations</unclear> of your situation as wonderfully as possible.
                    I shall take care of myself. And get word to you again as soon as possible. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Ever yours </salute>
                    <signed>P.H. Powers </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
