<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0310"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A0310">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: James R. McCutchan to Rachel Ann McCutchan,
     March 17, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county james r mccutchan to rachel ann mccutchan, march 17 1862</title>
        <author>McCutchan, James R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A0310</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501818</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: James R. McCutchan to Rachel Ann McCutchan, March 17, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county james r mccutchan to rachel ann mccutchan, march 17 1862</title>
            <author>James R. McCutchan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Rockbridge Historical Society Collection, Special
       Collections, Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-03-17">1862-03-17</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Home Front, Patriotism, Troop Movement, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A0310T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>McCutchan's letter describes the beauty of the Shenandoah Valley where his regiment is
     encamped, as well as the sad goodbyes he witnessed leaving Winchester and Strausburg.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-03-17">March 17th, 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Near Mt. Jackson</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Rate,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I received your letter some time since + would have answered sooner, but times have been too
     stiring for a while to spend much time writing letters. </p>

    <p>We left Winchester on the 11<hi rend="super">th</hi>, of this month + fell back to
     Strausburg; we stayed there a few days, + we are now about to middle way between Edinburg + Mt.
     Jackson. Our encampment is a very pretty one, in a beautiful pine grove, on the bank of the
     Shenandoah River. The surrounding country is exceedingly beautiful rivalling any in natural
     charm that I have ever seen.</p>

    <p>I felt sad when we left Winchester. although it is a very corrupt place in my estimation
     still there are a great many there who <orig reg="are">ar</orig> true and loyal to the South +
     it was hard to leave them to the mercies of those who have no hearts to feel even for
     themselves or others. Some were laughing + some crying as we came through town + there were
     many sad partings too - Two companies in our <abbr expan="regiment">reg'mt</abbr> were
     principally made up in Winchester, + these were forced to part with those near and dear to
     them.</p>

    <p>They were compelled to have mothers + sisters <pb n="2"/>+ wives, + little ones, who were all
     they had on Earth to love, + leave them too, without a hope of seeing them again + no prospect
     of hearing from them. I had to cry myself when I came through Strausburg. The doors + pavements
     were filled with ladies old + young + even the little children were weeping <hi
      rend="underline">forced</hi> to do so by the tears of their Mothers + Sisters. Such scenes are
     romantic, but I envy them not their feelings, when they feel themselves cut <orig reg="off"
     >of</orig> from their friends + left to the tender mercies of those <hi rend="underline">black
      hearted traitors</hi>, who are strangers to mercy. <unclear/> there is a time of retribution
     coming a time when we can relieve the broken hearted + lift them from the dust into which they
     have been trampled by the unhallowed foot of the oppressor.</p>

    <p>Our last stopping place was between Woodstock + Edinburg; we stayed there one night. It was
     the most romantic place I ever saw. Right on the edge of a high cliff on the side of the
     Shenandoah River. The cliff is on one side of the turnpike + the railroad on the other side
     crosses a deep chasm on trussel work 130 feet high. I will send you some Spruce Pine that I got
     there. I must write some to your Ma.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Yours truly</salute>
     <signed>J.R.M.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
