<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0321"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0321">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: P.H. Powers to Mrs. P.H. Powers, December 25,
     1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to mrs p h powers, december 25 1862</title>
        <author>Powers, P.H. </author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>David Samuel Freed </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 7</num> kilobytes </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">A0321</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved. </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501829</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War. </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>This transcription was taken from a photocopy of the original.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: P.H. Powers to Mrs. P.H. Powers, December 25, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to mrs p h powers, december 25 1862</title>
            <author>P.H. Powers </author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""/>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Source Copy Consulted: Photocopy from the collection of Fredericksburg- Spotsylvania County
       Battlefields National Memorial Military Park, Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-12-25">1862-12-25 </date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Women, Family, Home Front, Camp Life, Battle Description, National Government, Patriotism </term>
          <term>Regiment: 1st Va. Cav. </term>
          <term>Company: none </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp> </resp>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected. </item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="A0321T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Powers wishes his wife a Merry Christmas and informs her that the Confederates whipped
     Burnside at Fredericksburg and are now hoping for a peaceful separation from the Union.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Dec 25th 1862 Mrs P.H. Powers Care of Dr A.L. Baldwin Winchester, Virginia 
     <name type="recipient">Wife</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-12-25">Dec 25th 1862 </date>
      <name type="place">Camp Near Fredricksburg</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dearest Wife,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I hardly have the heart to wish you a Merry Christmas this beautiful Christmas Morning,
     because I will know merriment is not for you this day but I can and do wish you a happy day and
     the same to our little dears, who I suppose must be content with very meager gifts and very few
     sweet things. I thought of them when I first awoke this morning about day - And wondered what
     you managed to put in their stockings. Memory went back to the many happy Christmas days we
     have spent together with them. Alas! will the good old times ever return again? And you and I
     and our little ones dwell together in peace? I hope so. I believe so, but the heart
      <unclear>sickens</unclear> with the deferred hope.</p>

    <p>As I have been Jim's chief <hi rend="underline">cook</hi> for a week, since his servant left
     not much time was given me this morning for such sad affections, with the responsibilty of a
     Christmas breakfast on my mind. So I stirred myself from a warm bed <pb n="2"/><del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>. A Major Quartermaster to a Captain <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> but necessity - is a hard
     Master. And you know I can do anything I <hi rend="underline">try</hi> - better cook than
     starve. I wish you could have been present to witness my success and partake of my viandes -
     Barbecue Rabbit - Beef Hash with Potatoes, hot bread and coffee. If the darkies all leave us, I
     shall be able to render you some Assistance. We are very comfortable in camp - have good Tents,
     and wood in abundance to keep off the frost. I have been exeedingly busy for the last week
     assisting Jim in paying off the troops and really he needed it. He worries at every thing -
     Allows every trifle to ruffle his equanimity and makes himself constantly unhappy without
     cause. I wish from my heart he could get out of the Department he is in. Though I see no hope
     for him -</p>

    <p>He had a letter from Robert yesterday - All well. And nothing new - I have written you
     several times since I have been here but as yet have not heard from you. Continue to write -
     some of your letters will<pb n="3"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>. I wrote you some account of the great fight - but you will see from the
     papers how Terribly whipped Burnside was, and what a commotion it has produced in Yankeedom. I
     think the sky brightens and our chances for peace improve. But still the war may linger on
     another year, or even to the end of Lincoln's term. It is as warm this morning as June. And
     every thing bright - If I only was with you for the day at least I would have a happy Christmas
     - </p>


    <p>We are invited to dine with Tom Ballard - And as I am interrupted, I must now stop. With love
     to all - And kisses and loving messages to my little <unclear>pups</unclear>,</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Very <abbr expan="Affectionately">Affy</abbr> Yours</salute>
     <signed>
      <hi rend="underline">P.H. Powers</hi>
     </signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
