<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0329"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0329">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    March 1, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, march 1 1862</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0329 </idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998-03-31">3/31/98 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501837</idno>
      </publicationStmt>

            <seriesStmt>
                <p> </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, March 1, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, march 1 1862</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-03-01">1862-03-01 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement </term>
                    <term>Regiment:52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>Company:F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0329T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh tells about a southerner who has turned to guiding Federal troops through
                    his native Virginia.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-03-01">March 1st, 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Alleghehany, Pochohontas, VA </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Sir I and Fry received the letter you sent us on the 25th February and was glad
                    to hear from you all at home. I would have answered you letter sooner but did
                    not feel well enough. I have had the jaundice working on me for about eight days
                    now which makes me feel very lowlifed and mean. they have come out on me now. I
                    look about as yellow as a pumpkin. I feel better now since they have come out on
                    me. You were speaking of reenlisting. I have not reenlisted yet nor none of our
                    company have yet. it is a heap talk in the regiment about reenlisting. I have
                    come to the conclusion to wait awhile and see how I get along with my first
                    twelve months before I reenlist. As to the property Mother has left I have
                    nothing to say one way or another. any way that suits you all will suit me. We
                    had a false alarm here on the 22nd of Feb. about fifteen yanks and old slaten
                    the Yankees pilot come up to Wilfongs about 12 o clock in the night and swore
                    that the rebels would be driven out of camp in a few hours then went away and
                    when they got out of sight Wilfong brought the news to camp. we were rousted out
                    about half past one and waited with expectation till day but they never come.
                    This man slaten lived about three miles from our camp is a union man and is well
                    acquainted through all these mountains joined the army on cheat [Cheat Mountain]
                    and is their pilot. General Johnson offered five hundred dollars and his freedom
                    from Military duty to any man that would bring old slaten to him dead or alive.
                    on the 27th we had another false alarm. we were ordered to the ditches about 8 o
                    clock in the night. what caused this false alarm was two of our men went down
                    the Greenbrier River road after whiskey. one got drunk. his companion got him as
                    far back as he could thinking to get him back to camp but could not which
                    detained him till after night. he lost his way come to the pickets. they fired
                    on him taking him to be the Yankees. he fired five times at our pickets with a
                    revolver in return. our pickets fell back to the next post at wilfongs. this man
                    they took to be the Yankees come to wilfongs got his supper. Scouts were sent
                    out to see if the Yankees were coming found this man at Wilfongs and he told
                    them all about it. They put him in the guardhouse. I dont know what they will do
                    with him. we stayed in the ditches about two hours. it was as cold as thunder
                    two. then returned to our quarters. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>A W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
