<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0332"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0332">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    January 1, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, january 1 1863</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0332</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501840</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, January 1, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, january 1 1863</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>                    
          </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-01-01">1863-01-01 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Enlistment, Home Front,
                        Troop Movement </term>
                    <term>52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A0332T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh writes about subjects ranging from substitutes and enlistments to
                    battlefield losses.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-01-01">January 1st, 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Port Royal, Caroline County, VA </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I again take the opportunity to write you a few lines. I received a letter dated
                    22nd November on the 8th of December directed Co G instead of F Stating that you
                    had got a substitute for me and did not get him in an account of him not stating
                    to his age correctly and answered it right off. I dont know if you got it or
                    not. I also received the one you wrote on the 7th of December on the 28th it
                    being 21 days else I would have wrote sooner. D A Plecker arrived at our camp
                    about the 18th December and I got my cloths all right. he said that Harris had
                    gone to Richmond to try for a substitute for me and that he had been bothered
                    very much this trip oil account of us being he had sold out before he got to us.
                    I would have sent a letter with him but did not have time. he said he was going
                    straight on to Richmond for more goods. </p>
                <p>Captain Bunigardner they will take a boy from <unclear>10</unclear> to years old
                    man over 45 good in the Neighborhood of two thousand dollars for a substitute as
                    I dont think that I could get one for less now. As I stated in my other letter
                    that you might make a trip or so yet or get some one to tend to it you have done
                    and dont succeed about 10 days. We had orders to put up shanties those that
                    tents. our Co. has tents now. we have two large ones and some small Yankee
                    tents. </p>
                <p>We can make out pretty well this winter I think now. We had pretty weather ever
                    since the fight a day or two. The weather is not as cold here as it is in old
                    Augusta. We got in the fight on the 13th December thats our Brigade. Our Brigade
                    escaped pretty well. it was about 80 killed and wounded in our Brigade. we had
                    eight wounded in our regiment. amongst them was Captain Dabney. he has died
                    since of his wound. he was shot through the hip with grape shot. Our Captain had
                    his coat tail torn also with a grape shot. none of our Co was hurt in the fight.
                    But in a day or two after the fight in coming off picket one of our company was
                    shot in the arm by the name of Mayfield. </p>
                <p>I was on scout Christmas. eleven of us had orders to scout around the
                    neighborhood to take up stragglers that were loitering without proper authority.
                    we had fine times. we got gingerbread and turnips. plenty in our
                    <unclear>round</unclear>. we are enjoying ourselves pretty well to day. Newyear
                    it is a pretty day here. we have still some gingerbread to eat but we have to
                    buy it. As I have no news of importance and you have received the news of the
                    fight I will close. this leaves me well and I hope </p>
                <p>As I have no news of importance and you have received the news of the fight I
                    will close. this leaves me well and I hope you are all enjoying good health. I
                    wish you all a happy </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>AW Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
