<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0338"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0338">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    December 25, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, december 25 1861</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0338 </idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501846</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, December 25, 1861</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, december 25 1861</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-12-25">1861-12-25 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Home Front </term>
                    <term>52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A0338T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh tells about building fortifications and making other preparations for
                    future skirmishes with Union troops. He also reports on illnesses in camp.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-12-25">December 25, 1861 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Tip Top, Pocohontas County, VA</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I take this opportunity to write a few lines home I received your letter dated on
                    December 15th on the 19th and was glad to hear from you all I wrote a letter
                    home on the 9th of December and on the 16th I suppose you did not get all the
                    letters I wrote home Some must have been mislaid I have been writing nearly
                    every week on an average We have been trimming and burning brush ever since the
                    fight we had no fortifications for the canon the day of the fight we have five
                    now we have been blockading some roads also and extended our trenches around
                    further we will have a better chance at the yanks if they come now the brush
                    being burnt from around our fortifications they had a better chance then we had
                    the day of the battle they could lay behind the brush and logs concealed and
                    when we would raise up to look for them they would fire at us they knew exactly
                    where to look for us in the trenches we had a false alarm here last Monday we
                    were ordered in our trenches about five o'clock in the morning all the regiments
                    were ordered in the trenches we waited for the Yankees till about an hour by sun
                    and no yanks come so we went home to our breakfast disappointed the way the
                    alarm got out was that some of our men slipped the pickets that night to hunt
                    some liquor and When they returned the pickets heard them and took them to be
                    yanks and fired a couple rounds on them and run in no one was hurt Wm Cupps is
                    doing pretty well now since he has been put on duty he had done no duty since he
                    belonged to the army worth naming until a few weeks ago the Doctor would not
                    have him on the sick list no longer so he had to go on duty Wm H Fry is well and
                    bustling around Jacob Harvey Craun is nearly well again he is taken off the sick
                    list and goes on duty again Adam Craun is not well &amp; has not been for
                    some time having a kind of diarrhea and jaundice Adison L. Hisner is has not
                    been well for some time one of our boys named Philip Caffrey went home today
                    with the fever the balance of our Company are well that we have here now we have
                    none at the hospital here now Harvey Misner has gone home sick Wm Jammason had
                    been sick getting well again The health of our regiment is improving now not as
                    many sick as had been we have a dry Christmas here the boys had to go to work
                    today as well as any other day we work here on Sundays too as to myself I am
                    excused from duty to day having a bile on my leg which hurts me some otherwise I
                    am in good health as to getting a furlough it would be impossible now as we
                    ain't through with the work yet and look for the yanks every day towards spring
                    probably we may get them, it is just left to the officers choice if you and
                        <unclear>B</unclear> should come out you may bring a flannel and cotton
                    shirt along if you can get flannel yet if not it dont make no difference I
                    believe that is all I want now I will answer Josey letter next </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>AW Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
