<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0335"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0335">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, September
     23, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, september 23 1861</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">A0335</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved. </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501843</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, September 23, 1861</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, september 23 1861</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""/>
          </publicationStmt>

          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg- Spotsylvania
       County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park, Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-09-23">1861-09-23 </date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Home Front, Troop Movement </term>
          <term>52nd Va. Inf. </term>
          <term>F </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp> </resp>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="A0335T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Kersh provides news of the battle of Cheat Mountain. </p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-09-23">September 23, 1861 </date>
      <name type="place">Ottobine Chappel, Highland County VA</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Sir </salute>
    </opener>
    <p>I take this opportunity to inform you how we are getting along I have nothing of importance
     to write to you there are rumors come to camp every day nearly but they prove to be false as I
     stated in my other letter that the Yankees were leaving Cheat Mountain proves to be false it is
     said that they are still there and well fortified Our men cant fight them where they are to any
     advantage it is their intention. now I believe to surround them and cut off their supplies if
     they can their provisions must be scarce now as I heard some of our boys say the other day that
     their rations was one cracker a day for each man I dont know how true it is so many lies are
     raised The news came to camp yesterday morning that they Yankees fired on the militia at
     Petersburg with their artillery and scattered them every direction but it is believed to be a
     false report now they say that the Rockbridge Militia is called out to go to Petersburg Our
     Colonel Received a dispatch from Winchester yesterday that they want a Reinforcement there They
     intend to tare up some railroad and burn some Bridges probably we may go there yet in the
     rounds. the fact is we dont know where we may be called to go as I had stated in the letter I
     written before this that we started for Greenbrier River and had to change our line of March
     for Petersburg we Marched ten miles on our way for Petersburg camped and are still encamped at
     Strait Creek Autobine Chapel some call it forks of waters Autobine Chapel I dont know which is
     the proper name </p>
    <p>The regiment and artillery that was to meet us here from Bedford part which was in Staunton
     when we left went down to Wises Legions The Danville flying artillery come here on Tuesday
     evening from Greenbrier River they had <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> artillery they had intended going with
     us But the two regiments that had started from Greenbrier River to meet us here and were called
     ordered back again and so they started early this morning for the Allegheny Mountains We had a
     company of troopers from Monterey Captain Miller intends making an artillery company he is
     going to Start to Staunton to Morrow to see if he can get cannon We have a very nice camp
     ground flat bottom between the Mountains Since I written first Some of us have been taken sick
     Junius R Craun has the yellow Jaundice he is getting well again William Cupp has been right
     poorly getting better Joseph Goin William vanfossen also went to the Hospital the three some of
     the boys has got the Measles some the Mumps none but James Craun in our mess sick as to myself
     I am well as common the boys are all in good spirits and seem anxious for a brush with the
     Yankees I would like for you to write how you are all at home if you write Direct your letter
     to Hull in care of Colonel Baldwin 52nd Regiment Virginia Volunteers </p>
    <closer>
     <salute>Yours Respectfully </salute>
     <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
     <seg type="postscript">P S Colonel Baldwin has an express which follows his Regiment which
      enables soldiers to send and receive letter promptly </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
