<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0346"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0346">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    May 24, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, may 24 1863</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0346</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501853</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, May 24, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, may 24 1863</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-05-24">1863-05-24 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Troop Movement </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>Company: F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000-07">July 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0346T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh provides a second account of the battle of Fredericksburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-05-24">May 24, 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Fredericksburg, VA</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your letter on the 22nd and was glad to hear from you all at home. We
                    have a good many troops camped about us here. It is thought that the Yankees
                    intend to try us again here </p>
                <p>Since they found out that Jackson is dead It is said that they appear keen to try
                    us again It is true we have lost a good General but we still have a few more
                    smart men left let them come I dont believe that they are as anxious to fight as
                    they let on to be Just mere talk they have the advantage of us at Fredericksburg
                    on account of the big number of siege guns they have planted there As long as
                    they are under shelter of them they can talk large Just let them advance and we
                    are ready for them we got a great many guns knapsacks shovels picks and such
                    things in the last fight They been sending them off from the depot Hamiltons
                    Crossing ever since the fight It is a detail made in our regiment of about
                    twenty five men every day to help unload and load the cars It is also details
                    made out of other regiments in our Brigade to stand guard and fatigue duty It is
                    a good many old suttlers at the Station They sell very high too beans one dollar
                    a quart one dollar for about a quart of irish potatoes and other things in
                    proportion It is Adam Wiseful warm here now has been for several days we have no
                    shade the timber has all been cut for firewood We expect to move out of our
                    cabins in a few days about a half mile in the woods in the shade </p>
                <p>We have tolerable good water here but not as Good and cool as in Augusta Our Mess
                    got ourselves good little tents and knapsacks and blankets in the last fight it
                    was thousands of old united States blankets and little tents scattered over the
                    battle field I sent a letter by John Hale to male in Staunton or Sidney which I
                    suppose you have received by this time </p>
                <p>You were speaking of coming down I did not look for you as you have nobody
                    capable of attending to your business and a busy time too You were speaking of
                    Cavalry taking quarters in my house I have no objections so long as they act
                    like gentlemen You were speaking of the people being panic struck and come
                    flocking through Mount CrAdam Wiseford by the thousand I do hope that we, our
                    men, will be able to put the thing through soon and that folks might go home and
                    have some peace Fredericksburg is pretty much torn to pieces with shells the
                    most of the citizens have moved Adam Wiseay a great many houses has been
                    entirely destroyed </p>
                <p>Me and some of the boys took a walk over the battlefield at Fredericksburg before
                    the last fight we could see plenty of old half decayed Yankees some with their
                    heads sticking out arms hands and feet sticking out it was Adam Wiseful sight to
                    behold </p>
                <p>As I have nothing much to write about I will close I am well and hope these few
                    lines may find you all in good health your affectionate Brother </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your affectionate brother </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
