<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0340"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0340">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    January 29, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, january 29 1862</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0340 </idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501848</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, January 29, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, january 29 1862</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>

                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-01-29">1862-01-29 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Desertion/Leave, Home Front, Family </term>
                    <term>52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A0340T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh talks about about provisions and supplies in camp and also mentions
                    desertions.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh </name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-01-29">January 29, 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Allegheny, VA </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your letter on the 27th and was glad to hear from you all at home We
                    had snow here on the 24th about 4 inches deep it stormed and blowed like the
                    Dickens here it blowed the snow through our old clapboard roofs and sifted it
                    over us some It is pleasant weather here now the snow is nearly all gone again
                    and it is getting muddy again Since I commenced this letter it has commenced to
                    rain you may Judge from this how uncertain the weather is here in these old
                    mountains I wrote a letter home on the 23rd the roads were awful here then but
                    in the evening turned cold and it froze the ground hard and the roads were
                    getting good again but if it stays warm and rains much they will get bad again
                    you stated in your letter that you and Plecker expect to come out in a few weeks
                    I would be very glad to see you here If you come you may bring those two shirts
                    and a bottle of Professor Woods hair restorative that I have on the shop loft in
                    that old walnut chest I think I left it in there when I left home if it is not
                    there it is locked up in my desk and you need not put yourself to any trouble to
                    get any unless you should come through Staunton when you come out it can be got
                    at Dr. Youngs Staunton it is none nearer than Staunton or Harrissonburg that is
                    all I want I believe except a box of provisions Soldiers here do not have any
                    objections to a box of provisions as they sometimes get tired of Bull Beef as to
                    the affair between me and H Fry it is all right as far as I know I will just
                    leave that note in Esq Fultons hands as he was agreed to take the note and
                    collect it You stated in your letter that Samuel Whitmore wished to settle his
                    yearly rent it will suit me first rate if you do attend to it for me It will
                    oblige me and further more I am very much obliged to you for what you have done
                    for me Jacob Crist arrived here yesterday with his son George Who had run the
                    blockade they did not get to stay at home more than a day and half till his
                    father brought him back he was put in the Guardhouse and court marshaled and the
                    sentence pronounced upon him is ten days confinement in the guard house fined $
                    .50cts and reduced to ranks John Myers is elected in his place David Snell got
                    back this evening the boy that Crist run off with we will take him to the guard
                    house in the morning All is going on smoothly in Camp and as I have no news of
                    importance to write I will close </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P S I forgot to state that I am well all right </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
