<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0347"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0347">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to Josephine Kersh,
                    September 29, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to josephine kersh, september 29 1863</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0347</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501854</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to Josephine Kersh, September 29,
                            1863 </title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to josephine kersh, september 29 1863</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-09-29">1863-09-29 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Home Front, Women, Family, Troop Movement </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 52 VA Inf </term>
                    <term>Company: F </term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="d1">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh writes to his niece about recent battles and discusses life at home.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Josephine Kersh </name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-09-29">September 29, 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Summerville Ford, Orange County, VA </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Miss Josephine </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Miss Josephine I seat myself to write you a few lines as I have not written you a
                    letter for some time We are still camped on the Rapidan river at Summerville
                    Ford We guard the ford and picket along the river The river is the line between
                    Orange and Culpepper us and the enemy The Yankees have advanced their picket
                    lines the distance between us is about five hundred yards at places They have
                    also reinforced their picket The picket dont fire on each other now They hollow
                    at each other sometimes and sometimes exchange news papers It is against orders
                    but they will do it Our brigade and Hokes guard Summerville Ford Hays brigade
                    guards Raccoon Ford a mile below here Gordons Brigade (Gen. John B. Gordon) is
                    about a mile above here Our Camp is about a half mile from the river behind a
                    big hill if we want to see blue bellies all we have to do is to walk on top the
                    hill and we have a fair view of the Yankee picket lines Camps wagon trains we
                    have a good position along the river here we have the heights We have ditches
                    and rifle pits thrown up here I dont think they will attack us here as we have a
                    good position We got orders last night to keep two days rations cooked a head
                    which is a pretty good sign for a move of some kind soon It was a cavalry fight,
                    on the 22nd near Madison Court house our cavalry repulsed them drove then, back
                    across Robinson river with little loss on our side Stewart fought them it was
                    reported that the Yankees got him which is false </p>
                <p>They have been giving some furloughs this summer but it is stopped now one out of
                    our company got to go home on fifteen days furlough if they commence giving
                    furloughs pretty soon this fall I may get home on furlough this winter sometime
                    if I have luckAmbrose Moyers Cal Frazier and James Plecker were here to see us
                    since we been camped here several times their camp is not far from here They
                    were well Ambrose talks of going home soon his horse is lame Two boys that were
                    severely wounded in our company at the Sharpsburg fight arrived here lately
                    William Stover and Edward Anderson David Snell is also got back he was wounded
                    in the Gettysburg fight slight Sam Atgenbright Bill Sheets and Joe Fauber were
                    sent to the hospital before we moved to the Camp Lieut. A H Craun is here sick
                    he will be sent off to some hospital if he dont get better soon Frazier Missner
                    Cupps Junius Craun Jacob H Craun and the balance of the boys in our company are
                    well I would like very much to see you all at home I am well and hope these few
                    lines may find You all in good health I will close by sending you one and all my
                    best respects </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>from your uncle </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
