<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0349"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0349">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    March 12, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, march 12 1864</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0349</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501856</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, March 12, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, march 12 1864</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Photocopy from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-12">1864-03-12 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>Company: F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0349T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh tells his brother about life in camp and the burdens of military duty after
                    his recent furlough.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-12">March 12, 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Orange County, VA</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I take the present opportunity to write you a few lines to let you know how I am
                    getting along I arrived in camp about Seven 0 clock in the evening much sooner
                    than I had expected the cars made good time I found the boys in our new camp
                    cabins all complete and comfortable They moved in them five or six days before I
                    arrived I found the boys in F all well and in fine spirits And about the first
                    question asked after how do you do how did you enjoy yourself at home was have
                    you got your old fiddle along I told them I had I had to get it right out and
                    commence playing right off We have a stag dance in one of our cabins every night
                    most It was some fighting going on the day I arrived here the Yankees made a
                    raid for Richmond I will not attempt to give you a description of the fight as
                    you have got the news in the papers long before this reaches you Our Brigade had
                    orders to be ready to march at any time but we were not called out The picket
                    was reinforced </p>
                <p>Pat arrived here on Saturday the 5th with the boxes all safe and sound Colonel
                    Skinner had sent a wagon up to the court house for them I was on picket when my
                    box came Our Brigade got orders to be ready to march at a moments warning I was
                    very much afraid that I would lose the best part of my box but that night the
                    orders were countermanded It was a false alarm got out some way All is quite
                    along the Rapidan now and we are in our cabins, enjoying ourselves and doing
                    Justice to the contents of our box John B Nash had some provisions sent him in a
                    box with Rusmisel the box was put in the wagon at Orange Court House but some
                    rascal stole it out before it arrived in camp So they lost a box between them
                    Harey (Harvey?)Craun and Peter Lambert left here on furlough on the 8th Lieut.
                    Adam H Craun and John C. Rutherford also left here a couple days ago on a
                    furlough. It is four out on furlough now in our Co We had several big rains here
                    lately which raised the Rapidan very much It is a river that raises very quick
                    any way and is very rapid Sam and I went a fishing the other day. We caught a
                    good mess duty is heavier than ever on us a heavy picket is kept up along here
                    and a good many in the guard house to guard keeps us on duty nearly all the time
                    Role call four times a day and drill twice a day when the weather will permit So
                    we dont get much time to go fishing Yesterday and the day before was rainy it
                    rained very hard here Today is clear and warm as I have nothing more worth
                    writing about now I will have to close by sending you all my tenderest regards
                    and thanks for your kindness to me I am well and hope these few lines may find
                    you all well write and let me know how you are getting along as often as
                    convenient </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
