<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0341"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0341">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    February 4, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, february 4 1862</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0341</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501849</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, February 4, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, february 4 1862</title>
            <author>AW Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-02-04">1862-02-04 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Family, Women, Death/Casualties </term>
                    <term>52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0341T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh reacts to the news from home about the death of his mother.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-02-04">February 4th, 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Allegheny, Pocohontas County, VA</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your letter on the 3rd stating the unexpected death of our Mother
                    Little did I think when your letter come to hand that it contained such sad news
                    My feelings may be better be imagined then described being away from home and
                    being denied the pleasure of ever seeing her face again on earth The thoughts of
                    never seeing the object I held most dear on earth makes me feel very sad indeed
                    But we have the consoling thought that she is gone to a better world where the
                    wicked cease from trouble and the weary are at rest Therefore we ought to try
                    and walk more upright and try to obtain that rest which is prepared for the
                    righteous in a better world than this That we may meet together in that land
                    where parting is no more If it would been any chance of getting furlough, I
                    would have come home long ago But there is where they fooled us when we
                    volunteered promised us furloughs but never gave them it is still rumored in
                    camp that we will get furloughs before long the Married men to go first but I
                    wont believe it till I see it We had a snow here on the 2nd about five inches
                    deep it drifted some the snow being very fine and the wind blowing kept our
                    cabins pretty wet inside the boards on our cabin do not fit down very close
                    therefore it has all chance to come in the weather is fair here now and it is
                    not so very cold the winter here so far is about like our common winter in
                    Augusta the roads here are froze up and dont appear very bad now trains of
                    wagons come in regular still with provisions we fare pretty well here much
                    better than I expected we get plenty to eat still nothing strange going on in
                    camp the boys are lively and kicking around all our company are well except two
                    that are here and they are getting well again they had the fever one of our
                    messmates come in the other day he stated that the balance were coming in a few
                    days that had went home on sick furlough we have ten or twelve able to come as I
                    have no news of importance I will close I am in good health and hope these few
                    lines may find you enjoying the same blessing </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your brother </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
