<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0353"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A0353">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    January 27, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, january 27 1863</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0353</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501860</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, January 27, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, january 27 1863</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-01-27">1863-01-27 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Home Front </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 52 VA Inf </term>
                    <term>Company:F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0353T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh tells his brother that he has little hope of obtaining a substitute.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-01-27">January 27th, 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Near Port Royal, Caroline County, VA</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I take this opportunity to drop you a few lines to let you know that I am well
                    and hope that when these few lines come to hand they may find you all at home
                    enjoying good health. We had some right rough weather here a few days back it
                    snowed several snows the deepest of which was about six inches deep. It has
                    turned warm now and the snow is all gone today is a beautiful day here we got
                    our house done before it got set in cold we have as comfortable quarters as we
                    had back on the Allegheny mountains now We were under Marching orders a week or
                    so back the Yankees were advancing but when it Set in bad weather they went back
                    again So we are still here Yet and I hope we may stay here a good while yet I
                    like this place very well it is not so cold as in August a I am sorry to state
                    that we lost one of our messmates the other day John S Myers as you have heard
                    before now I suppose he died last Sunday Morning between one and two o clock he
                    was sick about one week dyptheria was his compliant his body was sent home Ellis
                    Myers his brother went along on ten days furlough the balance of the boys in our
                    company are all well now It is no more case of dyptheria, in the Regiment as I
                    know of now it appears to be more healthy here than on the Allegheny Mountains
                    at least the health of this Regiment is better now Things are quiet in Camp now
                    no signs of a fight General Hooker has command of the Yankee army here now got
                    tired of old Burnsides again and pitched him out I received your letter mailed
                    the 18th of Jan stating that you wished me to see the Captain and Colonel in
                    regard to substituting I went to my Captain and he gave me such Poor
                    satisfaction that I have given up the notion of having a substitute put in he
                    talks Just contrary to what he did a month or so ago. He said then that he would
                    take a good Virginian in now he would not take a man over forty five Years old
                    that they cant stand service he said he would take a stout boy under eighteen of
                    good Parentage if the boy pleased him when he sAdam Wise him and that I might
                    have bring five or six before one would please him So I though the best Plan
                    would be to give it up so you may give up trying for one I know you have done
                    all you could for one and am much obliged to you for what you have done and
                    intend to satisfy YOU for your trouble It is all my own fault that I did not get
                    one in I would not have written in this letter in regard to substitute if I had
                    known whiter you received the answer to your other letter or not. </p>

                <p>We go on picket once in eight days we go ten miles our posts are in sight of Port
                    Royal our whole regiment goes at a time and stays three days at a time. We have
                    pickets fifteen or twenty miles along the Rappahanock river. We go on posts
                    right on the riverbank sometimes and can see the Yankees riding or walking on
                    the other side. Our reserve is left about one mile and a half in the rear. Jacob
                    Harvery Craun and Frazier is still in yet. </p>

                <p>It is six in our mess now A H Craun Ellis Myers Wm Vanfossen Samuel Argenbright
                    Joseph Eddy and myself as I have no important news to write I will close </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
