<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0567"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A0567">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John N. Snider to Kittie J. Snider,
                    March 17, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john n snider to kittie j snider, march 17 1863</title>
        <author>Snider, John N. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0567</idno>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501864</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John N. Snider to Kittie J. Snider, March 17, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john n snider to kittie j snider, march 17 1863</title>
            <author>John N. Snider </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: John N. Snider Letter, March 17, 1863, (MS
                            91-063), Civil War Collection, Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic
                            Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-03-17">1863-03-17 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Desertion/Leave, Family</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 14th Va. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0567T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Snider, a member of the 14th Va., writes to his sister about bad weather and the
                    high food prices in camp. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Kittie J. Snider </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-03-17">March the 17 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Salem </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <orig reg="once">onse</orig> more seat <orig reg="myself">my self</orig> to
                    write you a few lines to let you know that, i am well and hope these few lines
                    may find you all enjoying the same blessing of god, well, i have been looking
                    for Brother <abbr expan="James">Jas</abbr> since last saturday but he has not
                    came yet i was sure he would get here <orig reg="today">to day</orig>, he may
                    come yet this evening for it is only one oclock, Bill Anderson came a few
                    minutes ago so did Hugh Adams,</p>

                <p>Well after i <orig reg="commenced">commensed</orig> writing Hugh handed me a
                    letter from you &amp; Sarah &amp; J. Horn, i was glad to hear that you
                    all are well Hugh says if James started yesterday morning he <orig reg="won't"
                        >wont</orig> get here <abbr expan="until">til</abbr>
                    <orig reg="tomorrow">to morrow</orig>, we have had some very rough <orig
                        reg="weather">wether</orig>, last <orig reg="sabbath">sabeth</orig> night
                    was very rough, i never heard heavier thunder nor seen sharper thunder in my
                    life it rained very hard <orig reg="till">til</orig>
                    <pb n="2"/>
                    <orig reg="midnight">mid night</orig> and then got very cold, I was <orig
                        reg="Corporal">Corpel</orig> of the guard that night. <orig reg="there"
                    >they</orig> is still some snow here yet the roads <orig reg="are">is</orig>
                    awful bad, we are getting along very well we have good quarters and plenty to
                    eat now it was for one <orig reg="week">weak</orig> that we did not get <orig
                        reg="any meat">no meet</orig> only what we bought our mess bought one side
                    of bacon and it cost us four dollars and thirty <abbr expan="cents">cts</abbr>
                    apiece it was seventy five <abbr expan="cents">cts</abbr> a pound we have the
                    half of it yet and the side that Jacob Anderson brought with him we are getting
                    plenty of beef <orig reg="again">a gain</orig> it is dried beef nearly <orig
                        reg="all">al</orig>
                    <unclear>
                        <orig reg="rounds">ronds</orig>
                    </unclear> it is about right to make good <orig reg="steak">stake</orig>, I can
                    beat the woman frying <orig reg="steak">stake</orig> we get plenty sugar and
                    rice but we don't use the rice i wish i had a chance to send it home, </p>

                <p>John Kirkpatrick &amp; Davy Dice started home on <orig reg="furlough"
                    >furlo</orig> yesterday i don't want to go til we get our horses we have drawed
                    dried beef to do us <orig reg="till">til</orig> the <orig reg="middle"
                    >midle</orig> of April so i think about that time we will get our horses. <pb
                        n="3"/> i got a letter from brother <orig reg="William">Wiliam</orig>
                    yesterday he wrote it the 10 &amp; the 11 he is well he <orig reg="wrote"
                        >rote</orig> very little it is not worth reading i will send it to you, I
                    reckon you have a big time going going to old bucks to singing, I did not think
                    you would go up there you had better come out to our singing some night and you
                    will hear something that is worth <orig reg="listening">listing</orig> at, well
                    we just heard that <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Lackey has got home i hope
                    it is true and the rest of the boys will get home soon, we have preaching every
                        <orig reg="sabbath">sabeth</orig> in camp, i think our <orig reg="Chaplain"
                        >Chaplin</orig> is a fine man his name is Crook, i believe, i have no more
                    news to write so i will close for this <orig reg="evening">eavening</orig>.
                        <orig reg="please">pleas</orig> give my love to all the friend that think
                        <orig reg="worthwhile">withwhile</orig> of <orig reg="inquiring"
                    >enquireing</orig> after me, i hope these few lines will find you all well write
                    soon and give me all the news tell <orig reg="Cousin">Cousen</orig> John I will
                    write to him soon, i would like very much to send my old boots and a shirt home
                    tell mother i would <pb n="4"/> like for her to make me a saddle blanket if she
                    can i have not had my comfort <del hand="h1">on</del>
                    <orig reg="since">sence</orig> i came out i have most <orig reg="too">two</orig>
                    many <orig reg="clothes">cloths</orig> now but i <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    think we will leave here til we come home for our horses this leaves me well, i
                    will write as soon as James comes out, i remain your <orig reg="brother">brothe</orig>
                    <orig reg="till">til</orig> death so <orig reg="goodbye">good by</orig> to all
                    and may god bless and watch over you all is my <orig reg="sincere">sincier</orig>
                    <orig reg="prayer">prair</orig>. </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>John N. Snider </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">To Kittie J. Snider </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
