<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0574"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0574">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: A. G. Guskins to His Cousin,
                    December 30, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county a g guskins to his cousin, december 30 1860</title>
        <author>Guskins, A. G. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0574</idno>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501871</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: A. G. Guskins to His Cousin, December 30, 1860</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county a g guskins to his cousin, december 30 1860</title>
            <author>A.G. Guskins </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Cochran Family Letters, 1860-1861, (MS 92-032),
                            Civil War Collections, Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic
                            Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-12-30">1860-12-30 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, National Government, Patriotism, State Government</term>
                    <term>Regiment: none </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0574T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Guskins writes from South Carolina and provides an update on political life in
                    that state following its secession from the Union. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cousin</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-12-30">Sunday night, Dec. 30, 1860 </date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Cousin </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>It is now nearly three years since I last wrote to you, so without any excuse
                        <orig reg="here">hear</orig> goes. </p>

                <p>I have no news that will interest you so I will write some thing about crops and
                        <orig reg="politics">politick</orig> and <orig reg="anything">any
                    thing</orig> that I may chance to think of, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> corn &amp;
                    cotton crops have been very short all over the State this year. corn at this
                    time is worth $1.25 per bushel and cotton is worth nothing. my crop of cotton
                    will fall 20 bags short of last years. my corn crop was very good. I will have
                    some to sell. You have <orig reg="heard">heared</orig> long before this that
                        <abbr expan="South">S.</abbr> Carolina has <hi rend="underline"
                    >seceded</hi>, every person in the State shouts glory to God &amp; I say,
                    Amen. People all over the United States believed and said that <abbr
                        expan="South Carolina">S.C.</abbr> was <orig reg="afraid">a fraid</orig> to
                    quit the Union. they can now think what they <orig reg="please">pleas</orig> of
                    us. S. Carolina has fifty <orig reg="thousand">thousan</orig> ready at this time
                    to <orig reg="march">murch</orig> any <orig reg="where">whare</orig> they may
                        <orig reg="be">bee</orig>
                    <orig reg="needed">kneeded</orig>. if it <orig reg="were">was</orig> even to
                    Washington, you know enough of the history of our people to tell of what kind of
                    material they are composed of, the worst black Republican at the North will<pb
                        n="2"/> admit that the people of <abbr expan="South  
 Carolina">S.C.</abbr>
                    will fight and history has yet to record the time and place <orig reg="where"
                        >whare</orig> an enemy has seen the back of a South Carolinian. <abbr
                        expan="South">S</abbr> Carolina would be glad if all of the Slave States
                    would secede as our interest is the same. but if they <orig reg="won't"
                    >wont</orig> we are prepared to take care of our selves.</p>

                <p>The State Convention has sent R.W. Barnwell, J. H. Adams &amp; J.L. Ovr____
                    Commissioners to Washington to demand the <orig reg="Forts">Fortes</orig> at
                    Charleston of the President if the President will <orig reg="give">giv</orig>
                    them up. it will <orig reg="be">bee</orig> well for man kind, for it will <orig
                        reg="be">bee</orig> a revolution without a blood shed. but if he <orig
                        reg="doesn't">dont</orig> give them up <abbr expan="South">S</abbr> Carolina
                    will take them let it cost what it may.</p>

                <p>I will mail three papers to you with this letter, one of the papers has the <abbr
                        expan="South Carolina">S.C.</abbr>
                    <hi rend="underline">Ordinance</hi> in it. I want Franklin to commit it to
                    memory. </p>

                <p>Enough of <orig reg="politics">politicks</orig>, let me write some thing about
                    Fannie and <hi rend="underline">the</hi> baby. Fannie's health is very good and
                    she looks better than you ever saw her. I will say but little about our <del
                        hand="h1">lit</del> child for without doubt he is the finest looking child
                    of his age that you ever saw<pb n="3"/> I would <orig reg="be">bee</orig> glad
                    for you to see him for you would then confirm what I have said. Fannie is
                    anxious to visit you and Mary but I fear it will <orig reg="be">bee</orig> a
                    long time first as I have not the money to spare. We both would <orig reg="be"
                        >bee</orig> more than glad if you and Mr. Mcchesney would come and spend the
                    winter and spring with us. If Mr. Mcchesney <orig reg="can't">canot</orig> come
                    you and Franklin might and if you <orig reg="can't">canot</orig>why then send
                    Franklin or Johny. If you will come and spend two or three months with us I will
                    try and let Fannie go back with you. You can come if you want to and you must
                    come as me and Fannie are more than anxious to see you and little Adam. I will
                    bet you any amount that I can show the finest looking boy of the two so come
                    along and no excuse, as we are very anxious to see you. Our little boy has cut
                    two teeth, he has never been sick a day, neither has he ever been washed in warm
                    water, save the first time. Do come and come quickly, as I have more to tell you
                    than you ever <orig reg="heard">heared</orig> of.</p>

                <p>Mr. John Cothran died about two months ago.<pb n="4"/></p>

                <p>Me and Fannie send our best love to you all, <orig reg="hoping">hopeing</orig>
                    that this will find you all well and the baby in particular. Permit me to
                    request you to answer this as soon as it comes to hand. </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours affectionately </salute>
                    <signed>A.G. Guskins, Mill Way, Abbeville <abbr expan="District">Dist.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="South">So.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Carolina">Ca.</abbr>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
