<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0803"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;


<!ENTITY garb3a SYSTEM "uva-lib:503013" NDATA uvaHighRes>
<!ENTITY garb3b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503014" NDATA uvaHighRes>
<!ENTITY garb3c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503015" NDATA uvaHighRes>
]>
  
 <TEI.2 id="A0803">  
 <teiHeader type="migrated">  
  
    <fileDesc>  
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Addie Garber to Thomas Garber, January 19, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county addie garber to thomas garber, january 19 1862</title>
        <author>Garber, Addie</author>
        <editor> </editor>
        <respStmt>  
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>  
          <name>Alice Carter</name>  
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>  
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>  
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>  
  
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
      <publicationStmt>  
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>  
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>  
  
        <idno type="VCDH">A0803</idno>  
  
        <!--
 <availability>  
 <p>Publicly accessible </p>  
 <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>  
 <p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>  
 </availability>
-->  
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998</date>  
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503012</idno>
      </publicationStmt>  
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil  
 War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>  
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>  
  
  
      <sourceDesc>  
        <biblFull>  
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Addie Garber to Thomas Garber, January 19, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county addie garber to thomas garber, january 19 1862</title>
            <author>Addie Garber</author>
            <editor> </editor>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>  
          <editionStmt> 
            <p> </p> 
          </editionStmt>  
          <extent>3 pages</extent>  
          <publicationStmt>  
            <publisher> </publisher>  
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>  
            <date value=""/>  
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Garber Family Letters, Augusta County  
 Historical 
 Society, Staunton, Virginia </idno>  
          </publicationStmt>  
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>  
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>  
        </biblFull>  
      </sourceDesc>  
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Augusta County Historical Society, Staunton, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>  
  
    <profileDesc>  
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-01-19">1862-01-19</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>  
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>  
        <keywords>  
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Family, Home Front</term>  
          <term>American Civil War</term> 
        </keywords>  
      </textClass>  
    </profileDesc>  
  
    <revisionDesc>  
      <change>  
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy  
 Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>  
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>  
      </change>  
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>  
 </teiHeader>  
  
 <text id="A0803T"> 
 <front id="d2"> 
 <div1 type="summary" id="d3"> 
 <p>Addie Garber writes to her brother about the health and daily activities of  
 family members. 
  
  
 </p>  
  
 </div1>  
 </front>  
  
 <body id="d4"> 
  
 <div1 type="letter" id="d5"> 
 <opener> 
  
  <pb n="1" entity="garb3a" pid="uva-lib:503013"/> 
  
 <name type="recipient">Thomas Garber</name>  
  
 <dateline> 
 <date value="1862-01-19">Jan 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> 
 1862</date>
  <name type="place">Staunton</name>  
 </dateline>  
 <salute>My Dear Brother Thomas,</salute>  
 </opener>  
  
 <p>Your Chaplain Mr. Maury came out just now to see us (I reckon <hi  
 rend="underline">us</hi>) if not I came in first one after Pa to see him.  I  
 like him very well, wish he would have stayed all day, so I could have heard him  
 talk all more about you, he kindly offered to carry a letter to you.  He  
 preached for us yesterday morning, and if he preaches that way in camp he is  
 sure to do some good. Please become well acquainted with him and always go <hi  
 rend="underline">to meeting</hi>.  You have not written dear brother since you  
 left us, <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> you write me a few lines soon?  I fear  
 you did not enjoy your visit home much.  did you.  Sandie has been here for a  
 couple of days went up to Rockbridge to see Lida.  Cousin John is sick as he  
 sent after him as he wants to come home.  Saturday evening six girls and six  
 gentlemen left here to take a ride.  I was in the party and we almost froze to  
 death we had to get off at some person's house &amp; warm ourselves.  When Sandy  
 came home he told a tale about Ashers coming home  
  <pb n="2" entity="garb3b" pid="uva-lib:503014"/> 
 
 I went down to the cars two evenings in succession to meet him.   
 The second evening we met Cousin Will who had come up from Richmond and he said  
 that he had been down to see the boys and they were expecting a fight so he  
 advised Asher to stay until it was over.  He has the furlough though and can  
 come home when he wants to.  It is so terribly cold today.  I wonder if you are  
 warm enough.  Has Fred returned to camp yet.   rather has he reached there.  I  
 do hope you whipped the Yankees good this last time.</p> 
  
 <p>Sisters children have been quite sick (Allie &amp; Lewis) poor little Leslie  
 is still so.  They have the whooping cough also.  Sister Lizzie and her boys get  
 <orig reg="along">a long</orig> very well.  They do not go to school.  She (I  
 think she said so) teaches them at home.  Mag &amp; Margie came out here for me  
 to go to Mrs. Opie's but as the young preacher was here I <orig  
 reg="wouldn't">would'nt</orig> go.  I knew Mary Opie was not at home too.  I  
 told them so but they did not want to know it.</p> 
  
 <p>Did you read the books you carried with you.  Mrs. Forest &amp; Jennie L are  
 going to try to get North as far as Washington.  Jennie said she would take a  
 letter for me so I'll honor cousin Mab so far as a letter will go.  <del hand="h1">Maggie  
 told me if I would carry a letter</del> I stayed with <del hand="h1">Marge</del> Aunt  
 Nancy last night &amp; we had a fine breakfast this  
  <pb n="3" entity="garb3c" pid="uva-lib:503015"/> 
 
 morning.  Tommie if you ever want those three dollars I asked you for Xmas send  
 me word and you shall have them.  I never intend and never so intended spending  
 them.  I only asked for them to keep you from spending them in some useless  
 thing which you would not want.  Perhaps some day you'll need three dollars  
 <hi rend="underline">little as it now may seem.</hi></p> 
  
 <p>Ma spoke to Mr. Maury as though he had the charge of  you telling him to take  
 particular care of you.  he said he was very young himself.  I wish you could  
 come home and have a nice time.  and a nice long furlough.</p>   
  
 <p>Lewis writes home frequently I believe.  I wish you would do so too my dear  
 Tommie.</p> 
  
 <p>Pa got two hogs and Ma is busy making sausage and cutting them up.  don't it  
 seem queer just to have two hogs at a butchering.  We killed our <hi  
 rend="underline">poor</hi> little calf Friday which was a great distress to  
 Nellie.  I have written rather a longer letter than usual.  and now my distress  
 is where I will get an envelope.  I really cannot raise but one and that has a  
 United States postage stamp on it.</p> 
  
 <closer> 
 <salute>Good bye now my dear brother please write soon to your sister.</salute>  
 <signed>Addie</signed>  
  
 <seg type="postscript">Really if someone is not going down to the Cavalry I  
 cannot write to you for I do not know what Post Office you are near.</seg>   
 </closer>  
 </div1>  
 </body>  
 </text>  
 </TEI.2>  
  
 