<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0811"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;


<!ENTITY garb11a SYSTEM "uva-lib:503041" NDATA uvaHighRes>
<!ENTITY garb11b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503042" NDATA uvaHighRes>
<!ENTITY garb11c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503043" NDATA uvaHighRes>
<!ENTITY garb11d SYSTEM "uva-lib:503044" NDATA uvaHighRes>

]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0811">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Thomas Garber to Addie Garber, December 6, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county thomas garber to addie garber, december 6 1862</title>
        <author>Garber, Thomas</author>
        <editor> </editor>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice Carter</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A0811</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503040</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>


      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Thomas Garber to Addie Garber, December 6, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county thomas garber to addie garber, december 6 1862</title>
            <author>Thomas Garber</author>
            <editor> </editor>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p> </p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Garber Family Letters, Augusta County Historical
       Society, Staunton, Virginia </idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Augusta County Historical Society, Staunton, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-12-06">1862-12-06</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Military Authority, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A0811T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Thomas Garber tells his sister about his successful escape from a small group of Yankee
     soldiers. </p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <pb n="1" entity="garb11a" pid="uva-lib:503041"/>
   

     <name type="recipient">Addie Garber</name>

     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-12-06">Dec 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Near Gordonsville</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Sister Addie</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>You complain of my not writing home often enough I have not been <orig reg="making"
     >makeing</orig> excuses before this because I have none to make but here lately I have <del
      hand="h1">had not</del> not had any paper and today I went to Capt Eskridge and he gave me
     this little bit. I would like to have been home when Mike was there but I would much sooner
     come home X Mass &amp; from what you said in your letter I expect to be there then. Dr.
     Williams got here last tuesday &amp; said the Col would certainly be here on the next
     tuesday I hope he will how did you like him I like him very much he is a nice man. Dr Burton
     &amp; Col Burks had a little fuss and the Dr sent in his resignation the Col accepted it
     &amp; forwarded it this took the <pb n="2" entity="garb11b" pid="uva-lib:503042"/>
      little fellow by <orig reg="surprise">supprise</orig> and he <orig
      reg="begged">beged</orig> to withdraw it <orig reg="stating">statiing</orig> as his reason
     that he intended to get a transfer &amp; then he applied for that and in a few days he
      <orig reg="withdrew">with drew</orig> that so we <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> get rid of him
     which every man in the Regiment <orig reg="wishes">whishes</orig> to do. Has Capt Balthis
     resigned or not tell me in your next letter. Where is Mike Company at now. I <orig reg="heard"
      >hird</orig> that Earley division was in the Luray Valley I hope it is left there for then the
     boys will have a <orig reg="chance">chanc</orig> to get home X Mass. On the 29th of Nov we had
     a little fight with the Yanks they had got in between us &amp; Winchester before we knew
      <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> about it. Old Allen the driver had riden one of the
      <orig reg="wagon">wagen</orig> horses out to get some clothes washed when the news came so I
     put my horse in the wagon and got on the one of the Col and started for Berrysville with the
     Regiment Major Massie in command we only had about 100 men we cut off a squadron of the yankees
     and could not get the men to charge them the Major ordered a charge &amp; about half of the
     men went the flag was in front in that crowed the rest of them stayed <pb n="3" entity="garb11c" pid="uva-lib:503043"/>
     in the woods the Major ordered me back to bring them up I went back
     and <orig reg="tried">tryed</orig> to get them to come but could not do it they were cowards
     and would not go they started towards town I went with them and when we got there I <orig
      reg="heard">hered</orig> there was some Yanks on the other side I asked the men would they go
     with me they said they would so we started <orig reg="off">of</orig> at a gallop and just
     before I turned the corner I looked around and saw the men going up sneak like the old boy was
     after them I then determined to see how many Yank they were &amp; report to the Major I
     went on around the corner and looked down the street and there was a whole Yankee Regiment I
     had my pistol in may hand I raised it up and fired it wheeled my horse and started up the
     street 8 or 10 Yanks after me shooting and howling like brave men after one man with a flag, I
     never run a horse faster in all of my life. And the next morning <pb n="4" entity="garb11d" pid="uva-lib:503044"/>
      when I got to town I came in by myself with the <hi rend="underline"
      >old flag</hi> hanging on my <orig reg="shoulders">sholders</orig> as hungry as a bear (for I
     had not <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> to eat <del hand="h1">since</del>for 24 hours) an
     old lady was at standing at the door as soon as she saw me she <orig reg="hollered"
     >hollowed</orig> at the top of her voice Oh Sally come here here is that Color bearer &amp;
     then she pitched in to thus come in sir come in I so glad to see you I was sure the yanks had
     gotten come in &amp; get your Breakfast I told her certainly &amp; I went in &amp;
     got a firstrate breakfast so much <orig reg="running">runing</orig> out of town with the
     Yankees after me. I hope to be with you X mass if not it <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> be
     because I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> want to <orig reg="come">com</orig> for I <orig
      reg="don't">dont</orig> know hardly how much I would give to see you all Good by give my love
     to Pa Ma Kate &amp; Nellie and Sister Seal &amp; Margie.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your Bro</salute>
     <signed>Thos. M. Garber</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
