<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1106"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1106">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: A. J. Gilkeson to Gilkeson's brother
                    (probably Hugh Gilkeson), January 21, 1866</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county a j gilkeson to gilkesons brother probably hugh gilkeson , january 21 1866</title>
        <author>A. (J.) Gilkeson</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1106</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501909</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: A. J. Gilkeson to Gilkeson's brother (probably Hugh
                            Gilkeson), January 21, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county a j gilkeson to gilkesons brother probably hugh gilkeson , january 21 1866</title>
            <author>A. J. Gilkeson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Hugh W. Gilkeson Collection,
                            SHC-052, Northwest Georgia Document Preservation Project, Shorter
                            College, Rome, Georgia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Northwest Georgia Document Preservation Project, Shorter College, Rome, Georgia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-01-21">1866-01-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Agriculture, Family, Home Front, Medicine/Hospitals,
                        Race Relations, National Government, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Douglas Michael O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1106T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter, Gilkeson updates his brother on the family's health. He goes on
                    to deliver his impression of the attitudes of African-Americans toward contract
                    labor. He closes by complaining about new postwar land taxes and a struggling
                    economy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-01-21"><abbr expan="January">Jan.</abbr> 21st/66</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Brother</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received a letter from you several weeks since. I would have replied sooner but
                    for the fact, that having sent your letter out to David soon after I received
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">it</add>, I was under the impression until
                    yesterday that he had answered it. I was delighted to hear from you once more;
                    and truly thankful to hear that you were all living and in your usual health. My
                    little family are all in their usual health also. <abbr expan="Emily(?)"
                    >Em.</abbr> and my two little girls returned from Wheeling, about ten days
                    since, whither they had been on a visit since the last week in October. I took
                    them out, and on my return home I met with a merchant from Chattanooga, who was
                    on his way home from New York, whither he had been to purchase goods. I thought
                    it a good opportunity to communicate with you, as it was then very difficult to
                    send a letter directly through to Summerville. (Indeed I do not know that it is
                        much<pb n="2"/> less difficult yet.) I accordingly wrote you on board the
                    cars and gave the letter to him to mail in Chattanooga which he promised to do.
                    That was written on the 2<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">nd</hi>
                    </hi> of November but I have never heard whether you ever received it.</p>
                <p><abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi> You will observe
                    more than a week has elapsed since I wrote the foregoing. The reason of the
                    delay in finishing my letter is this. I did not have time to finish it on the
                    day I commenced it, and I concluded the next day that I would wait until there
                    might be a decided change, one way or the other, in David's condition, who was
                    then quite ill. He has been very much better now for three or four days past,
                    and, I think, with care will be well in a short time. He has had an attack of
                    inflammatory rheumatism, but not near so severe an attack as he has had. But his
                    nervous system seemed to become very much deranged, and he was in a state of
                    delirium, most of the time, for three or four days. He has been sick about one
                    month: suffered<pb n="3"/> a good <unclear>eal</unclear> with rheumatism in his
                    arms, hands and legs, the first two weeks; but has been in a measure clear of
                    pains for the last ten days. He has no negro men employed now: he has, however,
                    two white men and boy about seventeen years old. Ann &amp; Mary are still
                    there, but I learn indirectly that they contemplate leaving in the spring. Ben
                    still remains with me and also my woman, and are both doing well. Henry left
                    David soon after the surrender, and is now living with William Guthrie. The
                    negroes are very trifling, as a general thing; and none of them are willing to
                    contract by the year, and a majority of them do not seem to be willing to
                    contract at all for any length of time. Business of all kinds is very flat now,
                    and there seems to be no money in the country. It is almost impossible now to
                    collect a few Dollars from the best men in our community. And what is more the
                    tax collector is here now gathering in the Land Tax. I very much fear many of
                    our farmers will forfeit<pb n="4"/> their land from their inability to pay the
                    Tax. The Tax here is 27 cents on the 100 Dollars on the assessment of 1860. And
                    if the Tax is not paid in a <unclear>certain</unclear> time the government will
                    sell the land and appropriate all the money arising from the sale. <orig
                        reg="Ain't">Aint</orig> the Yankees the most fiendish nation on the face of
                    the earth? We have just got in money sufficient ($42.50) to pay the Tax on
                    Father's Estate. Write me and let me know whether you will be able to pay the
                    Taxes on your land. If not, and the thing is possible, we must
                    <unclear>assist</unclear> you in order to save your land. <abbr expan="Emily(?)"
                        >Em</abbr> and the children send much love to you and your children. How
                    much we all would be to see you and them. Write so soon as you receive this and
                    find me all the news. And now I must close May a kind providence protect you and
                    yours</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I <unclear>am as ever</unclear> your affectionate brother</salute>
                    <signed>A. J. Gilkeson</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
