<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1116"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1116">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Letitia R. Smiley to Sister (Mary?),
                    January 30, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county letitia r smiley to sister mary , january 30 1867</title>
        <author>Smiley, Letitia R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1116</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501919</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Letitia R. Smiley to Sister (Mary?), January 30, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county letitia r smiley to sister mary , january 30 1867</title>
            <author>Letitia R. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers, Accession
                            #1807, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-01-30">1867-01-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity,
                        Death/Casualties, Family, Medicine/Hospitals, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1116T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Smiley delivers news about school and about her friends and acquaintances there.
                    She discusses academics, weddings, social interactions, health, and general
                    news. At one point she mentions hearing noise from outside and assuming it was
                    "darkies shouting."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-01-30">Jan 30th 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">A. F. Seminary Staunton Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear sister</salute>
                </opener>

                <p> As Rebecca expects to go home tomorrow I thought I would write home by her. I
                    have been very well since I wrote home with the exception of cold. Maggie Dudley
                    went home last Monday and right sorry we were to have her go. After Annie Fulton
                    found out Miss Mary would let Mag go she wrote home to see if her Pa would let
                    her go. he asked last week if she would let her her off. She said if anyone else
                    tried to get off she wouldn't go but if they didn't she might go, &amp;
                    would let her know the last of this week &amp; if you hear me that will be
                    the end of it. Becca is almost crazy to get home. She looks like she thinks
                    tomorrow will never come. Mary Scheffer is going home next week. Miss M<hi
                        rend="super">c</hi>Clure is coming next Friday and will take Mary's place in
                    the room I suppose M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> Flynn from Georgia will be here with his daughter soon. He is a
                    Presbyterian preacher &amp; some of the teachers were wishing he would
                    happen here on Sunday &amp; preach. They had one of their little concerts
                    here last Saturday night. The music was very good but it certainly was the
                    driest hateful old thing, afterwards ever was the compositions were <hi
                        rend="underline">charming</hi>, <hi rend="underline">charming</hi>. Miss
                    Mary gave them to brother <unclear>Ed</unclear> to read. Mary Turk's was read
                    &amp; she was powerfully scared. Just after we came from church Sunday
                    night. we heard such a dreadful hollering. we went bursting out on the porch,
                    thought it was the darkies shouting. but it was the cry of fire. we all thought
                    it was <add hand="h1" place="inline">in</add> the American Hotel. &amp;
                    didn't know any better till the<pb n="2"/> next morning when we found out it was
                    a chimney in the Methodist Institute. the consequence was we didn't have any
                    fire that night. We all went to the Lyceum last Friday night a week. The
                    question discussed was "Is the mind of woman naturally equal to that of man. I
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know when I laughed so much, liked Howe
                    Peyton's speech the best: I tell you he is smart to be such a witchy looking
                    creature. Law Mary I <hi rend="underline">broke</hi> our <hi rend="underline"
                        >bedstead</hi> down last Saturday evening, went to sit down on the bed when
                    such a racket &amp; clatter as I never heard before. I looked around to see
                    what was the matter, when lo! &amp; behold, <hi rend="underline">bed</hi>
                    &amp; <hi rend="underline">me</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">were both on the floor</hi>. I gathered myself up &amp;
                    went to work &amp; made the old thing up, when down it came again. so I had
                    to go &amp; tell Miss Agnes. Uncle Chess propped it up with a box. I tell
                    you we had to lie mighty still that night; for every time we would move, one of
                    the slats would drop out &amp; by morning three or four of them were on the
                    floor, but we are getting better used to the lame thing now. Becca says she is
                    bound to go down to see you when she goes home. &amp; when that time comes,
                    you must be very entertaining as I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> expect she will
                    talk much. We had a regular <hi rend="underline">cat</hi> &amp; <hi
                        rend="underline">dog</hi> fight this morning, nearly all the girls got
                    frightened &amp; run into Miss <orig reg="Howard's">Howards</orig> room
                    &amp; frightened her nearly to death, said there was noise enough for some
                    terrible <hi rend="underline">cat</hi>astrophe, but the affair was finally
                    settled by the cat; it leaving the schoolroom <hi rend="underline"
                    >screaming</hi>. Miss Baldwin is getting high up in the picture. she read the
                    rules out the other morning at the breakfast table. some of them were if a girl
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> get to the breakfast table in less than five
                    minutes, after the ringing of the bell, she gets one demerit: if not there at
                    all she gets two. <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig> you may believe we all go
                    down even if we were half dead.<pb n="3"/></p>
                <p>Thursday night. The girls are studying for Trigonometry examination. they appear
                    to be a good deal frightened. say they <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know any
                    more about it than if they had never seen inside of a book. I want you to try
                    &amp; borrow <orig reg="Butler's">Butlers</orig> Analogy for me, as I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> think it will be very long till we will need it: we
                    finished the 1<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">st</hi>
                    </hi> book of Roman History this morning &amp; in consequence of that and
                    the examination I haven't many lessons for tomorrow We are continually changing
                    servants here. Uncle Chess' wife has had two strokes of Apoplexy &amp; is
                    not expected to live. she is Patsy's mother &amp; she had to go &amp;
                    take care of her. <orig reg="I'll">Ill</orig> declare there are some of the
                    biggest geese here ever was. they run at the least noise, just now one of the
                    chairs fell over against the chimney. some of them run like a wolf was after
                    them. others declared <del hand="h1">there</del> some big thing had fallen down
                    the chimney, &amp; I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know but what they would
                    have had the town aroused, if some of us <orig reg="hadn't">hadnt</orig> told
                    that cause of the disturbance. Mary Smith's party comes off in about two weeks.
                    she was here last Saturday inviting some of the girls I suppose. Heard Ella G
                    Saying Saturday there would be nothing done but talk &amp; fix for three
                    weeks. Nealie Sout was here one day this week. the girls say they never saw as
                    great a change on any person. I suppose you have heard of the sad death of her
                    brother before this. Mrs Wills came this evening. I haven't seen her but the
                    girls say she is mighty pretty. she has a might sweet little baby too. guess by
                    the time she gets away from here he'll be so cross she can't manage him. I think
                    this day will about finish your sleigh-riding. I was startled half out of my
                    wits the other day by Lucy's saying, Tish, Pa told me<pb n="4"/> to tell you he
                    expected your ma would have to send for you soon. he said you had just been
                    going a riding. Mary had a letter from Nat Wallace the other day. says M<hi
                        rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">rs</hi>
                    </hi> Charlie Irvine has a fine boy: I heard about that <unclear>
                        <hi rend="underline">tother</hi>
                    </unclear> one. <hi rend="underline">Little</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">Christ</hi> but <orig reg="didn't">didnt</orig> hear
                    whether it was <hi rend="underline">pretty</hi> or not. Were you up there at
                    preaching that evening? A great many people think <unclear>Meg's</unclear>
                    sister is to be married soon to D<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> Trevy. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know but shouldn't be surprised if
                    it did come off. By the way I heard M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Gauley was going down into that neighborhood to go
                    into <orig reg="business">bisiness</orig>. Mary &amp; Annie<del hand="h1"
                    >s</del> are writing compositions <orig reg="tonight">to-night</orig>, stories
                    about young widows in the lone cottage by the sea, appears to be rage with them
                    this time Jinnie Beard had not heard that Nize was married heard though that she
                    was to be &amp; says I suppose when she steps out on the floor she will feel
                    like closing her female eyes..she sent her love to you &amp; Anna said Mary
                    to write her. Now if you <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> write &amp; tell me
                    all the news I'll, I'll, well I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> what <orig
                        reg="I'll">Ill</orig> do. If people ask you how I am getting along down
                    here, you can tell them, very well, when I can take the time and patience to
                    write this much. Write soon and often to your</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Affectionate sister</salute>
                    <signed>Letitia R. Smiley</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I went down street but couldn't find any buttons the size
                        of that one, there were some just like it but a size smaller. If you think
                        they will do you can let me know and I will send them to you the first
                        opportunity.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
