<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1115"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1115">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: L. (Letitia?) R. Smiley to Writer's
                    sister (Mary?), December 4, 1866</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county l letitia r smiley to writers sister mary , december 4 1866</title>
        <author>Smiley, L. [Letitia?] R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1115</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501918</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: L. (Letitia?) R. Smiley to Writer's sister (Mary?),
                            December 4, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county l letitia r smiley to writers sister mary , december 4 1866</title>
            <author>L. (Letitia?) R. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers, Accession
                            #1807, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-12-04">1866-12-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Family, Medicine/Hospitals, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1115T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Smiley discusses the health, activities, and weddings of friends, family, and
                    acquaintances. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-12-04"><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 4<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">th</hi></hi> 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">A. F.<lb/> Seminary Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Sister</salute>
                </opener>

                <p> I received my clothes yesterday evening by John but didn't have time to write so
                    I thought I would write today. I have gotten nearly well of my cold. I was very
                    much surprised to hear of Miss Tassie Houston's death, as I had not heard of her
                    sickness. Becca had a letter from home this morning, which said they were all
                    better but Miss Jane. It certainly must be a dreadful kind of fever. Miss Bettie
                    Loyle, Miss Agnes' neice died about two weeks ago. Grandma &amp; Miss Agnes
                    were very much distressed about it. Mattie Tate came here yesterday as a
                    boarder. M<add hand="h1" place="inline">r</add><del hand="h1">iss</del> Haddell
                    is going to Richmond to enter into business. I think she feels right sorry. We
                    have had a new boarder since you were here. Miss M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Garrek,
                    from Pulaski. Becca wrote to her cousin M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">rs</hi>
                    </hi> Dunlap to send for her Friday evening. Miss Mary told her she had better
                    write. Her father was down to see her <abbr expan="Saturday">Sat</abbr>. I tell
                    you she was glad. We all went to the Episcopal church last Sunday night.
                        M<unclear>r. Jenkin</unclear> will preach on Friday night &amp;
                    Saturday. We walked out to <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Byers last Saturday
                    morning met M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> Leckey there. Mary Dudley stayed all day. <unclear>Suslie</unclear>
                    Stephenson &amp; I wouldn't stay but we had mighty work to get off from
                    Mattie. I believe M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Gauly is to be one of M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> East's waiters. wonder who he will wait with. It sounds funny to say <orig
                        reg="we're">were</orig> going home week after next. it seems like Christmas
                    oughtn't to be here yet. I reckon <orig reg="it's">its</orig> because we haven't
                    had any cold weather. Think Ean Fulton did have a rainy day sure enough for
                    wedding. why in the world didn't they both get married the same day. just two
                    troubles &amp; expenses. Tell <unclear>Niza</unclear> she <orig
                        reg="mustn't">musn't</orig> laugh when<pb n="2"/> she gets married. I wish I
                    could go to some of their weddings. did you have much fun at Eme's wedding. How
                    is cousin Nancy Berry now? where will John &amp; <unclear>Niza</unclear>
                    live? <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig>. What did the <hi rend="underline">
                        <unclear>thing</unclear>
                    </hi> look like that day? &amp; how did the <hi rend="underline">
                        <unclear>Jucen</unclear>
                    </hi> enjoy herself? I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think the glove pattern is
                    at home. I know I loaned it to Bettie Echard. &amp; I <orig reg="don't"
                    >dont</orig> think I could tell you how to trim the dress...I have seen some
                    trimmed <del hand="h1">across the</del> with three rows of velvet across the
                    breast. then turned &amp; go up to the seam on the shoulders. I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> know where I could get a pattern for the tails.
                    perhaps M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">rs</hi>
                    </hi> Turk has the pattern like Lucy's, if you like them you can make them that
                    way. I have not thanked D<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> Spragins for my present yet. Miss Howard has given up having Geometry
                    examination before Christmas as we would have too much to<del hand="h1">o</del>
                    think of at once. We will have our examination on Heaven Tuesday before the
                    Cantanta. I don't think braided bodies will do wear then, will send my white
                    body home and have it done up before that time. I reckon that will do. I expect
                    you will be right busy until after the wedding. I want to send this down to the
                    office now so it will go up tomorrow. I will look for you <abbr expan="Saturday"
                        >Sat.</abbr> a little, bet you <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> come through.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Sister</salute>
                    <signed>L R Smiley</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
