<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1400"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1400">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Robert Yates Ramsey to Unknown, August 31, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta robert yates ramsey to unknown, august 31 1864</title>
        <author>Ramsey, Robert Yates</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Kid W.</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Kid W.</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A1400</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501939</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Robert Yates Ramsey to Unknown, August 31 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta robert yates ramsey to unknown, august 31 1864</title>
            <author>Robert Yates Ramsey</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Letters from Robert Yates Ramsey, Accession 27295,
       Personal Papers Collection, The Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-08-31">1864-08-31</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Arts/Leisure, Battle Description, Church/Religious Activity, Medicine/Hospitals, Military
      Authority, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A1400T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Ramsey writes to an unidentified friend from a hospital, apologizing for some action which he
     believes has wounded their relationship. He discusses a few military campaigns and considers
     joining Mosby's famed Rangers after his recovery.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-08-31">Wednesday August 31<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Staunton</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Friend</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>To have the honor of being a correspondent of yours, would be a privilege, which, I feel
     assured, would afford me a vast amount of enjoyment. But since our last meeting, (on the 25<hi
      rend="super">th</hi> last,) I have been led to believe that you then anticipated but little
     real enjoyment, or satisfaction, from a correspondence with us <hi rend="underline">being</hi>
     so unworthy of being so highly honored For this reason I feel a considerable delicacy in
     writing, and indeed the thought of not writing at all, forced <orig reg="itself">its
     self</orig> upon me, so powerfully, that for a time, that it had well nigh gained the day. If
     it be true that you cherish such thoughts [and it may be, that they are only too true] <del
      hand="h1">But</del> I think it <pb n="2"/> nothing more, or less, than your duty, (and
     certainly no harm) to inform me of the fact. I censure no <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> for speaking the
     truth, thought it be at my expense. It is only that we may fairly understand each other that I
     write to you now. I know that you are uncertain, as to whether I will write or not; but I think
     I hear you say you give yourself but little concern about it. Very well: that is <orig
      reg="alright">all right</orig> speak it out boldly; and I assure you, we shall soon understand
     each other. It is far from being my desire to prolong a correspondence, which would be far from
     satisfying to you. And I hope you will pardon me, if <add hand="h1" place="inline">I</add> say
     it was to obtain definate information, in regard to this correspondence that caused me to make
     that very <orig reg="inappropriate">unappropriate</orig> demonstration, on the (ever-memorable)
     morning (to me) of the 25<hi rend="super">th</hi> of August. But let me ask you to pity me,
     when I confess that I was <pb n="3"/> met by a force, so irresistible that I was Gallently
     repulsed, and obliged to retreat somewhat in disorder, and doubtless, leaving behind the
     wounded; and without gaining the desired information period. But I sincerely hope that there
     were no wounded, at least, none that were more severely wounded than I was:
     <unclear>just</unclear> remember if I was wounded, it matters not: I censure no one but <orig
      reg="myself">my-self</orig> for it. But please pardon me talking this nonsense. I know <del
      hand="h1">the</del>if you are looking for a letter from me, you are not expecting it to be
     made up, of this sort of material. - Probably I am <add hand="h1" place="inline">doing</add>
     wrong by expressing my thoughts in this way - I am <orig reg="naturally">naturaly</orig> of a
     rebellious nature; and these may only be <orig reg="rebellious">rebelious</orig> thoughts that
     have been forced upon me; and have no foundation: I hope that this is all. I cannot blame <del
      hand="h1">a</del> persons for <orig reg="ceasing">ceaseing</orig> to <orig reg="bestow"
      >bestoow</orig> his affections upon <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> whom <del hand="h1">they</del>
     <add hand="h1" place="inline">
      <del hand="h1">he</del>
     </add>
     <add hand="h1" place="inline">they</add> cannot like. <pb n="4"/> I <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> no hard
     feelings towards you. <unclear>But</unclear> on the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> they are <unclear>warm</unclear>, and <unclear>gregarious</unclear>.</p>

    <p>But, allow me, (in conclusion, on this subject,) to say that though this correspondence may
     cease to exist; yet our relations towards each other, as <hi rend="underline">true friends</hi>
     shall never cease. It is not my intention to wound your feelings by and of these <orig
      reg="absurd">ab<unclear>e</unclear>surd</orig> expressions; - to touch the tender cords of
     your generous heart, would be an experiment, which I have no particular fancy and which I dare
     not attempt. I am declared here as a patient only, in the hospital, and do not dislike it as
     much as I had expected though it is rather lonesome to me, as I am not acquainted about here. I
     spend my time in walking and sitting about the streets, when I have no reading, writing, or
     other duties to claim my attention. I <unclear>intent</unclear> to appear again before the
     board as soon as it meets in our <hi rend="underline">ward</hi>, if I can get a recommendation
     from the <hi rend="underline">ward</hi> surgeon.</p>

    <p>I guess we have no news except what you will have heard before this reaches you. Rumor says
     that Early has had a fight, and <orig reg="whipped">whiped</orig> the <orig reg="Yankees"
      >yankeys</orig> badly, and captured - - - prisoner<unclear>s</unclear> four or five hundred,
     and they say he is now at Bushers hill twelve miles below Winchester Lee, (I am glad to hear)
     has captured two thousand prisoners, and nine pieces of artillery, but the yanks still hold the
     Weldon railroad.</p>

    <p>I had the wholesome pleasure of listening to two sermons last sunday; - and of drinking in
     the ward, or of "feeding upon the sincere <unclear>milds</unclear> of the word", as preached
     from the pulpit, of the Episcopal Church. - Excellent sermons; but not to be compared with that
     delivered by Mr. Preston, at <hi rend="underline">Rocky Spring</hi> If possible, I <pb n="1"/>
     would be glad to hear from you soon. A letter from a friend is always welcome by me, and never
     rejected - - direct to the care of <hi rend="underline">Woods &amp; Gilkeson</hi></p>

    <closer>
     <salute>yours truly</salute>
     <signed>Yates Ramsey</signed>
     <seg type="postscript"><abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> 1<hi rend="super">st</hi><lb/>P.S.
      As I did not get this sent off yesterday, I will add a line, to say that I did not succeed in
      getting another leave of absence, but have improved so fast, that they consider me fit for
      duty, and I will start for the command tomorrow morning. There are some wounded coming in from
      down the Valley; and among those who came in this morning, was <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr>
      <abbr expan="William">Wm.</abbr> L. Jackson. He has a right bad wound - look pretty <del
       hand="h1"/> It is reported that what few men are left of the 25<hi rend="super">th</hi>
      <abbr expan="Regiment">
       <unclear>Rg</unclear>
      </abbr> have got permission to go to other commands, <orig reg="until">untill</orig> the
      prisoners shall be exchanged. But I think it <orig reg="hardly">herdly</orig>
      <pb n="3"/> probable that he would give them that privilege. In case it be true, I guess I
      will have to flank a horse and try and share some of the glorious reputation, attached to the
       47<hi rend="super">th</hi> battalion <lb/>
      <lb/> Should you think to confer upon me the honor, of receiving a letter from your hand
      please direct to <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> "D." 25 <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
      <abbr expan="Infantry">Inft.</abbr>: <orig reg="Jones's">Jones</orig> brigade <orig
       reg="Gordon's">Gordons</orig> Division; and to the care of <abbr expan="Captain">Captn</abbr>
      G. C. Merrill. <lb/>
      <lb/> And now, as I am again banished from the gayeties, and pleasures of home scenery, and
      the associations attached thereto; and called upon to behold more lively scenes, in the field
      of activity, and strife, there to receive my dues in the way of suffering; you will allow me
      to close this very <hi rend="underline">unwholesome</hi> epistle, by <orig reg="saying"
      >sayin</orig> to you,<lb/>Farewell.<lb/>Yours <orig reg="Robert">R. R.</orig> Yates</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
