<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1418"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1418">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Amelia [Unknown family name] to Eddie
                    [Unknown family name], December 11, 1869</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta amelia unknown family name to eddie unknown family name, december 11 1869</title>
        <author>[Unknown last name], Amelia</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1418</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501957</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Amelia [Unknown family name] to Eddie [Unknown family name],
                            December 11, 1869</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta amelia unknown family name to eddie unknown family name, december 11 1869</title>
            <author>Amelia [Unknown family name]</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>5 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Unknown</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Unknown</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1869-12-11">1869-12-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Church/Religious Activity, Education, Slavery</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1418T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Amelia writes to her brother Eddie, telling him about school. She discusses her
                    African-American students and mentions their future projects.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1869-12-11"><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 11. /<abbr
                                expan="1869">69</abbr></date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother Eddie</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I am sorry to know you have been so sick and suffered so much. However I hope you
                    are better now and able to <del hand="h1">see</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">read</add> this letter. Do not wonder if I put in
                    many things wrong as the girls seem to be possessed with a talking mania <orig
                        reg="tonight">to-night</orig>. We have been so quiet before that it makes
                    more difference with me than I thought possible. I have my scholars all to
                    myself now and like it first rate. I have not whipped any yet and <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> think I shall as Amelia has <pb n="2"/> given me
                    permission to send all unruly ones to her to deal with. They are going to have
                    compositions next Wednesday. Some of them have never written any before and I
                    expect they will be funny enough. I will send you in this; a specimen of some
                    poetry one of my young boys tried to write. The other day an Indian visited our
                    school. He was seven feet high and just as straight and erect as could be. He
                    was eighty years old. His hair was white as snow as stood up all over his head.
                    He had a fur <del hand="h1">cap</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">bag</add> slung across his shoulder. We did not
                    know who he was and felt rather frightened when we saw him walking in. He
                    introduced himself as the father of some of our best scholars. He is a kind of
                    doctor among the colored people. He was formerly a slave <pb n="3"/> from
                    Florida: but <orig reg="traveled">travelled</orig> with his master nearly all
                    over the Union. He is very entertaining telling hunting stories as well as
                    stories of the war I wish<del hand="h1">ed</del> you could go with me some day
                    to the cabin they live in out by the great fire place filled with blazing logs
                    and hear him tell stories. One of his boys is very smart only nine years old and
                    reading nicely in the fourth reader. I am quite proud of my scholars I can tell
                    you, they are getting <add hand="h1" place="inline">on</add> so well. The night
                    school is just as amusing as ever, and I cannot help laughing. The colored
                    people here are going to have an exhibition next week. They have got it all up
                    themselves. They are going to have some tableaux too. I expect it will be as
                    good as going to the <orig reg="minstrel">minastrel</orig>
                    <pb n="4"/> and better too as that is all sham and this will be the real
                    article. I have picked out three pieces for some of my boys to speak and that is
                    all I have had to do with it. I wrote a letter to Roland <orig reg="today"
                        >to-day</orig> and am going to try and write him oftener in the future as I
                    shall have more time now. <orig reg="Mr.">Mr</orig> Cristy <orig reg="wrote"
                        >wote</orig> me a nice long letter the other day telling me all about <orig
                        reg="Albert's">Alberts</orig> conversion. They must be very glad and I hope
                    he will make a true earnest christian. Here is the poetry James Tynell had in
                    his composition. The "title" of the composition was this, where he got it from I
                    am sure I do not know, "Who ought to have the credit Columbus or Washington?
                    Columbus for <del hand="h1">settling</del> discovering it or Washington for
                    settling it." He took the side of Columbus, I copied the whole thing and will
                    bring it home with me, it is a great curiousity. Here is the poetry I will write
                    it on the top of the first page. Try and get well and write me a nice long
                    letter,</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Love to all From</salute>
                    <signed>Amelia.</signed>
                    <pb n="1"/>
                    <seg type="postscript">"When floating me the mile deep<lb/> Not a tree was to be
                        seen<lb/> And when the men all grumble<lb/> It would make any <orig
                            reg="man's">mans</orig> heart <add hand="h1" place="inline">humble</add>
                        <name type="recipient"><lb/> But just think of this great carnage<lb/> That
                            was on that long voyage<lb/> Who was that great man? C. <del hand="h1"
                                >Columbus"</del><lb/> Columbus"<lb/> Beat that if you can, you
                                <unclear>Academites</unclear></name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
