<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1427"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1427">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Alonsa Rounds Sterrett to Lora, April 4,
                    1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta alonsa rounds sterrett to lora, april 4 1870</title>
        <author>Sterrett, Alansa Rounds</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1427</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501966</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Alonsa Rounds Sterrett to Lora, April 4, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta alonsa rounds sterrett to lora, april 4 1870</title>
            <author>Alonsa Rounds Sterrett</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library,
                            The Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-04-04">1870-04-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1427T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sterrett writes that she has been down with Neuralgia and discusses news from
                    various relatives.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-04-04">April 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1870</date>
                        <name type="place">Riverside</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Very Dear Lora;</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I was delighted to get your letter of March 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> I really
                    thought I should answer it right away, but I have been suffering a great <orig
                        reg="deal">dial</orig> lately from Neuralgia, &amp; my eyes pain me when
                    I write at night. But I am determined another week shall not pass, and find your
                    dear letter unanswered. So although it is <hi rend="underline">Monday</hi>,
                    &amp; I act in the capacity of <hi rend="underline">Bridget</hi>, while my
                    girl is <hi rend="underline">Washing</hi> I will sit down and write until time
                    to get dinner for the farm hands. When I <abbr expan="received"
                        >rec<unclear>'</unclear>d</abbr> yours, I had just mailed a letter to Sarah
                    in which I sent some messages to you, little dreaming I should so soon receive
                    the letter I had looked for so long and vainly. I am so glad you are so happy
                    and very thankful that you have given <pb n="2"/> your heart to the blessed
                    Savior, and <hi rend="underline">with</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">your</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">husband</hi> have professed Him before the world. I know by
                    happy experience what an increase of joy and peace, <hi rend="underline"
                        >religion</hi> has brought to your wedded hearts I pray that you both may
                    prove "bright and <hi rend="underline">shining</hi> lights" in this world of
                    darkness, sin &amp; sorrow.</p>

                <p>I had the pleasure of seeing Stiles a few weeks since at Uncle Jed's. He had
                    changed so much in the years since I had seen him, I could scarcely recognize
                    the handsome mischievous, baby pet, in the tall boy before me. I wondered if he
                    wasn't homesick, for he said he wanted to see them all at home right badly. I
                    had a very cool reception from <hi rend="underline">our</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">Aunt</hi>, and have concluded not to give her the <orig
                        reg="opportunity">oppurtunity</orig> to treat me so, soon, again.</p>

                <p>May just came to me for permission to take her doll and walk on the lawn. So I
                    put on her little hood, &amp; red cloak <pb n="3"/> and she kissed me "bye".
                    She will be <hi rend="underline">three</hi> years old the 14<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="instant">inst.</abbr> She grows rapidly, &amp; becomes daily
                    more interesting as her mind develops. She is a <hi rend="underline">world</hi>
                    of comfort to her Pa &amp; me. I received a letter from Ma last week, and
                    she says sister Emma, (Mrs. <abbr expan="George">Geo.</abbr> P. Holman) has a
                    beautiful little daughter! How I would like to see Emma and her <hi
                        rend="underline">bridling</hi>! She has an excellent husband, and a lovely
                    home Our family were all well, and still delighted with the climate, soil,
                    scenery, &amp;c, of <hi rend="underline">Oregon</hi>, and especially with
                    the celebrated Willameth Valley, where they live. I am very anxious for brighter
                    skies natural, financial, and political. Are not you? By the way, is "<hi
                        rend="underline">Mayor</hi> Ellyson" your husband's father? I was very much
                    interested in the correspondence between <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr>
                    Walker &amp; <abbr expan="General">Canby</abbr>, in which <pb n="4"/>
                    reference is made to Mayor Henry Ellyson, &amp; wondered if he and your
                        <orig reg="father-in-law">fatherinlaw</orig> were not the same.</p>

                <p>Do you know that Nannie was in Richmond last week? Yes; she was there from
                    Thursday <abbr expan="evening">eve.g</abbr> until Saturday morning. It rained
                    Friday and she didn't get anywhere except to Capitol Square. She stopped at the
                        <hi rend="underline">Exchange</hi>. About a month ago she went to Salem,
                    Roanoke <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> to visit a <orig reg="schoolmate"
                        >school-mate</orig>, and while there, here uncle William was appointed a
                    delegate to the Valley <orig reg="Railroad">Rail Road</orig> meeting in
                    Baltimore, &amp; wrote to her to meet him in Charlottesville, &amp; he
                    would take her on with him. She did so, and they spent one week in Baltimore.
                    There she heard <hi rend="underline">Carlotta Patti</hi> sing, and <hi
                        rend="underline">Ritter</hi> the great Pianist, played. She was quite <hi
                        rend="underline">carried</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">away</hi> with the concert From Balt <pb n="5"/> imore they
                    went to Washington, where they spent two days, visiting all the public
                    buildings. Georgetown, Arlington, &amp; <abbr expan="Mount">Mt.</abbr>
                    Vernon. Went by water to Richmond. Nannie was so <hi rend="underline">sorry</hi>
                    she did not know your address, for she was anxious to see you. She enjoyed her
                    trip mightily, and <hi rend="underline">declares</hi> she has been <hi
                        rend="underline">half</hi> around the world! She came home last Saturday
                        <abbr expan="evening">eve,g</abbr>, and we certainly were glad to see her.
                    She is well, and sends a great deal of love.</p>

                <p>Do you ever see Maggie Eidson, alias, Mrs. Pete Wilson? I hope when I visit
                    Richmond I may see both of my old scholars, Lora and Maggie.</p>

                <p>I have stopped to get dinner for the hands, and "snack" for Frank, and now as I
                    have a chance to send this to Churchville, I must close. <pb n="6"/> Give my
                    love to your Ma &amp; Pa when you write, and all the family. I do not feel
                    as if your husband were exactly a stranger, and shall therefore follow the
                    promptings of my heart, &amp; ask you to present him with my kindest
                    regards.</p>

                <p>Will you not write very soon? I do want to hear from you often.</p>

                <p>Goodbye</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your loving friend</salute>
                    <signed>Allie M. Sterrett</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
