<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2568"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2568">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     December 17, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, december 17 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2568</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502057</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, December 17, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, december 17 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-12-15">1862-12-15</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Death/Casualties, Home Front, Slavery, African Americans, Church/Religious
      Activity, Battle Description, Troop Movement, Patriotism</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2568T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes a recent battle, and discusses affairs at home, such as servants and
     children.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-12-17">Wednesday Dec. 17<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Camp at Moss Neck Caroline Co. Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="Dear">Dr</abbr> Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I just <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> your letter of the 10<hi rend="super">th</hi>, the
     first word from home since I left, <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> I have written four or five
     times --I am very sorry you have had such a time with Anna, &amp; hope she is now better
     and may continue so -- for I know it is very hard on you to have so many cares -- I see, by
     your letter, that you are worn down by care, and so have the "horrors" -- You will say I do not
     appreciate your troubles, but I know I do, and fully feel for them all, but words are of little
     use &amp; I can only hope for days of peace and respite from the stern demands of cruel war
     to enable me to fix myself &amp; family as I would desire, and so they may have as much of
     comfort as this changing and uncertain world can supply -- I do not expect to find any
     perfectly satisfactory <orig reg="state">sate</orig> of things in such a condition of being as
     this, and only hope to <hi rend="underline">use</hi> its transitory pleasures and ills, mixed
     as they are, as preparatory for a better &amp; surer world -- <pb n="2"/></p>
    <p> I have written to you about Allen -- I will see to the payment of his hire &amp;c, and I
     wrote to you to know what you desired about servants &amp;c and hope to hear from you in a
     few days, in reference to that. I wrote you a gloomy letter the day before the big fight of
     Saturday, in which I indulged in gloomy anticipations of what might happen on the morrow, but
     my gloomy mood passed with the day, although that day brought sadness to many hearth stones --
     gloom to many a household, yet God's good Providence spared me -- and I am thankful, truly
     thankful, for my own sake &amp; ten thousand times more on my family's account -- and may
     God for his Son's sake still shield me -- May that it may be so, My Dear, &amp; teach our
     little ones to ask protection from our Heavenly Father for me from the "arrow that flieth at
     noonday"</p>
    <p> The account of the battle in the papers is a very good one -- and you can form a good idea
     of what was done from that. The enemy crossed back night before last, during a storm, to the
     other side of the Rappahannock -- leaving his dead on the field, although he had asked and
     obtained <pb n="3"/> a truce to take off his wounded and bury his dead and had collected them
     from the battle field for that purpose -- thus tacitly admitting that he had been completely
     whipped -- cut short in his onward career towards Richmond -- We heard that the enemy intended
     to cross last night at Port Royal, 20 miles below Fredericksburg, so we started yesterday
     morning and came on down the Rappahannock &amp; came on to this place on our way to Port
     Royal, but heard that the enemy had not come down, so we halted by the wayside and bushed it
     for about half the night then the Gen. froze out and we hunted up a house and slept soundly
     until 10 o'clock this morning, the first time for several nights -- Burnsides has disappeared,
     but I guess we will soon find out his whereabouts. We are some 14 miles from the <abbr
      expan="Railroad">R.R.</abbr> now, but have constant communication -- My letter did not reach
     you in time for my box -- so I shall be content until such time as I can come or it can be
     safely sent to me to the care of Maj. Hawks at Guinea's Station <abbr
      expan="Richmond, Fredericksburg, &amp; Petersburg  
 Railroad">R.F.&amp;P. R.R.</abbr>
    </p>
    <p> I went down to the enemy's lines during the day <pb n="4"/> of truce and saw the Yanks carry
     off their dead -- I tell you they lost a great number -- they lay in heaps in many places, <hi
      rend="underline">mown</hi> down by the steady and continued fire of our brave soldiers.</p>
    <p> Our position was a very fine one, our men sheltered by the woods -- but we had many killed
     &amp; wounded by the shells of the enemy from long range guns -- One <orig reg="Battalion"
      >Battallion</orig> of our Artillery had 119 horses killed &amp; disabled and 98 men -- The
     line of battle was four miles long -- and the enemy had three lines of troops reaching about
     that distance and then masses of troops besides.</p>
    <p> Write to me soon my Dear -- I will try to come up soon and see about servants &amp;c
     &amp;c -- and I have some hopes we may be through with this war by Spring and, if my life
     is spared I may return to my family &amp; the pursuits of peace. If any one says I might
     pay my debts from my salary I can only say that such a person is a heartless wretch --
     destitute of patriotism and ignorant of what it costs a soldier to serve his country and defend
     such souless creatures as the set of sharks at home that think only of gain and personal
     aggrandizement -- I will write to Nelly a few lines though I have a head ache and feel badly
     tonight having been up so much of late</p>
    <p> Good bye and God bless you all </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
