<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2580"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2580">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, June
     4, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, june 4 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2580</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502069</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, June 4, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, june 4 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Only original available is a typed copy.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-06-04">1862-06-04</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Death/Casualties, National Government, Enlistment, Military Authority, Patriotism,
      Church/Religious Authority, Slavery, African Americans, Battle Description</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2580T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his brother to ask him to hire someone to help Hotchkiss' wife on the
     farm. He also relates news about the army, including the exploits of General Ashby.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-06-04">June 4th., 1862</date>
      <name type="place">New Market, Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="dear">dr.</abbr>
      <abbr expan="Brother">Bro.</abbr></salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have been so busy of late that I have not had time to write but a few lines about our
     Winchester victory, which you have all heard of. We made a terrible sensation throughout the
     North, Lincoln called for all the militia of the whole country to go to Washington to defend
     the capital, and they are rushing as fast as possible to defend Washington as they say. Old Abe
     ordered Fremont, Shields, Banks, and McDowell to strike after us, therefore, after securing our
     spoils, stores of the most valuable kind, arms etc., we have moved back for new combinations,
     to be followed by new results, no doubt. We are confident of success whenever our General sees
     fit to strike a blow, under the blessing of Providence, which follows his prayers and his
     exertions. I hope you are all getting along well and in comparative quiet, away as you are from
     the constant dangers, the daily and mighty toils and labors of contending armies. May God
     enable us to keep the foe away from our homes with his ruthless and despoiling hand. I am every
     day more and more impressed with the belief that of all human evils war is the greatest, the
     most degrading and horrible, - one from which all engaged in it long to be <hi rend="underline"
      >delivered</hi>. Misery and suffering all around them, suffering and anxiety at home.- Nothing
     but the preservation of our dearest rights could ever induce me to have anything to do with it,
     but we must fight out our destiny, come weal, come woe, and leave those that war does not sweep
     away to prove whether blood has been shed for good or for evil.</p>
    <p> We are having a tremendous rain, flooding everything, but it falls most heavily upon our
     enemy just now, by the blessing of a kind Providence, for they are compelled to take by ways
     and pursue us over unbridged rivers, and in the mean time we will rest and prepare to strike
     again. <pb n="2"/>
    </p>
    <p> Nelson, I wish you would hire some one, for me, to <hi rend="underline">work</hi> and <hi
      rend="underline">completely</hi> make my garden and send the bill, if necessary and I will pay
     it. My wife says she has not been able to get it well made, and I do not wish her to weary
     herself and make herself sick trying to work it.-- Do attend to this for me at once_ and have
     it well done, and I will be very thankful.</p>
    <p> I wish you would also buy, if ours is gone or scarce, 10 or 15 bushels of corn and send it
     to Sara for her use as she may wish.- I do not ask any of these things in complaint, but I
     cannot see to having it done, and I ask you to do it for me.- I long for war to end that I may
     go to my home in peace and stay there, content with any lot Providence may bestow.</p>
    <p> Yesterday the gallant Gen. Ashby, (for he is now a General) being attacked when alone by
     some 50 Yankee Cavalry, collected some straggling soldiers of ours and charged on them and
     killed some 25 and put the rest to flight, capturing horses, saddles, pistols etc., etc. I have
     some things I purchased for you in Winchester. When I can get a chance I will send them to you.
     I was sorry that I had not a chance to buy and send many things, but I had not. There are many
     things there to sell. Love and good wishes to all. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr>
      <abbr expan="brother">bro.</abbr></salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Write to me.</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
