<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2592"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2592">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss,
     January 24, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, january 24 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2592</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502081</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, January 24, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, january 24 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>The only original is a typed copy.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-01-24">1864-01-24</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Military Authority, Family, Women, Patriotism, African Americans, Slavery</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2592T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss relates news from home to his brother, including information about the death of
     their sister. He also discusses food prices, Confederate currency, and servant hiring.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-01-24">Jan., 24th., 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Home,</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear brother;-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have not heard from you for a long time, <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> I have written, and
     wrote last, but I know you expected me before now, and I was sure I should have been to see
     you, but I am not my own master, as you very well know, for all of us in the army are entirely
     subject to the wills of others. I got a furlough of 25 days the middle of December, and came
     home and was constantly busy to provide for the wants of my family for the coming year,
     intending to go back to your house, but the very day I got back to camp I was ordered to the
     Valley for duty, and have my headquarters now in Staunton, though I shall spend most of my time
     in the mountains.</p>
    <p> But, oh my Brother, I have sad news to tell you, our sister Jenny is dead. She died after
     the birth of a child that died also; thus we depart, one by one,- how sad the condition of our
     poor parents, now living at the old home, by the bridge, to have one by one those that have
     been their solace and support taken from them. Would God that we might be near to comfort them
     in their declining years. It is a heavy blow, for Jenny was truly their only remaining
     daughter. Heaven help them in their deep affliction.</p>
    <p> Nancy McKune wrote to Sara, by flag of truce, and the letter came yesterday. She did not say
     when Jenny died. Her daughter, Viola, is married to a <abbr expan="gentleman">gentm.</abbr> at
     Port Jervis. Mrs. Comfort is very well. She says everything is <unclear>tight</unclear> and
     people have hard times to get along.</p>
    <p> I come out last night, go away in the morning. I have an office in Staunton; Breeze
     Johnson's old office. If you can come over come there for the night. My men will be there if I
     am not. I do not see that I can get the potatoes you bought for me, so you had better dispose
     of them as best <pb n="2"/> you can, unless you can send us some to Staunton. It costs us a
     great deal to live now, the currency has depreciated so much. I only look forward to the day
     when it shall become worthless, then there will be an improvement. Independence must come
     before long in spite of any impediments in currency, etc We must expect hard times, but we must
     learn to endure them. My neighbors kindly sold me provisions at government prices, or I should
     not have been able to support my family. We have 9 pigs, quite a windfull at such times as
     these. Sara has been quite sick, had something like quinzy. She is not better. I sold the
     animal I wanted you to keep to E. Geeing and bought another of Liehliter. Richard comes to us
     the 15th of April. I shall feel much easier then, having some trusty one here. I got a girl of
     Col Sterrett for Sara for $60. I hired William again for $300. Cy. wants you, if you come over,
     to bring his things. He lives with Mr. Baylor, I think. Did you succeed in paying up your hire?
     I shall try to come by your house when I return to the army if I can. I want to see you all
     very much. Come over if you can and bring me 2 <abbr expan="bushels">bush.</abbr> of Sweet
     Potatoes, dispose of the rest. Write to me to Staunton and let me know how you all are, and how
     you are getting along.</p>
    <p> My regards to Dr. Y. and family. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff.</abbr> Brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
