<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2595"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2595">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss,
     December 30, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, december 30 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2595</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502084</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, December 30, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, december 30 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>The only original is a typed copy.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-12-30">1864-12-30</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Military Authority, Family, Women, Slavery, African Americans</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2595T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his bother while on furlough. He describes the weather, the hiring of
     slaves, and news of various neighbors, friends, and family.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Nelson H. Hotchkiss Howardsville Albemarle Co. Va.
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-12-30">Dec. 30th., 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Loch Willow, Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear Brother;-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p> I had made every arrangement, gotten the furlough, etc., to go to see you and bring my wife
     and children, when the weather took such an unfavorable turn I had to decline going and trust
     to getting another furlough when the weather becomes more propitious. I am very sorry for we
     had all counted on a Merry Christmas with you and a happy reunion, since it has been so long
     since we have met. The children were terribly "put out" as they had been thinking of the visit
     for a long time and making plans for enjoying the festive season with their cousin, but I hope
     when the season advances that it may become milder and dry up some, then I can let you know
     when to meet us and we will have the visit yet, by the blessing of God. It is very bad going
     here now, it has snowed, sleeted, rained, frozen and thawed by turns until the foundations are
     almost broken up and the mud has put an embargo on all movements; I was never as muddy in my
     life as a few days ago in coming from camp home; had to take three trials at my boots before I
     got them clean. The Maslin boys are here tonight on their way from home to their command,
     Rosser's old Brigade, which is encamped near Swope's Depot. They have both grown very much and
     are quite hearty and make fine looking young men. James acts as a courier at Brigade
     headquarters. I came home the day after the Yankees came up the Valley, and week ago today, and
     have been home and about ever since, looking after my affairs, etc. Our quarters at present are
     at Fishersville. I have rooms at a house near Mr. Hamilton's and am quite comfortably fixed; If
     you can come over, do, and see me there if you do not come further. We are getting along very
     well considering the times. <pb n="2"/></p>
    <lb/>
    <p>January 3rd. 1865. I had gotten this far when wife said it was bed time;- so I adjourned and
     have not found time to finish until now - late in the evening. I went to Staunton yesterday to
     hire a servant, but found that I could do nothing as they were all hiring for grain or produce
     of some kind and I find it hard enough to get what I want to eat. Servants hired very high;
     good men for 50 bushels of wheat and 50 of corn, enough to buy a servant in the market. The
     supply of servants was not at all equal to the demand. To secure William again, who has been so
     faithful to me, I bought him of his master who came up to sell him and his other servants -
     came in from Wisconsin, a genuine abolitionist, but like all the rest of them it must not cost
     him anything. I paid $5,000. Managed to raise $2,000 and borrowed $3,000 which I hope to find
     some way to pay before it falls due. Today I went to Staunton again and got a woman of Mrs.
     Opie - a first rate one, much better success than I expected. Today we finished a bridge over
     the river at Dudley's. I had our Engineer Troops come over and build it, put it across above
     the mill. Tomorrow I have four wagons to haul wood for me and hope to get up enough to last me
     through the summer, and next day I must go to camp again, my furlough having expired. Frank
     Sterrett is down below Petersburg with the 10th Virginia Cavalry, as also Bob Cochran, William
     Nelson, etc. They say they have a hard time of it. Henry Sieg is at home - jogging along as
     usual and enjoying very good health. We are having a very hard Winter - it has been snowing
     most of today and the ground is frozen quite hard. It is quite hard on stock, the supply of
     forage is so scant. I got as much fodder as will do me, I think, and a very good supply of corn
     - thanks to the liberality of my neighbors. </p>
    <p> John Bell and Mat Bell were married <pb n="3"/> last week. Dr. Hamilton is as attentive as
     ever to Mrs. Gooch. James Arthur Wilson goes with me hereafter. I had him transferred to my
     department. The people here are getting up a gib dinner for our army in camp in the country it
     is to come off next week.</p>
    <p> Give our love to all the children and Harriett. Tell Lora her Aunt wants her to write and
     tell her what sort of a cloak she got, the style of it, etc. Write to me to Fishersville and
     come and see me if you can. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your affectionate brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
