<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2906"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2906">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Phebe Ann McCormick to Enos Ott,
                    November 2, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county phebe ann mccormick to enos ott, november 2 1864</title>
        <author>McCormick, Phebe Ann</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2906</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502091</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Phebe Ann McCormick to Enos Ott, November 2, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county phebe ann mccormick to enos ott, november 2 1864</title>
            <author>Phebe Ann McCormick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Enos Ott Papers, Private
                            Collection of Gail Ott</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-11-02">1864-11-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Enlistment, Desertion/Leave, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2906T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter to her brother-in-law, Phebe discusses the feasibility of Enos
                    getting transferred within the military, the arrival of house guests, and the
                    return of some local men from service.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mr. Enos Ott<lb/>Camp Lee<lb/>Richmond<lb/>Virginia</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-11-02">November 2, 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Home</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your kind letter yesterday and was very glad to hear from you. You
                    speak of getting a transfer to M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Clanahan's Battery. I
                    would be glad indeed if you could as I would much rather you belonged to that
                    Company than to stay where you are. You remember that last night you were here,
                    you asked Frank if you could get <unclear>away</unclear>, but as in rather a
                    joking manner and he took it as such and did not give you a decisive answer, but
                    after considering the matter next morning, he thought you might be in earnest
                    and told me to tell you to come on if you had to go off service, that he <pb
                        n="2"/>would be very glad to have you as a member of their company and to
                    tell you to be sure and come on, that they would take on members. So you see
                    that you need not be uneasy about getting in if you wish, unless they have
                    closed down <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> since the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I owe him a letter soon
                    and I will write and ascertain all the particulars about it, whether you can get
                    in or not, but I almost know you can, for Eddie Brownlee is going to start to
                    that Company Thursday. Becca, Ginnie, Marie McCormick, Eddie Brownlee, one of
                    his sisters, and probably Amanda Miller are going to start down to the
                    neighborhood of Churchville Thursday. All going on business but Ginnie, and she
                    is going to her Aunt Sallies on a visit. Af <orig reg="course">coarse</orig> she
                    will bring your cloth home but her principal object is to pay <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    relatives &amp; friends a <pb n="3"/>visit. She has been over since last
                    Friday and is quite well. The <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <unclear>Parreiah</unclear> came over with Ginsife Friday &amp; <del
                        hand="h1"/> with us <unclear>big</unclear> night stayed for preaching
                    Saturday &amp; went home that evening. We had John, Sam Lightner, Charlotte,
                    and Aunt Jane that night. Sabbath evening we had Rev. W<hi rend="super">m.</hi>
                        M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Clure Rev. Dr. Thompson &amp; wife, General R.
                    D. Lilly Mr. John C. Echard Aunt Jane &amp; sisters family. <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen'l</abbr> Lilly, Mr. Echard and sister left the sisters
                    stayed all night. Cousin Robert came with me from Church &amp; stayed until
                    nearly bed time and was compelled to go to Staunton early next morning. Ma says
                    to tell you that she will send you a barrel with some supplies and <pb n="4"
                    />your overcoat by Mr. Thomas Shumate who is going down to Richmond next week if
                    he will take them, and she can still ascertain you are there. Write as soon as
                    you get this and let us know whether you can possibly get a transfer to
                    McClanahans Battery and will be coming to the Valley &amp; then we will know
                    what to do, whether to send it to Richmond or whether to wait until you come to
                    the Valley. We want you to write as soon as ever you get this and let us know.
                    Ginnie wrote to you a few days ago. I guess you have received it before this.
                    She would have written now but is very busy fixing to go down the country. We
                    received a letter from Davis at Staunton he was well. Henry Ott, George Cook,
                    Jas Brown Jas Callison George Cochran and several others were
                        <unclear>imprisoned</unclear> none of them got home Ott &amp; Jas
                    Callison you know got home from Richmond. <pb n="1"/>All send love to you Ginnie
                    is looking for a letter from you tomorrow You must write as often as you can and
                    let us hear from you Be sure &amp; write soon and let us know about your
                    transfer &amp; I remain as ever your devoted sister</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Phebe Ann</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
