<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2907"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2907">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Ginnie Ott to Enos Ott, November 12,
                    1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county ginnie ott to enos ott, november 12 1864</title>
        <author>Ott, Ginnie</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2907</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502092</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Ginnie Ott to Enos Ott, November 12, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county ginnie ott to enos ott, november 12 1864</title>
            <author>Ginnie Ott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Enos Ott Papers, Private
                            Collection of Gail Ott</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-11-12">1864-11-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2907T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter to her husband, Ginnie tells Enos about her recent stay at Aunt
                    Sallie's and how Jim Hanger was killed while in service.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mr. Enos Ott<lb/>Camp Lee<lb/>Richmond<lb/>Virginia<lb/>Care of Rev Henry
                        Brown</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-11-12">Nov 12th 1864</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Husband</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received yours of the ninth yesterday was glad to hear that you were getting
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">along</add> so well. I just returned from Aunt
                    Sallie's yesterday evening we had quite a nice visit they all wished you could
                    have been along; none of the girls were at home but Harriet Mattie is down at
                    Moscow with her sister her husband is dead, died at Lynchburg took <orig
                        reg="gangrene">gangreen</orig> in his wound had been dead a week <orig
                        reg="before">befor</orig> she got there she brought him home and buried at
                    Mr Howel's. We are in the neighborhood of Aunt's a week went down on friday went
                    to Mr. Heiser's Saturday Mr H took me to Nelson next day in the buggy we heard
                    Mr Preston preach. I was to see Cousin Hettie Heller on tuesday We got our cloak
                    cloth home it is <add hand="h1" place="inline">almost</add> as nice as broad
                    cloth your cloth is done, we could not bring it home as we were disappointed in
                    getting a buggy. Cousin Alf was at home busy making gold rings. I heard from
                    home yesterday they were all well I saw Mrs. Cooper, Essie, and Alex going down
                    to Aunt Sallie's Mag is down at Mr. Shirreys. <del hand="h1">Mr.</del> You spoke
                    of having a pair of boots made I do not know whether Mr. Row is at home or not I
                    dont think he is, his brother is at home sick, or was the last time I heard from
                    there I expect to go over home the first of next week I will find whether Mr.
                    Row is at home or not and let you know You said in your last letter you would
                    like for me to be down there to take dinner with you I would like to be there
                    some day, but much rather you were at home to eat with us. Phebe received your
                    letter thursday Ma said to tell you she did not send you any thing, as you
                    requested not she would like to send you some apples if she knew where to <pb
                        n="2"/>to send them Pa has not got all of his apples gathered yet he is busy
                    working with his potatoes &amp; corn he thinks he will have about 75 bushels
                    potatoes. there are some men here now gathering the corn out field for the
                    Artillery horses. I heard last Thursday that Jim Hanger was killed I do now know
                    whether it is true or not he went to see Miss Paxton in Rockbridge several times
                    when he was at home last summer, when she heard he was killed she said to his
                    sister I told you he would keep a bullet from killing some good man I believe I
                    have no interesting news to write this time Aunt Sallie's said to give their
                    best respects to you. The family all send their love to you. Sister is going to
                    Greenville and I will have to close as I have to send the letter over there. I
                    hope you will get home soon nothing more, but remain your affectionate Wife
                        <orig reg="until">untill</orig> death,</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Ginnie Ott</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I expect to go over home the first of next week, so you
                        may direct your next to Moffetts Creek.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
