<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2916"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2916">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Ginnie Ott to Enos Ott, December 8,
                    1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county ginnie ott to enos ott, december 8 1864</title>
        <author>Ott, Ginnie</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2916</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502101</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Ginnie Ott to Enos Ott, December 8, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county ginnie ott to enos ott, december 8 1864</title>
            <author>Ginnie Ott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Enos Ott Papers, Private
                            Collection of Gail Ott</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-12-08">1864-12-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Life, Desertion/Leave, Home Front, Medicine/Hospitals</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2916T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter to her husband, Ginnie discusses local acquiantances (including
                    Mayor Trout), her hopes that he will soon be out of the army, and recent prayer
                    meetings.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Moffatts Creek V<hi rend="super">a</hi><lb/>Dec 9<hi rend="super"
                        >th</hi><lb/>M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Enos Ott<lb/>Camp
                    Lee<lb/>Richmond<lb/>Virginia<lb/>Care of Rev Henry Brown
                    <name type="recipient">Mr. Enos Ott</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-12-08">Dec 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Husband</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Yours of the first came to hand last saturday I was glad to hear that you were
                    well and still there I am in hopes you will get home soon Mr Black and Mr Cooper
                    went to Staunton Tuesday and took your account book &amp; your papers had
                    just got there the day before Mr Trout thinks you will be sure to get home Henry
                    was saying he <add hand="h1" place="inline">hears</add> some men in the army
                    talking about getting up a petition to get you off. John Withers &amp; J
                    Wallace got home last Saturday, the things you sent by them come all right Mag
                    was at the Office when the stage got there and saw John Withers. Charlotte and I
                    were at Old Providence last Sabbath, went by Pas in the evening I asked them
                    what Mr Newton said about your hat and they said he said he would make it as
                    soon as he could. Phebe told me to tell you she would have written before this
                    but she was waiting on Pa to say when he would send the apples but she would not
                    wait any longer Harry has gone to work on the rail road and the apples cannot be
                    sent away <orig reg="until">untill</orig> he gets back, as Alex is sick and Jim
                    a poor wagoner. Mag is going to the Office this evening and to Mr Row's and I
                    suppose will get your boots as he was to have them done yesterday or to day but
                    I hope you wil get home before we have an <orig reg="opportunity"
                    >oppertunity</orig> of sending them to you. Joe Black came home monday night
                    &amp; started back yesterday morning says he has joined Shermans command but
                    he has not been in the army. Henry says to check on the bank for a thousand
                    dollars <add hand="h1" place="inline">for which exchange for</add>
                    <orig reg="specie">specia</orig> silver will do he would have written himself
                    but has not time he has some <pb n="2"/>some grinding to do and threshing today
                    &amp; expect to butcher tomorrow Mag &amp; Hannah have gone up to Mrs
                    McNutts to prayer meeting, there is prayer meeting every thursday at some of the
                    private houses. Mr Spencer is to be at a wedding tonight Mr Adam Brubeck
                    &amp; Miss Maggie <orig reg="Bowman">Boman</orig> are to be married, one of
                    the girls we saw in Staunton last fall. Cousin Willie Smiley has got home he
                    suffers very much yet with his wound had gangrene in it and they put something
                    on it to eat the disease out and it eat off one of the arteries he was at
                    Baltimore all the time. I believe I have no news of interest to write at this
                    time. We are all well. Davis writes that he is well and getting fat. I think
                    that camp life must agree with him better now than it did. I will close as I
                    cannot think any thing that will interest you, and it is almost dark. Nothing
                    more at present but remain your affectionate Wife until death.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Ginnie Ott</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
