<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2944"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2944">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    December 28, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, december 28 1864</title>
        <author>Spillman, Robert B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2944</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502114</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout, December 28,
                            1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, december 28 1864</title>
            <author>Spillman, Robert B.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-12-28">1864-12-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2944T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert writes to Kate about how he spent his Christmas and the health of his
                    family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-12-28">Dec 28<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Office <abbr expan="Chimborazo">Chimbo</abbr> Hosp No. 3
                            Richmond</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sweet Sister</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>The ever dear white winged messenger from your hand of the 23<hi rend="super"
                    >d</hi> just came duly to hand yesterday which found me <orig
                        reg="comparatively">comparitively</orig> well &amp; truly glad to hear
                    from you. Tis useless for me to undertake to give you an idea of the pleasure it
                    affords me to receive a letter from you or to <orig reg="describe"
                    >discribe</orig> the feeling &amp; interest with which each &amp; every
                    line is carefully read. Would that I could be the recipient of such dear letters
                    every day but truly it is a pleasure that such a character as I do not deserve.
                    Well Christmas is over, it past very quietly with me I met with no gay crowds or
                    rather visited no place where there was merry making. Christmas day I went to
                    Church &amp; heard a very good &amp; appropriate <orig reg="sermon"
                        >Surmon</orig> delivered by Doctor Duncan of this City in the <orig
                        reg="afternoon">after noone</orig> I called on a friend for a Short time
                    &amp; at night went to Church again. Thus past the day making the fourth
                    Christmas Since the war all of which I have spent away from home. The only treat
                    I had during this Christmas week was the receipt of you Ever welcome letter
                    which was handed me yesterday about <orig reg="noon">noone</orig>. I am just
                    learning how to appre<pb n="2"/>ciate such pleasures. <orig reg="It">it</orig>
                    was always very agreeable to me to correspond with my friend, but situated as I
                    am now makes it doubly so. <orig reg="Away">a way</orig> from my home &amp;
                    among Entire strangers leaves me quite a lonely life, it is truly more
                    monotonous here than it was in all my Experiences in camp. tis true, I believe
                    that I have made many <orig reg="friends">freinds</orig> while here but I am
                    deprived of the social comforts that I enjoyed with my company for there, I have
                    a fond brother whose society has been the greatest source of my pleasure ever
                    since I have been old enough to duly appreciate a brothers love and were I
                    deprived of a <orig reg="correspondence">correspondance</orig> with you <hi
                        rend="underline">dear Kate</hi> - dreary, &amp; <orig reg="almost">all
                        most</orig> comfortless, would be Every hour of my life. Just think what a
                    pleasure to have some dear loved one who, though separated from me by many
                    miles, still I have the pleasure of speaking with though it be through the
                    silent medium of the pen, tis truly gratifying believing as I do that I am
                    honored to night with this pleasure of writing to one who loves me with <hi
                        rend="underline">a pure sisterly unselfish love</hi> on whose word I may,
                    with impunity confide, believing that her pure heart knows no treachery, one
                    whom I love above all others of her sex, save her to whom I have given my heart
                    &amp; hand, with the promise <pb n="3"/>that the arm &amp; hand which
                    wields this pen shall shield her fragile form, through a life time that I hope
                    may be as pleasantly ahead as the few short hours are now in writing to my dear
                    Sister Kate.</p>

                <p>You stated in your letter that you wished to know how many brothers &amp;
                    sisters I have. I have four brothers &amp; four sisters. There are nine of
                    us in all. My Father and Mother are both living. My Father is nearly 75 years
                    old. My Mother about 66. I am the youngest son living, I have one sister younger
                    than my self. She is the youngest child &amp; she is grown. Well Kate last
                    Tuesday the 20<hi rend="super">th</hi> one year ago we parted a day Ever to be
                    remembered by me. <orig reg="What">what</orig> wonderful changes has taken place
                    since that <orig reg="eventful">Eventfull</orig> day. Twas there &amp; then
                    that I <del hand="h1">gave</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">took</add> the last fond looks upon one who has
                    made a lasting impression upon me though I never (at that time) Expected to see
                    or hear from you again but so forcibly was I impressed <del hand="h1">though
                    you</del> and strangers as we were these lines presented them selves to me.
                    <lb/>"We met as perfect strangers, <lb/>"But when we came to part <lb/>"Love had
                    improved its image <lb/>"Upon my throbbing heart <lb/>And upon the impulse of
                    the moment I determined to write to you regardless of the result which I did
                    &amp; am proud <pb n="4"/>to say that I have never regretted it. I have
                    found that my ideas of physiognomy &amp; human nature in my slight
                    observation has served me justly. <orig reg="You">you</orig> have proved to be
                    the realization or rather the result of my course has been a realization of what
                    might have been termed a castle built in the air for you are all that I had
                    fancied you were in my silent musings <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> simple language, <hi
                        rend="underline">a pure hearted kind affectionate good girl</hi>.</p>

                <p>Well dear Kate, I will not impose any longer on your patience, but will close my
                    uninteresting &amp; uninstructive letter. <orig reg="You">you</orig> must
                    remember me kindly to your dear parents &amp; your sisters. <orig reg="Say"
                        >say</orig> to your Sisters that I am glad to hear that they are so merry
                    hope you all spent a gay Christmas. I wish I could have been with you, tell miss
                    Molly that I did not get light but probably it was for the want of spirits.
                        <orig reg="Tell">tell</orig> her not to leap <orig reg="too">to</orig> soon
                    - who knows but what Lou may give me a sacking - <del hand="h1">the Old Augusta</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">then Rose Dale</add> might have increased charms
                    for me, <orig reg="goodbye">goodby</orig> dear Kate I hope miss Molly will
                    pardon me, for my bold suggestion. <orig reg="With">with</orig> my warmest
                    wishes for your <orig reg="welfare">wellfare</orig> &amp; happiness,</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain as ever <hi rend="underline">affectionately</hi></salute>
                    <signed>Robert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
