<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2948"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2948">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    December 22, 1865</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, december 22 1865</title>
        <author>Spillman, Robert B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2948</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502118</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout, December 22,
                            1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, december 22 1865</title>
            <author>Spillman, Robert B.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-12-22">1865-12-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Economy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2948T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert writes to Kate about his plans to move to Maryland for the work and wishes
                    her a Merry Christmas and Happy New Year.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate Armentrout<lb/>Greenville<lb/>Augusta Co Va</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-12-22">Dec 22nd 1865</date>
                        <name type="place">Fredericksburg Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Own Sweet <abbr expan="Sister">Sis.</abbr> Kate</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your most dear, &amp; ever welcome letter of the 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi>
                    <abbr expan="instant">inst.</abbr> reached me safely a few days ago which found
                    me very well &amp; truly glad to hear from &amp; to hear that you
                    together with your father's family were enjoying good health &amp;
                    prosperity, with the exception of the little bad feeling which prevented you
                    from attending Church but I truly hope that ere this reaches you, you may be
                    fully restored to perfect health again. Well <abbr expan="Sister">Sis.</abbr>
                    Kate it is now drawing <pb n="2"/>very near Christmas. Many in this place are in
                    anticipation of a gay time, at balls &amp; parties but I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> expect to be here during the Christmas. My calculation is to
                    leave here Christams night for home if I am not disappointed. That is if the
                    Steam Boat does not fail to make its usual trip from Baltimore. I cannot tell
                    now whether I will return to this place soon or not, it depends altogether upon
                    future arrangements. I reckon you had better not answer this, until you hear
                    from <add hand="h1" place="inline">me</add> again as there is no regular line of
                    communication to my County &amp; as it is near mid winter the Steamers are
                    about making <orig reg="their">there</orig> last trips. Consequently we are <pb
                        n="3"/>soon to be deprived of the only means of Public conveyence or
                    Communications with this place Should I return to Fredericksburg again I will
                    write to you immediately. I truly hope you may spend a pleasant time during the
                    Christmas. I really wish it was in my power to visit you this Christams I am
                    sure I could spend a pleasant time. <orig reg="It">it</orig> was two years the
                        14<hi rend="super">th</hi> of this month since we parted. Well do I remember
                    that <orig reg="eventful">eventfull</orig> day. What strange things time has
                    brought about. Two years ago we knew each other only as strangers tonight I
                    address you my Dear Kate as Sister &amp; must say as I have often said I
                    love you as such I feel like I am writing to one <pb n="4"/>who truly merits all
                    my love, in whose heart I am proud to say I have a place, according to my
                    unshaken confidence in your most noble &amp; worthy self. Remember my dear
                    Sister that though we be ever separated, you will ever be a bright star on the
                    pages of my fond memory if life is spared &amp; fortune smiles I am
                    determined to see you. I assure you there is nothing that would be more
                    gratifying to me than a visit to Rose Dale, the home of my much <orig
                        reg="loved">love</orig> Sister Kate. The night is growing old I must close
                    for the present by wishing you a Merry Christmas &amp; happy New Year my
                    love to all, wish your dear self may God forever bless you.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Brother">Bro</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>Robt</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
