<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2951"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2951">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    May 18, 1866</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, may 18 1866</title>
        <author>Spillman, Robert</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2951</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502121</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout, May 18, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, may 18 1866</title>
            <author>Robert B. Spillman</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-05-18">1866-05-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2951T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert writes to Kate of his worsening eyesight and how he now has to wear
                    eyeglasses. Expressing his continued brotherly affection for her, Spillman says
                    he hopes to see her soon and recounts local events.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-05-18">May 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Seeds farm <abbr expan="Westmoreland">West</abbr> Co Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Sister Kate</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>You very kind and ever dear letter of the 5<hi rend="super">th</hi> of April was
                    duly <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> which found <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">me</add> quite well &amp; truly glad to hear from you. I
                    reckon you think very strange of me for not replying sooner but when I tell you
                    the reason I know you will forgive me. About 5 or 6 weeks ago my eyes became so
                    very weak that I could not possibly see to read of wrote consequently I could
                    not answer your letter, &amp; even now, it is with the greatest difficulty
                    imaginable that I can barely make out to write I am reduced to the <orig
                        reg="painful">painfull</orig> necessity of wearing glasses. <orig reg="It"
                        >it</orig> is truly a sad <orig reg="misfortune">missfortune</orig> for ones
                    eyesight <add hand="h1" place="inline">to be</add> so seriously impaired as is
                    the case with me at this time, but I hope by the constant use of green glasses
                    to have my sight restored. My Brother once <pb n="2"/>suffered with the same
                        <orig reg="misfortune">missfortune</orig> but regained his sight by wearing
                    glasses. I hope I may be equally fortunate.</p>

                <p>Well Sweet Sister (Oh! how I love to call you Sister) you must not expect a long
                    or interesting letter this time for it is very <orig reg="painful"
                    >painfull</orig> to my eyes while I am writing &amp; besides I <orig
                        reg="can't">cant</orig> see the lines on the paper consequently my writing
                    will be very crooked &amp; imperfect <add hand="h1" place="inline">all</add>
                    of which I hope you will excuse. I am really sorry that I cant write so as to
                    interest you for your <hi rend="underline">dear sweet letters</hi> are always so
                    truly interesting to me, I wish my mind was more expansive, or that I was
                    capable of producing language that when transmitted to paper would fully <orig
                        reg="unbosom">unbossom</orig> my self to you. That I could tell you in
                    impressive language how dear you are to me &amp; how <del hand="h1"
                    >much</del> I appreciate your friendship. <orig reg="Had">had</orig> I the
                    intellect of a Byron &amp; could <add hand="h1" place="inline">wield</add>
                    the pen of a Novelist then might I give you some idea of my <hi rend="underline"
                        >profound</hi> admiration <pb n="3"/>of your <orig reg="inestimable"
                        >instimable</orig> worth as a <hi rend="underline">lady</hi> a <hi
                        rend="underline">Christian</hi> a <hi rend="underline">true noble</hi>
                    &amp; <hi rend="underline">constant</hi> friend one whose love I regard as a
                    boon too sacred to be bestowed upon one so <orig reg="insignificant"
                        >insignifficant</orig> as my worthless self. I cannot use figurative
                    language therefore Dear Kate, can only say I believe you are good &amp; in
                    simple language say, I love you &amp; am devoted to you more than any friend
                    under the same circumstances. It is truly greivious to <del hand="h1">my</del>
                    me Dear Sister that I am so situated that I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> visit
                    you. I know of nothing that would afford me so much pleasure as to be convenient
                    so I could enjoy your society often, but if ever I am blessed with means
                    &amp; opportunity, rest assured I will certainly visit you.</p>

                <p>Well <orig reg="Sister">Sis</orig> Kate, I have no news to communicate that would
                    be interesting to you times are exceedingly dull &amp; money scarcer than I
                    ever knew it before. Farming is the <orig reg="principal">principle</orig> order
                    of the day, though crops are looking <pb n="4"/>very badly in consequence of the
                    cold wet season, fears are entertained that crops will be very short this year
                    as the weather keeps so unnaturally cool. The health of the people is <orig
                        reg="generally">generly</orig> good in this community. I am in better health
                    than I have been for six months. My brother enjoys fine health. My father's
                    family is well himself excepted. <orig reg="He">he</orig> is quite old very
                    infirm &amp; constantly complaining.</p>

                <p>You must remember me kindly to your father &amp; family, with much love for
                    your self</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain as ever your fond friend</salute>
                    <signed>Robt. B. Spillman</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Write Soon</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
