<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2952"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="A2952">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Amanda C. Armentrout to William F. Brand,
                    June 3, 1866</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta amanda c armentrout to william f brand, june 3 1866</title>
        <author>Armentrout, Amanda C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2952</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502122</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Amanda C. Armentrout to William F. Brand, June 3, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta amanda c armentrout to william f brand, june 3 1866</title>
            <author>Amanda C. Armentrout</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-06-03">1866-06-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Women, Church/Religious Activity, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2952T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kate pleads with Willie to forgive her while recounting the story of the Biblical
                    serpent who led good Christians astray and away from the Lord. She says that she
                    was wrong to accuse Willie of acting wrongly by operating a distillery and
                    drinking.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-06-03">June 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi> 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Rose Dale</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sweet brother</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your very dear letter of 24 last Wednesday never was a letter read
                    with more interest than that; it found me enjoying the best of health one of our
                    dear <orig reg="Saviours">Saveirs</orig> best blessing (but how unworthy am I
                    for it) I can say dear brother that I was truly glad to hear from you &amp;
                    do thank my heavenly Father that he put it in your dear good heart to write
                    Willie dear boy I have wronged you will you forgive me I believe I have found
                    forgiveness in the dear Lord but will you forgive for I have been the cause of
                    all this trouble Oh dear brother it will kill me if you <orig reg="don't"
                    >dont</orig> forgive; just to think that I am the cause of my dear <orig
                        reg="bossom">bosom</orig> companions being lost, <orig reg="eternally"
                        >eternially</orig> lost. Oh my dear dear <orig reg="Saviour">Savier</orig>
                    <orig reg="pity">pitty</orig> &amp; forgive for I will give you my life for
                    the salvation of that dear soul yes dear brother I will spend &amp; be spent
                    for you though the more abundantly I love you the less I be loved; I deserve
                    nothing but your hatred &amp; contempt can I ever be happy again not <orig
                        reg="until">untill</orig> I see the dear one changed yes a Christian. <pb
                        n="2"/>Yes my dear brother if you allow me to call you thus last year you
                    started out with prospects bright &amp; <orig reg="alluring"
                    >allureing</orig> &amp; these were your words Kate I am going to make or
                        <orig reg="break">brake</orig> &amp; for <orig reg="whom"><add hand="h1"
                            place="inline">w</add>home</orig> for what for an unworthy <orig
                        reg="creature">creture</orig> as I (me) that did not deserve the notice of a
                    cat let alone the notice of one so pure so noble so good at heart as thou all
                    went on well prospect bright &amp; <unclear>brighning</unclear> grain came
                    in on <orig reg="every">evry</orig> side I must surely be the happiest man
                    living. Oh is this not flattering it is (like) an ideal lover or will be soon
                    but hark I hear a noise &amp; in come a fine looking old gent (<add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">Ah</add> the serpent coils in eden bows) Well Mr B
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> you want to go in <orig reg="partnership"
                        >pardnership</orig> with me you will make <orig reg="money">mony</orig> at
                    it; at what why <orig reg="having">haveing</orig> your grain distilled I <orig
                        reg="won't">wont</orig> go I must make my money some other way my good heart
                    &amp; God <orig reg="says">sais</orig> I must not go Ah come <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> listen at that you will make enough soon to get
                    married Ah that is charming well I must wait a while &amp; yes I must go
                    &amp; see K &amp; see what she <orig reg="says">sais</orig> about it Pa
                    &amp; K both oppose <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> care so much for Pa but K
                    is the one he lays it all out in flattering terms she said do as you <orig
                        reg="please">pleas</orig> &amp; Mr B <orig reg="says">sais</orig> at
                    last consented &amp; his word goes as far as mine with with me &amp;
                    farther too; he goes back but <orig reg="conscience">concience</orig> &amp;
                    Pa <orig reg="says">sais</orig>
                    <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> go but I am doing it <pb n="3"/>for K when he gets
                    back serpent enters what say you well I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know I
                    believe I will; well lets draw the article but we must have a dram first no I
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> indulge her come going in do such business
                    &amp; <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> last &amp; yourself besides you have
                    a cough &amp; it will help it; well K told me to take <orig reg="something"
                        >somthing</orig> for my cough &amp; that is the very thing any thing for
                    K all done for K. come Mr B there is a party a head tonight lets go no I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> care about it I just got a leter from K &amp;
                    she is very cold &amp; indifferent she is always writing something about
                    some nice fellow or her dear friend R that I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    <orig reg="believe">blieve</orig> she thinks as much of me as she ought I will
                    go &amp; a way he goes come Mr B join in the dance I can't come ah well I
                    will K is perhaps having her fun I will <orig reg="too">to</orig> drove away
                    sorrow Mr B you are very lively to night but it is all put on what is the matter
                    with you well I will tell you I fear my first love is blasted Oh my dear her
                    then thou only knows the agony of that dear heart. Soon the serpent goes to K he
                    has done his will with B he tell her that B has got to drinking she writes a
                    hasty &amp; insulting letter &amp; it insults &amp; <orig
                        reg="wounds">wonds</orig> B <orig reg="says">sais</orig> I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> care I will go &amp; see her &amp; quit her at once I
                    have done all this for her &amp; this is the thanks I got he comes but love
                    &amp; <orig reg="pity">pitty</orig> enters that good heart I will tell her
                    all my bad deeds &amp; she will <pb n="4"/>turn me off but instead it bound
                    her nearer to him &amp; what next the serpent is at work he <orig
                        reg="tells">tell</orig> K much &amp; she believes &amp; what is the
                        <orig reg="consequence">consecuence</orig> God knows she suffers for it but
                    is she <orig reg="alone">a lone</orig> no no Oh she ought to be she <orig
                        reg="deserves">diserves</orig> it all &amp; more but enough of this.</p>

                <p>My dear brother I take up your letter to read it &amp; how must I write can I
                    answer it you have used <orig reg="candor">cander</orig> you <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> love me &amp; can I blame you Oh you hate me what must I do
                    Oh my dear Jesus <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> thou help me and direct me Willie
                        <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> you try to love me if I be a better girl you
                    asked me once to try &amp; love you &amp; I did. brother you may you
                    have been laughed at &amp; ridiculed here lately for your indifference for
                    company; well you are not alone for I have been all that &amp; more scolded
                    &amp; threatened to be whipped for it &amp; what is it for not for the
                    worldly happiness of any one but it is for the salvation of a dear soul the one
                    who I have been the cause of being lost what is worldly happiness compared with
                    this eternity how long Oh how long shall we not meet in heaven where there are
                    no changes no sin &amp; sorrow known Oh my dear brother <hi rend="underline"
                        >meet Oh meet me there</hi>.</p>

                <p>Billie you say you fear the consequences of marrying when your affections are not
                    settled, I acknowledge I am not smart but do you think for one moment that I
                    would marry a man that did not love me no I never expect to find one that really
                    does therefore I expect to remain single &amp; try &amp; make myself
                    useful to my fellow <orig reg="creatures">cretures</orig> one mans happiness is
                    enough for me to <orig reg="destroy">distroy</orig> I have sown my wild oats
                    &amp; now I expect to live a resigned life though it may be very short yes
                    soon I may sleep beneath the say but I can say with a thankful heart Oh death
                    where is they sting A grave where is thy victory but enough</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Midie</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
