<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2962"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2962">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Amanda C. Brand to William F. Brand,
                    November 17, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta amanda c brand to william f brand, november 17 1867</title>
        <author>Brand, Amanda C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2962</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502132</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Amanda C. Brand to William F. Brand, November 17, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta amanda c brand to william f brand, november 17 1867</title>
            <author>Amanda C. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-11-17">1867-11-17</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2962T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Now married to Willie, Amanda writes to her husband of neighborhood occurrences
                    and family members.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Mr. William F. Brand<lb/>Alone Mills<lb/>Rockbridge Co<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Mr. William F. Brand</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-11-17">Nov 17th 1867<lb/>Sabbath night</date>
                        <name type="place">Rose Dale</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear dear husband</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have not <orig reg="read">Read</orig> any letter from you yet but if you are
                    like me you are anxious to hear from me yes dear one I am very anxious to hear
                    from you but more anxious to see you I am very well was very sick one day last
                    week my general health is very good Pa's family are all well with the exception
                    of sis F. she is complaining very much of her limbs Sis Lizzie &amp; her
                    little ones were up today Ida stayed with us I went with sis L this evening in
                    the <orig reg="carriage">careage</orig> to <orig reg="prayer">prayr</orig>
                    meeting none of our family were at church today Oh dear Willie you know not how
                    much I wished for you today I looked for you last evening <orig reg="until"
                        >untill</orig> late <orig reg="hoping">hopeing</orig> you would come I tell
                    you I am home sick or sick to see you any how this has been a long day to me or
                    my thoughts have been mostly about you wondering where my dear Willie was I am
                        <orig reg="striving">striveing</orig>
                    <pb n="2"/>to become more thoughtful than I have been I have had many serious
                    thoughts about my <orig reg="inconsiderateness">inconsideratness</orig> but I
                    hope that it all be forgotten by thee &amp; when I do <orig reg="err"
                    >ere</orig> again that you will draw me close to thy bosom &amp; reprove me
                    kindly for it dear one you know not how much it <orig reg="grieves"
                    >greaves</orig> me to think that I am so thoughtless but I always was a wayward
                    child &amp; I do hope that you will <orig reg="pity">pitty</orig> &amp;
                    forgive Oh dear Willie how I wish you were here tonight I will certainly expect
                    you next Saturday evening.</p>

                <p>There are two gents here tonight Mr. <unclear>Hies</unclear> Crobarger &amp;
                    Willie Shields John <unclear>Sune</unclear> was here Thursday night <orig
                        reg="until">untill</orig> bed time &amp; he failed to come last night he
                    &amp; Sam A are going to visit you &amp; I at Christmas tell the girls
                    they must set <orig reg="their">there</orig> caps for them Miss EA Shuey expects
                    to visit me very soon after I move so I hope I will not get <orig reg="homesick"
                        >homsick</orig> but I must close for tonight Flossie is here in <orig
                        reg="bed">bead</orig> she sends much love to you &amp; your dear one
                    sends all hers to you &amp; a kiss beside<lb/>your wife<lb/>Kate</p>

                <p><pb n="3"/>Nov 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> I have been very busy today had not
                    time to get the blues my health is very good this evening hope this may find you
                    enjoying the same; I expect to go a visiting tomorrow take Ida home from there
                    to Mr Richard I do not know when I will be ready to move three weeks at <orig
                        reg="farthest">fartest</orig> I hope I am busy fixing I have <orig
                        reg="authorized">otherized</orig> Pa to buy a stove, several hogs, &amp;
                    a saddle if they go cheap at some of the <orig reg="sales">sails</orig> around
                    here hope it will meet with your approbation you must bring some money down with
                    you &amp; come prepared to go to Staunton dear one I am very anxious to see
                    you &amp; hear from you hope you did not catch cold working on the <orig
                        reg="dam">damm</orig> well dear one I must soon close as I am writing with
                    out fire remember me kindly to all inquiring friends tell Lizze I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> want her &amp; the Lieut to get <pb n="4"
                    />married <orig reg="until">untill</orig> I return tell Rash that Miss Lightner
                    is looking very well <unclear>Matter</unclear>
                    <orig reg="rumor">rumer</orig>
                    <orig reg="says">sais</orig> cousin Maggie Crist is to be married at Christmas
                    to Mr Goodlow but enough O may my dear husband lead a pious &amp; happy life
                    is the daily <orig reg="prayer">prayr</orig> of thy fond wife</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Kate a Brand</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
