<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2976"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2976">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    January 2, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, january 2 1863</title>
        <author>Brand, William F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Mary Elizabeth McCaskill</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2976</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502146</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout, January 2, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, january 2 1863</title>
            <author>William F. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-01-02">1863-01-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2976T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William writes to Kate of camp life giving specific information on his messmates
                    and the health of friends in the army.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Miss A. Kate Armentrout<lb/>Greenville<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Miss A. Kate Armentrout</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-01-02">Jan 2th 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Winder</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>It is with pleasure that I again seat myself to drop you a <orig reg="few"
                    >fiew</orig> lines I arrived safely in camp Monday last. I was very glad to see
                    the boys and <orig reg="they">thay</orig> seemed glad to see me with them again
                    My health has been very good since I left home I thought Saturday night in
                    Staunton was one of the <orig reg="loneliest">lonliest</orig> nights that I ever
                    spent I had a very nice time coming down on the cars I had very little or no
                    trouble with the box for Jake he would make me eat a meal or two with him for
                    fetching it down to him I mess with Christ Abe Trotter Lightner Abury &amp;
                    Bretton <orig reg="there">thare</orig> is some talk of <pb n="2"/>us forming a
                    new mess I suppose you have <orig reg="heard">hurd</orig> of our victory in
                        <orig reg="Tennessee">Tenasee</orig> I think the picture of our <orig
                        reg="Confederacy">confederacys</orig> is <orig reg="brightening"
                    >brightning</orig> and I hope before long we will be a free and <orig
                        reg="independent">independant</orig> people the army is in the very best of
                    Spirits the boys are mostly speculating as soon as Plunkett brings a load the
                    boys buy him out &amp; then sell at a small profit I believe Abe has made
                    twenty Dollars today. Well <orig reg="they">thay</orig> had one on <orig
                        reg="guard">gard</orig> last new years night the boys all said if <orig
                        reg="they">thay</orig> had have been in my place thay would have <orig
                        reg="stayed">staid</orig>
                    <orig reg="until">untill</orig> after <orig reg="New Year">newyear</orig> I am
                    very well <orig reg="satisfied">sadisfied</orig> that I have got back to the
                    company We have a very nice camp <pb n="3"/>and I hope we may stay <orig
                        reg="here">hear</orig> for some time we are in eight miles of Ginnie Station
                    We have plenty of wood <orig reg="but">put</orig> the water is not very good, I
                    was very much obliged to you for the fine pickle you sent me to eat on my
                    departure from Greenville. You ought to have seen me part with Hattie I know you
                    would have sent me a larger pickle. I found Cous, Jimmie looking rather badly he
                    has not been well for some time I gave him the apple as you requested with your
                        <orig reg="sympathies">simpathies</orig> in his late <orig reg="distress"
                        >distresses</orig>. I found Bros, Charles &amp; John well and <orig
                        reg="hearty">harty</orig> I have taken a very bad cold since I returned to
                    camp put hope it will soon <orig reg="wear">ware</orig> off I have been very
                        <orig reg="cheerful">cheerfull</orig> ever since I <pb n="4"/>got to camp
                        <orig reg="there">thare</orig> is no news of importance to write I expect we
                    will <orig reg="have to">hafto</orig> go on picket tomorrow The boys are mostly
                    all well Curg is looking splendid. John Meeks <orig reg="arrived"
                    >arrieved</orig> in camp today our Company No. over forty for duty I would have
                    written <orig reg="sooner">soon</orig> but we had to <orig reg="move"
                    >moove</orig> and then build us bunks oh kate how often I think of you, and wish
                    for the time when I may be your true and constant companion you are constantly
                    with me in my dreams be <orig reg="cheerful">cheefull</orig> my Kate for by the
                    will of providence I will soon return write soon as I am <orig reg="always"
                        >allway</orig> glad to hear from you <orig reg="goodbye">good by</orig> my
                    one dear Kate as it is almost dark</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>from your true and affectionate friend</salute>
                    <signed>Willie Boy</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
