<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2983"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2983">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    January 21, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, january 21 1864</title>
        <author>Brand, William F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Mary Elizabeth McCaskill</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2983</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502153</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout, January 21, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, january 21 1864</title>
            <author>William F. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-21">1864-01-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties,
                        Medicine/Hospitals, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2983T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William writes to Kate that he will release her if she so desires although he
                    loves her. He then describes the sickness of her brother John and his resulting
                    furlough as well as camp life.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Miss Kate Armentrout<lb/>Greenville<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate Armentrout</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-21">January 21th /64</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Randolphs</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I take the present opportunity of answering your letter of the tenth. I was truly
                    glad to hear from you But alas it bore tidings that went like <orig
                        reg="poisoned">poisind</orig>
                    <orig reg="missiles">misles</orig> to my heart I have set down before for the
                    purpose of writing to you; but my heart failed me, And now with a sad heart, I
                    attempt to drop you a few lines, My health is very good, this I sincerely hope
                    may find you enjoying both health and <orig reg="happiness">hapiness</orig>, I
                    have no news of moment; worth your <orig reg="attention">attneention</orig> so
                    you must look for an <orig reg="uninteresting">uninterresting</orig> letter You
                    may well imagine my heart is full <pb n="2"/>to over flowing; you ask me if my K
                    -- would prove faithless towards me could I forgive her. Dear Kate you know that
                    I have a forgiving heart If you should learn to love another man better than me;
                    or that you could enjoy your future <orig reg="happiness">hapiness</orig> better
                    with your first lover than with <orig reg="poor">boor</orig>
                    <abbr expan="Willie">W.</abbr> I would be heartless not to free you &amp;
                    forgive you; though I could never forget or <orig reg="cease">seace</orig> to
                    love you. To <orig reg="harbor">harber</orig> such thoughts as I have alluded to
                    above make me feel miserable: To think that my first love should be <orig
                        reg="wrecked">rect</orig> or thrown away on one <orig reg="far">fair</orig>
                    <orig reg="too">to</orig> good for me, one that is good pure &amp; <orig
                        reg="virtuous">virtueous</orig> who made vows unto me while her first love
                    seemed to be <orig reg="dying">dieing</orig> away, Then after a long time she
                    again meets him: &amp; her old love is rekindled for him, &amp; she to
                    good and kind to hide it from me has opened her <orig reg="whole">hold</orig>
                    heart to me <pb n="3"/>And asks me what she ought to do under such circumstances
                    Dear Kate what kind of an answer can I give but pray Almighty God to help you to
                    prove true to who ever you love; best; I am <orig reg="resigned">resined</orig>
                    to the will of providence Dear Kate if you should ever learn to forget me I pray
                    thee to never boast of having fooled me; <orig reg="thereby">thareby</orig>
                    <orig reg="adding">ading</orig> pain to a true but wounded heart, if you should
                        <orig reg="cease">sease</orig> to love I would have nothing to live for in
                    this world; I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> see that I should desire to live out
                    this war But would be <orig reg="willing">wiling</orig> to throw my self in
                    danger of the <orig reg="missiles">misles</orig> of death that I might quit this
                    frail world &amp; be at <orig reg="rest">reast</orig> I will change this; to
                    me; <orig reg="painful">painfull</orig> subject. I hope that you are happy and
                    are trying to <orig reg="interest">interrest</orig> your kind &amp; docile
                    Brother that is now with you. I hope he may enjoy <orig reg="every">evry</orig>
                    hour <pb n="4"/> of his short stay at home. I was on picket when he started for
                    home; Brother John is at home on furlough poor fellow was very sick when he left
                    camp I went as far as Orange with him. I have had to haul him <orig reg="there"
                        >thare</orig> in a ambulance I have never <orig reg="heard">hurd</orig> from
                    him but hope he arrived <orig reg="safely">safly</orig> at home, No doubt he
                    will pay you all a visit before returning to camp, oh yes you said that in
                    fifteen days that Lizzie was going to leave home you left me to guess for what
                    purpose I supposed that she is going to get married if so I would like very much
                    to be at home &amp; see her name changed my kindest regards to L --
                    &amp; tell her that I wish her much <orig reg="happiness">hapiness</orig>
                    through all the changes of this life My <orig reg="respects">repects</orig> to
                    all enquiring friends if <orig reg="there">thare</orig> be any I had a very
                    strange dream the other night I <orig reg="dreamt">drempt</orig> that me
                    &amp; you had fallen out &amp; Rachel Crobarger was <orig
                        reg="interceding">interseeding</orig> for me, I must close you must write
                    soon &amp; a long letter give me all the <orig reg="particulars">perticulars</orig>
                    <orig reg="concerning">consurning</orig> L nothing more</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>But remain yours truly as ever</salute>
                    <signed>W.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">You will please never show this to any one</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
