<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A3002"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A3002">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris,
                    September 23, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county tony pastor to annie harris, september 23 1862</title>
        <author>Tony Pastor</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A3002</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502162</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris, September 23, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county tony pastor to annie harris, september 23 1862</title>
            <author>Tony Pastor</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris,
                            September 23, 1862, Nellie Harris private collection</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-09-23">1862-09-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties,
                        Medicine/Hospitals, Military Strategy, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A3002T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Writing to his lady friend Annie, Tony describes a recent successful march into
                    Maryland, including the capture of Harper's Ferry. He mentions a great ensuing
                    battle but says he has no time to discuss it in detail.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-09-23">Sept. 23<hi rend="super">d</hi>, 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Martinsburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Annie,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your most welcome letter dated the <unclear>5</unclear><hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    has just this moment come to hand, which believe me was read with delight
                    &amp; interest, it being the only one <orig reg="received">recived</orig>
                    from any source whatever for more than a month. You have no idea how much good
                    it does a poor soldier to get a letter from absent friends, especially those who
                    are as near &amp; dear as I believe you to be. I was truly glad to hear that
                    you were in the enjoyment of your usual health. hope you may continue to enjoy
                    the same so long as you are permitted to pilgrimmage in the wicked world of
                    ours. Suppose that you have had a full account of the battles as manassas before
                    this; taking this for granted I will not occupy your time with a repetition, but
                    will hasten on to give you a brief account of our trip into Maryland. We crossed
                    the <pb n="2"/>river near Leesburg after the battles at Manassas &amp;
                    proceeded to Fredrick City in Fredrick County. We captured some few stores,
                    &amp; all the wounded &amp; sick in Hospital, numbering some 500, the
                    most of whom were convalescent, took <unclear>possession</unclear> of the
                    Baltimore &amp; Ohio Rail Road &amp; Telegraph wires, destroyed the
                    bridge. here we camped a few days, from thence we marched in the direction of
                    Hagerstown to a little town called Boonsboro here we had a little skirmish with
                    some <orig reg="Yankee">Yankey</orig> Cavalry, which resulted in killing one
                    &amp; capturing one, from thence we marched to Williamsport a little town on
                    the Potomack, where we recrossed the river, from thence to Martinsburg where
                    there were several thousand Yanks (Longstreet &amp; Hill Divisions remaining
                        <pb n="3"/>in Maryland) but before we reached the place they made their
                    escape to Harper Ferry. We remained there a short time, after which we went on
                    towards the Ferry, in the mean time Hills division marched on to the "Maryland
                        <orig reg="Heights">hights</orig>," &amp; <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> on the
                    "Virginia", Jackson bringing up the rear. When we got about 3 miles of the
                    Ferry, we could see the Yankee tents <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> on "Bolivar <orig
                        reg="Heights">hights</orig>" - this was on Saturday evening. On <orig
                        reg="Sabbath">Sabath</orig> morning our batteries opened on them from the
                        <orig reg="heights">hights</orig>, which was responded to by the enemy, but
                    our men having a much higher position rendered their shot inaffective. we were
                    then completely around them with <add hand="h1" place="inline">no</add> chance
                    of their making an escape. Old Jack sent in a flag of truce demanding an <pb
                        n="4"/>unconditional surrender they asked till the next day. The firing was
                    kept up all day &amp; on monday morning our batteries opened again having
                    changed their position, it was not long until they hoisted the white flag. Old
                    Jack was soon in their midst, thus ended the scene - about 13,000 prisoners were
                    taken including 1,500 Negroes, 15000 stand of small arms, 50 pieces of
                    artillery, 1500 horses 4 or 500 wagons ambulances &amp; a <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    We were then marched on to Shepardstown Crossing into Maryland were our forces
                    were attacked by McCleland, Burnside, &amp; in fact the whole of their army
                    from Washington &amp; on the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> just one of the
                    greatest battles of the war was fought, of which I have no time now to speak,
                    suffice it to say our loss was very heavy, &amp; that of the enemy <orig
                        reg="equal">eqal</orig> as heavy if not more so. I must close for tonight.
                    If we dont move in the morning I will add a few lines more Good night god bless
                    you.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours, in haste</salute>
                    <signed>Tony</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
