<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A3025"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A3025">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris, June
                    10, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county tony pastor to annie harris, june 10 1861</title>
        <author>Pastor, Tony</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A3025</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502185</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris, June 10, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county tony pastor to annie harris, june 10 1861</title>
            <author>Tony Pastor</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris, June
                            10, 1861, Nellie Harris private collection</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-06-10">1861-06-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Women, Homefront, Enlistment</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A3025T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Pastor describes one of his first guard duties and the general hardships he has
                    faced in his early time in the army. He also asks Annie to find more recruits
                    for his company, offering specific suggestions and mentioning that his company
                    is falling behind the others in numbers. Parkers also hopes that all is well on
                    the homefront, and he sends his regards home.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-06-10">June 10<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Bolivar</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dearest Annie,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p> I received your very welcome epistle on saturday evening &amp; was truly
                    glad to hear that you were in good health &amp; enjoying <orig
                        reg="yourself">your self</orig> to the extent you spoke of. I am sorry to
                    tell you that I lost your last letter. I was taking a short walk in the evening
                    after reading it, on very <hi rend="underline">important</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">business</hi> of which I will not now take time to notice
                    further, but I'll tell you all about it if I live to get back to Old Augusta</p>
                <p>We have just returned this morning from guard duty. we were ordered out last
                    night as a picket guard started between seven &amp; eight oclock &amp;
                        <orig reg="traveled">
                        <unclear>travailed</unclear>
                    </orig>; between 2 &amp; 3 miles to an Old Mill, where we made our <orig
                        reg="headquarters">
                        <hi rend="underline">head</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">Quarters</hi>
                    </orig>. we then posted one half of them around at different points<pb n="2"/>
                    where they stood for four hours. The other half staying at the mill, not being
                    allowed to go to sleep, as we were expecting to have an attack. some of our boys
                    were pretty badly scared. at seven oclock we started back for our Old Quarters
                    where we arrived at half past eight pretty hungry. we then partook of <hi
                        rend="underline">Bread</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">Beef</hi> with
                    coffee to our satisfaction &amp; now <hi rend="underline">I</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">am</hi> seated at <del hand="h1">at</del> table in the
                        <abbr expan="Captain's">Capt's</abbr> office writing to <hi rend="underline"
                        >my</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">dear</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">Annie</hi>, whilst many of our Boys are fast <orig
                        reg="asleep">a sleep</orig> in their rooms. Billy McK. is laying close by me
                    knocking it off at the rates of "<hi rend="underline">forty</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">miles</hi> an hour". I am so sleepy that I can't hardly see
                    the paper myself &amp; if I should make mistakes I hope you will excuse me.
                    I <abbr expan="received">reced</abbr> a note from your cousin Anne yesterday
                    through Mr. Craig which believe <hi rend="underline">me</hi> I esteemed very
                        much<pb n="3"/></p>
                <p>I am glad to know that the ladies are cared for by the few that are left behind.
                    I hope you will be successful with <hi rend="underline">the</hi> Old Bachelor.
                    You must not let your cousin Annie get ahead of you, but I expect she is already
                    ahead. as he lives so convenient to her. I understood you to say you were over
                    with Tom. how is he &amp; <unclear>Hamm</unclear> getting <orig reg="along"
                        >a long</orig>? notify him to hold himself in reading to go. For I think all
                    will have to go soon. I wish you would try &amp; get some recruits for us -
                    tell <hi rend="underline">Davis</hi> he'll have to go &amp; he better come
                    &amp; join company I think you might get lotts of boys for <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        "<hi rend="underline">Pett</hi>" you know you can do any thing in the world
                    with him. we would like to have about fifteen or twenty more. Our <abbr
                        expan="company">comp</abbr> is falling behind the others. They have been
                    getting a number of recruits in some of the <orig reg="companies"
                    >company's</orig>. Capt. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/><pb n="4"/> Compy is now in Shepards
                    town I suppose they will have a good time. There's so many nice ladies there. I
                    almost wish I was there myself. I can't remember what was in your letter, so I
                    can't answer as I would like to. This is the only sheet of paper I have,
                    &amp; I have no money to pay postage so I'll have to quit. I <orig
                        reg="can't">cant</orig> get a bit of change no way nor no how but I expect
                    its best so. For if I had, I would spent it foolishly.</p>
                <p>I must bring this filthy sheet to a close. hope to hear from you soon.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>as ever yours</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">Tony</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">P</hi>
                    </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I saw John T______ this morning as I was coming home. he
                        looks very well &amp; seems to be in fine spirits. He
                        <unclear>papier</unclear> a <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> on you says you were the finest
                        looking lady he saw at church. I think he is in love. I suppose I had better
                        be on the look out but I'll take the chances &amp; trust to providence
                        for the result.<lb/> N.B. Please let no one this sheet Annie<lb/> Tony
                    P</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
