<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A3030"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A3030">
     <teiHeader type="migrated">

          <fileDesc>
               <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris,
                         December 24, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county tony pastor to annie harris, december 24 1861</title>
        <author>Pastor, Tony</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                         <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                         <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                         <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                         <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                    </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
               <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                    <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                    <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                    <idno type="VCDH">A3030</idno>

        <!--
                    <availability>
                         <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                         <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                         <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                              University of Virginia</p>
                    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                    <date value="2002">2002</date>
               <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502190</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
               <seriesStmt>
                    <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
               </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                    <note/>
               </notesStmt>

               <sourceDesc>
                    <biblFull>
                         <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris, December 24, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county tony pastor to annie harris, december 24 1861</title>
            <author>Tony Pastor</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                                   <resp/>
                                   <name/>
                              </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                         <editionStmt>
                              <p/>
                         </editionStmt>
                         <extent>4 pages</extent>
                         <publicationStmt>
                              <publisher/>
                              <pubPlace/>
                              <date value=""/>
                              <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Tony Pastor to Annie
                                   Harris, December 24, 1861, Nellie Harris private
                              collection</idno>
                         </publicationStmt>
                         <seriesStmt>
                              <p/>
                         </seriesStmt>
                         <notesStmt>
                              <note/>
                         </notesStmt>
                    </biblFull>
               </sourceDesc>
          </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

          <profileDesc>
               <creation>
                    <date value="1861-12-24">1861-12-24</date>
               </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
               <handList>
                    <hand id="h1"/>
               </handList>
               <textClass>
                    <keywords>
                         <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Military Authority,
                              Military Strategy, Patriotism, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
                         <term>American Civil War</term>
                    </keywords>
               </textClass>
          </profileDesc>

          <revisionDesc>
               <change>
                    <date value=""/>
                    <respStmt>
                         <resp/>
                         <name/>
                    </respStmt>
                    <item/>
               </change>
          <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
     </teiHeader>

     <text id="A3030T">
          <front id="d2">
               <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                    <p>Pastor writes that his Company, without him because of an illness, traveled
                         to destroy a dam but was unsuccessful. He says that he and his fellow
                         soldiers are considering joining the regular army so that they can have
                         furloughs.</p>
               </div1>
          </front>
          <body id="d4">
               <div1 type="figure" id="d5">
                    <p>[picture of a cannon firing beside a "Stars and Bars" flag with 10
                         stars]<lb/> Bright banner of freedom with pride I unfold thee;<lb/> Fair
                         flag of my country with love I behold thee,<lb/> Gleaming above us in
                         freshness and youth;<lb/> Emblem of liberty, symbol of truth;<lb/> For the
                         flag of my country in triumph shall wave,<lb/> O'er the Southerner's home
                         and the Southerner's grave.<lb/>
                         <lb/> Confederate States of America </p>
               </div1>
               <div1 type="letter" id="d6">
                     <opener>
                         <dateline>
                              <date value="1861-12-24"><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 24th
                              1861</date>
                         </dateline>
                         <salute>Dear Annie,</salute>
                    </opener>

                    <p> I am again seated by the same old fire place, where I was when I last wrote
                         you. We have just returned from one of the severest marches we have had
                         since we came into the service - namely a trip to the <orig reg="Potomac"
                              >potomack</orig>. <del hand="h1">2</del> Two weeks ago yesterday there
                         was a detachment of 4 companies from our Regiment sent to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                         so 4 on the <orig reg="Potomac">Potomack</orig>, for the purpose of
                         breaking up the dam. I was unwell at the time, consequently was left behind
                         to take care of the baggage in company with three or four others who were
                         in a like condition. Our company was one of the 4. they took the cars at
                         Stephenson's Depot which is within a few hundred yards of our camp. from
                         thence they went to Charlestown, where they stayed a day. from thence they
                         marched through Shepards Town on to the dam<pb n="2"/> which was for the
                         time to be the scene of action. They had two pieces of the Rockbridge
                         Artillery with them for the purpose of scaling the walls. But <orig
                              reg="owing">oweing</orig> to the fact of <orig reg="there"
                         >their</orig> being so many Yankees on the opposite shore, &amp; the
                         almost impossibility of breaking the dam, they returned to martinsburg
                              (bring<add hand="h1" place="inline">ing</add> with <add hand="h1"
                              place="inline">them</add> 8 prisoners - Consisting of 1 <abbr
                              expan="Captain">Capt</abbr>, 2 <abbr expan="Sargeants">Srgts</abbr>
                         &amp; 5 Privates. They had been sent out as a scout &amp;
                         unfortunately for themselves were discovered by our <hi rend="underline"
                              >galant</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">brave</hi>
                         <abbr expan="Colonel">Coln.</abbr> Ashby who with a detachment of his
                         Cavalry soon surrounded them &amp; in a few moments they were our
                         prisoners. They fought like heroes till the very last, &amp; even after
                         our men had taken them, one of them attempted to shoot, but it was no use.)
                         Our men remained in Martinsburg <orig reg="until">untill</orig> the 16<hi
                              rend="super">th</hi> at which time the rest of the Regiment joined
                         them in Company with the whole of the Brigade. We then went to <unclear>sam
                              so</unclear>
                         <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> - which is still higher up the river. For the purpose of
                              breaking<pb n="3"/> it, in which we succeeded nobly, <orig
                              reg="losing">loosing</orig> but one man. he was a member of the
                         Rockbridge Rifles by the name of Parks. It would be useless for me to
                         attempt to give you a full <orig reg="description">discription</orig> of
                         all that we saw &amp; heard, whilst on the <orig reg="aforesaid"
                              >afforesaid</orig>
                         <orig reg="expedition">expidition</orig>. suffice it to say that we had the
                         pleasure of seeing a goodly number of Yankees. <unclear>paid</unclear> the
                         compliments of the day by throwing <hi rend="underline">bomb</hi> shells at
                         each other &amp; many other attractive scenes <orig reg="too">to</orig>
                         numerous to narrate at present I must <orig reg="hasten">haten</orig> on to
                         a conclusion as it is <orig reg="very">verry</orig> cold this morning so
                         much so that I can scarcly write. I recognize a letter from Tom B. last
                         night, was glad to hear that he was enjoying himself so much with the
                         ladies. Hope he may <add hand="h1" place="inline">be</add> successful in
                         winning the affections of some fair maid.</p>
                    <p>I wish I could be with you all tomorrow to get something good at eat for
                         dinner, but alas; it <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> be so. How great the
                         contrast will be with<pb n="4"/>
                         <hi rend="underline">many</hi> of <hi rend="underline">us</hi> this
                         Christmas to what it was last. But I hope this will not be your lot. May
                         you have a merry time in the <unclear>prayers</unclear> of us all.</p>
                    <p>A great many of us have almost come to the conclusion to join the regular
                         army, as there is no prospect of us ever getting home any other way. <orig
                              reg="If">I</orig> we join the regular service we will be allowed
                              <unclear>60</unclear> days furlough &amp; <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> of 50
                              <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> which is considerable <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to many - Well
                         I must stop for the present &amp; make some arrangements for dinner.
                         Give my best respects to Miss Jenni &amp; Mollie &amp; all the rest
                         of my lady acquaintances.</p>

                    <closer>
                         <salute>Yours in haste</salute>
                         <signed>Tony P</signed>
                         <seg type="postscript">P.S.<lb/> Let me hear from you after the <orig
                                   reg="holiday">hollyday</orig>, &amp; give me a full history.
                              I had forgotten to say that I had received your last, the perusal of
                              which was a source of <hi rend="underline">much</hi>
                              <hi rend="underline">pleasure</hi> I assure you<lb/> Tony P<lb/><lb/>
                                   M<hi rend="super">c</hi> sends his love to you all with a desire
                              to hear from you soon. If <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> out any <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                              old <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> send M<hi rend="super">c</hi> &amp;
                                   <unclear>soldier</unclear>
                              <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> want to make sure <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                              <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                              <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                              <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> much like getting in a big bust</seg>
                    </closer>
               </div1>
          </body>
     </text>
</TEI.2>
