<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4051"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4051">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August
     30, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 30 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4051</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502250</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August 30, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 30 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-08-30">1863-08-30</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Desertion/Leave, Church/Religious Activity, Camp Life, Arts/Leisure, Military Authority,
      Women, Home Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4051T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his wife, describing a Sunday in camp, the sermon, and music and dancing
     entertainment. He gives his wife his thoughts on education/religious training for the
    children.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-08-30">Aug. 30<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
      </hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2<hi rend="underline">
       <hi rend="super">nd</hi>
      </hi> Corps Orange <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr></name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Darling Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have not heard from you but once since the one joyful day I spent at home &amp; feel
     uneasy at your unusual delay, but think the excitement that has been in the Valley may have
     prevented, in fact unfitted you, for anything but care for the passing hour -- I suppose the
     danger of an invasion of our quiet home has passed away &amp; I thank God for it, &amp;
     you are saved from the presence of our cruel enemy. It is Sunday morning, we have had a sermon,
     a morning lesson, from Habakkuk &amp; all but myself have gone over to the churches, I
     remain to attend to anything that may need attention, but all is quiet &amp; in war we are
     almost in profound peace -- in fact too much of ordinary life is becoming a part of our camp
     life, and the tendency to amusements is far to prevalent for<pb n="2"/>times like these. But
     there are two sides to this question &amp; much philosophy &amp; some Scripture in the
     song "Let the wide world wag as it will, We'll be gay &amp; happy still" &amp; the text
     "There is a time for all things" &amp; "There is nothing better than for a man to eat
     &amp; drink &amp; enjoy the good of his labor". The Fast day was well &amp;
     solemnly observed, but yesterday there was a gay picnic, with music &amp; dancing, at Gen.
     Johnson's <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> -- to which all the officers of the
     Division &amp; the Corps <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> were invited, all but
     two or three went from here -- I did not feel like going -could not think so much gaiety right,
     though I am fond of rational amusements &amp; like the <hi rend="underline">cheerful</hi>
     phase of things. I have been very busy &amp; have much to do just now, as the surveys of
     the country, from the parties in the field are coming in &amp; I am making copies so we may
     have a set of accurate maps for our use &amp; this long rest is a perfect harvest time for
     business, &amp; I cannot <hi rend="underline">now</hi> see my leaving time, but shall
     obtain it before the winter that I may<pb n="3"/>prepare for it for you, &amp; have things
     comfortable fixed up -- (D. V.) Mr. Lacy <abbr expan="received">recd</abbr> a few days ago a
     box of the nice English Bibles &amp; Testaments procured by Dr. Haze &amp; I got a set
     of the Gospels, four pretty little volumes, in flexible black covers, beautifully printed, for
     Nelly, as she is learning the Scriptures, they are very pretty every way &amp; then the
     dear child can have the satisfaction of learning a whole volume -- I shall send them when I can
     safely &amp; I have another set which I shall keep a volume of at a time to read, but send
     the others to you, in charge for my darling little Anna, whenever she shall begin to learn the
     Scriptures &amp; I have a nice Nonpareil Testament for My Dear Little Wife, which I think
     she will like, it is small &amp; plain, clearly printed &amp; has a soft &amp;
     pleasant cover &amp; I think will add a new pleasure to the reading of the Sacred Volume
     she loves so well --<pb n="4"/>The weather has been quite cold for several days &amp; I
     slept cold last night for the first time in a long while, but such is a soldier's life. I have
     a copy of the Life of Jackson, which I wish to send to you though it is not very good &amp;
     not very entertaining to us that have read the living Man -- yet it has in it much to interest
     others -- Gen. Lee is still in Richmond, maturing something I suppose &amp; the cool
     weather will invite to action &amp; soon the horrid carnage of the battle will disquiet the
     eye &amp; sicken the heart. "O when will man cease to do evil? &amp; when, O Lord! will
     Thy kingdom come &amp; Thy will be done on earth as in Heaven -- I heard Harman wish to go
     home <orig reg="today">to-day</orig> &amp; infer that his wife is in an <hi
      rend="underline">interesting</hi> condition -- Mrs. Ewell is still here, but do not think her
     presence is very good for the Old gent -- so says the Dr -- the "bold, bad man" as our Capt.
     Johnson says --</p>
    <p> I have no news my Dear -- my letter is very dull &amp; I am rather stupid myself so this
     letter will only be like opening the door &amp; looking at you, or rather letting you look
     at me &amp; then bowing myself out. Write to me, my Love, if only a little &amp; asking
     for "Heavenly blessings without Number" for all my little home circle, I will say good- bye </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">How is Allie's health now -- have you heard? I shall send you money this
      week. Yours of the 28<hi rend="super">th</hi> came last night -- good -- first rate &amp;
      I hope my 2 last are with you -- I have not heard of my slippers or letter - - Send Nelly to
      the school if it will relieve you -- but I believe there will be little saved &amp; if we
      can educate them as we set out -- But I do not want you to have all the burden of it</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
