<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4065"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4065">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     December 6, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, december 6 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4065</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502264</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, December 6, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, december 6 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-12-06">1863-12-06</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, Battle Description, Military Authority, Camp Life, Arts/Leisure,
      Church/Religious Activity, Patriotism, Family</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4065T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his wife, describing a skirmish with the Union troops, and discussing the
     patriotism of the soldiers in the Army of Northern Virginia.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-12-06">Dec. 6<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
      </hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place">"Morton House" -- Orange Co. Va --</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear One:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>This is Sunday night &amp; though I have written to you this week &amp; have nothing
     of interest to communicate, I cannot forgo my custom of having a chat with you at this time
     regularly -- It is said the enemy has removed his infantry across the Rappahanock into Fauquier
     Co -- only keeping his cavalry in Culpeper -- his trains of wagons to his calvalry pass down to
     their camps in full view of our infantry camps -- &amp; yesterday some of our men went over
     yesterday &amp; had a skirmish with them. Some think Gen. Lee may go over to attack Meade,
     but I hope not, it is too late in the season, &amp; we might find ourselves in the midst of
     a winter storm &amp; suffer much. Today has been quite cold, sharp wind -- I have spent the
     day at home, reading &amp; talking. Read Doddridge's Life, my Bible &amp;c. Mr. Lacy
     preached in one of the Brigades not far from here -- He is a good talker &amp; has now
     formed one of my mess &amp; consequently I see much of him -- he always has something good
     to tell &amp; whiles away much of the tedium of the men -- society, camp life &amp;c.
     Everyone longs for the conclusion of the war &amp; a return to their homes, yet no one
     talks of giving but until our liberties are obtained -- come what may. A few days ago, while we
     were in the <unclear>near ch</unclear> I found <abbr expan="Washington">Wash.</abbr> Reeves
     &amp; Lil. Stout marching back from where they<pb n="2"/> had been as a guard &amp;
     they told me they had not had any rations for a day &amp; a half -- so I invited them to
     come and spend the night with me, as our camp was near -- &amp; I had a big supper prepared
     and you may believe they did it justice, it would have done you good to see the hungry fellows
     eat -- they slept in my tent &amp; breakfasted with me &amp; then went to camp -- very
     grateful for my hospitality -- they are both good soldiers - Reeves an excellent one &amp;
     very neat -- Lil retains much of his former self, but has been improved by the duties &amp;
     labors of a common soldier -- Our men endured much hard labor unrepiningly during our late
     movement - - in fact I do not thing the world ever saw a nobler &amp; more unselfish set of
     men than the Army of Northern Va -- I shall apply for my furlough some time about the 20<hi
      rend="underline">
      <hi rend="super">th</hi>
     </hi> &amp; intend to ask for 20 days. I much hope that Richard will come up before I get
     home -- I know Garber is very loth to part with him, but he promised me that he might come when
     he got his fall work done -- But some way will be provided I trust, for the Lord has been very
     gracious to us in these days of trial &amp; suffering &amp; let us humbly acknowledge
     his mercy &amp; strive to obey in all things his most holy commandments -- Kiss my little
     daughters for me, may the Lord make them good &amp; amiable, abounding in modesty &amp;
     all Christian graces -- May the Lord bless &amp; keep you all -- My loved ones -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Ever sincerly your husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
