<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4071"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4071">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, April
     21, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, april 21 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4071</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502266</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, April 21, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, april 21 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-04-21">1864-04-21</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Women, Battle Description, Prisons/Prisoners, Military Authority, Arts/Leisure, Family,
      Death/Casualties</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4071T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss relates news of camp and the army to his wife.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-04-21">April 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Morton Hall</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Own Dear One:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I know you are expecting to hear from me &amp; I will not disappoint you by a longer
     delay. I wrote you on Sunday -- We got off on Monday &amp; got through to <abbr
      expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> the same evening - all in good spirits &amp;c -- I
     found my horses at the Depot -- they had stood the trip well -- Found Mrs. Ewell still here but
     making arrangements to move to Richmond -- she was much pleased with her things - butter, eggs
     &amp; flour -- She has been at work today packing up &amp; starts tomorrow We are all
     much gratified at the news of the capture of Plymouth N. C. by Gen. Hoke of our Army -- he took
     1600 Yanks &amp; many guns &amp;c, thus made possible some other movements that you
     will hear from before long -- I hope &amp; that will do us much good -- every thing seems
     to work well this &amp; by God's blessing I think it will be to us the most successful year
     of the war --</p>
    <p> Every thing here is very quiet but the storm may come at any time<pb n="2"/> I think we are
     ready for it &amp; that we shall succeed -- Everything here is as quiet as the country away
     from the army -- we only see the soldiers now &amp; then as they go to or return from
     picket -- The General intends to go into camp in a day or so so that we may get used to it. The
     grass is very nice &amp; green here &amp; our horses are doing well -- if we can stay
     here a short time they will improve much --</p>
    <p> The Chief Commissary sent us some fine fish today -- I wish I could send mine up to you --
     they issue good rations to our troops, better than ever before -- but corn meal is the only
     bread stuff they issue now -- </p>
    <p> I have been a good deal amused by a Life of Gen. McClellan, by <unclear>Portorn</unclear>
     that they have here -- it was evidently gotten up under "Little Mac's" own eye for his benefit
     -- but there are many rich confessions in it.</p>
    <p> I sent a good many things home but want to send some more as soon as I can -- I do not
     intend to be troubled by much baggage, especially as we are not allowed much --<pb n="3"/>Col.
     Faulkner was here a few days ago -- he desires to come back to the Army &amp; will come to
     our <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> I suppose -- he is not satisfied away -- Dr.
     Dabney will soon publish the 1<hi rend="super">
      <hi rend="underline">st</hi>
     </hi> Vol. of his Life of Jackson -- it is said, by those that have seen it, to be very well
     written -- he makes no mention of "Maj. Gen" -- L. H. Smith of the <abbr
      expan="Virginia Military Institute">V. M. I </abbr> in all the book - because he could say
     nothing creditable to him in reference to his dealings with Gen. Jackson.</p>
    <p> We now have a Maj. Gen. -- M. L. Smith as our Chief <abbr expan="Engineer">Eng</abbr> -- I
     have not yet made his acquaintance -- he rides his horse as erect as a ramrod. Pendleton looks
     finely -- getting married has had a good effect on his appearance -- his wife has gone to
     Richmond to live with a cousin of his -- who is on duty there -- The change in water has made
     us all feel a little badly, but we are getting over it --</p>
    <p> I am working closely to get ready for the campaign -- Write to me often -- I shall be very
     anxious to hear -- Many kisses for you all -- Nelly &amp; Anna &amp; "My Dear" May the
     Lord bless you - </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
