<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4094"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4094">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     September 3, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, september 3 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4094</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502289</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, September 3, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, september 3 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-09-03">1864-09-03</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Home Front, Troop Movement, Military Strategy, Military Authority, National Government,
      Battle Description, Camp Life, Agriculture</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4094T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss relates to his wife the latest troop movements and skirmishes. He also discusses
     the coming presidential election in the North, particularly the McClellan ticket and its
     implications for peace.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-09-03">Sept. 3<hi rend="underline"> <hi rend="super">rd</hi> </hi> 1864 --</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters Valley District">Hd. Qrs. V. D.</abbr> Stephenson's Depot</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Sara:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Yours of the 27<hi rend="underline">
      <hi rend="super">th</hi>
     </hi> came to hand in two days -- the first <hi rend="underline">late</hi> news I have had from
     you in a long time -- so you know it must have been very welcome -- the more so that it
     contained good news -- that is news of your good health &amp; spiritis &amp;amp; the
     good rains &amp;amp; prospects of something to eat &amp;c. We are constantly moving
     about, as usual; yesterday we moved from Bunker's Hill towards Charlestown, intending to attack
     the enemy, Averill found we were moving &amp; drove in our cavalry Vaughn's Brigade, which
     offered but little resistance to him &amp; then ran away leaving some 14 wagons in his
     hands &amp; compelling us to return from our movement to look after him -- we drove him
     away &amp; recaptured some of the wagons -- We came back here for the night -- had a
      very<pb n="2"/> long march -- Today we move again, back to Bunker's Hill &amp; then after
     the Yankees again. It is said part of the Yankee troops have gone to City Point -- if so we
     shall give them a staggering blow -- We cannot rely upon our cavalry to hold points &amp;
     that makes it very difficult for us to move rapidly as we have to guard our trains constantly
     We learn by the late papers that McClellan &amp; Pendleton are the nominees of the Chicago
     Convention -- I have not seen the Platform -- but think it must be a peace one -- Pendleton is
     a southern man in principle &amp; it is thought he will be for peace -- everything
     indicates a strong peace movement in the North &amp; they may succeed in electing their
     candidates The nights are getting quite cold, but the days are very pleasant. I will write to
     Mr. Geeding about the horse -- should like to know what he will <pb n="3"/>give -- he knows
     what horses sell for now -- Ask him?</p>
    <p>Sept. 5<hi rend="underline">
      <hi rend="super">th</hi>
     </hi> -- I did not finish my letter before we were started off to join Gen. Anderson who had
     gon to Berryville &amp; there met &amp; defeated the advance of the Yankees towards
     Winchester -- whipping a corps with a division -- We went down to aid him &amp; found the
     Yanks had entrenched themselves strongly so we did not attack them, but the defeat Anderson
     gave them caused their cavalry to come back from a raid they had started way up the Valley, so
     our object was accomplished -- Yesterday we came back to <orig reg="Stephenson's"
     >Stephensons</orig> where we now are, in time to join our Cavalry in a fight they were having
     with Averill &amp; we drove him back several miles, until dark stopped the pursuit -- One
     of Alfred Wilson's sons was wounded in the fight, not <orig reg="severely">severly</orig>
     though -- we had several of the Cavalry killed &amp; wounded -- They behaved well <pb n="4"
     />It rained very hard last night &amp; today it is very moist -- We are being smoked by
     camp fires &amp; lounging round to pass the day -- I think the rain will do much good --
     making the ground fit for plowing. I suppose McClellan will be elected as nearly all the Army
     of the Potomac goes for him -- Pendleton, the nominee for Vice Pres., is a man with strong
     Southern feelings &amp; a peace man, it is said -- Evidently the Peace &amp; War men
     have made a compromise matter of the nominations &amp; will all be for peace if the signs
     of the times are as much in our favor as they are now. We are very well assured of the fall of
     Atlanta, since the Yanks have official <orig reg="dispatches">despatches</orig> announcing it,
     but we are full of hope that even good may come from temporary ill &amp; that Hood has not
     given up the place but for good &amp; sufficient reasons -- I am in excellent health --
     Hope to hear from you today again -- it seems a long time between your letters - Love to the
     children &amp; blessings for you from our Merciful Heavenly Father -- Write often My Sweet
     one -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">P.S. I send you, by mail, the May Iss. of Harper's Magazine --</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
