<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4092"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4092">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August
     15, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 15 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4092</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502287</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August 15, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 15 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-08-15">1864-08-15</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Troop Movement, Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Prisons/Prisoners, Military
      Authority, Military Strategy</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4092T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes troop movements and skirmishes with Federal troops, but no major
    battles.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-08-15">Aug 15<hi rend="super">
        <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
      </hi> 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Fisher's Hill</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I wrote to you the day we left Winchester &amp; enclosed some Ribbons for the children
     &amp; one or two other things -- I have not heard from you for some days but knowing that
     you will hear all kinds of stories &amp; will be anxious to hear the truth I will write
     again, though briefly -- We came back here on Saturday the enemy advancing in force to the
     vicinity of Strasburg but halting to deliberate as soon as they found we had reached a place
     where we intended to fight them &amp; since then they have been lying on the banks of Cedar
     Creek, 3 miles beyond Strasburg &amp; we on the banks of Tumbling Run 2 miles this side of
      <abbr expan="Strasburg">S.-g</abbr> with an occasional forward movement of Cavalry &amp;
     skirmishers first on one side &amp; then on the other, with no results -- We have been
     having a signal station on the end of Massanutten Mt. above Strasburg -- yesterday the enemy
     sent up 60 men to capture it, but our men got away &amp; we sent up a company of
     sharpshooters &amp; drove them away, capturing three &amp; killing two of them, with no
     loss to us -- today they have sent up again &amp; we have sent to dislodge them -- <hi
      rend="underline">that</hi> &amp; some little skirmishing is all that breaks the monotony
     of staying out here all day in the sun &amp; dust awaiting the advance of the enemy, or for
     "something to turn up" -- -- it is very<pb n="2"/>tiresome, but I suppose will not last longer
     than today, for Anderson with Longstreet's Corps, reaches Front Royal this morning &amp;
     Fitz Lee is already there, so we will soon be in Condition to assume the offensive again
     &amp; start Sheridan, who now commands the "Yanks" here, on the track so well beaten by
     Banks, Fremont, Shields, Milroy, &amp; Crooks &amp; Co. We just got a letter from Mosby
     in which he says he fell on the enemy's train day before yesterday at Berryville &amp;
     Captured &amp; destroyed 75 wagons, got some 200 prisoners &amp; some 600 mules
     &amp; horses &amp; killed a good many &amp; also he fell on a scouting party that
     was going to Culpeper &amp; routed them capturing &amp; killing a good many, Mosby is
     certainly one of the bravest spirits we have -- quiet &amp; modest, a fine looking fellow,
     but always in motion &amp; reaping a rich harvest of spoils -- William &amp; Sam.
     Chapman are both captains in his command -- &amp; are highly esteemed by him, I understand
     --</p>
    <p> We had a little rain last night &amp; it is pleasanter today than heretofore -- it has
     been intensely hot -- but we have managed<pb n="3"/>to stand it so far -- &amp; if we can
     whip the force that is now before us it will be a fine thing for the country. I think, as
     heretofore, that this campaign will go far to end the war &amp; do not think there will be
     much if any fighting after this campaign. No doubt the entire army will be here before long
     &amp; the field of battle be transferred to the Banks of the Potomac or North of it. Grant
     was at Harper's Ferry a few days ago &amp; is, no doubt, trying to get away from Richmond
     as best he can -- I got a very fine young horse in Maryland, it only cost me $100. in
     Confederate money, as Gen. Early let us have horses at the cost price there, paying in
     Confederate money the value fixed on them in Federal -- it was a good thing for me &amp;
     will enable me to sell one of my horses &amp; help to get along &amp;c whenever Charley
     gets in order I want to sell him if horses command a good price I hope there may be some
     cessation of active operations so I may get home for a few days early in Sept -- My shirts are
      <pb n="4"/>getting somewhat worse for wear &amp; I think I shall try to buy some ready
     made ones if we get where there are any, I believe white ones do as well as any others in the
     army &amp; they usually last longer -- I do not think it best to have any pants made of my
     cloth just now -- if you have not done anything to them just keep the cloth safely -- I will do
     all I can for your memoranda bless your dear little heart I wish you had all the things you <hi
      rend="underline">want</hi> I hope Parkins carried up the box of cups &amp; saucers
     &amp; that you have gotten it by this time. Write me how the children like the books -- I
     sent them &amp;c &amp;c Write me my love -- I know you have hard times this hot weather
     &amp; wish I could be at home to attend to affairs but be of good cheer -- all will yet be
     well -- Love &amp; kisses &amp; blessings for you all -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
