<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4103"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4103">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     November 5, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 5 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4103</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502298</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, November 5, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 5 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-11-05">1864-11-05</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Enlistment, National Government, African Americans, Slavery, Women,
      Church/Religious Activity, Home Front, Family</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4103T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes camp life, troop enlistment, and miscellaneous news about friends and
     neighbors, a church meeting, and Northern opinion of the war.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-11-05">Nov. 5<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
      </hi> 1864</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters Valley District">Hd. Qrs. V. D.</abbr> New Market
       Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>The labors of the day being over &amp; night with its quiet -- Saturday evening quiet,
     &amp; the prospect of a day of rest in anticipation, I will do, what I have thought of
     doing all the week, write you a long letter -- You will ask why I have put it off, -- if you
     could look into my 8 by 10 cloth house, with camp stove in one corner, Robinson &amp;
     drawing table in one corner, Oltman, ditto, in another &amp; your "other half" Do, in
     another &amp; all busy from 8 A.M. to 3 P.M. &amp; then some at night, you would not
     ask the question, for you would know that I am pretty well tired out when bed time comes, for I
     have not yet gotten used to the confinement, we have been such rovers this summer that I have
     been in the saddle more hours than in my office &amp; now the Reports of the <orig
      reg="year's">years</orig> operations are to be made out &amp; the number of maps, plans of
     battles &amp;c to be made is almost incredible, but I have gone at it with a will &amp;
     intend to finish them within the year, if possible.<pb n="2"/> Everything is quiet -- we are
     drilling the army &amp; getting it thoroughly reorganized &amp; ready for any emergency
     or opportunity. The reserves &amp; detailed men are coming in rapidly &amp; being
     examined &amp; assigned either to the army or light duty, as they are found capable or not.
     I saw M. J. M Hanger today, he has been passed for "light duty" &amp; will go to Richmond
     with the others -- he told me Mr. Euritt was also "passed" for the same &amp;, recommend
     for his trade at a "post" or light hospital duty &amp; he will be sent on at the same time
     &amp; may get to Staunton, in the shops there, that is the best that can be done for him
      <hi rend="underline">now</hi> -- the Government is determined to have <hi rend="underline"
      >every one</hi> -- I hope Mrs. Euritt will bear it calmly &amp; she may rest assured that
     Mr. <abbr expan="Euritt">E.</abbr> will not be exposed if unfit for field duty. I still think
     all "things work together for good" to indicate a speedy conclusion of the war &amp; if we
     are able to keep the enemy at bay, as heretofore, to the end of this campaign we shall not be
     troubled by them another year -- I learn from a scout that the prevailing <pb n="3"/>opinion at
     the "North" is that the war will end this year. By the way, the Yankees down here say they are
     going back below Winchester as soon as the Election is over -- I am sorry Reed has gone, if he
     has, but I think he will be back -- Mr. Euritt came to see me &amp; looked very well, I
     thought. I enclose you some Yankee stamps -- I did not tell you of the paper in my saddlebags
     -- I see you have <hi rend="underline">found</hi> it. -- use what you need for yourself, but do
     not let any go, for it is <abbr expan="Engineer">Eng.</abbr> property that I sent home for safe
     keeping -- by the way I sent off all my white envelopes, I believe -- if this reaches you
     before <abbr expan="William">Wm</abbr> leaves, send me 25 back. Maj. Bell was to send Maj.
     Green's clothes &amp; bed out to our house, but I reckon he sent them away in his flight
     &amp; has not brought them back -- I will write to him about them -- Glad you had a good
     time chestnuting &amp; that you are able to stir about -- nothing like it -- helps
     digestion &amp; keeps the clouds out of the head &amp; makes one <hi rend="underline"
      >sleep</hi> well at night -- <pb n="4"/>I enclose to you every day or so, the files of the
     papers that I get here -- so you can get the reading of them &amp; put them away -- If Miss
     Susan does anything to the coat I want it <hi rend="underline">turned</hi> -- if she has not
     undertaken "the job" why you may let it rest -- The Methodists are having "Big Meetings" here
     &amp; revivals - crowded houses day &amp; night -- the soldiers are near enough to come
     to meeting -- I imagine William has not been of much service to you -- the weather has been bad
     -- &amp; he has wanted to be with "Maj" &amp;c -- but if you got your fall work some of
     it off your hands I will, by the blessing of Providence get home in time to have some work done
     before <orig reg="New Year's">New Years</orig>. Put my bottle of ink in a safe place -- I shall
     draw some money Monday &amp; will avail myself of the first chance to send you some -- I
     wrote to you to get all the items I left on the <unclear>memo</unclear> for you -- they will
     all be needed - especially the "bread" -- &amp; potatoes -- I sent for the gloves for Miss
     Kate -- hope they will come -- I wrote you about Mr. R's shirt -- he is away tonight -- Write
     often -- be of good cheer &amp; May Heaven's choicest blessings be with all my "dear ones
     at home" -- Nelly can read the "Humming Bird" in the "Examiner" </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
