<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4112"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4112">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, June
     16, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, june 16 1870</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4112</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502303</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, June 16, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, june 16 1870</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1870-06-16">1870-06-16</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Women, Military Authority, Church/Religious Activity, Home Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4112T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his family from Lexington, describing a dinner at General Lee's and
     Church attendance. He comments on affairs at home.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1870-06-16">Jun. 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1870</date>
      <name type="place">Lexington Va. </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife &amp; Children --</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I was greatly delighted on hearing from you through Nelly's delightful letter of a week ago
     today, for I had looked for a letter two days before &amp; not getting one was sadly
     disappointed -- I intended to write to you last night but had one of my inveterate head aches
     &amp; so could do nothing but "kill time" &amp; try to get sleepy &amp; finally got
     to sleep well towards morning &amp; so, by my ususal remedy, got pretty much well again,
     barring the "sore" head that remains as a sting behind. I was sorry to hear that "Ma" has
     neurolgia -- I am a full convert to open fires again -- I have felt so much better, every way,
     since using them &amp; shall surely "turn out" the Latrobe as Ma desires -- In fact I wish
     you would open &amp; use the fire place at once, only firing up the "heater" when very cold
     -- I think you would all be benefitted by it -- I was <hi rend="underline">astounded</hi> to
     hear that Stiles had come -- I had no idea that he was coming &amp; expressly told Uncle A.
     that I did not <pb n="2"/>want him to come unless <hi rend="underline">you</hi> wrote to Aunt
     &amp; asked for him to come -- I cannot conceive how he got the idea into his head any
     other way -- I hope to be home for a day or so in a week or 10 days and will then see --
     &amp; hope in the mean time you may get along without much trouble -- but I really feel
     better satisfied that you have some male in the house that is white. I am glad you got an
     arrangement for a boy to do your chores &amp; hope you will get all the help you feel that
     you want &amp; I will provide for it. I am very busy &amp; have been feeling very well
     until yesterday. I had no idea there was so much difference in the climate -- it is so much
     warmer here -- I am satisfied -- than in Staunton -- I dined at Gen. Lee's last Thursday, by
     invitation, with Mrs. Gen. Albert Sidney Johnston &amp; daughter from <abbr
      expan="California">Cal<hi rend="underline">
       <hi rend="super">a</hi>
      </hi></abbr> &amp; Col. W. P. Johnston &amp; wife -- we had an interesting talk after
     dinner about <abbr expan="California">Cala.</abbr>, the Chinese &amp; c. I called at Dr.
      <orig reg="Madison's">Madisons</orig> Friday, after dinner &amp; had a pleasant visit
     there -- they had many <pb n="3"/>questions to ask about all of you, Staunton &amp;c --
      <orig reg="They">The</orig> use open grates now -- have not used their furnace this year -- I
     have not called at any other places as yet -- I have a fine <abbr expan="Philadelphia"
     >Phila.</abbr> photograph of Gen. Lee with his autograph which he gave me -- it is for Ma -- so
     none of the rest of you need speak for it. In writing to Mr. Haynes I enclosed a photograph of
     Gen. Lee with his Autograph to Mrs. <abbr expan="Haynes">H</abbr> -- and told him to tell her
     it was a "rebel" present -- I went to Church twice today -- at 11 A.M. to the <abbr
      expan="Presbyterian Church">Pres. Ch.</abbr> where Dr. Kirkpatrick preached a long &amp;
     very good sermon &amp; the choir sang <hi rend="underline">very mechanically</hi> &amp;
     the organ was played <hi rend="underline">very jerky</hi> with 10 minutes preludes -- At 4 P.M.
     I went to Episcopal <abbr expan="Church">Ch.</abbr> &amp; heard Dr. Pendleton on "How
     beautiful are the feet &amp;c. The Dr. had to rub the government twice -- I don't think you
     could find as many "unregenerate" rebs, in any other place in the state -- it "crops out" all
     around -- &amp; I could not help thinking Ma would find here many "congenial spirits" -- I
     have just been reading the "Central" -- a good number -- I thought how you had all read it
     today also -- It would <pb n="4"/>be a much more endurable "exile" if I could be at home on
     Sunday &amp; when I coem I shall make it so as to take in a Sunday -- I got the Spectator
     -- much obliged -- but you need not send any more for I find <hi rend="underline">all</hi> the
     town papers at the printing office &amp; go there &amp; run them over -- Sandy Garber
     was here last night -- as full of troubles as ever &amp; as shiftless -- has had a fuss
     with <unclear>"Dunning"</unclear> &amp; drove him off -- but told me he had heard that he
     had gone back yesterday -- I am much gratified at <orig reg="Nelly's">Nellys</orig> statement
     of what she intends to do in the way of study &amp; hope she may &amp; will persevere
     -- I know Anna is getting along also &amp; if you both get so you can go to school of
     course I shall send you -- but you can learn <hi rend="underline">more</hi>, far more, with <hi
      rend="underline">"Mother,"</hi> if you will -- We will see when I come - - I am sorry to hear
     that Grand Ma is worse -- I hope she may get better &amp; that Ma may find her in the
     spring in her ususal health - Mr. Ruffner came to see me &amp; we had a <hi
      rend="underline">long</hi> talk -- he is sanguine of success - I don't think Allan will run --
     This letter is for <hi rend="underline">all</hi> &amp; I want all to write -- I won't
     excuse Ma -- I want the continuation of the sweet good page she gave me -- Stiles [?] must be a
      <hi rend="underline">good</hi> boy says uncle Jed -- <orig reg="Heaven's">Heavens</orig>
     blessings on you all -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Yours in love --</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
