<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A5021"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A5021">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Martha Trimble to Alexander McCorkle, June 27,
     1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county martha trimble to alexander mccorkle, june 27 1867</title>
        <author>Trimble, Martha</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A5021</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502313</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Martha Trimble to Alexander McCorkle, June 27, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county martha trimble to alexander mccorkle, june 27 1867</title>
            <author>Martha Trimble</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>6 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Bumgardner Family Papers, Accession #5974-c,
       Special Collection Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville,
      Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1867-06-27">1867-06-27</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2002">Spring 2002 </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Original consulted; corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A5021T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>An aunt writes to her nephew of his family history, including references to the McNutt,
     McCorcle, Trimble and Porter families.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Alexander McCorkle</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1867-06-27">June 27th, 1867</date>
      <name type="place">Holly Hill</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Nephew,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>After a long interval, I have concluded to <hi rend="underline">attempt</hi> a reply to your
     kind, &amp; welcome letter. It always gives me sincere pleasure, to hear of the welfare
     &amp; prosperity of my dear friends, &amp; their families; Since your letter came to
      <hi rend="underline">hand</hi>. I have seen, &amp; become slightly acquainted with your
     son cousin Gamble; We were all much pleased with him &amp; would like much to see more of
     him. He does not look like you, yet there is something about him which reminds me of you. In
     the tones of his voice - there is often a striking <hi rend="underline">resemblance</hi>. Yet I
     think it is his manner rather than his appearance or voice, which I seem to <hi
      rend="underline">recognize</hi>.</p>

    <p>So far as I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> your friends and relatives in Rockbridge are all
     well &amp; doing <hi rend="underline">well</hi>
     <pb n="2"/> though many of them suffered much &amp; were sorely tried whilst the war
     lasted.</p>

    <p>My family (I mean your cousin Joseph Hub.'s children) are all married (except Agnes) so that
     my present family is very small, consisting of Agnes, her Father, &amp; Myself. Just now
     Frances McNutt is here on a visit, the first she has paid us for fourteen <hi rend="underline"
      >years</hi>. Her husband is Dr. John McNutt, a son of your Uncle William McNutt. They live in
     Monroe <abbr expan="County">Cty</abbr> Missouri. Alexander has long lived in New Orleans,
     William was killed during the war at Spottsylvania C H. His wife, a daughter of cousin Mildred
     Johnston's, is living near us; she has four <hi rend="underline">children</hi>. Joseph is
     living in Lexington; Ashlie married Mr. Adolph Echart, &amp; lives in Baltimore. Josephine
     Married Mr. Granville Campbell, &amp; lives in this county. Phebe the youngest child
     married Mr. John F Baker, a Presbyterian minister. She is with us at present. You ask me to
     tell you of your ancetors the McNutts especially. I never had a taste for tracing up
     relationships - but <pb n="3"/> since you desire it I will without preclude or apology, tell
     you what I know of them.</p>

    <p>Mr. John McNutt, &amp; his wife Catharine Anderson removed from Ireland &amp; settled
     in this county where they brought up a large family - two daughters &amp; seven sons. One
     of the daughters married an Englishman named Rhodes, &amp; the other Rebecca married Mr.
     John McCorcle by whom she had three children Alexander, Samuel &amp; <hi rend="underline"
      >Catharine</hi>. Mr. McNutt's sons were Alexander, John, Issac Robert Benjamin &amp;
     William &amp; Joseph. Robert was killed at the battle of Cowpens &amp; his
     brotherinlaw, W. McCorcle died on his way home - from a wound received in the same battle.
     After Mr.McCorcle's death his widow married Mr. Arther Glasgow by whom she had a large family
     of children.</p>


    <p>My Father Mr. John Grigsby married a Miss Etchison by whom he had five children, James, John,
     Charles, Sarah and William. Sarah Grigsby (my half sister &amp; your Grandmother) married
     Mr. Thomas Welch of Orange County. They had <pb n="4"/> two sons and five daughters. One of the
     daughters married Alexander <hi rend="underline">McCorcle</hi>, a son of John McCorcle
     &amp; Rebecca McNutt. After the death of my Father's wife he married a Miss Porter by whom
     he had three sons, Joseph, Elisha &amp; Reuben, &amp; five daughters, Jane (Paxton)
     Rachel (McNutt) Martha (Trimble) Elizabeth (McNutt) &amp; Frances (<hi rend="underline"
      >Beccum</hi>). Two of my sisters you <hi rend="underline">perceive</hi> married McNutts,
     Sister Rachel married Alexander McNutt, &amp; Elizabeth married William McNutt, your Grand
     mother's Brother. Cousin Gamble was anxious to know in what way he was related to the Porter's.
     He is not related by blood - but is connected by marriage. My mother was a Porter and two of
     her daughers married McNutts. Now cousin Alexander I have told you what I could of your
     ancestors, but cannot begin to trace out their decendants. They have obeyed the command given
     to our ancestors of old multiply &amp; replenish the earth. Their name is <hi
      rend="underline">legion</hi> - Yet so far as I know they are all Moral and Respectable people
     - many of them <hi rend="underline">pious</hi>. Cousin Alexander I think of you often &amp;
     pray for your prosperity, &amp; that you may be the means of leading many souls to Christ.
     I seem to stand almost alone all my family &amp; all who knew me when I was young have
     passed away, &amp; I feel that nothing which this world can give <pb n="5"/> will make us
     happy even in this life. I pray that I, and all my dear friends may be enabled to choose as <hi
      rend="underline">Joshua</hi> of <hi rend="underline">old</hi> that they may serve the Lord. I
     should like to see you once more &amp; if you find it in your power to pay another visit to
     your native land while I am spared do call &amp; see me. I know you have many friends more
     nearly related by blood - but I think there are none who more earnestly desire your welfare.
     Your parents were dear friend whose memory I shall ever <hi rend="underline">cherish</hi>. Give
     my warmest love to your wife &amp; children. I remember your wife as she was when I saw her
     - but I suppose Time has not spared her the bloom &amp; freshness of <hi rend="underline"
      >youth</hi>. It always suprises me cousin Alexander to find persons I regard as young -
     looking <hi rend="underline">old</hi>. A few more years and the places which knew us now will
     know us no <hi rend="underline">more</hi>. I have written you a long letter - When you have
     time &amp; inclina <pb n="6"/> tion I would like you to write to me again. But whither you
     find time to write or not I would request an interest in your prayers. My family all unite with
     me in love toyou &amp; <hi rend="underline">yours</hi> Farewell may you ever be happy is
     the earnest wish of your affectionately attached Aunt</p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed>Martha Trimble</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Cousin Alexander, Aunt desires me to say that Mrs. John McNutt - the
      mother or you Grand Mother McCorcle, had a brother who emigrated from Ireland &amp;
      settled in Botetourt County. He was the Father of Colonel Anderson of that cty who was an
      elder in the presbyterian church. Your Uncle Robert Glasgow married a daughter of his. Mrs.
      Jenkins wife of Rev. Wm Jenkins, pastor of Falling Spring church, is his Grand daughter.
      Remember us all affectionately to your wife &amp; family and accept of much love for
      yourself from us all, your sincere friend <unclear>Amos</unclear></seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
