<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A5046"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A5046">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Gerald E. Crist to his cousin Mary,
                    March 18, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county gerald e crist to his cousin mary, march 18 1862</title>
        <author>Crist, Gerald E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A5046</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502330</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Gerald E. Crist to his cousin Mary, March 18, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county gerald e crist to his cousin mary, march 18 1862</title>
            <author>Gerald E. Crist</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: McGuffin Family Papers, Accession
                            #6732, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-03-18">1862-03-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Enlistment, Home Front, Patriotism, Prisons/Prisoners</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2002-11">November 2002</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A5046T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>G. E. Crist writes to his cousin Mary about camp life in general, his worries
                    about his mother, once the militia is called up. He also writes about his
                    growing urge to fight and his faith that they will eventually win the war.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-03-18">March 18th 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Alleghany</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cousin</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your kind letter of the Fourteenth which was read with much pleasure.
                    I was glad to hear from you as well as from home. I have been well since I wrote
                    to you. The boys are generally well. We are all getting along very well. We have
                    good times here now, not much to do and plenty to eat. There is not much news
                    here now except that of the <orig reg="militia">malitia</orig>. There has not
                    been any recruits came here yet but we are expecting some before long. Some of
                    the men have reenlisted to go into a Cavalry company. Cousin John M. Baylor has
                    joined that company. I have not re-enlisted yet and I do not intend until our
                    time is out, perhaps I may have a chance to stay at home but if I have to go
                    again I intend to go in a <orig reg="volunteer">volenteer</orig> company. I am
                    sorry to hear that the <orig reg="militia">malitia</orig> have to be called out.
                    I know there will be hard times with those who are left at home. But they will
                    have make the best of it as we are into trouble and must get out the best way
                    that we can.</p>

                <p><pb n="2"/>Well cousin Mary I do pity poor George but I <hi rend="underline"
                    >cant</hi> cry for he has as good reason to go as the rest of the boys. I know
                    they will have hard times as well as many others who are already in the field.</p>

                <p>I do not know what <hi rend="underline">Mother</hi> is to do for she cannot <orig
                        reg="stay">say</orig> by herself. I know of no plan to suggest unless she
                    can get someone stay with her to attend to the beasts. If she could hire some
                    person to plant a little corn and sow some oats, but she can do as she thinks
                    best. I would be glad if you could stay with her if you could. I know she will
                    be very lonesome. You must all do the best you can and do not get alarmed at
                    every thing that you hear for it is half true that you hear. keep your courage
                    up and do not think we are to be subdued so easy. Our cause is a just one and I
                    believe the God of battles will be with us, and bring us off victorious in the
                    end. There is some talk here that we will have to fall back to Staunton but I do
                    no think that we will leave this point yet. I have just heard that the <orig
                        reg="militia">malitia</orig> in this county pendleton and highland have been
                    ordered to this place next thursday.</p>

                <p><pb n="3"/>Tell Mother that I am not in need of any thing but if she has an
                    opportunity she might send me a box if she does she must send some Sole leather
                    as it is very scare here. I want my <hi rend="underline">watch</hi> more than
                    any thing. If it is fixed she might send it with Lieutenant Summers. Lieutenant
                    Lambert or Robert McFarland. James Clinebell has not gotten his box yet but I
                    suppose he will get it as soon as a train comes out. Luther R. Waid went home
                    some time ago and <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Humphreys had him arrested
                    and sent out here he has just arrived and is in the <hi rend="underline">guard
                        house</hi>. There is about Twenty Five men in the guard house, most of which
                    have run the <hi rend="underline">Blockade</hi> as we call it, went home without
                    permission. While have been writing the boys are quite merry. This is a fine day
                    and a good many of the boys are washing their clothes. I have not learned to
                    wash yet I always get some one else to wash for me. I do not cook either the
                    mess that I stay in have John Engleman hired to cook. We pay him seventy five
                    cents apiece when the bread is baked for us and One Dollar when we get flour.</p>

                <p><pb n="4"/>I believe I have written all that would interest you. you must write
                    soon and tell me all the news in old Augusta. Give my love to all inquiring
                    friends. I do not want to see home until the <orig reg="yankees">yankeys</orig>
                    are all driven from our soil I feel more like fighting, now than I have since I
                    have been in the service. I must close for this time</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain your Cousin</salute>
                    <signed>G. E. Crist</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Direct to Staunton Company I 52nd <abbr
                            expan="Regiment Virginia Volunteers">Reg. Va. Vol.</abbr> care of Col.
                        J.B. Baldwin. <lb/>Lewis Dull is well and sends his respects to you and
                        Mother. When you write let me know where Ezra and the <orig reg="Militia"
                            >Malitia</orig> are</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
