<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A5052"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A5052">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Martha L. Roadcap to Charles W.
                    McGuffin, December 14, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county martha l roadcap to charles w mcguffin, december 14 1863</title>
        <author>Roadcap, Martha L.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A5052</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502336</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Martha L. Roadcap to Charles W. McGuffin, December
                            14, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county martha l roadcap to charles w mcguffin, december 14 1863</title>
            <author>Martha L. Roadcap</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: McGuffin Family Papers, Accession
                            #6732, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-14">1863-12-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Death/Casualties, Women, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2002-11">November 2002</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A5052T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Martha Roadcap's letter to her son, Charles W. McGuffin, mentions his stay with
                    the Baylor family during his recuperation, although he has currently come to
                    stay with his grandmother. Martha asks her son about the clothes that he need,
                    and mentions what she has already sent to his brother, John.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Charles W. McGuffin, Middlebrook, Virginia</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-14">Dec 14<hi rend="super">th</hi>/1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Son</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have thought it a long time to hear from you &amp; I concluded to drop you
                    a few lines to know how you were getting along badly I am afraid since you got
                    home to your Granmas for I know you have not that good attention that you had
                    when you were at Mr. Baylors. Knowing that there was <orig reg="no">now</orig>
                    one at Granmas to attend to your wounds as they had been attended to. But I
                    hope, that you have met with some kind friend there who will wait on you well.
                    We are all tolerable well now but Abram &amp; Christian have been very sick.
                    Abram had the dyptheria last week he is not able to do any thing yet so I have
                    been very busy you may know waiting on them. I would have like to have come to
                    have seen you if I could have done so before now. I received the package from
                    Miss Mary Baylor after you left with the coat &amp; buttons also <del
                        hand="h1">from</del> a letter from her, stating how you were &amp; that
                    they missed you very much, was the last account that I had from you. Miss Mary
                    is a very nice girl &amp; I do not know how you will ever compensate for
                        <del hand="h1">your</del> her kindness to you. I am in hope that <hi
                        rend="underline">God</hi> will reward her for her kindness towards a
                    soldier. I received a letter from your brother John last week he was very well
                        <pb n="2"/> He wanted one flannel shirt badly. I have it ready for him now.
                    I sent him since I came home one <abbr expan="pair">pr</abbr> slips one shirt
                    &amp; 1 <abbr expan="pair">pr</abbr> socks. He wrote to me he did not want
                    his pants until later in the season towards Spring. We heard on yesterday that
                    the old <hi rend="underline">Stonewall</hi> Brigade was in Staunton. I hope it
                    is so, so that, I can send him a box of provisions &amp; his shirt. I have
                    it all ready for him.. Charlie your coat is done &amp; finished yesterday
                    ready for you to wear. I would like to know if Granma is going to give you a
                    pair of pants or not, if she is I will not make yours now, for I will run short
                    myself. I have to give Jonnie a pair, I would like to know how you are to get
                    your coat, I think you had better try to come after it as I would like to see
                    you very much. Give my love to your Granma &amp; to Edgar's girls, tell
                    Uncle Kemp he must save my ham of meat for me, that it is a long time a coming
                    but it will be mighty good when I get it. Write to me very soon Charlie as I am
                    very anxious to hear from you. I am looking for a letter from Miss Mary this
                    week. The family all join in sending love &amp; accept a portion from your
                    mother. Come soon nothing more but remain your Mother until death,</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>M L Roadcap</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
