<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A5510"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A5510">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Marshall McCue to John Howard
                    McCue, February 12, 1858</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john marshall mccue to john howard mccue, february 12 1858</title>
        <author>McCue, John Marshall</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Amanda Mushal</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A5510</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502361</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Marshall McCue to John Howard McCue, February
                            12, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john marshall mccue to john howard mccue, february 12 1858</title>
            <author>John Marshall McCue</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Marshall McCue to John
                            Howard McCue, 12 February 1858, McCue Family Papers, Accession Number
                            4406, Special Collections, Alderman Library, University of
                        Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-02-12">1858-02-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Education, Family, State Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A5510T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John Marshall McCue apologizes to John Howard McCue for his delay in answering
                    John Howard McCue's letter and assures him that he has followed the right course
                    of action in his financial difficulties. John Marshall McCue writes that the
                    legislature has been discussing a public printing bill, describes a speech given
                    by Mr. Dawson of Georgia concerning the purchase of Mount Vernon, and comments
                    that discussion has stalled in the legislature regarding the "Idiotic
                School."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-02-12">12 Feb /58</date>
                        <name type="place">Ballard House</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <hi rend="underline">My dear Howard</hi>
                    </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I regret exceedingly that my delay for a day or two in acknowledging your <orig
                        reg="favor">favour</orig> of Monday <hi rend="underline">may have
                    caused</hi> the suspicion in your mind that I <hi rend="underline">could under
                        any circumstances</hi> have thought hardly of <hi rend="underline"
                    >you</hi>--</p>

                <p>My dear friend &amp; relative, I do most sincerely <orig reg="sympathize">
                        <hi rend="underline">sympathise</hi>
                    </orig> and <hi rend="underline">feel with</hi> you, but <hi rend="underline"
                        >censure</hi> you or <hi rend="underline">reflect</hi> upon you <hi
                        rend="underline">never Oh no never</hi>--and I do most sincerely regret that
                    I let my engagements in &amp; out of the house, delay me in writing to
                    you--I had fixed on <hi rend="underline">this</hi> evening to write at any rate
                    and a moment ago, in calling at the office for my letters &amp;c found your
                    second letter--in which, I fear you feel that I have treated you <hi
                        rend="underline">badly</hi> or <hi rend="underline">unkindly</hi>--I never
                    entertained the most remote opinion of the sort, and approve the course<pb n="2"
                    /> you have taken--I do not know that you could have done otherwise and I doubt
                    not <abbr expan="it is">'tis</abbr> all for the best--I know Cousin Liz well
                    enough to believe that she is <hi rend="underline">just the sort of woman</hi>
                    to console you and sustain you in this emergency--God bless her--I wish there
                    were more like her--as I doubt not they will be found in emergencies--In regard
                    to the liabilities that I may have incurred by endorsing for you my dear
                    Cousin--do not let them disturb you in the least--I have not felt any anxiety on
                    that account--I assure you and <abbr expan="although">altho'</abbr> I myself in
                    common with <hi rend="underline">all</hi> will feel &amp; <hi
                        rend="underline">do feel</hi> this pecuniary pressure yet I hope I can get
                    along--I wish I had it in my power to <hi rend="underline">aid you</hi> in this
                    your trying hour--I would do it most cheerfully--Bear up like a man--Let your
                    noble wife &amp; your interesting family nerve your energies to meet any and
                        all<pb n="3"/>responsibilities of any kind soever--<abbr expan="It is"
                    >'Tis</abbr> always darkest just before day &amp; I doubt not this will in
                    your case only be a momentary darkness--Imboden with me since I <abbr
                        expan="received">rec<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> yours--He said to me the
                    night I was at the <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> Hotel he wanted to talk
                    with me about your matters--but the opportunity did not present itself before he
                    had to leave--</p>

                <p>I reiterate, that you must not suppose for a moment that I reflect on you in any
                    manner whatever--No, no, not in the slightest particular. Give much love to
                    Cousin Liz for me--and <hi rend="underline">assure her</hi> in the strongest
                    language you can use--of my undiminished love and affection for her--and the
                    full assurance I have always entertained that she will be equal to any changes
                    of fortune either prosperous or adverse--and Heaven grant it may soon prove to
                    be of the former character--</p>
                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>I have little to communicate of interest in legislation--Have spent nearly a <del
                        hand="h1"/> discussing the reports majority &amp; minority in regard to
                    the public printing &amp; adopted the latter <orig reg="today">to day</orig>
                    cutting down the printing 25 <orig reg="percent">per cent</orig>--Had a M<hi
                        rend="super">r</hi>. Dawson of <abbr expan="Georgia">Ga.</abbr> here last
                    night to <orig reg="address">adress</orig> the citizens on the subject of
                    purchase of Mt. Vernon--and such a stupid &amp; miserable <hi
                        rend="underline">bore</hi> as he proved himself to be--you could not <orig
                        reg="imagine">immagine</orig> to yourself--and such a wet blanket as he has
                    thrown over the whole subject only those who felt an interest in it, can
                    believe--He is no relation of <abbr expan="Honorable">Hon</abbr> W<hi
                        rend="super">m</hi> C. Dawson <abbr expan="deceased">dec<hi rend="super"
                        >d</hi></abbr>--formerly in U. S. <abbr expan="Senate">Sen.</abbr>--but is a
                    Kentuckian by birth of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> parents &amp;c</p>

                <p>W<hi rend="super">m</hi> Ballard Preston was here a day or two ago--on <del
                        hand="h1"/> for Europe--Has succeeded to a favorable extent in his mission--</p>

                <p>Not much said in regard to the Idiotic School--There will hardly be time I fear
                    to get it <abbr expan="through">thro'</abbr> unless in an extra session. </p>

                <p>It has been snowing industriously all day--Do you have a prospect of ice?</p>

                <p>Please excuse the hurry &amp; brevity of my letter--I want it to go by <orig
                        reg="tomorrow's">to-morrow's</orig> mail--Let me hear from you soon and
                    believe me very truly &amp; sincerely</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>
                        <hi rend="underline">Your relative &amp; friend</hi>
                    </salute>
                    <signed>J.M. MCue</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
