<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6005"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6005">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, January
     9, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, january 9 1862</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6005</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502368</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, January 9, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, january 9 1862</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-01-09">1862-01-09</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Family, Prisons/Prisoners</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6005T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick writes about friends in the guard house, illness in camp, and his assignment to a
     work detail making clapboards. He also tells his wife that he received food packages.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-01-09">January the 9 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Alleghany Tip Top</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Wife</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take this opportunity this morning as I have time to inform you that I am well at present
     and I hope when these few lines comes to hand that they may find you and your sweet little boy
     enjoying good health and all of my friends the same.</p>
    <p>We have a great deal of sickness here at this time. James Lewis is very low with the
     erysipelas. He had the sore throat in the first place, he is very low. His face and head is
     swollen up, that his eyes was nearly shut and his face is <orig reg="as">a s</orig> black on
     one side as it can be, but he is a little better this morning, but I hardly think he will get
     over it. William Offlighter is not very well at this time. All the rest of the creek boys is
     well.</p>
    <p>Hiram Coyner &amp; Wright is out of the guard house. They only was in the guard house 12
     days. They did not punish them any but kept them in the guard house at night and made them work
     in the day under a guard. Little Tommy Offlighter sends his love to you all. He has been well.
     We have bad weather here, we had some snow this week and it is raining here this morning and it
     is very foggy too, but it is not as cold here as I thought it would be out here in the
     mountain.</p>
    <p>Jan 12.</p>
    <p>Dear Lizza I will send you a few more lines. I wrote some of this a few days ago and I have
     been at work on a regular detail. We have to walk five miles morning and evening. We are making
     clapboards. I don't have to stand picket or do any other duty as long as I am on a regular
     detail.</p>
    <p>It is very warm this morning. We are all well this morning. Mr. Lewis is better. Mr. Grass
     has been very sick, he has been sick two or three weeks but he is on the mend. Dear Lizza I
     received the you sent by Dr. Drummons yesterday and all the rest of the things which was ten
     apples and twenty cakes and the sausage and the hickory nuts that you put in my pants pocket.
     Tell mother and Amanda and Carry that I am much obliged to them for their kindness and I got
     the bottle of whiskey. James McDaniel give it to me but did not tell me who sent it to me, but
     I think you sent it to me. I was very glad to get them and also I am much obliged to you for
     them. I have not seen Dr. yet. I had no chance. Mr. McDaniel <unclear>said</unclear> to me last
     night if I wanted to send you a letter that I had better writelast night, but I didn't have no
     candle. I send my pants back. I will tell more the next letter as I have no time. Give my love
     to all. Nothing more but reamin you affectionate husband until death</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Henry H. Dedrick To his Dear Wife, Good by, write soon </salute>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
