<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6010"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6010">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, June 8,
     1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, june 8 1862</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6010</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502373</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, June the 8 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, june the 8 1862</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-06-08">1862-06-08</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave, Family, Military Authority,
      Military Strategy, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6010T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick discusses military actions in the Valley on the days prior to the Battle of Port
     Republic. He also records the death of General Ashby of Ashby's Calvary.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-06-08">June the 8 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Camp two miles below Port Republic, VA</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take this opportunity to write you a few lines to let you know how and where I am. I am
     well at this time and I hope these few lines may find you and the boy enjoying the same
     blessing of health.</p>
    <p>We are two miles below Port Republic at this time, but I don't know how long we will stay
     here and I do not know where we will go. Some thinks we will go to Staunton, but it is hard to
     tell where we will go. The Yankees is between us and Harrisonburg. They have been following us
     pretty close, but we have not been very bad scared yet. Our brigade had a little fight last
     Sunday on the right had side of Strassburg. We had one wounded in our regt. and three of Capt.
     Lusk's artillerymen they was wounded by one of his own <unclear>firings</unclear>. I don't know
     how many the yankees lost.</p>
    <p>Last Friday our brigade was in the rear to cover the retreat about two miles this side of
     Harrisonburg. The yankee cavalry run up on Ashby's cavalry and fired on them. Ours returned the
     fire and then charged on them and took 52 of their cavalrymen prisoner. On Col., one Maj., two
     Capt., and two killed. We had one wounded and he was a Major. Ashby run them back within two
     miles of town and then he sent for us to assist him. We turn back and went two miles back along
     the road and then flanked out to the right through a strip of woods and went about one mile.</p>
    <p>The 44th, 58th VA and the 1st Maryland Regts. was before our Regt. and they seen the yankees
     coming round to flank us, and the 58th laid down in the brush and as they come up they fired on
     them and the yankees was so much confused they wheeled and run back apiece and then they turned
     and fired on our men and we had a hot time of it for a little while, but we drove them back
     with three small Regt. Our Regt. was not engaged in it. There was about ten thousand of the
     yankees. Our loss was 75 killed and wounded. General Ashby was killed in the first of the
     engagement. I don't know how many the yankees lost, but from all accounts their loss was great.
     I expect the yankees got a good many of our men from Winchester up to Harrisonburg men that was
     broken down. We have taken 3.2.12. prisoners since we have been in the valley. </p>
    <p>I have more news but I have not the time to write. I have been down within a quarter of a
     mile of Charlestown. The health of the soldiers is very good. Hiram Coiner is well and so is
     Mr. Lewis. Hiram come to us last Tuesday below New Market. None of the rest of the boys that
     ran off have come back but Hiram. They haven't done anything with him yet. I don't know what
     they will do with him.</p>
    <p>Dear Lissa I would be very glad to see you and the little boy at this time and also the rest
     of my friends. Give my love to all inquiring friends if there be any, butaccept a great portion
     for your self. May god bless you all and save you all. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>From your affectionate husband. H.H.D.M.E.D.</salute>
     <signed/>
     <seg type="postscript">Josiah Balsley is well and sends his love to you all. I received the
      letter you wrote on the 23 and I sent an answer but I have not heard from it. Write as soon as
      you can. God bye for this time.</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
