<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6046"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley15 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503137" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley15b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503138" NDATA uvaHighRes> 

 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6046">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, April 26,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, april 26 1861</title>
        <author>Smiley, Mary A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6046</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503136</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, April 26, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, april 26 1861</title>
            <author>Mary A. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent> pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-04-26">1861-04-26</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>African Americans, Agriculture, Church/Religious Activity, Enlistment, Family, Home Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6046T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Mary Smiley writes to her brother, requesting longer letters describing his life in camp.
     Smiley recounts happenings at home, including the formation a home guard to protect against
     "negroes" and "mean whites," and gives her brother instructions on maintaining his health.
     Thomas Smiley's mother adds a note at the end of the letter exhorting him to put his faith in
     God.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Thomas M. Smiley </name>
    </head>

    <opener>
 
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley15" pid="uva-lib:503137"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-04-26">Friday night, 10 o'clock<lb/> April 26<hi rend="super">th</hi>
      1861</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Brother</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>As we are getting your other uniform ready to send I will write a little and send it in your
     bundle for we do not know where to direct to, and I suppose you will be certain to get it If
     the weather is as warm where you are as it has been here for the past few days you will
     certainly need something lighter than your winter uniform We have received two letters from you
     one Wednesday and one <orig reg="today">to day</orig> and I tell you we (as well as others)
     were about as anxious to hear from you as we could well be only Thomas they were entirely <orig
      reg="too">to</orig> short Ma wants you to write the occurences of every day, if possible, and
     then when you get enough to send it home. It appears like there has been a stop put to <orig
      reg="business">buisness</orig> of every kind there is very little doing except what is obliged
     to be done that is farming. Pa has been ploughing this week. it sets very hard with him.
     Runnels is still about he has joined a <orig reg="volunteer">vollunteer</orig> company at
     Brownsburg. The Brownsburg troop passed this evening on their way home I guess there would be a
     great many persons glad this evening. I wish wish we could be surprised in the same way.
     Providence congregation looked sadder last Sabbath than it has done for many a long day. There
     has been a Home Guard formed around here and I suppose it is needed for some of the negroes are
     not to be trusted even around here and then they are backed by some of the mean white folks
     There is one of the Sensabough that there has been a talk of taking to jail and they have a son
     of Davies Kerrs in jail. We are all well and have been since you left and we want you to be
     very careful of your health do not expose yourself rashly if you get your clothes wet try and
     dry them and above all dont sleep on wet clothes if it is possible to have them dry for as you
     know it is so very much more injurious to health than when you are taking exercise<pb n="2"  entity="Smiley15b" pid="uva-lib:503138"/></p>

    <p>
      We would like very much to know what sort of a life you lead in
     camp What have you to eat and have you plenty of it. great fears are entertained that you will
     suffer for food so many soldiers and where will bread come from to feed them Who cooks for you
     or do you have to do it yourselves and <del hand="h1">w</del>how are you camped, in houses in
     tents or in the open air with the sky for your covering. I would like very much to know who
     your messmates are. How is cousin John Berry getting along has he got his spirits raised yet or
     is he still down. I reckon you live in excitement I hope you dont have to live on its so near
     the city. If you want <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> write for it and if we have an
     opportunity we will send it.</p>
    <p>Farewell dear brother do yor duty as a soldier and as a man and if I never see you again may
     we meet above.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>from your sister </salute>
     <signed>Mary A Smiley</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">P/S/ Write often and tell me when you received this and where to direct
      to so that we can write. Mary</seg>
     <seg type="postscript">Dear Son I<lb/> It is with a trembling hand and a sad heart that I t<del
       hand="h1">h</del>ake this pencil in my hand to drop you a fine but fearing that I may never
      have another opportunity I will exort you once more to put your trust in the mighty God of
      Jacob take Jesus Christ for your Saviour and then if you even fall in the battle field you
      will still be safe There has been much fervent prayer offered for you and the dear <orig
       reg="friends">frends</orig> who has gone from amongst us. O will you not pray for yourself.
      Nothing more From your affectionate mother C. Smiley <lb/> To her son T. M Smiley. <name
       type="recipient">Thomas M Smiley</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
