<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6053"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley55 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503159" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley55b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503160" NDATA uvaHighRes> 

 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6053">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, May 30, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, may 30 1861</title>
        <author>Smiley, Mary A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6053</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503158</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, May 30, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, may 30 1861</title>
            <author>Mary A. Smiley </author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-05-30">1861-05-30</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Enlistment, Homefront, National Government, Patriotism</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6053T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discussion of mobilization, national election, and civilian division over secession.
     Describes women's sewing activities for the troops.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley55" pid="uva-lib:503159"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-05-30">May 30<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take my pen in hand this morning to write you a few lines We are all well except ma who has
     headache she had intended writing you but is not well enough. It is said here that the Southern
     Guard's have left for Wheeling which I hope will prove a false report We all will not feel as
     well satisfied as before if it proves true that you have left Harpers Ferry. Old Jimmy Cambell
     has got down he came in a few minutes ago he says they <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> like to
     stay at the poor house that his <hi rend="underline">sister Sallie</hi> is not well has had
     sore throat and consumption again. He looks the same old Jimmy with his head <orig
      reg="propped">proped</orig> up with his <hi rend="underline">dickey</hi> and a great <orig
      reg="scarf">scaf</orig> on his face. We have been making tents at Newport this week there was
     some 20 or more there yesterday and the day before sewing at them We made four at Newport I
     expect there will be big doings at Newport Saturday it is expected to raise a secession flag
     then. You would certainly have laughed had you seen the way Mr B. Beard was pestered for a 50
     cent piece to help pay for the flag but he wouldn't give any for to get a flag but would give
     double if they would not put it up. The ladies of Providence in Rockbridge are making uniforms
     this week for a company that has lately been formed Rockbridge guards <abbr expan="Captain"
      >Capt</abbr> Curry It is desired they shall be fitted out this week in order that they may go
     under command of a Christian Colonel &amp; <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr> Colonel
     The election has passed and as far as heard from is said to have been the most orderly
     &amp; quiet for a great while Augusta has 10 votes against ratification at Newport none was
     cast but I believe there would have been that many polled had the unionists voted<pb n="2" entity="Smiley55b" pid="uva-lib:503160"/>
    Hutchens are all unionists I believe even to the women Some of us
     got to arguing with Eliza yesterday but we might as well have tried to make her believe that
     the sun shines here in the night as to make a secessionist of her, and this is the way with all
     the unionists Tell John Beard he must try to make a secessionist of his father and Sam. I
     believe I have but little more to write not knowing whether you are still at Harpers Ferry
     although I hope you will still be posted there now that that place is fortified it will appear
     hard to have to leave at least for abolitionist Wheeling</p>
    <p>I want you to tell me whose mess Kes Kerr is in No doubt you would be greatly surprised to
     see him as much so as his leave was sudden. Ma says if you have <orig reg="anything">any
     thing</orig> rather private to write home to write on a slip of paper and put it in as your
     letters are read or heard by a great many <orig reg="everyone">every one</orig> is anxious to
     hear the news from the camp also if you want <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> from home to
     say so and tell right out it appears to us as if we ought to send <orig reg="something">some
      thing</orig> but we <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know what you want We would be very sorry if
     you want or need <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>, and we have it, not to know, so that we
     might sent it now we wish to know whether you do, and if so, what, as we have had plenty of
     opportunities and will have if you are or will still be at Harpers Ferry. <abbr expan="Captain"
      >Capt</abbr> Hite talks of taking the tents to you in his wagon free of expense if you are
      <orig reg="still">sill</orig> at the Ferry will probably start Saturday if he goes. The stamps
     which we we sent you will not do you much good unless you have them used up before the first of
     June as postage will then be five cents Pa got a great parcel of stamped envelops but will send
     them back so that we will not lose <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> by it. Thomas have you
     received your secession badge yet Hannah was telling us that she had made one for you but Ma
     told her she ought not to have done it as it would be a mark for the enemy to shoot at. You
     must excuse all these mistakes scratches &amp; blotches in this nor you must not <orig
      reg="criticize">criticise</orig> it so closely as you used to do</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain your affectionate sister</salute>
     <signed>Mary A Smiley </signed>
     <seg type="postscript"><hi rend="underline">P/S/ Ma has the headache very bad is scarcely able
       to be of bed</hi> I shall direct this to Harpers Ferry notwithstanding the report that you
      have gone to Wheeling I suppose if so it will be forwarded to that place</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
