<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6056"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley26 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503168" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley26b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503169" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 
 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6056">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Letitia Berry to Thomas M. Smiley, June 6, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county letitia berry to thomas m smiley, june 6 1861</title>
        <author>Berry, Letitia</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6056</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503167</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Letitia Berry to Thomas M. Smiley, June 6, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county letitia berry to thomas m smiley, june 6 1861</title>
            <author>Letitia Berry</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-06-06">1861-06-06</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Enlistment, Family, Home Front, Patriotism</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6056T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discusses troop mobilization, women's sewing for the troops, and communities' divisions over
     the war.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Mr Thomas Smiley Presents
     <name type="recipient">Thomas M. Smiley</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley26" pid="uva-lib:503168"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-06-06">June 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Cousin Thomas</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have just finished a letter to Cousin Jimmie and will endeavor to drop a few lines to you
     although I fear they will not interest you as I have not much news to communicate to you We are
     all tolerably well except John he has not gotten entirely well yet has not worked any but one
     day he gave out and has not tried it again. Your fathers folks were well this morning father
     saw Cousin Billie in Newport. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Curries Company started
     yesterday I was in Middlebrook when they passed they all looked very lively went to Staunton in
     wagons, there was about twenty wagons I think. They were very well fixed, the best of any of
     the <orig reg="companies">comapanies</orig> from about here, had their tents, knapsacks
     canteens and almost <orig reg="everything">every thing </orig> necessary for a soldier, the
     ladies have been sewing for them in Brownsburg for two week about sixty there every days and
     five sewing machines. We have been sewing for you all this week in middlebrook made 61 pants,
     your tents started <orig reg="today">to day</orig> I do not know whether the pants went or not.
     I wish you were here to go in our bible class it is hard I tell but we will have to study the
     harder we have it in the <orig reg="session">cession</orig> room now severals of the class have
     gone to the army but it is still increasing have from thirty to thirty five,<pb n="2" entity="Smiley26b" pid="uva-lib:503169"/>
      Mr. Junkin is to preach at newport Sunday evening I wish you could
     be there to hear him. Hugh Beard has come home. got home last saturday; he is a good-deal
     fleshier than he was when he went away; his mother <orig reg="didn't">did'nt</orig> know him I
     believe; but I think he has not changed scarcely at all. He says the Missourians a fighting
     among themselves about half are for the north &amp; half for the south. The Militia has got
     orders to hold themselves in readiness They are looking for a call daily. and what will become
     of the rest of us if they are taken away. There was word came yesterday that the Lincolnites
     were to be in Lexington last night, &amp; the home guards all gathered up their guns and
     started up there last evening and when they got as far as Brownsburg they found it was a false
     report. Well I will stop for I know you will be tired reading this scribbling. Please write
     soon for we are anxious to hear from you All send their love to you. Give my respects to
     inquiring friends not excepting yourself. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain your Cousin.</salute>
     <signed>Letitia Berry</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
