<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6051"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley22 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503153" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley22b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503154" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6051">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, May 16, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, may 16 1861</title>
        <author>Smiley, Mary A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6051</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503152</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, May 16, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, may 16 1861</title>
            <author>Mary A. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Viriginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-05-16">1861-05-16</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Enlistment, Family, Homefront</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6051T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discusses parents visit to cousins, marriage in neighboring town, and troop mobilization.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Thomas M. Smiley</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
  
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley22" pid="uva-lib:503153"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-05-16">Thursday May 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take the present <orig reg="opportunity">oportunity</orig> to write you a few lines we are
     all well and hope you are enjoying the same blessing good health Aunt Ellen received your
     letter and came down yesterday she thought we would be anxious if we did not get a letter. you
     are out of stamps and <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> get any Pa got right for you yesterday and
     I will enclose them in this and send. Pa and ma have gone to Cousin James Berrie's I had
     intended to go but pa <orig reg="couldn't">couldnt</orig> give up going with his wife I reckon
     and as I was cut out of going, as clear as a whistle, Pretty time of the year for <hi
      rend="underline">him</hi> to be visiting is it not. Mrs Turk and ma have at last made that
     long talked of call at Mr Junkins. They spent the day at Mrs Strains and went down a little
     while in the evening. Maggie Canier was married yesterday morning in the church at Providence
     and just started for the North to visit her husbands people before leaving America I would have
     liked to have seen them married very well but of course as I was not one of the invited guests
     I would not like to go without others were going that were uninvited I have heard that those of
     your company who did not go or<pb n="2" entity="Smiley22b" pid="uva-lib:503154"/>
      got substitutes have been sent for why has that been done it is
     very strange to me. I think it would have been as well for to let Adam Yago stand and then if
     the militia is called he may have to go and he will have harder times than if he gone as a
     volunteer I believe the Brownsburg troop starts <orig reg="today">to-day</orig> for Staunton it
     is to stay there a day or two I heard Kes Kerr went yesterday and wanted to go as substitute
     for a Swisher but I hardly think he is going for he did not say <orig reg="anything">any
     thing</orig> about it when we were there Smallwood is going in Sai Strongs place. Last Saturday
     was big muster day as you call it at Middlebrook pa went down he wanted to see Morgan but he
     had not got home. Mr Echard had the great misfortune to break down in his <orig reg="buggy"
      >bugy</orig> with a lady Sunday going to St John's. As I have no news to write I think I had
     better quit I guess if I would wait <abbr expan="until">till</abbr> this evening I might have
     plenty but I want to send today as the mail does down I wrote last week and sent by mail and as
     the Irishman wrote to his <orig reg="sweetheart">sweethart</orig> I want to know <orig
      reg="whether">wheter</orig> you got it and if you <orig reg="did not">didnot</orig> I want to
     know <orig reg="anyway">any way</orig>. You must write soon and often for remember we are
     always anxious to hear. Mrs Turk sends her best respects to you &amp; Tish unites with me
     in sending much love to you our brother, and give my best respects to my <orig
      reg="acquaintances">acquaintences</orig> at Harpers ferry</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain your affectionate sister</salute>
     <signed>Mary A. Smiley</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
