<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6066"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley36 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503197" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley36b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503198" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley36c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503199" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley36d SYSTEM "uva-lib:503200" NDATA uvaHighRes> 

 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6066">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to His Sister, December 26,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to his sister, december 26 1861</title>
        <author>Smiley, Thomas M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6066</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503196</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to His Sister, December 26, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to his sister, december 26 1861</title>
            <author>Thomas M. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-12-26">1861-12-26</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6066T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discusses marching and skirmishing around in the Martinsburg area. Complains about the lack
     of provisions during a march.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sister</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1"  entity="Smiley36" pid="uva-lib:503197"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-12-26">Dec 26<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Stephenson</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Sister</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I will endeavor to write you a few lines this morning to let you know that I am well and hope
     you may be enjoying the same blessing when these few lines reach you. I hope you all enjoyed
     your Christmas as it was certainly a beautiful day here at any rate We got back to camp last
     Sunday evening after an absence of two weeks the greater part of the time being made up in
     marching night and day I wrote to you from Martinsburg telling you of our first trip to dam No.
     four in which we did not do much execution besides taking a few prisoners; on the next day
     after I wrote the brigade came on and we took up the line of march for dam Number five we <orig
      reg="stayed">staid</orig> there until saturday morning when we left for camp during our stay
     there we tore up the dam and stopped operations on the canal for the winter there was one man
     killed on our side a Mr Parks belonging to the Rockbridge rifles and one of the <orig
      reg="artillery">artilery</orig> was wounded I do not know how many of the enemy<pb n="2" entity="Smiley36b" pid="uva-lib:503198"/>
     
           were killed as the skirmishing was done altogether across the river but there was
     several of the enemy seen to fall and carried off by their friends it is strange there was not
     more of us killed than was as the bombs were bursting around us the whole time some of our
     company picked up <orig reg="pieces">peices</orig> of shell that fell close to them Our company
     or a part of it were at work in the dam one night the enemy did not see us going in the dam but
     after we had been in the dam an hour I went to the top to look around and in the moonlight they
     could see me when they opened fire upon us the first balls whistled over my head and after that
     I got out of the way when they opened a perfect shower of balls upon us but we were <orig
      reg="pretty">prety</orig> well protected and fortunately no one was hurt. M<hi rend="super"
     >r</hi> Andrew Lucas arrived here last sunday evening just about dark I received the things you
     sent me and it just come in time as we were about out of provisions we do not fare very well on
     a march as there is not time to cook our provisions. but in camp we fare very well</p>
    <p><pb n="3" entity="Smiley36c" pid="uva-lib:503199"/>
     the roundabout you sent fits me very well and the socks I will keep although I do not
     need them just yet but I suppose I will need them <orig reg="afterwhile">after while</orig> I
     will send the box home by M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Lucas we have got knapsacks and I will send
     my sachel with what things I have I sent the undershirt home again as I do not like to wear
     them here I have put my uniform coat in and some lead and other things sam Lucas has a pair of
     pants and a flannel shirt in and David Hanger put in a pair of old socks John Beard sent his
     old knapsack it is a black one and the other sachel is B.F. Hupps. I had some other things but
     when we moved <orig reg="everything">every thing</orig> that could not be taken along was
     thrown away and destroyed the <unclear>Cad</unclear> is in a little poke it was picked up from
     off the field at Manassas. John Clemmer told me to write that he wanted enough of cloth like my
     roundabout to make him a coat and pair of pants he said he would give two dollars a yard or
     whatever you sold it at and pay the money as soon as he got the goods when you write let me
     know whether you have any of the cloth to spare or not.<pb n="4" entity="Smiley36d" pid="uva-lib:503200"/></p>
    <p> But I must stop writing as I have taken up the most of my paper already</p>
    <closer>
     <salute>Give my love to all inquiring friends and relations and receive a large share yourself</salute>
     <signed>T. M. Smiley</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">I send you a button taken off the coat of a dead United States soldier
      who fell on the battlefield of Bull run July 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1861<lb/><lb/> T. M
      Smiley</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
