<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6100"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;


<!ENTITY Smiley70 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503274" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
<!ENTITY Smiley70b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503275" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
<!ENTITY Smiley70c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503276" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6100">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Emily Hull to Thomas M. Smiley, April 22, 1865</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county emily hull to thomas m smiley, april 22 1865</title>
        <author>Hull, Emily</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6100</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503273</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Emily Hull to Thomas M. Smiley, April 22, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county emily hull to thomas m smiley, april 22 1865</title>
            <author>Emily Hull</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1865-04-22">1865-04-22</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Home Front, Agriculture, Family, National Government, Patriotism, Prisons/Prisoners,
      Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6100T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter to Thomas M. Smiley, Emily Hull describes her family's new home and the events
     going on in their lives. In addition, she discusses the death of President Lincoln and
     reaffirms her constant faith in the southern cause.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley70" pid="uva-lib:503274"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1865-04-22">April the 22<hi rend="super">nd</hi> 1865</date>
      <name type="place">Columbia Boon <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><abbr expan="Missouri">Mo.</abbr></name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Friend</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have just arrived at home once more, was glad to find <orig reg="your">youre</orig> letter
     here waiting for me, it is always a pleasure to received them; and take great delight in
     answering your letters, but the great misfortune is, I never have <orig reg="anything">any
      thing</orig> interesting to write. I have been trying to make me a school for some time but
     have failed in every attempt. I was late in beginning I was in Johnson <abbr expan="County"
     >Co.</abbr> and when I came back the schools were all taken or at least the ones that I wanted.
     Mary and Darthula are teaching we have to paddle our own canoes. I am afraid my canoe will be
     very hard to manage this summer, but I <hi rend="underline">trust</hi> that I may land on the
     shore safe. We are not living on the same farm we were, when I last wrote to you but on a great
     deal prettier place, I feel<pb n="2" entity="Smiley70b" pid="uva-lib:503275"/> more like I was at home here than anywhere I have been since I
     have been in the state The dwelling is of brick, two rooms above &amp; two below; brother
     Frank is living in one end of the house, he &amp; pa are going to farm together; we will
     have <orig reg="plenty">plinty</orig> of fruit of different kind if nothing happens it, the
     trees are all in bloom, We are having a very backward spring, the farmers have never began to
     plough yet. Southern persons are very low spirited here they think we will have worse times
     since the death of Lincoln. I am <orig reg="loath">loth</orig> to believe the southern men,
     after having so much of the best blood of the South <orig reg="spilled">spilt</orig> will
     surrender to the very ones that caused so much trouble, I am glad to find that there are some
     that are true to the cause. I would like to have peace but not the way we are to have it, I
     would be willing to suffer the hardships of war four years longer if at the close, we could
     have <hi rend="underline">freedom</hi> with our peace.<lb/> I am glad to know your Sister Mary
     is going<pb n="3" entity="Smiley70c" pid="uva-lib:503276"/> to school, for it is the only thing a person can retain, education
     I mean. It always was very important to have an education, but it appears to be more essential
     now than ever. The family join me in love to you and the other boys that are in prison; also to
     friends who are now living in the Old Dominion state. I remain as ever </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your Friend</salute>
     <signed>Emily Hull</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
