<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6140"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6140">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jesse Rolston, Jr., to Mary Rolston, April 3,
     1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jesse rolston, jr to mary rolston april 3 1863</title>
        <author>Rolston Jr, Jesse</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6140</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502410</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jesse Rolston, Jr., to Mary Rolston, April 3, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jesse rolston, jr to mary rolston april 3 1863</title>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent/>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Joyce DeBolt Miller, ed., "Until Seperated by
       Death": Lives and Civil War Letters of Jesse Rolston, Jr., and Mary Catharine Cromer
       (Bridgewater, Va.: Good Printers, Inc., 1994), p. 28.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Joyce DeBolt for giving us permission to print these letters, and
        Barbara Rolston for bringing this collection to our attention.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Published Source</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-04-03">1863-04-03</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Death/Casualties, Church, National Government, Prison/Prisoners, Agriculture</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6140T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Rolston comments on the punishments for soldiers who "flank" fights, and about the loss of a
     member of their company. He also gives advice to his wife who is managing their farm in his
     absence.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-04-03">April 3-1863</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Hamilton Crossing<lb/> Spotsylvania County Va</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Companion</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I seat <orig reg="myself">my self</orig> this morning to inform you how i am and how i have
      <orig reg="been">bin</orig> since my last letter. I have had a bad <orig reg="cold"
     >coald</orig> for the past <orig reg="week">weak</orig> but i have had a good appetite to eat
     all the time. I am well at <orig reg="present">preasent</orig> and <orig reg="hoping"
     >hoaping</orig> that when you receive this that it will find you <orig reg="enjoying"
     >injoying</orig> good health and in good spirits and <orig reg="hope">hoap</orig> all of our
     family friends and <orig reg="neighbors">neighbours</orig> may be <orig reg="enjoying"
     >injoying</orig> the same blessing. I received your letter that you sent by <abbr
      expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> A Airhart in the first of April. J just came off of picket that
     day and we <orig reg="enjoyed">injoyed</orig>
     <orig reg="ourselves">our selves</orig> very well considering such a spell of weather as we
     had. we was gone three days. the first day it rained very hard all day. the second day it was
      <orig reg="cold">coald</orig> and the wind blew very hard and <orig reg="cold">coald</orig>
     all day. the third day but quite pleasant until <orig reg="evening">eavening</orig> after we
     got in camp. it clouded up and the next morning it was a snowing. it fell about 2 or 3 inches
     but it soon melted after it quit snowing and <orig reg="made">maid</orig> a slop. it has been
     quite moderate since. the man that was send to richmond that you spoke of had went home three
     times and he would when <del rend="none" hand="h1"/><pb n="2"/> camp in times of a fight would run off
      <abbr expan="until">til</abbr> it was over. it is harder on them that flank a fight than them
     that <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>. they have <orig reg="been">bin</orig> hard on some of the
     others too. there is Jacob and David Shull and John and Richard Michael sent to richmond April
     1st for six months hard labor and 6 months pay. that was their sentence. <abbr expan="William"
      >Wm.</abbr> Shull <orig reg="hasn't">hasnt</orig> had his trial yet-April 5th. I am well and
     hearty but it pained me when i read in your kind letter the death of your brother. it makes of
      <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> in which a man <orig reg="has">hasa</orig> but a few days and full of <orig
      reg="trouble">troubel</orig>. god giveth and then taketh away. blessed is the name of the
     Lord. We have lost another one of our company. Absolom Michael yesterday morning at 7 <orig
      reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> departed this life to a world <orig reg="where">whare</orig>
     <orig reg="there">their</orig> is no more parting. he wasn't sick but about 2 weeks. he had the
      <orig reg="typhoid">tifoid</orig> fever. he was <orig reg="able">abel</orig> to walk about
     some until the <orig reg="evening">eavening</orig> before he died. life is uncertain in the
     army as well as at home. i <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know but what he is better off now
     than if he had a lived to heard his trial for his case would be <orig reg="been">bin</orig>
     hard the way they <orig reg="punished">punishe</orig> the others. i <orig reg="don't"
     >dont</orig> think <orig reg="we'll">well</orig> stay <orig reg="here">heare</orig> many more
     days until we move it <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> report in camp now that we are to go out back in the
     mountains west of <orig reg="Staunton">Stanton</orig> but i <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
     <orig reg="know">no</orig>
     <orig reg="where">whare</orig> we will go for they take take us <orig reg="where">whare</orig>
     they please. <orig reg="the">they</orig>
     <orig reg="yankees">yankeys</orig> appear to be quiet and they say they don't want to <orig
      reg="fight">fite</orig> if they can help. they say <orig reg="there">their</orig> is a great
     many of them will go home the first of May or <orig reg="rebel">rebell</orig> against <orig
      reg="old">oald</orig> Abe. if they do that the war <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> last much
     longer. from what i can <orig reg="hear">heare</orig> and see i <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
     think [letter torn away here]...if you think you can manage any more corn <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the
     bottom <orig reg="field">feald</orig> as you <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> have oats enough to
      <orig reg="sow">sew</orig>. the field of <orig reg="cornstubbles">cornstubels</orig> on the
     hill could plant some in <orig reg="there">their</orig> and if you <orig reg="don't"
     >dont</orig> plant <orig reg="there">their</orig> sow the best of the ground in oats as far as
     it will go and let the remainder be until <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> put more on your self than you can
     manage. it is not <orig reg="worthwhile">worth while</orig> to expose <orig reg="yourself">your
      self</orig> to put out a crop if you <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> get any out of it. you can
     keep the stock off the new ground field and the orchard. it will make as much hay as well. keep
     the stock if the season suits and what luck do you have with your help?</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>So no more at <orig reg="present">preasant</orig> but remain yours</salute>
     <signed>from Jesse Rolston</signed>
     <seg type="postscript"><orig reg="write">rite</orig> and [letter gone] <name type="recipient"
       >Mary Catherine Rolston</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
