<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6217"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6217">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    May 28, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, may 28 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6217</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502458</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, May 28, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, may 28 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, May 28, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-05-28">1868-05-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6217T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert announces that Evans' missing letter arrived, and details the unhappiness
                    it had caused her to be without it. She describes her devoted love for
                Evans.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-05-28">May 28, 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt. Solon Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>The letter which disappointed me so much on Tuesday, came <orig reg="today">to
                        day</orig> (Thursday) &amp; how pleasantly my heart was relieved of all
                    anxiety. I wrote to you yesterday by Mr. Jerry Hall telling you of my
                    disappointment, &amp; suppose you <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> the
                    letter, &amp; was surprised to hear that I did not get your letter Tuesday.
                    I have it now &amp; <abbr expan="although">tho'</abbr> short I thank God for
                    it, as it is from you my love. I would rather get <hi rend="underline">one</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">line</hi> written by your dear hand <orig reg="than"
                    >then</orig> sheets full from <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> else. but I love
                    for you to write me long letters when you have time. This last one <pb n="2"/>I
                    willingly Excuse as you were busy. I can't tell you how many things I <hi
                        rend="underline">imagined</hi> which made me just as unhappy as <orig
                        reg="anyone">any one</orig> ever could be in this life, by not getting your
                    letter Tuesday. I was perfectedly miserable from Tuesday evening, until 10
                    O'clock <orig reg="today">to day</orig> when your dear letter came &amp;
                    made my heart free from suffering. I love you so that when I do not see you or
                    get letters from you I suffer deeply, &amp; long. The whole world seems
                    dark, &amp; dreary to me, &amp; I cannot find peace &amp; pleasure
                    with <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig>, or in any way. I find happiness in
                    nothing on Earth when I think I have lost your love &amp; I know by my
                    heartaches then that with you is my <pb n="3"/>only real happiness in this life
                    &amp; do beleive that I could not live if you did not love me. You must not
                    smile &amp; say I just think so now. I do not just think so, for I know that
                    my happiness depends upon you, &amp; that I never truly loved until I loved
                    you, &amp; it is my nature to love you with all my soul my heart, mind
                    &amp; strength &amp; loving you so could I ever be happy, &amp; live
                    without your love? I feel that I could not. May God bless our love for <orig
                        reg="each other">eachother</orig> always is my daily prayer. I was so
                    disappointed when I read in your letter that you cannot come Saturday. how can I
                    spend another long week without seeing you my love. It seems that I cannot wait
                    so long <pb n="4"/>for Oh! I do want to see your dear face so much, so much--I
                    am saying truly just as I feel. I do want to see you this week for it is so long
                    since you were here, &amp; then you were with me such a short time,
                    &amp; to be with you is the greatest pleasure of my life--a pleasure I love,
                    &amp; thank God for giving me. My dear pa &amp; Ada have not returned
                    yet. we are looking for them <orig reg="today">to day</orig>. There is a letter
                    here for pa from <abbr expan="General">Gen'l</abbr> Imboden who is well again.
                    My Editor Mr. Wartman of Harrisonburg is here attending the Musical Convention.
                    his wife just died a few weeks ago. Ella would say he has no heart, I think so
                    myself. I love you with all my heart, Soul, &amp; nature, &amp; will
                    while we both live. I want to see you more <orig reg="than">then</orig> I can
                    write in words Oh I do wish you could come Saturday, if you cannot come (but I
                    hope you will) write to me Tuesday. All send love. I send love &amp; a
                    loving kiss to you. God bless you my love, my heart is only yours</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
