<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6232"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6232">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    September 30, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, september 30 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6232</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502473</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, September 30,
                            1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, september 30 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, September 30, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-09-30">1868-09-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6232T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert discusses the upcoming move of her family to Buffalo, Virginia, and her
                    love for Evans.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-09-30">Sept 30 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt. Solon Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have your dear &amp; welcome letter of the 29 I was so glad to hear of your
                    safe arrival home. I thank you my love for your cheering words in regard to my
                    becoming satisfied in my new home. I shall be so for the sake of my dear papa he
                    loves to see his family happy as much as <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> in
                    the world &amp; I shall let him see that I am not an ungrateful child
                    &amp; that I will love him when, &amp; <orig reg="wherever">where
                    ever</orig> he goes. My dear kind papa Oh! <pb n="2"/>how earnestly I do wish I
                    could keep every Earthly trouble &amp; anxiety from his pathway through life
                    &amp; at last insure him a home in <orig reg="Heaven">Heavan</orig>, but I
                    cannot May God bless him is my heartfelt prayer. I wish you could step in at
                    this time you would think we are going away by the appearance of <orig
                        reg="everything">every thing</orig> in &amp; out of the house. I think
                    we shall all be very happy in our new home this winter if we live &amp; can
                    keep pa with us all the time, &amp; I think we shall have the mail arranged
                    all as we wish. I could not be contented two long weeks without hearing from
                    you. one of the greatest pleasures I have is getting your dear letters &amp;
                    answer <pb n="3"/>-ing them. &amp; I do hope that pleasure will not be kept
                    from me at Buffalo. I hope for the best in this as in all other affairs of life.
                    I know you will still love me but then I like best during the two weeks that you
                    are away from me to read the dear, &amp; sincere expressions of your
                    affection in your letters. I do love to read them. They tell me how dear I am to
                    you my love. Your letters are dear &amp; welcome to my heart. I read them
                    over many times.</p>

                <p>Miss Regina, &amp; Billie <unclear>Tems</unclear> spent <orig reg="today">to
                        day</orig> with us. Miss Regina told me to tell you that she was very sorry
                    she did not get to see you last Sabbath. I have concluded not to spend the
                    winter down the Valley but to go with my dear pa to our Buffalo home. I shall be
                    far <pb n="4"/>happier there doing my duty &amp; then I can see you often my
                    love if I went to Page I could not see you &amp; I would rather be with you
                        <orig reg="than">then</orig> all on Earth. I would rather be where I could
                    see you <orig reg="than">then</orig> all other places in the world. I am happy
                    then very happy. I feel as if I have just what is dearest to my heart with me
                    &amp; I ask for nothing more only that I might always have you with me. I
                    cannot yet tell if I shall go to Buffalo by Staunton. If I do you shall know I
                    would love so much to go with you to Staunton I will tell you if I live in time
                    for you to come for I <unclear>dearly want</unclear> to see you again before I
                    go &amp; here where you &amp; I have spent so many sweet &amp; happy
                    hours together the very happiest hours of my life I have spent here with you my
                    love. I love you with all the unchanging devotion of my heart &amp; Soul
                    &amp; ever shall while I live you are truly the first &amp; only love of
                    my heart &amp; Soul &amp; ever will be my only love. All send love. I
                    send a loving kiss to you. My heart you have with all its devotion. God bless
                    you my love always. Write to me soon. I love you above all others</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
