<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6240"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6240">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    November 20, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 20 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6240</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502481</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, November 20, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 20 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, November 20, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-11-20">1868-11-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6240T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert writes Evans and discusses her delayed letter, snow in the mountains,
                    family news, and David's upcoming visit.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-11-20">Nov. 20 /'68.</date>
                        <name type="place">Buffalo, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have both of your dear letters. The one by Hamie I answered Wednesday but did
                    not get to send it. Thursday Hamie went to the half Station Early some time
                    before the cars came but he could not get to see the mail Agent as the cars did
                    not stop that morning at the Hotel. one of the workman held out his hand for the
                    letter as the one I sent before was so long reaching you Hamie would not give it
                    to him. I knew you would be very much disappointed my love but you were not <pb
                        n="2"/> more so <orig reg="than">then</orig> I was by not getting my letter
                    off. I love to write to you &amp; when you do not get letters from me now it
                    is because I can't get to send them that is the only reason in the world my
                    love. I am so glad you are coming up <orig reg="tomorrow">to morrow</orig> if
                    you live. Ma was not angry when she came home. she did not blame you but was
                    glad to be at home again I told her why I wanted Hamie to go with you &amp;
                    she said it was right. You must not mind <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>
                    Ada tells you for I sometimes think she don't know herself what she says. I do
                    wish she would be more considerate &amp; have some regard for your feelings.
                    I don't <pb n="3"/> know what to think of her You must not be troubled at <orig
                        reg="anything">any thing</orig> she may say to you. The Magazine &amp;
                    the Ledgers came safely &amp; I thank you My love for those tokens of your
                    thoughtful kindness for me when absent. I do appreciate any favor, or gift in
                    the world from you, if it was only a fragment I would love &amp; keep it
                    because you gave it to me. Have you ever been in the Mountains when the snow was
                    falling thick &amp; fast, so that you could not see any distance before you,
                    covering the Mountains in a shroud of white. imagine how it is with us this
                    Morning at the Palace. I am here by a bright warm fire surrounded without by
                    Mountains <pb n="4"/> &amp; snow. I am here but my thoughts are with you the
                    one dearer to me <orig reg="than">then</orig> all on Earth. I wish I could see
                    you <orig reg="today">to day</orig> if you were here I should be very happy. but
                    that cannot be just yet. I have the cheering &amp; blessed hope of being
                    with you soon my love Tell Magnus we are looking for him tomorrow with you but I
                    expect he will come on the cars. You must not think me selfish for wanting you
                    to come every week. I love you &amp; feel as if I can't be satisfied if I do
                    not see your dear face every week the time seems so long to me when you are away
                    my love. I know you have to travel a lonely road by <orig reg="yourself">your
                        self</orig> in the night it does trouble me to think of you coming alone
                    &amp; I do wish you could come earlier in the day or have company I am
                    always thinking of your safety &amp; comfort. I love you with all the
                    devotion of my heart &amp; soul &amp; ever shall. you are all the world
                    to me. my only happiness depends upon you. you have all my affection of heart
                    soul &amp; mind. come if you live tomorrow my heart says come &amp; do
                    not disappoint me. May God bless you &amp; let you come. My love to one who
                    loves only you. All send love. I send a loving kiss. Come.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Loving</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
