<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6513"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6513">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, June 21,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, june 21 1861</title>
        <author>Hatcher, Clinton</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6513</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502524</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, June 21, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, june 21 1861</title>
            <author>Clinton Hatcher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>8 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Evans-Sibert Family Papers, 1849-1900, Accession
       27770, Personal Papers Collection, Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond,
      Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-06-21">1861-06-21</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Enlistment, Military Authority, Patriotism, Slavery, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005-01-31">January 31, 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Andre Fleche</name>
        </respStmt>

        <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6513T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Clinton Hatcher describes camp life, conveys his anxiousness to meet the Yankee abolitionists
     in battle, and criticizes men too cowardly to defend their women. He encourages Mary Sibert in
     her discussions on national affairs and comments on the nature of her sex, including her
     rumored flirtatiousness and heartlessness.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-06-21">June 21<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">st</hi> </hi> 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Mason</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Miss Mary:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I received your letter on the evening of the day before yesterday and have been so busy ever
     since that although it deserved a more speedy answer it has been really impossible for me to
     write.</p>

    <p>We are now as you see from the place of date in camp at Leesburg. Col. Hunton said he would
     be up in an hour to muster us regularly into service and I have concluded to employ the
     interval in <unclear>inditing</unclear> you a hasty <pb n="2"/> epistle. I am sitting flat on
     the ground with the paper resting on a very rough hand trunk which is the best substitute for
     an "escritoir" which I have been able to find. The novelty has not yet worn off of this manner
     of life and although considerably unpleasant I only amuse myself with its hardships and am
     perfectly satisfied. Last night there was so much noise that I found it impossible to sleep
     much with a <hi rend="underline">soft</hi> pair of boot heels under my my head. I think it
     quite probable that I shall be sergeant of the guard tonight. Our fare is splendid <pb n="3"/>
     except that the coffee is so hot that it takes all the skin off of our mouths, the butter (what
     little we get) is old enough to vote, the beef is tougher than sole leather and the bread is
     hard and stale. I knew before I came into camp exactly what I would be compelled to endure and
     as it is in the cause of my country I am determined not to become dissatisfied and shall do all
     I can to keep others in good spirits. We expect a regiment here from the Junction to-day as
     there are 1500 Yankees just across the river. Since I last wrote to you I have been riding <pb
      n="4"/> nearly all the time trying to get more recruits for our company. Last Monday night I
     rode all night and until Noon on Tuesday I do hope the Yankees will cross the river soon for
     they will keep us here for some time drilling and unless the Abolitionists come over to us we
     will not get a shot at them. My gun has a splendid bayonette and I hope to have an opportunity
     to use it.</p>

    <p>You seem to think that your writing on the affairs of our nation may be disagreeable to me. I
     can assure you it is not. I like to hear your <pb n="5"/> your opinons on every subject.</p>

    <p>Indeed among the many things which I have calculated upon to wear off the gloom of a
     monotonous military, or rather camp, life your letters So long and interesting have been put
     down for no small share.</p>

    <p>You ask about our uniform it is to be grey, <orig reg="trimmed">trimed</orig> entirely with
     blue. Our company is as I believe I told you called the "Blue Mountain Boys".</p>

    <p>As I have been going round recruiting, the cowardice of some of our Virginia boys has made me
     wish I could swing them all to a limb. Any man who would not <pb n="6"/> risk his life to
     defend such ladies as we have in the Old Dominion does not deserve the name of a Virginian.</p>

    <p>I am truly glad to hear that I am not yet forgotten by you; and I can assure you that in my
     waking dreams a form seen but three times <hi rend="underline">often</hi> passes before my
     gaze.</p>

    <p>I am really sorry you did not answer my other question and I shall insist on a <orig
      reg="fulfillment">fulfilment</orig> of your promise to answer it in your next. I was told
     several times while I was in Augusta that you were a noted flirt and universally considered
     perfectly heartless; yet such reports <hi rend="underline">sometimes</hi> arise without much
      <pb n="7"/> foundation and I <hi rend="underline">hope</hi> this is false.</p>

    <p>I do really <hi rend="underline">think</hi>, as you say, candidly that some ladies "can be
     trusted" but I do not <hi rend="underline">know</hi> that fact, Most that I have had an
     opportunity to know well were only to be trusted sometimes. And constancy is certainly the
     exception and far from being any thing like the general rule.</p>

    <p>I should like very much to see that love letter of which you spoke and will send it to me
     will promise to look "as solemn as a mule" (to use a favourite similes of a friend of mine now
     at Pensacola) all the time I am reading it.</p>

    <p>I never had the pleasure of <pb n="8"/> receiving a real love letter in my life and have
     seldom seen the "rare airs".</p>

    <p>I received a long letter from Chum last week, after a terribly long silence. He spoke of
     returning to Augusta and joining the army. I wish he would come and join us.</p>

    <p>The drum has just beaten "to arms" and I must close this letter which I am almost ashamed to
     send. But I hope you will make the necessary allowances and write me a long answer very soon.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain as ever, most truly your <hi rend="underline">sincere</hi> friend</salute>
     <signed>Clinton</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
