<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6515"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6515">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, July 27,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, july 27 1861</title>
        <author>Hatcher, Clinton</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6515</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502526</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, July 27, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, july 27 1861</title>
            <author>Clinton Hatcher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>8 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Evans-Sibert Family Papers, 1849-1900, Accession
       27770, Personal Papers Collection, Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond,
      Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-07-27">1861-07-27</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Enlistment, Military Authority, Military
      Strategy, Troop Movement, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005-01-31">January 31, 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Andre Fleche</name>
        </respStmt>

        <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6515T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Clinton Hatcher recounts his role in the battle at Manassas Junction in July 1861 and
     relishes his next opportunity to bayonette a Yankee. He also addresses Mary Sibert's concerns
     about the propriety of their correspondence and hints at his feelings.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Miss Mary A. Sibert<lb/>Mt. Solon<lb/>Augusta Co.<lb/>Va.</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-07-27">July 27<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Berkeley</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Miss Mary:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Your, as usually, most welcome letter was received on yesterday morning and read with unusual
     pleasure. We had just returned the evening before from Manassas Junction, tired and low
     spirited, so your letter was quite <orig reg="useful">usefull</orig> to cheer me up.</p>

    <p>On Thursday before last we left our camp near Leesburg and marched down within about six
     miles of the Junction; here we were kept in a continual state of alarm, we had to stand or
     march in the sun all day and then sleep on our arms all night without either tents or even
     blankets and were usually aroused several times during the night by alarms and compelled to
     stand in line of battle until our scouts could be thrown out and ascertain <pb n="2"/> that no
     enemy were near. We had about half enough of stale bread &amp; cold fat meat to eat not
     near half enough muddy water to drink. We had become so accustomed to false alarms that on
     Sunday when they drew us up in line of battle behind a hill, I had not the slightest idea that
     we would get a sight of the enemy. About nine O'clock we were formed <hi rend="super">as a
      reserve</hi> behind some small trees and underbrush which served to hide us without offering
     us the least protection. Shot, shell and minnie balls fell round us like hail but still we were
     kept in line of battle exposed to their fire without being able to return a shot until about
     one O'clock when Gen. Beauregard rode up. We gave him three good hearty cheers and then turning
     to Col. Hunton he said "Colonel had your regiment without a moments delay to the thickest part
     of the battle." <pb n="3"/> We came through the woods in dreadful disorder on account of the
     density of the undergrowth, but as we emerged we gave a shout, so loud and terrific that the
     two regiments of Yankees who had been placed there to oppose us broke and ran. We then marched
     to the relief of the extreme left wing. As we came up we met the South Carolinians and
     Alabamians in full retreat, they said that the day was lost and that all our men were in
     confusion and retreating, but still we marched steadily on notwithstanding the storm of grape,
     canister, shell and minnie balls which were flying round; when within about three or four
     hundred yards of the enemies right wing we halted and took the enemies fire without being able
     to return a shot until the South Carolinians and Alabamians <pb n="4"/> formed <hi
      rend="underline">behind</hi> us, then we charged with a shout. The enemy seeing men charging
     with such alacrity when they thought their victory complete and our ranks in remediless
     confusion, became frightened and ran away. We took the house which defended their right wing
     and then stormed and captured the battery which had been pouring shell and shot into our ranks,
     but the enemy fled so soon that the fire which we sent after them did little <orig
      reg="execution">esxicution</orig>. After the battle was over we started about sunset and
     marched eight miles to <orig reg="Manassas">Manassa</orig> Junction in quick time before we
     could get any thing to eat or drink. About ten minutes before we were ordered into the battle
     two of our men took all the canteens of the company and started after water, they were unable
      <pb n="5"/> on their return to find our regiment, so we had to fight all day and then march
     eight miles without any thing either to eat or drink. Our company escaped almost miraculously
     without even a man hurt, but the left wing of our regiment, behind which an Alabama ensign was
     carrying his flag, his regiment having all retreated, was cut to pieces dreadfully. Seventeen
     of the men in one of our companies fell the first fire.</p>

    <p>Gen. Beauregard complimented our Regiment very much, thanked our Col. for the gallant conduct
     of his command and said that we had turned the tide of battle and gained the victory when the
     South Carolinians and Alabamians were retreating.</p>

    <p>I have not attempted to give an <pb n="6"/> account of the battle but only to let you know as
     briefly as possible something of the part <hi rend="underline">we</hi> took in it. I expect
     even this has wearied you nearly to death by this time and so I will drop that subject. I am so
     heartily tired of it I know as you can be, for I can't get a crowd of fellows here now to talk
     of any thing else but the battle of Sunday.</p>

    <p>My feelings while <hi rend="underline">in</hi> the battle were hardly unpleasant. I believe I
     would soon become fond of the excitement at least I rather <hi rend="underline">hope</hi> I
     shall be in one bayonette charge before I leave the service. Besides wanting to stick my
     bayonette in a Yankee I wish to see if I can feel as cool when marching on the steel as I did
     while the balls were whistling round me.</p>

    <p>I never felt the whole day as if there was a possibility of a <pb n="7"/> ball's striking me.
     I had a kind of presentiment that I would not be killed.</p>

    <p>Please excuse my writing with a lead pencil and putting you to so much trouble to read it but
     pens and ink have gone out of fashion in camp and are "<unclear>vavae ares</unclear>," here.</p>

    <p>I am very sorry that Chum did not come on and join our company. I want to see him very much.
      M<hi rend="super">
      <hi rend="underline">c</hi>
     </hi>Donald's legion, consisting of some of the bravest and best men in our county left for the
     neighborhood of Staunton a few days ago to check the advance of the enemy from the west. I
     don't know where we will go next, but would not be surprised any morning to receive orders to
     march either to Maryland or Washington "via" Alexandria. But I have already promised to <pb
      n="8"/> stop talking about the war.</p>

    <p>You say you "do not expect I care much whether I have your esteem or not". <hi
      rend="underline">Indeed</hi> you are <hi rend="underline">very</hi> much mistken. I would
     consider it a misfortune of unusual severity &amp; If I lost that esteem by any misconduct
     of my own I could never forgive myself for the act. Do not hesitate to write as frank and
     candid letters as you can, they need no apology. I like your free and open style; but for my
     part I <hi rend="underline">dare</hi> not write half that I think and feel. I am sorry that our
     acquaintance has really been so brief and especially that you remember that fact, for my part
     it seems to me that I have known you <hi rend="underline">almost</hi> always.</p>

    <p>I should be perfectly delighted if the varied fortunes of my ever changing life could once
     more bring me up at Mt. Solon. I love that sweet little village and more I ---- will not say.</p>

    <p>I have been interrupted several times for roll calls and drills while writing this hasty
     letter and now I must close for the <unclear>nine</unclear> O'clock <unclear>drill</unclear>.</p>


    <closer>
     <salute>Please write me another of your long interesting letters very soon and believe me ever
      to be your devoted and unchanging friend</salute>
     <signed>Clinton</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">P. S. I expect to write to Chum <orig reg="today">to day</orig>.</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
