<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7118"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 


<TEI.2 id="A7118"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, April 18, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to samuel hunt, april 18 1866</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 5.019 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7118</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date> 
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500234</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, April 18, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to samuel hunt, april 18 1866</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>2 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, April 18, 1866, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1866-04-18">1866-04-18</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Economy, Race Relations, Church/Religious Activity, Arts/Leisure</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7118T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>John Scott asks Samuel Hunt whether funds collected from local blacks for clothing distributed by the AMA should be used to reimburse Mr. Hunt or whether those funds should be used to help pay off rent for a church Scott had acquired and turned into a schoolhouse.  He says he is concerned that leaving the matter unresolved over the summer might allow the "secesh negrohaters" in Staunton to take the schoolhouse from the AMA.  He also mentions that local blacks helped raise money by putting on a concert in town, and that they had arranged to have a fair on the first of May.</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">S Hunt</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1866-04-18">Apr 18/66</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>I received a note from the rooms, I suppose as it was written on paper with the printed heading of yours, but signed S R. Montross in which letter was stated that there are <del hand="h1">th</del> four boxes of clothing on the way for Freedmen</p>

<p>Now as it is summer almost and the people are at work I think the most of them will be able to pay a trifle on these clothes, What I wish to ask is.  What I shall do with the money?  Shall I hand it over to Mr Tukey as I do book money at the end of each month and then use it to mitigate your expenses?  The church<pb n="2"/> in which we teach is not yet secure as there is $166. yet due on the first installment of $666.  At your suggestion it might be applied to help pay that and would be of advantage.  I dare not leave the thing so insecure to go home at vacation for no one knows what these secesh <hi rend="underline">negrohaters</hi> would do  The colored people think of holding a fair the first of May to raise the money and I think they will nearly do it  We have just held a concert of religious pieces mostly, among the children of the day school and raised 54 dollars to help pay for the church.
</p>
<closer>
<salute></salute> 
<signed>J. Scott</signed> 


</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>