<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7126"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="A7126"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, November 30, 1868</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, november 30 1868</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 6.106 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7126</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500242</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, November 30, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, november 30 1868</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>2 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to E. P. Smith, November 30, 1868, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1868-11-30">1868-11-30</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Race Relations</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7126T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Scott reports on the growing popularity of the AMA schools in Staunton and states that he is "going out immediately to hunt up a temporary assistant among the older scholars."  He closes with a complaint about the continuing shortage of suitable books for his students.</p> 
</div1> 
</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Rev. E. P. Smith</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1868-11-30">Nov 30th 1868</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute></salute> 
</opener> 
<p>Latest dispatch 4 P.M.  <hi rend="underline">Great rush to the "Excelsion" school of Mr Scott</hi>!!  Help and Books wanted!--<hi rend="underline">immediately</hi></p>
	<p>My numbers have gone up to day from 55 to <hi rend="underline">80</hi> more are coming tomorrow  Numbers are coming from the country to take board in the city that they may attend school.  Children are <hi rend="underline">teasing</hi> their parents to let them come.  Others are begging for <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and one woman told me her sick daughter a little girl of seven had not sat up for days but arose immediately on hearing of my arrival--and begged to go school  Here I am without books or help</p>
	<p>I am going out immediately to hunt up a temporary assistant among the older scholars till the teacher arrives, and even then she will be wanted at this rate.</p>
	<p>I have just written an order to Chaplain Manly at Richmond for a few books till those you send me shall arrive.  I do not have to visit as I expected to <hi rend="underline">keep out of sight</hi> as much as possible, for the sight of me in the street is a guarantee for a fresh crowd of children next day.  I am compelled to send for more books<pb n="2"/> in view of the certain increase of numbers but will be as sparing as possible</p>
	<p>In my letter this morning I did not order any Outline maps but if you can send them I hope you will  If you are obliged to strike off anything from the bill for which I send at present let it be the charts.  But primary charts are of very great use in the absence of suitable blackboards--and primmers</p> 
	<p>One little girl this morning who had no book was learning the Alphabet from the fragment of an old <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> was gone.  Don't get expensive ones on pasteboard as cheep paper ones will do, and I can put a cloth back on to preserve them.</p>
	<p>There were but few books in the city suitable for these children and I have bought them all and sold again to day to the children who still begged for more.</p>
	<p>I hope this will reach you in time to enable you to add to the bill I sent this morning,--befor you have boxed up those books I then ordered.</p>


<closer>
<salute>Very Respectfully</salute> 
<signed>John Scott</signed> 
<seg type="postscript">Send in addition to the bill of Books ordered this morning the following<lb/>
Arithmetic Davies written (Com Schl) 1/2 doz<lb/>
Arithmetic (any Primary (with multiplication table)--1 doz<lb/>
Geography Montieths No 1-- -- -- 2 doz<lb/>
Outline maps -- -- -- one set<lb/>
(Cheep) Primary Charts (not for drawing) one set<lb/>
Crayon a few, 1 small box &amp;lt 2 Boxes
</seg> 
<name type="place">New York</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>