<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7148"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7148"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, February 26, 1869</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, february 26 1869</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 5.766 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7148</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500264</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, February 26, 1869</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, february 26 1869</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>4 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to E. P. Smith, February 26, 1869, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1869-02-26">1869-02-26</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Church/Religious Activity, Economy, Race Relations</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7148T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Scott reports complications with attaining the necessary votes from the Methodist church "Trustees" to begin construction on a new schoolhouse and once again complains about pastor "Lewis's" fervent attempts to hamper the AMA's mission in Staunton.</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">E. P. Smith</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1869-02-26">Feb 26/69</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>I write not of necessity, but it may be interesting to you to hear of our School House project.</p>
	<p>There is no equal to this colored minister.  His ingenious and persistent opposition to every plan for the education of these children is a favorable comment on the ability of the negro.</p>
	<p>The plan which I sent you of a little addition to our room passed the Vote of the "Qarterly Conference" though it was opposed by the minister til past Midnight  We thought we were successful but as the matter had to go<pb n="2"/> before the Trustees there was still a chance for mischief and you may be sure the Preacher lost no time in influencing the minds of all he could to <hi rend="underline">not</hi> build a House</p>
	<p>Wednesday night they had a meeting but before that I had traveled many a mile to find the Trustees at their work where I could talk to them that this minister might not persuade them against the school.</p>
	<p>We were again kept till midnight.  Lewis the minister tried every way to prevent a vote.  He was chairman and he would not <hi rend="underline">allow me a word</hi> of advice or counsel, as he feared the force of my remarks in<pb n="3"/> its influence on the Trustees and I had to sit there till midnight and see those poor people falsified and their interests misrepresented, and belied.</p>
	<p>He succeeded in preventing a vote to build as an addition to the basement any School house.</p>
	<p>But presently a little African ingenuity was displayed on the other side.  One of the Trustees was strongly in favor of school and made such an overwhelming speech that a vote was taken to build a school house--but not to adjoin the Church</p>
	<p>Every man voted for it.  But alas they<pb n="4"/> dont know the cost.</p>
	<p>I fear we shall not have it this season.</p>
	<p>After the vote was taken the Minister tried still to make the people believe they had no right to put the House.  The meeting finally broke up without any regular adjournment and as one Trustee after another came out Lewis was still left contending.  I dont know but he remained all night and talked to himself.</p>
	<p>I trust the Lord will do something with us  I dont know what--Our school increases</p>


<closer>
<salute></salute> 
<signed>John Scott</signed> 

</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>