<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7141"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 



<TEI.2 id="A7141"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, January 25, 1869</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, january 25 1869</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 6.719 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7141</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500257</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, January 25, 1869</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, january 25 1869</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>3 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to E. P. Smith, January 25, 1869, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1869-01-25">1869-01-25</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Race Relations, Church/Religious Activity</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7141T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Scott complains about pastor "Lewis," arguing that "Lewis" continually attempts to thwart his efforts to acquire a classroom in Staunton's black Methodist church.</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Rev E P Smith</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va.</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1869-01-25">Jan 25 1869</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute></salute> 
</opener> 

<p>We still have no place in which to teach.  The Trustees of the church met on Friday night and held a council until midnight.  Lewis the Preacher who turned the school and teacher out of doors was present and so browbeat and frightened the Trustees with the idea that they had no right to allow the church to be used for that purpose that they did not even take a vote upon it  The probability is that after eight weeks or--so, many will leave and the school can all be held then in the Basement.  It seems a pity to have to rent a room and fit it up for use.  Beside that no room can be had in this part of the city where the children are accustomed to come.  If we get a room it will be at the other end of the city.</p>
	<p>I dont know what to do.  I never saw a case parallel to this.</p>
	<p>There is an old leaky kitchen close<pb n="2"/> by the school house belonging to the preacher  Last week I sent a few scholars at a time down there and they recited and then returned to the crowded basement while the teacher waited for another class.  I shall have to do the same this week; and think of trying to secure that kitchen for the rest of the Season; which by removing partitions can be used.  <hi rend="underline">The minister</hi> has gone so that I can't even do that to day or ascertain whether it can be done at all.  <hi rend="underline">Shall</hi> I rent if it is necessary to save the school.</p>
	<p>The colored school Committee are bound by contract to furnish a place in which to teach but they will not be likely to do it if the kitchen can not be had.</p>
	<p>The affair is greatly injuring the usefulness of the school but it will do some good beside</p>
	<p>There is no chance to build a school house here this year nor probably any next; as the methodist denomination have 1200 dollars to raise toward a burying ground just bought, and the Baptists have bought lumber for a church to be built in warm weather.  Yet this may be accomplished this coming summer and I hope will be--and the event of turning us out doors has brought the Baptists to say that whenever their church is done we may teach in<pb n="3"/> that in welcome.  So that next year we shall be likely to have a place to teach which we might not have had, had it not been for this affair which has awakened new sympathy with us.  This Preachers time is out on March first and he is not likely to be sent back and I think things will prosper if we can live til then  Nor have I quite given up the idea of going into the church.  There is a white Presiding Elder here belonging to this same Conference as do these colored, and so soon as he returnes I hope to work thro' him and get the church.</p>
	<p>I have also written to Bishop Simpson of Philadelphia for his advise and shall use every worthy effort to secure the house</p>
	<p>Should we fail after this year I think the post should be <hi rend="underline">abandoned</hi> until a school house can be built.  The people are so enraged at the act of their Pastor that they would build it now if they had the funds.</p>
	<p>Do you wish to advise me.  I am prematurely wearing out under the influence of very unexpected difficulties--and some unusual ones which have almost <unclear>dubled</unclear> my care and labor--</p>

<closer>
<salute>Respectfully</salute> 
<signed>John Scott</signed> 

<name type="place">N Y</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>