<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7193"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 

<TEI.2 id="A7193"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: C. E. Dewey to Samuel Hunt, March 31, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county c e dewey to samuel hunt, march 31 1866</title>
        <author>Dewey, C. E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 6.617 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7193</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500309</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: C. E. Dewey to Samuel Hunt, March 31, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county c e dewey to samuel hunt, march 31 1866</title>
            <author>C. E. Dewey</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>4 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: C. E. Dewey to Samuel Hunt, March 31, 1866, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1866-03-31">1866-03-31</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Women</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7193T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Dewey provides a school report for the month of March and elaborates on her students' reverence for honesty.</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient"></name> 
<name type="place">Staunton</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1866-03-31">March 31<hi rend="super">st</hi></date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Mr Hunt</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>My school has been much pleasanter this month than I expected it would be, in a building with three other schools <unclear>occupying</unclear> the remaining corners.  I miss my quiet little school-room where the children had less to attract their attention from their books; but they are much stiller than I could expect.  I have almost entirely broken up the habit of whispering but it is more difficult to keep them from studying in that annoying buzzing under tone.  However they are improving in this respect in the day school + <unclear>as</unclear> my night school it has ceased entirely.</p>
	<p>I had partly expected to find<pb n="2"/> the children dishonest + untruthful <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> other + more experienced leaders <del hand="h1">encouraged</del> strengthened the feeling <del hand="h1">but</del>  Either I have been more fortunate in my scholars or my plan of trusting them without tempting them is a success for I have not found a single instance of theft and but three or four of falsehood.  From the first I have tried to teach them how wrong both were; while at every case of falsehood I have made an example.  They prize highly my confidence in them one of my most trying scholars said to me one day, "Miss Dewey I have never told you a story + I never mean to for then you couldn't trust me any more <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> believe me."  Some days ago I took to school a number of painted cards, as rewards for the children, all I had I suppose I left them on a little shelf close to the children's seats  After<pb n="3"/> a day or two I went to get some from the box in which they were kept + to my surprise, found yet more than half as many as I thought I had brought up.  I felt so confident that I said to the scholars "I'm afraid some of my little girls have been taking some of my tickets.  It makes me feel very sorry to think so for I felt I could trust them.  I made some inquiries, but wafer denials were all I received.  When I came home, to make certain I looked where I had been in the habit of keeping them + there to my surprise found all that I had lost I felt greatly mortified + sorry + I determined to apologize the Monday next, but before then one after another would drop in + <del hand="h1">would</del> ask me, in Sunday school "Did you find your cards?" And "Oh, I <hi rend="underline">am</hi> <hi rend="underline">so</hi> glad;" when I said "Yes;"  "I couldn't bear to have you think me a thief"--"I lay awake<pb n="4"/> thinking about it last night; it troubled me so;" were remarks by different children.  All seemed so relieved I felt as if I could never suspect them again.  Calling on the mother of some of my children the other day, little Annie said to me, "I never tell a story now without thinking of you."  "Why Annie" said I "do you ever tell stories?"  "Sometimes, but I try not to."  "Yes" said her mother, "she has improved greatly, for now if she tells a story she often says 'I'll take that back, it isn't true.'"--So our work here has its fruit, even now, + we believe that the harvest of which the first fruits are now given, will be a very bounteous one.  But not with us be the glory.  It is God's work + it is indeed marvelous in our eyes.</p>	


<closer>
<salute><hi rend="underline">I remain very respectfully</hi></salute> 
<signed><hi rend="underline">C. E. Dewey</hi></signed> 

</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>