<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7623"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7623">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                    Hester J. Nadenbousch, April 20, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, april 20 1864</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7623</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502624</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, April 20, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, april 20 1864</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                            Hester J. Nadenbousch, April 20, 1864, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters,
                            Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy,
                            Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-20">1864-04-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Family, Home Front, Military Authority, Patriotism,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7623T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch writes his wife with the good news that his resignation has been
                    accepted and he is out of the army. He will come home as soon as he is well and
                    able. For the moment, he will not because he does not wish to take an oath of
                    loyalty to the Union. He tells his wife not to worry about confiscation of their
                    property, as everything will be sorted out after the war. He expresses the
                    opinion that the coming campaigns will decide the issue and asserts that
                    Confederate forces are in good shape and highly motivated by such issues as the
                    enlistment of black men in the Union army. He also sends messages for his
                    children.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-20">April 20/64</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I again have an <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> by which I hope to
                    send you a few lines &amp; of course embrace it as you may be glad to hear
                    from me though not anxious to write me</p>

                <p>I have just received official notice of the acceptance of my resignation
                    &amp; yesterday turned over the command of this post I now am out of office
                    (a citizen) I feel like an uncaged bird after 3 long years of close servitude I
                    now am liberated (could say more here but <orig reg="won't">won<hi rend="super"
                            >t</hi></orig>)</p>

                <p>I am still much crippled up with Rheumatism am hardly able to limp about the
                    house but hope so soon as the weather clears up &amp; settles to get better.
                    I have suffered amazingly for the last 5 weeks.</p>

                <p>Well I suppose the next thing you want to know is when I am coming home This I
                        <orig reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig> positively say but certainly so soon as the way is open</p>

                <p>I must first now try &amp; get well &amp; then arrange other matters we
                    are doing a fine business here and would much prefer having you here with me,
                    which I think can be done before long And if the way is not soon <pb n="2"/>
                    open we will try &amp; make some other arrangements for the best You wrote
                    me to come home This I <orig reg="can't">
                        <hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">cant</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </orig> do now I would be compelled to take the Oath or be imprisoned this I
                    have not concluded to do yet &amp; hope there will be no necessity for it My
                    own opinion is that there will be some heavy fighting in <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va</abbr> this spring &amp; that this will about end the war I trust to
                    god it may for I am sorely tired of it Our troops are in the best condition and
                    much more determined than ever known. The negro soldier seems to fire them up. I
                    think this <orig reg="spring's">springs</orig> campaign will settle the question
                    of subjugation</p>

                <p>I hope you have gotten over the <orig reg="mood">mude</orig> you were in when I
                    last heard from you it pained me so to see you so low spirited &amp;
                    disponding You try &amp; keep a home some place there and full &amp;
                    plenty to live on. take care of yourself &amp; family and <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> bother about the property if taken it will only be temporarily
                    &amp; <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> last we will still own it all let it go
                    now &amp; <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> let any one annoy you about it all
                    will be right I still have <add hand="h1" place="inline">full &amp;</add>
                    plenty here to <hi rend="underline">keep you well</hi> if all other was <hi
                        rend="underline">entirely gone</hi> to which I am daily trying to add. I am
                    anxious now to know the exact condition of things as I have heard <pb n="3"/> so
                    many reports about our matters. how I would like to see you now and hope it will
                    not be long until we meet If you <orig reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig> write get some friend to write me fully about our private
                    matters I enclose you a small draft on a party in Maryland you give to H L Staub
                    &amp; ask him to have it collected for you. or if he <orig reg="can't"
                            >can<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig>, get some one else to collect for you whoever collects can
                        in<unclear>sert</unclear>sert their name in the draft and you use the money
                    &amp; let me know if you need money as if you do I can buy here such fund<hi
                        rend="super">s</hi> as you can use there</p>

                <p>My love to all the children &amp; Miss Jane. <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    let the children be too closely confined at school as it might injure their
                    health. try and train them up as well as you can Bring them up in the fear of
                    the lord &amp; to do good</p>

                <p>My Dear children be obedient to your Ma who is now more than over burdened with
                    grief &amp; trouble conduct yourselves in such way as to make her happy.
                    attend school try &amp; learn as fast as can Keep off the streets and out of
                    bad try to be good &amp; do good. We are separated now but it will not be
                    long so I soon expect <pb n="4"/> to see and be with you and hope we can then
                    all live happy together give my love to all our kin &amp; kind friends</p>

                <p>Hester as I wrote you M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> J Thomas &amp; family is here with us &amp; Miss G Snodgrass</p>

                <p>M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">rs</hi>
                    </hi> G had a frollic 4 days ago &amp; produced 2 boys one dead the other
                    alive &amp; she doing well I have nothing new of importance to write you. I
                    hope soon to get well</p>

                <p>Write soon</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <abbr expan="John">J</abbr>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
