<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8005"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="A8005">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William Kinney to Alexander H. H. Stuart,
     November 30, 1852</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william kinney to alexander h h stuart, november 30 1852</title>
        <author>Kinney, William</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A8005</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502657</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William Kinney to Alexander H. H. Stuart, November 30, 1852</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william kinney to alexander h h stuart, november 30 1852</title>
            <author>William Kinney</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Kinney to Alexander H. H. Stuart, 30
       November 1852, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the Related Stuart and Baldwin Families,
       1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Box 3, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia
       Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1852-11-30">1852-11-30</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>State Government, Agriculture, African Americans, Slavery</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A8005T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Kinney relates to Stuart legal matters in Staunton, the election of "Mr. Toms" to "cashier,"
     the upcoming appointment for "Marshall for the Western District of Virginia." Also asks about
     rumor he heard that Stuart was contemplating buying a farm near Washington, D. C. </p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">W.m. <hi rend="underline">Kinney</hi><lb/><hi rend="underline">Staunton</hi></name>
     <name type="place">Staunton</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1852-11-30">30th: Nov. 1852</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Stuart.</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have been wishing and intending to write you for some time past, but Courts Banks &amp;
     c. have interposed to prevent my carrying it out. our Superior Court is just about to adjourn
     the Judge being compelled to leave in the <orig reg="morning">morng</orig>: to attend the
     District or intermediate Court of appeals, which meets tomorrow at Charlottesville. the whole
     of our Term has been occupied with criminals, four have been convicted, one a hung jury in, and
     one acquited, one of the four convicted has a motion <unclear>depending</unclear> for a new
     trial, which the judge is to decide this <orig reg="morning">morng</orig>: not a civil common
     law case was tried, some few chancery cases were disposed of. The court will adjourn to the
     31st <orig reg="January">Jany</orig>: when an extra term will be held extending if necessary to
     the 1st March.</p>
    <p>We have been beset with troubles and difficulties about our Cashier on the day we were to
     elect one the friend of Mr. Jns. Wayt of Waynesboro: placed him in nomination <orig
      reg="though">tho</orig> a very worthy man, I could not think him for many reasons suited to
     the place, but his friends <orig reg="Colonel">Col</orig> Crawford, <orig reg="William"
     >Wm</orig> A Bell, &amp; J B. Breckinridge pressed his claims most earnestly. <orig
      reg="Misters">Messrs</orig> Price, Eskridge &amp; myself those of Handsen,
      <unclear>Clerk</unclear><pb n="2"/>&amp; <unclear>Court</unclear> chose of Mr. Toms. after
     serious ballotings, finding we could make no choice between them, Eskridge placed the name of
     N. K. Trout in nomination, which after two ballots resulted in his election by a vote of 7 to
     1. I voting against him for Handsen, he not having been consulted he asked he might be allowed
     a few days to make up his mind, which was allowed, and he finally declined his relatives old
     Mr. Stribling, <orig reg="Doctor">Doct.</orig> L. S. Nichols, Jeff &amp; myself all being
     opposed to his accepting. So contest came on again, between the three first named candidates,
     and resulted as before, being divided as at first &amp; we adjourned over to Thursday last
     in order that we might learn Sheffeys views, which we did. Toms was his first &amp; Handsen
     his second choices. we met again and after two ballots, it resulted in the unanimous election
     of Toms. Handsen I preferred to any other on various accounts, some of which you &amp; me
     spoke of when in Washington, but it seemed as <orig reg="though">th'o</orig> some Gentleman who
     he had expected to have voted for him, would not go for him, finding this to be the case I
     finally voted for Tom's, who I have every reason to believe will make us an excellent Cashier,
     he has been with us for several days &amp; all seem to be much pleased with him, we set out
     tomorrow for Washington, Alexandria &amp; York &amp; will probably see you I have
     requested him to see <unclear>Chall </unclear>Brothers &amp; <unclear>Selden</unclear>
     &amp; Co. we have to elect<pb n="3"/> a clerk on Saturday, thus far we have poor materials
     out of which to choose.</p>
    <p>There was some little dissatisfaction expressed by some few individuals on the first
     announcement of the appointment of Marshall for the Western District of Virginia, but it
     appeared in a measure to have died away, but the effort is now being made to get up excitement
     about it, and to put in a thorough bred Loco. It is represented that Ambler was not a resident
     of the Western District, that you could find no man in it fit for the office, &amp; had to
     go to the Eastern District &amp; to a County that have wished a Marshall for the <orig
      reg="East">E.</orig> District. they say he was living in Fauq &amp; carrying on a cheese
     factory. that all Mr. Mason influence cannot and shall not save him. Letcher &amp; Judge
     Kenney were here yesterday quite <unclear>wrathy</unclear> on the occasion. I said to Letcher I
     had heard that Dr Graham would be a prominent candidate for the office he replied he did not
     know, said <orig reg="General">Genl</orig> D B Layne was the most so he thought, you may rest
     assured powerful efforts will be make to defeat Ambler. The office is a good one &amp; many
     want it.</p>
    <p>Taylor got home last night &amp; improved a good deal on his trip. he tells me you are
     talking of purchasing a farm near Washington, I hope with no view to a residence. old Mr <del
      hand="h1"/> yesterday said you was going to <orig reg="Baltimore">Balto</orig>: to <del
      hand="h1"/>, as that. I hope she is mistaken &amp; that we shall have you back among us in
     March.</p>
    <pb n="4"/>
    <p>The health of Staunton is now pretty good. we have had some right severe weather, but <orig
      reg="today">to-day</orig> is pleasant.</p>
    <p>The Judge has refused the new trial.</p>
    <p>With my best respects to Mrs. Stuart &amp; the family of Harper</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Very Respectfully &amp; truly<lb/>Yrs</salute>
     <signed>Wm Kinney</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">P.S. <unclear>Rich</unclear> Jos Wood <orig reg="administrator"
      >adm</orig> to whom the money for the sale of the Ballards negro is coming is <hi
       rend="underline">very pressing</hi> for it. I have mentioned it to Young several times. I
      told Robert I expected it would certainly be paid during this Court. Let me hear from you
      about it.</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
