<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8006"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8006">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Millard Fillmore to Alexander H. H.
                    Stuart, February 9, 1854</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county millard fillmore to alexander h h stuart, february 9 1854</title>
        <author>Fillmore, Millard</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8006</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502658</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Millard Fillmore to Alexander H. H. Stuart, February
                            9, 1854</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county millard fillmore to alexander h h stuart, february 9 1854</title>
            <author>Millard Fillmore</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Millard Fillmore to Alexander H.
                            H. Stuart, 9 February 1854, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the
                            Related Stuart and Baldwin Families, 1776-1878, Accession #228-a,
                            Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1854-02-09">1854-02-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, Slavery, Unionism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8006T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Fillmore invites Stuart to accompany him on a tour of the South, then discusses
                    the Kansas-Nebraska Act which he thinks will be passed by the Senate, although
                    he fears the consequences.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1854-02-09">February 9. 1854,</date>
                        <name type="place">Buffalo</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Yours of the <orig reg="3rd">3o</orig> ult. came duly to hand but I have delayed
                    writing you from day to day, and week to week, 1st. because I had nothing
                    apparently worth communicating and <orig reg="secondly">2ndly</orig> because I
                    was trying to make some arrangements to take a Southern tour this Spring and if
                    I did so, I was <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> that it might suit your convenience to
                    accompany me. I have written to our mutual friend Mr. Kennedy who consents to
                    go, and I have also written to Mr. Granger who will go if he can arrange his
                    business so as to leave it, but of this he expresses considerable doubt. I think
                    a party of three or four would be most pleasant. Will you consent to make one of
                    it? I can assure you that I should be greatly gratified to have you, and I know
                    Mr. Kennedy would.</p>
                <pb n="2"/>
                <p>Our intention is to go down through the Southern Atlantic States, to Mobile and
                    thence back to Savannah where we will take a steamer for Havanna, and possibly
                    visit some other of the West India Islands, and thence to N. Orleans, and up the
                    Mississippi through Tennessee and <orig reg="Kentucky">Ky.</orig> to Cincinnati
                    and thence home. This route, however, may be shortened, lengthened, or varied to
                    suit circumstances. We would rendezvous at Baltimore, about the 1st of March,
                    and might hope to accomplish it all in from one to two months. Will you not go?
                    Can you spend the same length of time more pleasantly or even more profitably in
                    any other way? It seems to me not, so let us calculate on the pleasure of your
                    society.</p>
                <p>This Nebraska matter presents a new phase to things in Washington. But is it wise
                    for the South to set the example separating the compromise of 1820? If one
                    compromise be disregarded will not another be, and will not the South in the end
                    be left to the <hi rend="underline">tender mercy</hi> of Northern fanaticism
                    with an overwhelming numerical majority? These are<pb n="3"/> Serious questions
                    for the South and yes it may be difficult for her to resist the proffered favor
                    of Douglas' Bill. She may suspect the motive; she may see its fatal consequences
                    and its delusive benefits, but can she resist it?</p>
                <p>I think the measure will pass the senate by a decided majority, but its fate is
                    doubtful in the house, and there is reason to apprehend that it will reopen the
                    slavery agitation, <del hand="h1">much</del> with all its bitterness, if not all
                    its dangers to our Union. We had fondly hoped that this question was at rest,
                    for a time at least, but I fear we are to be disappointed.</p>
                <p>My children are very well, and join me in kindest remembrances to yourself and
                    Mrs. Stuart.</p>
                <p>I shall write Mr. Kennedy today that I have invited you to join us.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am truly yours,</salute>
                    <signed>Millard Fillmore</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient">Hon.<lb/>A. H. H. Stuart<lb/>Staunton, Va.</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
