<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8019"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8019">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: L. Luckett to Alexander H. H.
                    Stuart, September 2, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county l luckett to alexander h h stuart, september 2 1861</title>
        <author>Luckett, L.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8019</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502671</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: L. Luckett to Alexander H. H. Stuart, September 2,
                            1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county l luckett to alexander h h stuart, september 2 1861</title>
            <author>L. Luckett</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: L. Luckett to Alexander H. H.
                            Stuart, 2 September 1861, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the
                            Related Stuart and Baldwin Families, 1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Box 3,
                            Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-09-02">1861-09-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Troop Movement, Agriculture, Patriotism, Home Front, Slavery,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8019T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Luckett describes the "long tedious" trip back to Louisiana from Virginia. He
                    reports his crops are in good condition, and describes war prepartions for the
                    coming conflict of "Saxon against Norman, the Puritan &amp; Cavalier."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-09-02">Sep 2nd, 1861</date>
                        <name type="place">Ashbourne La</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>We had a very agreeable ride to Richmond, and made a stay in that City till
                    Saturday morning, when we started South. We were very much indebted to <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Cap.</abbr> Baldwin, for making our time as pleasant in
                    Richmond as it was <abbr expan="through">thro</abbr> his politeness &amp;
                    attention, we were able to see the manufacture of war instruments, from the
                    percussion cap &amp; minie ball, up to the Dalgreen gun &amp; rifled
                    Cannon. Ellen had a very pressing invitation to spend her time in the country a
                    few miles down Jame's River, and I was very near availing myself of it &amp;
                    pay a visit to Manassas on Saturday, which would have <unclear>enabled</unclear>
                    me to see the great fight of the 21st. But having no suspicion that another
                    battle would have followed so soon the one of the 18th, &amp; not having
                    heard from Home and the cotton gathering season with in a few days, I
                    unfortunately left on Saturday morning.</p>
                <p>We had a long tedious trip to orleans -- so much<pb n="2"/> detention from long
                    trains of Cars loaded with Soldiers, that we were detained in Bristol all day on
                    Sunday, and <unclear>delayed</unclear> another day in Loudon from a wash in the
                    road caused by the horrid rains I had seen fall for some time. The Battle of
                    Manassas had preceded us of course, and the war fever was raging along the road
                    in N. Orleans and at Home, with ten fold more violence than when I left.</p>
                <p>I found a Boat in Orleans ready for the mouth of the Red River, from which plain
                    we took steps for Alexandria, and reached home within two hours of three weeks
                    from the time I left. I found the crops of corn &amp; cotton any thing we
                    would desire--the first enough to bread us for two years in a pinch &amp;
                    the latter promising an abundant yield. But for the last two weeks we have a
                        <unclear>suspicion</unclear> of rain that rarely falls in our
                    Summers--bringing in their <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> too, two of the most destructive
                    pests that the Crop is subject to--Boll worm &amp; Cotton<pb n="3"/>
                    <unclear>pitter</unclear>. Several of my neighbors are now complaining that
                    their crops are half eaten up. I see very few in mine yet. We have also had
                    Typhoid Fever all around us, but have escaped yet, <abbr expan="though"
                    >th'o</abbr> Robert thinks we had two cases among the servants while I was
                    about. We have had &amp; are now having a great deal of little
                        <unclear>fever</unclear> among our field hands, only lasting two or three
                    days, but interferes very much with our Cotton picking. One planter on Bayou
                    Bocuffe had forty to come in on one day.</p>
                <p>The War Spirit is not abating, but burns as brightly as ever, Companies are
                    mustering or passing down <unclear>every week</unclear>--With a voting
                    population of about 1400 our Parish has sent <orig reg="off">of</orig> eight
                    companies &amp; now raising a Battalion of Horse. Our Wives &amp;
                    Daughters are busily engaged in Knitting socks &amp; making flannel under
                    clothing for the army in Virginia--all the latter article has been exhausted in
                    our Town &amp; we had to send to orleans for a supply, and the sewing
                        mach<pb n="4"/>ine &amp; the busy fingers are going from morning till
                    night. I believe our women have more Patriotism than our men, and the latter
                    would flag sometimes but for the former--not for love of Country, but for want
                    of energy--but the Ladies give them no <unclear>rest</unclear>, it is go ahead
                    with <unclear>things</unclear> here <unclear>&amp; forever</unclear>. This
                    war with all its ills of losses &amp; suffering &amp; blood is better
                    for us than <abbr expan="would">wd.</abbr> have been peaceful separation.</p>
                <p>There are many here on our confines, many in Texas &amp; many of our French
                    Creoles, who never go from home, &amp; have heard perhaps of Virginia
                    Maryland &amp; <abbr expan="North">N</abbr> Carolina, but know no more about
                    them &amp; care as little as for Canada or Cuba--This war will bring them
                    all in contact--Bull Run &amp; Manassas-Richmond &amp; Winchester--Blue
                    Ridge &amp; Arlington Heights--the by paths &amp; crossroads will be
                    familiar as their own Prairies &amp; Canebrakes--they will fight too side by
                    side &amp; eat together &amp; lie down together--&amp; many will
                    become familiar &amp; go down to their childrens children, where they fight
                    their battles or <unclear>gain</unclear> by the fireside-- <unclear>Who has brot
                        out too</unclear> the character of the <unclear>Raw</unclear> from whom
                        we<pb n="5"/> have separated a People who for generations, for love of money
                    &amp; gain, had <unclear>concealed</unclear> a perfidy, hypocrisy and
                    bloodthirstyness unequaled in the history of civilization. I doubt whether races
                    ever change their organic nature--the Catacombs of Egypt have revealed the fact
                    that the negro is the same formation <orig reg="today">to day</orig> that he had
                    three thousand years ago, and the Yankee is the same now that he was in the time
                    of Cromwell, hypocritical, <unclear>agrarian</unclear> and hating of other <del
                        hand="h1"/>--It is the same now that it was more than two hundred years
                    ago--the Saxon against the Norman, the Puritan &amp; Cavalier, and at this
                    time Mason &amp; Dixons line divids two Races as different, as the Irish
                    &amp; the English, the Gaul &amp; the German.</p>
                <p>As well might the Indian &amp; the White man live together as equals as the
                    Southern &amp; the Yankee.<pb n="6"/> The Huguenot is the same now he was in
                    the time of Henry the 4th brave, faithful &amp; religious &amp; the
                    Cavalier the same bold, <unclear>unchanaged</unclear>, high toned gentleman, as
                    when he fought &amp; gave his life for Charles the 1st.</p>
                <p>I wish the separation had been in an earlier day of my life--I <abbr
                        expan="would">wd.</abbr> like to live to see the South have a fair &amp;
                    untrammeled start in the race of Peoples, for I think She is destined to be as
                    far superior to all others as the <unclear>Caucasian</unclear> was to the Mongol
                    &amp; others.</p>
                <p>With a climate comprising nearly all the degrees of the temperate zone, from the
                    region of the apple to the orange; from that of the hemp to the wheat, to the
                    cotton &amp; sugar, with mountains containing all of the minerals of the
                    world, to the plains covered with cattle in countless herds, with an excess of
                    surplus of Cotton Sugar &amp; Tobacco alone of 300000000 and a people as<pb
                        n="7"/> brave &amp; chivalrous as the Romans in the height of fame, why
                    should we not be the greatest people in the world?</p>
                <p>Could there be a more significant sign &amp; more illustrative of the two
                    races, than the horrors of the present Northern cabinet--Abraham, Simon, Gideon,
                    Solomon, Caleb, and Hannibal--five parts Puritan &amp; one <orig
                        reg="African">Affrican</orig>. I hope our patriotic women may be able to
                    clothe our whole army with woolens for the winter--it would be an honor that no
                    other nation <unclear>can</unclear> attend to. The South can loan to the
                    Government 100 <unclear>millions</unclear> of cotton, the half of the Crop,
                    without any inconvenience to them, and do this as long as the war lasts,
                    &amp; make the interest by a direct tax with out a murmur.</p>
                <p>Our <hi rend="underline">Thunderbolt</hi> is expected to leave<pb n="8"/> Orleans
                    this night, &amp; is to receive the <unclear>fire</unclear> from the
                        <unclear>forty-1st</unclear>
                    <unclear>Mississippi</unclear> &amp; <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> as the
                    <unclear>proper</unclear> down to try <unclear>her</unclear> strength &amp;
                    capacity of resistance. She is entirely ironclad with a proboscis of iron, and a
                    Cannon of 120 lbs ball, to fire when she <unclear>strikes</unclear>.</p>
                <p>We shall be hard up here for coffee &amp; bacon by christmas, if the ports
                    are not opened before that. Texas with her beeves can supply the meat, but the
                    want of coffee will be a great trial to the patriotism of the Girls--They can
                    dispense with everything but rice, coffee &amp; chickens.</p>
                <p>Henry with the whole family is very anxious that you would let Sandy come out in
                    the fall spend the winter with us, we have an admirable Teacher &amp; he
                    would get the advantage of early rising as he has Scholars up by candle light in
                    the winter. Mrs. L. &amp; the Girls <unclear>desire</unclear>
                    <unclear>to be most affect</unclear>, remembered to you all.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Very <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> &amp; truly</salute>
                    <signed>L Luckett</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
