<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8024"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8024">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, October 7, 1860</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county j d imboden to john mccue, october 7 1860</title>
        <author>Imboden, J.D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A8024</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502675</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, October 7, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county j d imboden to john mccue, october 7 1860</title>
            <author>J. D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, 7 October 1860, Papers
       of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406, Box 4, Special Collections Department,
       University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1860-10-07">1860-10-07</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Economy</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A8024T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Imboden, who has been sick, discusses finances and a loan he helped secure for John
    McCue.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1860-10-07">Oct 7. 1860</date>
      <name type="place">Staunton</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear John.</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I would have written to you before now but I have been sick for two or three days.</p>
    <p>When I came home I fortunately met with your father, and talked over your affairs with him,
     and put at him to advance you $500. I did this for two reasons--first because I thought it was
     right--and secondly because I found it would be a difficult matter for <hi rend="underline"
     >me</hi> to spare the 500$ from the source I expected--or rather a doubtful matter for me to
     get it. Your father mentioned the stringency of money matters with him--and did not see
      <unclear>well here</unclear> he was to do it. I then proposed to advance $250 and that he
     should advance a like sum. He at once agreed to do this. The money to be sent you one day this
     week before I leave. We parted with that understanding.</p>
    <p>On yesterday I was down street a little while &amp; met him again--He told me that after
     going home he thought over the matter--and as tight as money was with<pb n="2"/>him he had
     determined to lend you the whole amount himself--not as a Loan as I had proposed, but as an <hi
      rend="underline">advancement</hi>--That that sum would do you more good now than would the
     amount hereafter--I told him I had no doubt of it and approved heartily what he proposed to
     do--So this matter is off your shoulders--I also named the Alec. Wills matter to him--but that
     is out of his power--and I cant see how that can be arranged--I wish it could for it would make
     you $600 very easily--But you will have to let it go unless you can strike some old fellow with
     money who will advance it and divide profits with you.</p>
    <p>I have been unwell more or less ever since I came home--and for the two last days confined to
     the house with the same complaint I had in <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>--It got a great deal worse--On
     Friday I sent for Dr. Baldwin who has put me nearly all right again. I hope by tomorrow to be
     entirely well--</p>
    <p>I found a letter here awaiting<pb n="3"/>me on my return from <unclear>Mr. McPhail</unclear>.
     We leave for Kentucky on next Thursday--the 11th.</p>
    <p>If I can get my matters fixed up tomorrow I will go to <unclear>Charlotte</unclear> on
     Tuesday--If I fail in this I will not leave till Thursday morning and then meet Mr. McPhail in
     Lynchburg Thursday morning.</p>
    <p>All our folks are well--With love to Coz. Liz and the children, I am as ever</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your friend</salute>
     <signed>J. D. Imboden</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">P.S. When Old Dr. Coleman pays up send me a check for my fee as I shall
      be pretty hard up this fall</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
