<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8035"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8035">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: George W. Imboden to John McCue,
                    October 6, 1858</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county george w imboden to john mccue, october 6 1858</title>
        <author>Imboden, George W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8035</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502686</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: George W. Imboden to John McCue, October 6, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county george w imboden to john mccue, october 6 1858</title>
            <author>George W. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: George W. Imboden to John McCue,
                            6 October 1858, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406,
                            Box 3, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-10-06">1858-10-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8035T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>George W. Imboden relates ongoings in Staunton and an attempted suicide.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-10-06">Oct 6<hi rend="underline">th</hi> 1858</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your favor of the 29 <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> was duly received and I
                    hasten to reply. I went out to your house this morning to see about the boxes,
                    you spoke about, they are not at the house and I could not ascertain whether
                    they were at the depot, all your boxes were thrown in a pile, I seen
                        <unclear>Burk</unclear> in regard to a car, he told me he would charge you
                    thirteen dollars for a car, and that he would ship your goods on Saturday next,
                    so that you may look out for them at Afton or on Monday, he says you can pay the
                    freight there as well as in Staunton.</p>
                <p>Well John there is no news of any importance in Staunton, things are still going
                    on in their usual course, <abbr expan="Though">Tho.</abbr> we miss you very
                    much, I have the question frequently asked me where you are, and how you are
                    pleased with Nelson, the Federal Court is in <orig reg="session">cession</orig>
                    <abbr expan="though">tho.</abbr> there will be very little business done at this
                    term, the Jarvis <unclear>land</unclear> suits will not be tried I think.</p>
                <p>We looked for you over this last<pb n="2"/>week. We have a very melancholy case
                    of attempted suicide. I allude to a man of the name of Bushnell from the city of
                    Washington who arrived in Staunton on Friday last and stoped at the American
                    hotel and in a fit of derangement attempted to kill himself--by shooting himself
                    in the back of the head, he is still alive at this time <abbr expan="though"
                        >tho.</abbr> there is no hope of his recovery, the ball entered above
                    &amp; behind the right ear and lodged in the fore part of the head, more
                    than a teacup full of brains were lying on the floor when he was found.</p>
                <p>I was down at Tinkling Spring on Sunday and took dinner at your Father's. They
                    are all well, the old gentleman had just returned from a trip to Albemarle,</p>
                <p>John thinks he will visit Nelson this next week if nothing happens,</p>
                <p>John there was a man in town on last Monday who wanted to pay some money to you
                    as the<pb n="3"/>surety of <unclear>Brodi</unclear>, I have forgotten his name,
                    he requested me to write to you and get the note as he is anxious to pay the
                    money! The parties interested in the deed of trust to you from
                    <unclear>Sillings</unclear> for the benefit of 1 A Patterson, were in town and
                    want you to execute a release deed, as the trust is satisfied.</p>
                <p>I believe I have given you all the news I have to write, and therefore will stop,
                    give my love to all the Family, and write soon and let me know how you are
                    pleased with your new home</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your friend</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">Geo W. Imboden</hi>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
