<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8064"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8064">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta County: E. Stuart to her son, circa 1860-1861</title>
                <title>[electronic resource] </title>
                <title type="sort">augusta county e stuart to her son, circa 1860 1861</title>
                <author>L. M. Powell</author>
                <editor/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Sarah Maxwell</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8064</idno>

                <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
                <availability status="public">
                    <p n="copyright">Copyright &amp;amp;amp;amp;#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                    <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
                </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
                <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502658</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
                <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
            </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Augusta County: E. Stuart to her son, circa 1860-1861</title>
                        <title level="m"/>
                        <title type="sort">augusta county e stuart to her son, circa 1860 1861</title>
                        <author>E. Stuart</author>
                        <editor/>
                        <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the 
                            Related Stuart and Baldwin Families, 1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                    University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861">1861</date>
            </creation>
            <langUsage>
                <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
            </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Slavery, Land, Taxes, Estate</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
            <change>
                <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University
                        of Virginia Library</name>
                    <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD
                    (uva-dl-tei).</item>
            </change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8064T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 id="d3" type="summary">
                <p>E. Stuart writes to her son about inheritance and debt. She also mentions relatives and acquaintances.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 id="d5" type="letter">
                <head>E. Stuart to her son,
                    c. 1860 - 1861</head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Thursday 17th
                        
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Son</salute>		Private
                </opener>

                <p>I was greatly surprised to find from your letter, that you were under the impression I 
was dissatisfied with the family having to pay their portion of what is due the estate.  The 
only objections I ever heard [] were from Jefferson, who objected on two points, the 
Kentucky Lands &amp; the Granny Miller Lot.  . . . As to myself I never intended to charge her 
a cent, believing the Lott was to be the consideration for her maintenance, &amp; for all the 
difference it will make to you, I would let it be settled in that way. . . .  Moreover Archy 
had the burthen of four old negroes Old Cato Esther Ben &amp; Stafford, &amp; Ben was a 
Loathsome cripple with a sore leg, but lived with Archy 15 years.  Sowers[?] estate gave 
three hundred for the keeping of a man, who was said to be a good gardener.  You are all 
my children &amp;amp;amp; I wish for nothing but justice among you.</p>
                <pb n="2"/>
                <p>//. . . .I have always my dear Son given you all due credit for your industry tact, &amp;amp; 
general good management, But then your dear Father preceded you in good management, 
or you would not have had the property which admitted of such good management &amp;
profitable results [] &amp;amp; your Grandfather also, who gave me the Land, which was 
exchanged for the aforesaid Kentucky Land.  My dear beloved Child, do justice love 
mercy, &amp;amp; walk humbly with your God.  Give yourself no unnecessary uneasiness about 
wealthy children, for in ninety nine cases out of a hundred they are the most thankless of 
human beings.  I approve of your writing to Harrison on the subject of selling Archy's 
Land. . . . I am induced to believe that it will pay Archy's debt to you . . . .What little 
money Archy has at interest, I do not wish touched, It requires no management, &amp; will 
always be available for the schooling of his children, &amp; a final resort in case of a state of 
starvation. . . . I am also anxious Gerard should sell off his surplus Land &amp; relieve himself 
of debt.  I will from time to time remind him of the necessity, but you 
can do more than any 
person on earth. Whenever I allude to his affairs, or my anxiety about his debts, he will not 
even make me an answer, or if at all, only yes or no.//. . .I do not 
think in all my life, I ever 
felt so perfectly depressed, &amp; unfit for business or social intercourse.  Every thing seems to 
me in a state of confusion &amp; helplessness. . . .Baldwin left me the day after his Mother &amp;amp; 
family went off.  If you should ever need a plain faithful industrious clerk, I can with a 
good conscience recommend Sam Dyer.  &amp; Roscoe Stuart hes just left here.  he seems to 
have a good opinion of Baldwin's sense[?].  I am pleased to see they appear attached to 
each other.</p>
                <p>I hope when you receive this scrawl, you will have Fanny &amp; little ones around you.  
God bless you all my My dearest Son</p>
                
                <closer>
                    
                    <signed>E Stuart</signed>
                    
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>