<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9906"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9906">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett,
                    November 13, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john d imboden to annie lockett, november 13 1870</title>
        <author>Imboden, J.D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9906</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502849</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, November 13, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john d imboden to annie lockett, november 13 1870</title>
            <author>J.D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: J.D. Imboden to Miss Annie, Nov.
                            13, 1870, John D. Imboden Papers, University of Virginia Library,
                            Accession Numbers 38-23, 580, 599, 2983a</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-11-13">1870-11-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9906T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden asks his new fiancee to accede to his preference for an early
                wedding.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-11-13">Sunday night Nov 13th 1870</date>
                        <name type="place">Keysville</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My darling-</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>To ensure a letter from you at the earliest moment, since you told me you would
                    not write till you <abbr expan="received">rec'd.</abbr> a letter from me, I have
                    managed to get a sheet of foolscap here, and before I retire will devote it to
                    you.</p>

                <p>I did not start a moment too soon this morning, as it occupied me <hi
                        rend="underline">all</hi> day hand mauling my mule to reach here a little
                    after dark. I only lost my way once, &amp; I charge that to you - I was
                    singing &amp; thinking of my Annie and permitting the mule to have its own
                    way when true to its instincts it took the wrong road &amp; I lost a mile of
                    distance before I was set right. The way I came today was more of a wilderness
                    than the other route. I only met six people during the whole day - and the
                    country had an abandoned wilderness aspect, that would have made me sad, but for
                    the happy frame of mind I was in all day. Being quite sure that no one would
                    hear me in the wilderness, I gave expression to my happiness in singing, at
                    times as loud as the leader at a camp meeting. I sing all the hymns I knew,
                    &amp; all the little snatches of good and sentimental songs I could
                    remember, and the whole day you were not absent <pb n="2"/>from my thoughts 3
                    minutes. If you could fully realize how dear you are to me you would not wonder
                    that I am so urgent to make the time as short as possible before I bring you
                    away with me forever. In thinking over today my wonderful good fortune in
                    winning you, and how grateful I ought to be to have secured your love at all,
                    &amp; then recalling the earnestness with which I begged you to consent to
                    our marriage in March after you had informed me how much you wished to have your
                    sisters present, it has occurred to me that you may have thought me too selfish
                    in thus trying to have you gratify my wishes at the expense of your own. And I
                    was almost sorry I had thus pressed you to do what might give you pain to comply
                    with. I am now conscious that I allowed my <del hand="h1">own</del> impatience
                    to have you at the earliest day my own dear <hi rend="underline">wife</hi> to
                    make me more importunate than I should have been to fix a day in March. And I
                    now feel that it is my duty to consult mainly <hi rend="underline">your</hi>
                    pleasure in this matter and to rely upon your love for me to comply with my
                    wishes if you can do so without marring your own pleasure &amp; that of your
                    sisters. You know my reasons for insisting upon our speedy marriage. You know
                    how earnestly I desire it. You know what a sacrifice of happiness it will be to
                    me to have that happy day delayed, and yet I would rather "possess my soul in
                    patience" and <pb n="3"/>bear the anxieties of a longer time than to feel that I
                    had purchased one hour of my happiness at the price of any disappointment to <hi
                        rend="underline">you</hi>. Trusting wholly to your love to do what is right
                    &amp; best for me &amp; for you, I now wish to say that you must fix a
                    time that will confer most pleasure upon yourself, &amp; should it be
                    further off than March I will try and be patient &amp; not complain. The
                    assurance that you love me, and will one of these days be my precious wife,
                    ought to bring me happiness enough to sustain me waiting you own good pleasure
                    in naming the day for crowning our happiness - and it shall.</p>

                <p>That sweet voluntary kiss you gave me this mornign as we left the parlor the last
                    time, when you stopped near the door, turned up your sweet face beaming
                    &amp; radiant with love &amp; confidence, not uttered, but spoken by
                    your eyes, to mine, is enough to live on &amp; be happy for weeks to come. I
                    am not writing boyish nonsense to you, but simply expressing to you the devotion
                    of a heart that has passed through firey ordeals in the past, that have only
                    added to its tenderness. When you said to me yesterday that you would be mine, I
                    felt that life again for me was to be tinted with rose colors, and I felt for
                    you as I impressed the first kiss upon the lips that had first spoken me into
                    this renewed joyous existence, an <pb n="4"/>unexpressible gush of tender love
                    for you that will never die in my heart or be forgotten. I do long for the time
                    to come when by all the sanction of the law &amp; of religion you will be
                    mine, &amp; folded in my arms you will no longer feel restrained by maidenly
                    timidity in telling me in words, over &amp; over again, what I already know
                    in your acts, that you do indeed love me, better than all the world besides. I
                    know the worth of a true woman's love. I know how pure - how unselfish &amp;
                    how exhaustless it is - and to be told again &amp; again that this treasure
                    is mine will be more than a compensation for all the anxiety &amp; all the
                    pain of the delay you may feel obliged to impose on me. How I wish you lived
                    where I could see you often. But as that cannot be you must write to me without
                    reserve and promptly in reply to all my letters. You told me you were not <hi
                        rend="underline">demonstrative</hi>. I want to teach you to become so. I
                    know you have deep &amp; tender feelings. You must express them in your
                    words &amp; acts both. Between <hi rend="underline">us</hi> there must be no
                    reserve, but the freest and most <del hand="h1">perfect</del> perfect exposure
                    of our hearts, each to the other. You will find me ever quick to respond in
                    sympathy &amp; in words to every utterance from your heart. Henceforth you
                    are interwoven in my life. You are ever present in my thoughts, &amp; every
                    act &amp; every plan of my daily life will be considered in reference to
                    your happiness.</p>

                <p><pb n="5"/>When you hear from your sisters, write me all they say. I know the
                    disparity in our ages will be commented on. By your sisters not unkindly but by
                    others it may be. Do not let it annoy you. You will find in me as young a heart
                    as ever laid its inmost affections upon the altar of wedded love - and as our
                    future living will depend <pb n="6"/>for their happiness, not upon what the
                    world may have to say but upon ourselves. I wish to begin early to teach you
                    what I have learned from a large &amp; long experience, that the less we
                    heed the thoughtless expressions of the herd of mankind the happier we are. <pb
                        n="7"/>Now my own darling Annie goodbye! Be joyous &amp; happy every
                    day. At your cousin's wedding I hope to hear you are as happy as the bride. I
                    don't know her but as your cousin I venture to send her a message. Tell her when
                    you move to Richmond she must come &amp; see you &amp; your husband and
                    see what a mistake she made in not marrying a widower instead of a young fellow.
                        <pb n="8"/>Give my love to all. In your own <hi rend="underline">family</hi>
                    circle talk of me every day. I want my name henceforth to be a household word as
                    one of your family. God bless you always my darling</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours forever</salute>
                    <signed>J.D.I.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
